Sentence,Entities
"""In the full confidence of valour and victory, I once aspired (said Adolphus) to change the face of the universe; to obliterate the name of Rome; to erect on its ruins the dominion of the Goths; and to acquire, like Augustus, the immortal fame of the founder of a new empire.","('Adolphus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"""The irruption of these nations was followed by the most dreadful calamities: as the barbarians exercised their indiscriminate cruelty on the fortunes of the Romans and the Spaniards, and ravaged with equal fury the cities and the open country.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Spaniards', 'NORP')"
"""The marbles of the Anician palace,""   were used as a proverbial expression of opulence and splendour;(23) but the nobles and senators of Rome aspired in due gradation to imitate that illustrious family.","('Anician', 'NORP'), ('23', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
(3),"('3', 'CARDINAL')"
(31),"('31', 'CARDINAL')"
(75),"('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 solemn treaty was stipulated and observed: Placidia was
 honourably restored to her brother; six hundred thousand
 measures of wheat were delivered to the hungry Goths;(164) 
 and Wallia engaged to draw his sword in the service of the
 empire.","('Placidia', 'PERSON'), ('six hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('164', 'CARDINAL'), ('Wallia', 'PERSON')"
"A bloody war was instantly excited among the
 barbarians of Spain; and the contending princes are said to
 have addressed their letters, their ambassadors, and their
 hostages, to the throne of the Western emperor, exhorting
 him to remain a tranquil spectator of their contest, the
 events of which must be favourable to the Romans by the
 mutual slaughter of their common enemies.(165)","('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('165', 'CARDINAL')"
"A considerable mass of treasure must 
 always have existed at Rome, either in the current coin of
 the empire, or in the form of gold and silver plate; and
 there were many sideboards in the time of Pliny which
 contained more solid silver than had been transported by
 Scipio from vanquished Carthage.(32)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Scipio', 'PERSON'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"A dark suspicion
 was entertained that some desperate wretches fed on the
 bodies of their fellow-creatures whom they had secretly
 murdered; and even mothers (such was the horrid conflict of
 the two most powerful instincts implanted by nature in the
 human breast), even mothers are said to have tasted the
 flesh of their slaughtered infants!(76)Plague.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('76', 'CARDINAL')"
"A decent and respectful
 attention was paid to the restoration of the capital; the
 citizens were encouraged to rebuild the edifices which had
 been destroyed or damaged by hostile fire; and extraordinary
 supplies of corn were imported from the coast of Africa.","('Africa', 'LOC')"
"A fine of three, or even five, pounds of gold was
 imposed on the absent representatives, who seem to have
 declined this imaginary gift of a free constitution, as the
 last and most cruel insult of their oppressors.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('five, pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"A master of that sublime science, who in a supper or assembly is placed below a magistrate, displays in his countenance the surprise and indignation which Cato might be supposed to feel when he was refused the praetorship by the votes of a capricious people.","('Cato', 'PERSON')"
"A more rational
 method of inquiry might not have been undeserving of the
 attention of the wisest princes, who could easily have
 resolved a question so important for the Roman government
 and so interesting to succeeding ages.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"A more regular discipline than
 could have been expected was maintained in the camp of
 Alaric; and the wise barbarian justified his regard for the
 faith of treaties, by the just severity with which he
 chastised a party of licentious Goths who had insulted some
 Roman citizens on the road to Ostia.","('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Ostia', 'PERSON')"
"A secure and profound peace, such as had been once enjoyed in the reign of Numa, succeeded to the tumults of a republic; while Rome was still adored as the queen of the earth, and the subject nations still reverenced the name of the people and the majesty of the senate.","('Numa', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"A victorious leader, who united the daring
 spirit of a barbarian with the art and discipline of a Roman
 general, was at the head of an hundred thousand fighting
 men; and Italy pronounced with terror and respect the
 formidable name of Alaric.(81)
Fruitless negotiations for peace, A.D. 409.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('an hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('81', 'CARDINAL'), ('409', 'CARDINAL')"
"About the same time a general amnesty
 was published in the name of Honorius, to abolish the guilt
 and memory of all the involuntary offences which had been
 committed by his unhappy subjects during the term of the
 public disorder and calamity.","('Honorius', 'PERSON')"
"About the same time he
 received a more honourable reinforcement of Goths and Huns,
 whom Adolphus,(80) the brother of his wife, had conducted, at 
 his pressing invitation, from the banks of the Danube to
 those of the Tiber, and who had cut their way, with some
 difficulty and loss, through the superior numbers of the
 Imperial troops.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'PERSON'), ('Adolphus', 'PERSON'), ('80', 'DATE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Tiber', 'LOC'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"About the same time, in the last years of the reign of Honorius, the GOTHS, the BURGUNDIANS, and the FRANKS, obtained a permanent seat and dominion in the provinces of Gaul.","('the last years', 'DATE'), ('Honorius', 'EVENT'), ('GOTHS', 'ORG'), ('BURGUNDIANS', 'ORG'), ('FRANKS', 'ORG'), ('Gaul', 'GPE')"
"Above
 four years elapsed from the successful invasion of Italy by
 the arms of Alaric, to the voluntary retreat of the Goths
 under the conduct of his successor Adolphus; and, during the
 whole time, they reigned without control over a country
 which, in the opinion of the ancients, had united all the
 various excellences of nature and art.","('four years', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Adolphus', 'PERSON')"
"According to their temper and circumstances, the estates of the Romans were either cultivated by the labour of their slaves, or granted, for a certain and stipulated rent, to the industrious farmer.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Adolphus connected himself with the usurper of Gaul;
 and imposed on Attalus the ignominious task of negotiating
 the treaty which ratified his own disgrace.","('Adolphus', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Attalus', 'PERSON')"
"Adolphus, assuming the character of a Roman General, directed his march from the extremity of Campania to the southern provinces of Gaul.","('Adolphus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Campania', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'LOC')"
"Adolphus, educated among a race of
 warriors, who esteemed the duty of revenge as the most
 precious and sacred portion of their inheritance, advanced
 with a body of ten thousand Goths to encounter the
 hereditary enemy of the house of Balti.","('Adolphus', 'PERSON'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Balti', 'PERSON')"
"Adolphus, king of the Goths concludes a peace with the empire, and marches into Gaul, A.D. 412","('Adolphus', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('412', 'CARDINAL')"
"Adolphus, king of the Goths, marches into Spain, A.D. 414","('Adolphus', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 414', 'DATE')"
"Afflicted by similar 
 calamities, and actuated by the same spirit, the Armorican
 provinces (a name which comprehended the maritime countries
 of Gaul between the Seine and the Loire)(174) resolved to 
 imitate the example of the neighbouring island.","('Armorican', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Seine', 'LOC'), ('Loire', 'LOC'), ('174', 'CARDINAL')"
"After he had distributed the civil and
 military dignities among his favourites and followers,
 Attalus convened an assembly of the senate, before whom, in
 a formal and florid speech, he asserted his resolution of
 restoring the majesty of the republic, and of uniting to the
 empire the provinces of Egypt and the East which had once
 acknowledged the sovereignty of Rome.","('Attalus', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"After the
 removal of Olympius, whose character was deeply tainted with
 religious fanaticism, the Pagans and heretics were delivered
 from the impolitic proscription which excluded them from the
 dignities of the state.","('Olympius', 'PERSON'), ('Pagans', 'NORP')"
"After the death of Singeric,
 the free choice of the nation bestowed the Gothic sceptre on
 Wallia, whose warlike and ambitious temper appeared, in the
 beginning of his reign, extremely hostile to the republic.","('Singeric', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Wallia', 'PERSON')"
"After the death of her husband, the
 most powerful subject of Rome, she had remained at the head
 of the Anician family, and successively supplied, from her
 private fortune, the expense of the consulships of her three
 sons.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Anician', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the deliverance of Italy from the oppression of the
 Goths, some secret counsellor was permitted, amidst the
 factions of the palace, to heal the wounds of that afflicted
 country.(143)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('143', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the usurpers of Gaul had successively fallen, the
 maritime provinces were restored to the empire.","('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"Alaric accepts a ransom, and raises the seige, A.D. 409.","('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('409', 'CARDINAL')"
"Alaric evacuates Rome, and ravages Italy, A.D. 410, August 29.","('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 410', 'DATE'), ('August 29', 'DATE')"
"Alaric marches to Rome, A.D. 408, October, etc","('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 408', 'DATE'), ('October', 'DATE')"
"Amidst the horrors of a nocturnal
 tumult several of the Christian Goths displayed the fervour
 of a recent conversion; and some instances of their uncommon
 piety and moderation are related, and perhaps adorned, by
 the zeal of ecclesiastical writers.(99)","('the Christian Goths', 'NORP')"
"Ammianus
 Marcellinus, who prudently chose the capital of the empire
 as the residence the best adapted to the historian of his
 own times, has mixed with the narrative of public events a
 lively representation of the scenes with which he was
 familiarly conversant.","('Ammianus\r\n Marcellinus', 'PERSON')"
"An
 officer of confidence was sent with an inconsiderable body
 of troops to secure the obedience of Africa; the greatest
 part of Italy submitted to the terror of the Gothic powers;
 and though the city of Bologna made a vigorous and effectual
 resistance, the people of Milan, dissatisfied perhaps with
 the absence of Honorius, accepted with loud acclamations the
 choice of the Roman senate.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Bologna', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"An Italian hermit, whose
 zeal and sanctity were respected by the barbarians
 themselves, encountered the victorious monarch, and boldly
 denounced the indignation of Heaven against the oppressors
 of the earth: but the saint himself was confounded by the
 solemn asseveration of Alaric that he felt a secret and
 preternatural impulse, which directed, and even compelled,
 his march to the gates of Rome","('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"An early and passionate 
 attachment determined him to fix his humble dwelling in one
 of the suburbs of Nola, near the miraculous tomb of St.
 Felix, which the public devotion had already surrounded with
 five large and populous churches.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nola', 'GPE'), ('St.\r\n Felix', 'FAC'), ('five', 'CARDINAL')"
"Arles, the seat of 
 government and commerce, was appointed for the place of the
 assembly, which regularly continued twenty-eight days, from
 the fifteenth of August to the thirteenth of September of
 every year.","('Arles', 'GPE'), ('twenty-eight days', 'DATE'), ('the fifteenth of August to the thirteenth of September of\r\n every year', 'DATE')"
"As early as the time of
 Hadrian it was the just complaint of the ingenuous natives
 that the capital had attracted the vices of the universe and
 the manners of the most opposite nations.","('Hadrian', 'PERSON')"
"As he marched from the port along
 the road which leads to the gates of Rome, he was
 encountered, terrified, and routed by one of the Imperial
 captains; and the lord of this mighty host, deserting his
 fortune and his friends, ignominiously fled with a single
 ship.(147)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('147', 'CARDINAL')"
"As soon as Alaric was in
 possession of that important place he summoned the city to
 surrender at discretion and his demands were enforced by the
 positive declaration that a refusal, or even a delay, should
 be instantly followed by the destruction of the magazines on
 which the life of the Roman people depended.","('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"As soon as the Romans had satisfied the rapacious demands of Alaric, they were restored, in some measure, to the enjoyment of peace and plenty.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as they have indulged themselves in the refreshment of the bath, they resume their rings and the other ensigns of their dignity, select from their private wardrobe of the finest linen, such as might suffice for a dozen persons, the garments the most agreeable to their fancy, and maintain till their departure the same haughty demeanour, which perhaps might have been excused in the great Marcellus after the conquest of Syracuse.","('a dozen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Marcellus', 'PERSON'), ('Syracuse', 'GPE')"
"As the barbarians had more occasion for money
 than for slaves, they fixed at a moderate price the
 redemption of their indigent prisoners; and the ransom was
 often paid by the benevolence of their friends, or the
 charity of strangers. (109)","('109', 'CARDINAL')"
"Assembly of the seven provinces of Gaul, A.D. 418.","('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('418', 'CARDINAL')"
"Astonished by such examples of domestic treason,
 Honorius trembled at the approach of every servant, at the
 arrival of every messenger.","('Honorius', 'PERSON')"
"At Rome commerce was always held in contempt; but the
 senators, from the first age of the republic, increased
 their patrimony and multiplied their clients by the
 lucrative practice of usury, and the obsolete laws were
 eluded or violated by the mutual inclinations and interest
 of both parties.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"At present, if a foreigner, perhaps of no contemptible rank, is introduced to one of the proud and wealthy senators, he is welcomed indeed in the first audience with such warm professions and such kind inquiries, that he retires enchanted with the affability of his illustrious friend, and full of regret that he had so long delayed his journey to Rome, the native seat of manners as well as of empire.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"At the Roman tables the birds, the squirrels, (45)  or the fish, which appear of an uncommon size are contemplated with curious attention; a pair of scales is accurately applied to ascertain their real weight and, while the more rational guests are disgusted by the vain and tedious repetition, notaries are summoned to attest by an authentic record the truth of such a marvellous event.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('45', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the age of forty he renounced the enjoyment of
 wealth and honour, of society and literature, to embrace a
 life of solitude and penance; and the loud applause of the
 clergy encouraged him to despise the reproaches of his
 worldly friends, who ascribed this desperate act to some
 disorder of the mind or body.(123)","('the age of forty', 'DATE'), ('123', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the distance of fourteen centuries we may be satisfied
 with relating the military exploits of the conquerors of
 Rome, without presuming to investigate the motives of their
 political conduct.","('fourteen centuries', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"At the head of a formidable
 army, Alaric conducted his royal captive almost to the gates
 of Ravenna; and a solemn embassy of the principal ministers
—of Jovius the Praetorian praefect, of Valens, master of
 the cavalry and infantry, of the quaestor Potamius, and of
 Julian, the first of the notaries was introduced with
 martial pomp into the Gothic camp.","('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Jovius the Praetorian', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Potamius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"At the head of an 
 army encumbered with rich and weighty spoils, their intrepid
 leader advanced along the Appian Way into the southern
 provinces of Italy, destroying whatever dared to oppose his
 passage, and contenting himself with the plunder of the
 unresisting country.","('the Appian Way', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"At the head of three hundred
 followers that fearless barbarian immediately sallied from
 the gates of Ravenna, surprised and cut in pieces a
 considerable body of Goths, re-entered the city in triumph,
 and was permitted to insult his adversary by the voice of a
 herald, who publicly declared that the guilt of Alaric had
 for ever excluded him from the friendship and alliance of
 the emperor.(97)","('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON')"
"At the hour of midnight the Salarian gate was
 silently opened, and the inhabitants were awakened by the
 tremendous sound of the Gothic trumpet.","('the hour of midnight', 'TIME'), ('the Salarian gate', 'FAC'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"At the moment when his
 despair, incapable of any wise or manly resolution,
 meditated a shameful flight, a seasonable reinforcement of
 four thousand veterans unexpectedly landed in the port of
 Ravenna.","('four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"At the same era the Spaniards
 were the terror both of the Old and New World; but their
 high-spirited valour was disgraced by gloomy pride,
 rapacious avarice, and unrelenting cruelty.","('Spaniards', 'NORP'), ('New World', 'EVENT')"
"At the same hour, and
 as if by a common signal, the cities of Italy were polluted
 by the same horrid scenes of universal massacre and pillage,
 which involved in promiscuous destruction the families and
 fortunes of the barbarians.","('the same hour', 'TIME'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"At their entrance through the Salarian gate they
 fired the adjacent houses to guide their march and to
 distract the attention of the citizens; the flames, which
 encountered no obstacle in the disorder of the night,
 consumed many private and public buildings, and the ruins of
 the palace of Sallust(105) remained in the age of Justinian a 
 stately monument of the Gothic conflagration. (106)","('the Salarian gate', 'FAC'), ('Sallust', 'GPE'), ('105', 'CARDINAL'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('106', 'CARDINAL')"
Attalus is created emperor by the Goths and the Romans.,"('Attalus', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Attalus, so long the sport of
 fortune and of the Goths, was appointed to lead the chorus
 of the Hymeneal song; and the degraded emperor might aspire
 to the praise of a skilful musician.","('Attalus', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Hymeneal', 'NORP')"
"Before Constantine
 resigned the purple, and in the fourth month of the siege of
 Arles, intelligence was received in the Imperial camp that
 Jovinus had assumed the diadem at Mentz, in the Upper
 Germany, at the instigation of Goar, king of the Alani, and
 of Guntiarius, king of the Burgundians; and that the
 candidate on whom they had bestowed the empire advanced with
 a formidable host of barbarians from the banks of the Rhine
 to those of the Rhone.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('the fourth month', 'DATE'), ('Arles', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Jovinus', 'PERSON'), ('Mentz', 'GPE'), ('the Upper\r\n Germany', 'GPE'), ('Goar', 'PERSON'), ('Alani', 'NORP'), ('Guntiarius', 'PERSON'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Rhone', 'LOC')"
Britain was irrecoverably lost. (177),"('Britain', 'GPE'), ('177', 'CARDINAL')"
"But Placidia soon obtained the pleasure of revenge; and the
 view of her ignominious sufferings might rouse an indignant
 people against the tyrant, who was assassinated on the
 seventh day of his usurpation.","('Placidia', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n seventh day', 'DATE')"
"But as 
 it was soon discovered that the vindication of their liberty
 would endanger their lives, and that the Goths, unless they
 were tempted to sell, might be provoked to murder their
 useless prisoners, the civil jurisprudence had been already
 qualified by a wise regulation, that they should be obliged
 to serve the moderate term of five years, till they had
 discharged by their labour the price of their redemption.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('five years', 'DATE')"
"But as the 
 emperors wisely acquiesced in the independence of a remote
 province, the separation was not embittered by the reproach
 of tyranny or rebellion; and the claims of allegiance and
 protection were succeeded by the mutual and voluntary
 offices of national friendship.(178)
State of Britain, A.D. 409-449","('178', 'CARDINAL'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 409-449', 'DATE')"
"But even the family
 of Proba herself was not exempt from the rapacious
 oppression of Count Heraclian, who basely sold, in
 matrimonial prostitution the noblest maidens of Rome to the
 lust or avarice of the Syrian merchants.","('Proba', 'PERSON'), ('Heraclian', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Syrian', 'NORP')"
"But he soon experienced that the principles of
 honour and integrity, which might regulate the ordinary
 conduct of Constantius, were superseded by the loose
 doctrines of political morality.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"But no
 sooner had the national troops been compelled to resign
 their post of the Honorian bands in the service of
 Constantine, than the gates of Spain were treacherously
 betrayed to the public enemy, about ten months before the
 sack of Rome by the Goths.(156)","('Honorian', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('about ten months', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('156', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the
 holy precincts of the Vatican and the apostolic churches
 could receive a very small proportion of the Roman people:
 many thousand warriors, more especially of the Huns who
 served under the standard of Alaric, were strangers to the
 name, or at least to the faith, of Christ, and we may
 suspect, without any breach of charity or candour, that in
 the hour of savage licence, when every passion was inflamed
 and every restraint was removed, the precepts of the Gospel
 seldom influenced the behaviour of the Gothic Christians.","('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('many thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('the hour', 'TIME'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"But the Tragic and Comic Muse
 of the Romans, who seldom aspired beyond the imitation of
 Attic genius,(62) had been almost totally silent since the 
 fall of the republic; (63) and their place was unworthily 
 occupied by licentious farce, effeminate music, and splendid
 pageantry.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('62', 'DATE'), ('63', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the costly instruments of the theatre, flutes, and enormous lyres, and hydraulic organs, are constructed for their use; and the harmony of vocal and instrumental music is incessantly repeated in the palaces of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But the court and councils of Honorious still
 remained a scene of weakness and distraction, of corruption
 and anarchy.","('Honorious', 'ORG')"
"But the daughter of Theodosius submitted
 without reluctance to the desires of the conqueror, a young
 and valiant prince, who yielded to Alaric in loftiness of
 stature, but who excelled in the more attractive qualities
 of grace and beauty.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON')"
"But the desire of obtaining the
 advantages, and of escaping the burthens, of political
 society, is a perpetual and inexhaustible source of discord;
 nor can it reasonably be presumed that the restoration of
 British freedom was exempt from tumult and faction.","('British', 'NORP')"
"But the hopes of peace were 
 disappointed by the weak obstinacy, or interested views, of
 the minister Olympius.","('Olympius', 'PERSON')"
"But the loftiness of these buildings, which often 
 consisted of hasty work and insufficient materials, was the
 cause of frequent and fatal accidents; and it was repeatedly
 enacted by Augustus, as well as by Nero, that the height of
 private edifices within the walls of Rome should not exceed
 the measure of seventy feet from the ground.(69)  III.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('seventy feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('69', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the plebeians of Rome, who disdained such sedentary and
 servile arts, had been oppressed from the earliest times by
 the weight of debt and usury, and the husbandman, during the
 term of his military service, was obliged to abandon the
 cultivation of his farm. (50)","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But the public treasury was exhausted; the annual rents of the great estates in Italy and the provinces were intercepted by the calamities of war; the gold and gems had been exchanged, during the famine, for the vilest sustenance; the hoards of secret wealth were still concealed by the obstinacy of avarice; and some remains of consecrated spoils afforded the only resource that could avert the impending ruin of the city.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"But there is a Providence (such at least was the opinion of
 the historian Procopius (94) ) that watches over innocence and 
 folly, and the pretensions of Honorius to its peculiar care
 cannot reasonably be disputed.","('Providence', 'GPE'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('94', 'DATE'), ('Honorius', 'GPE')"
"But there still remained an equal number in
 Rome and the adjacent territory who were animated by the
 same intrepid courage; and every citizen was trained from
 his earliest youth in the discipline and exercises of a
 soldier.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But they had
 imbibed, in the first fervour of the Reformation, the
 spirit, as well as the principles, of Luther.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Reformation', 'EVENT'), ('Luther', 'PERSON')"
"But this native splendour  (continues Ammianus)  is degraded and sullied by the conduct of some nobles, who, unmindful of their own dignity and of that of their country, assume an unbounded licence of vice and folly.","('Ammianus', 'PERSON')"
"But this transient prosperity was soon
 interrupted and destroyed by the revolt of Count Gerontius,
 the bravest of his generals, who, during the absence of his
 son Constans, a prince already invested with the Imperial
 purple, had been left to command in the provinces of Spain.","('Gerontius', 'PERSON'), ('Constans', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE')"
"But when he reached the southern
 promontory of Spain, (163) and, from the rock now covered by the fortress of Gibraltar, contemplated the neighbouring and fertile coast of Africa, Wallia resumed the designs of
 conquest which had been interrupted by the death of Alaric.","('Spain', 'GPE'), ('163', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gibraltar', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Wallia', 'PERSON'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON')"
"But when the
 prodigal commons had imprudently alienated not only the use,
 but the inheritance, of power, they sunk, under the reign of
 the Caesars, into a vile and wretched populace, which must,
 in a few generations, have been totally extinguished, if it
 had not been continually recruited by the manumission of
 slaves and the influx of strangers.","('Caesars', 'ORG')"
"But when the
 question was agitated in the senate; when it was proposed,
 as an essential condition, that those sacrifices should be
 performed in the Capitol, by the authority and in the
 presence of the magistrates; the majority of that
 respectable assembly, apprehensive either of the Divine or
 of the Imperial displeasure, refused to join in an act which
 appeared almost equivalent to the public restoration of
 Paganism.(78)
Alaric accepts a ransom, and raises the seige, A.D. 409.","('Capitol', 'ORG'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Paganism', 'NORP'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('409', 'CARDINAL')"
"But when the
 trumpet summoned him to arms; when he mounted his horse,
 and, bending down (for such was his singular practice)
 almost upon the neck, fiercely rolled his large animated
 eyes round the field, Constantius then struck terror into
 his foes and inspired his soldiers with the assurance of
 victory.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"By a skilful disposition of 
 his numerous forces, who impatiently watched the moment of
 an assault, Alaric encompassed the walls, commanded the
 twelve principal gates, intercepted all communication with
 the adjacent country, and vigilantly guarded the navigation
 of the Tiber, from which the Romans derived the surest and
 most plentiful supply of provisions.","('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tiber', 'LOC'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"By a wise and humane regulation the eight 
 provinces which had been the most deeply injured—","('eight', 'CARDINAL')"
By repeated experiments I was gradually convinced that laws are essentially necessary to maintain and regulate a well constituted state; and that the fierce untractable humour of the Goths was incapable of bearing the salutary yoke of laws and civil government.,"('Goths', 'NORP')"
"By the
 insolent order of the count of the domestics, the great
 chamberlain was shamefully beaten to death with sticks
 before the eyes of the astonished emperor; and the
 subsequent assassination of Allobich, in the midst of a
 public procession, is the only circumstance of his life in
 which Honorius discovered the faintest symptom of courage or
 resentment.","('Allobich', 'PERSON'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON')"
"By the imprudent conduct
 of the ministers of Honorius the republic lost the
 assistance, and deserved the enmity, of thirty thousand of
 her bravest soldiers; and the weight of that formidable
 army, which alone might have determined the event of the
 war, was transferred from the scale of the Romans into that
 of the Goths.","('Honorius', 'GPE'), ('thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"By the labour of a captive multitude
 they forcibly diverted the course of the Busentinus, a small
 river that washes the walls of Consentia.","('Busentinus', 'GPE'), ('Consentia', 'GPE')"
"By the pressing instances of the
 new favourites, these generals, unworthy as they had shown
 themselves of the name of soldiers,(2) were promoted to the 
 command of the cavalry, of the infantry, and of the domestic
 troops.","('2', 'CARDINAL')"
"Campania,
 Tuscany, Picenum, Samnium, Apulia, Calabria, Bruttium, and
 Lucania—obtained an indulgence of five years; the ordinary
 tribute was reduced to one-fifth, and even that fifth was
 destined to restore and support the useful institution of
 the public posts.","('Campania', 'GPE'), ('Tuscany', 'GPE'), ('Picenum', 'GPE'), ('Samnium', 'GPE'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Calabria', 'GPE'), ('Bruttium', 'GPE'), ('Lucania', 'GPE'), ('five years', 'DATE'), ('one-fifth', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifth', 'ORDINAL')"
"Captives and fugitives 
 Whatever might be the numbers of equestrian or plebeian rank
 who perished in the massacre of Rome, it is confidently
 affirmed that only one senator lost his life by the sword of
 the enemy.(108)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('108', 'CARDINAL')"
Character and victories of the general Constantius,"('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"Character of the Roman nobles, by Ammianus Marcellinus","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Ammianus Marcellinus', 'PERSON')"
"Compared to this immoderate wealth, an ordinary revenue of a thousand or fifteen hundred pounds of gold might be considered as no more than adequate to the dignity of the senatorian rank, which required many expenses of a public and ostentatious kind.","('a thousand or fifteen hundred pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"Constantine engaged himself by a solemn promise to
 deliver Italy from the Goths, advanced as far as the banks
 of the Po, and, after alarming rather than assisting his
 pusillanimous ally, hastily returned to the palace of Arles,
 to celebrate with intemperate luxury his vain and
 ostentatious triumph.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Po', 'LOC'), ('Arles', 'PERSON')"
"Death of Alaric, A.D. 410","('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('410', 'CARDINAL')"
"Death of the usurper Constantine, A.D. 411, November 28.","('Death of the usurper Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 411', 'DATE'), ('November 28', 'DATE')"
"During five months of the year a regular
 allowance of bacon was distributed to the poorer citizens;
 and the annual consumption of the capital, at a time when it
 was much declined from its former lustre, was ascertained,
 by an edict of Valentinian the Third, at three millions six
 hundred and twenty-eight thousand pounds. (55) III.","('five months of the year', 'DATE'), ('Third', 'ORDINAL'), ('three millions six\r\n hundred and twenty-eight thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('55', 'CARDINAL')"
"During the
 absence of Jovius the emperor was persuaded to assume a
 lofty tone of inflexible dignity, such as neither his
 situation nor his character could enable him to support; and
 a letter, signed with the name of Honorius, was immediately
 despatched to the Praetorian praefect, granting him a free
 permission to dispose of the public money, but sternly
 refusing to prostitute the military honours of Rome to the
 proud demands of a barbarian","('Jovius', 'PERSON'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"During the siege, some religious
 persons were satisfied that they had seen, either in dreams
 or visions, the divine form of their tutelar patron, yet it
 soon appeared by the event, that Felix wanted power, or
 inclination, to preserve the flock of which he had formerly
 been the shepherd.","('Felix', 'PERSON')"
"Each of the senators in the time 
 of the Punic war had accomplished his term of military
 service, either in a subordinate or a superior station; and
 the decree which invested with temporary command all those
 who had been consuls, or censors, or dictators, gave the
 republic the immediate assistance of many brave and
 experienced generals.","('the Punic war', 'EVENT')"
"Each of these cities, as in 
 all the other provinces of the empire, formed a legal
 corporation, for the purpose of regulating their domestic
 policy; and the powers of municipal government were
 distributed among annual magistrates, a select senate, and
 the assembly of the people, according to the original model
 of the Roman constitution. (182)","('the Roman constitution', 'LAW'), ('182', 'CARDINAL')"
"Each soldier, however, claimed an ample portion of
 the substantial plenty, the corn and cattle, oil and wine,
 that was daily collected and consumed, in the Gothic camp;
 and the principal warriors insulted the villas and gardens,
 once inhabited by Lucullus and Cicero, along the beauteous
 coast of Campania.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Lucullus', 'PERSON'), ('Cicero', 'PERSON'), ('Campania', 'GPE')"
"Eleven hundred and
 sixty-three years after the foundation of Rome, the Imperial
 city, which had subdued and civilised so considerable a part
 of mankind, was delivered to the licentious fury of the
 tribes of Germany and Scythia.(98)
Respect of the Goths for the Christian religion","('Eleven hundred and\r\n sixty-three years', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('the Imperial\r\n city', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"Eusebius the eunuch and the barbarian
 Allobich succeeded to the command of the bedchamber and of
 the guards; and the mutual jealousy of the subordinate
 ministers was the cause of their mutual destruction.","('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('Allobich', 'PERSON')"
"Every circumstance is dark and
 extraordinary in the short history of the reign of Jovinus.","('Jovinus', 'PERSON')"
"Exasperated by such an injury,
 which might have awakened the tamest and most servile
 spirit, they cast a look of indignation and hope towards the
 camp of Alaric, and unanimously swore to pursue with just
 and implacable war the perfidious nation that had so basely
 violated the laws of hospitality.","('Alaric', 'PERSON')"
Fall of Constantine—Gaul and Spain Are Occupied by the Barbarians—,"('Constantine', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"Fall of the usurpers, Jovinus, Sebastian, and Attalus, A.D. 411-416","('Jovinus', 'NORP'), ('Sebastian', 'PERSON'), ('Attalus', 'PERSON')"
"Fifty beautiful youths, in silken robes,
 carried a basin in each hand; and one of these basins was
 filled with pieces of gold, the other with precious stones
 of an inestimable value.","('Fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"First seige of Rome by the Goths, A.D. 408.","('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 408', 'DATE')"
"Followed by a train of fifty servants, and tearing up the pavement, they move along the streets with the same impetuous speed as if they travelled with post-horses and the example of the senators is boldly imitated by the matrons and ladies, whose covered carriages are continually driving round the immense space of the city and suburbs.","('fifty', 'CARDINAL')"
"For some reason of which we are ignorant, Gerontius, instead
 of assuming the diadem, placed it on the head of his friend
 Maximus, who fixed his residence at Tarragona, while the
 active count pressed forwards through the Pyrenees to
 surprise the two emperors Constantine and Constans before
 they could prepare for their defence.","('Gerontius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Tarragona', 'GPE'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Constans', 'PERSON')"
"For the convenience of the lazy plebeians, the monthly distributions
 of corn were converted into a daily allowance of bread; a
 great number of ovens were constructed and maintained at the
 public expense; and at the appointed hour, each citizen, who
 was furnished with a ticket, ascended the flight of steps
 which had been assigned to his peculiar quarter or division,
 and received, either as a gift or at a very low price, a
 loaf of bread of the weight of three pounds for the use of
 his family.","('the appointed hour', 'TIME'), ('quarter', 'CARDINAL'), ('three pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"From a life of
 idleness and want his troop were soon habituated to severe
 exercise and plentiful subsistence, and his private
 generosity often supplied the rewards which were denied by
 the avarice or poverty of the court of Ravenna.","('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"From a vain ambition of perpetuating their memory, they affect to multiply their likeness in statues of bronze and marble; nor are they satisfied unless those statues are covered with plates of gold; an honourable distinction, first granted to Acilius the consul, after he had subdued by his arms and counsels the power of king Antiochus.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Acilius', 'PERSON'), ('Antiochus', 'PERSON')"
"From all the
 adjacent houses a crowd of Christians hastened to join this
 edifying procession, and a multitude of fugitives, without
 distinction of age or rank, or even of sect, had the good
 fortune to escape to the secure and hospitable sanctuary of
 the Vatican.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Vatican', 'FAC')"
"From his camp, on the confines of Italy,
 Alaric attentively observed the revolutions of the palace,
 watched the progress of faction and discontent, disguised
 the hostile aspect of a barbarian invader, and assumed the
 more popular appearance of the friend and ally of the great
 Stilicho; to whose virtues, when they were no longer
 formidable, he could pay a just tribute of sincere praise
 and regret.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Stilicho', 'PERSON')"
"From that moment I proposed to myself a different object of glory and ambition; and it is now my sincere wish that the gratitude of future ages should acknowledge the merit of a stranger, who employed the sword of the Goths, not to subvert, but to restore and maintain, the prosperity of the Roman empire."" (130)","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('130', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the extremity,
 perhaps, of the Quirinal hill to the distant quarter of the
 Vatican, a numerous detachment of Goths, marching in order
 of battle through the principal streets, protected with
 glittering arms the long train of their devout companions
 who bore aloft on their heads the sacred vessels of gold and
 silver, and the martial shouts of the barbarians were
 mingled with the sound of religious psalmody.","('the Quirinal hill', 'LOC'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"From the morning to the evening, careless
 of the sun or of the rain, the spectators, who sometimes
 amounted to the number of four hundred thousand, remained in
 eager attention; their eyes fixed on the horses and
 charioteers, their minds agitated with hope and fear for the
 success of the colours which they espoused; and the
 happiness of Rome appeared to hang on the event of a race.","('the morning to the evening', 'TIME'), ('four hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"From the triumph of that general three 
 consulships in distant periods mark the succession of the
 Anician name.(16) From the reign of Diocletian to the final 
 extinction of the Western empire that name shone with a
 lustre which was not eclipsed in the public estimation by
 the majesty of the Imperial purple.(17)","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Anician', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('17', 'CARDINAL')"
"From these stately palaces 
 issued a swarm of dirty and ragged plebeians, without shoes
 and without a mantle; who loitered away whole days in the
 street or Forum to hear news and to hold disputes who
 dissipated in extravagant gaming the miserable pittance of
 their wives and children; and spent the hours of the night
 in obscure taverns and brothels in the indulgence of gross
 and vulgar sensuality.(60)
Games and spectacles","('Forum', 'ORG'), ('60', 'CARDINAL')"
"Fruitless negotiations for peace, A.D. 409.","('409', 'CARDINAL')"
"Genealogy of the senators 
 From the time of the Punic war the uninterrupted succession
 of senators had preserved the name and image of the
 republic; and the degenerate subjects of Honorius
 ambitiously derived their descent from the heroes who had
 repulsed the arms of Hannibal and subdued the nations of the
 earth.","('the Punic war', 'EVENT'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('Hannibal', 'PERSON')"
"Gerontius, abandoned by his own
 troops, escaped to the confines of Spain, and rescued his
 name from oblivion by the Roman courage which appeared to
 animate the last moments of his life.","('Gerontius', 'PERSON'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Hannibal at the gates of Rome 
During a period of six hundred and nineteen years the seat
 of empire had never been violated by the presence of a
 foreign enemy.","('Hannibal', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('six hundred and nineteen years', 'DATE')"
"Hannibal was astonished by the constancy of the
 senate, who, without raising the siege of Capua or recalling
 their scattered forces, expected his approach.","('Hannibal', 'PERSON'), ('Capua', 'GPE')"
"He
 celebrates with peculiar satisfaction this memorable triumph
 of Christ, and insults his adversaries by challenging them
 to produce some similar example of a town taken by storm, in
 which the fabulous gods of antiquity had been able to
 protect either themselves or their deluded votaries.(100)
Pillage and fire of Rome","('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('100', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"He
 required a solemn promise for his security; and after
 receiving, by the imposition of hands, the sacred character
 of a Christian presbyter, he ventured to open the gates of
 the city.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"He again listened to the dictates of love and prudence; and
 soon satisfied the brother of Placidia, by the assurance
 that he would immediately transmit to the palace of Ravenna
 the heads of the two tyrants, Jovinus and Sebastian.","('Placidia', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jovinus', 'PERSON'), ('Sebastian', 'PERSON')"
"He attacked Sarus at
 an unguarded moment, when he was accompanied only by
 eighteen or twenty of his valiant followers.","('Sarus', 'PERSON'), ('eighteen or twenty', 'CARDINAL')"
"He dreaded the secret enemies
 who might lurk in his capital, his palace, his bedchamber;
 and some ships lay ready in the harbour of Ravenna to
 transport the abdicated monarch to the dominions of his
 infant nephew, the emperor of the East.","('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"He encamped
 on the banks of the Anio, at the distance of three miles
 from the city: and he was soon informed that the ground on
 which he had pitched his tent was sold for an adequate price
 at a public auction; and that a body of troops was dismissed
 by an opposite road to reinforce the legions of Spain.(10) He 
 led his Africans to the gates of Rome, where he found three
 armies in order of battle prepared to receive him; but
 Hannibal dreaded the event of a combat from which he could
 not hope to escape unless he destroyed the last of his
 enemies; and his speedy retreat confessed the invincible
 courage of the Romans.","('Anio', 'FAC'), ('three miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Africans', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hannibal', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"He encouraged his troops
 boldly to seize the rewards of valour, and to enrich
 themselves with the spoils of a wealthy and effeminate
 people; but he exhorted them at the same time to spare the
 lives of the unresisting citizens, and to respect the
 churches of the apostles St. Peter and St. Paul as holy and
 inviolable sanctuaries.","('St. Peter', 'LOC'), ('St. Paul', 'GPE')"
"He entered Rome like the ancient
 conquerors of nations; and if the monuments of servile
 corruption had not long since met with the fate which they
 deserved, we should probably find that a crowd of poets and
 orators, of magistrates and bishops, applauded the fortune,
 the wisdom, and the invincible courage of the emperor
 Honorius.(166)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('166', 'CARDINAL')"
"He exterminated the
 Silingi, who had irretrievably ruined the elegant plenty of
 the province of Baetica.","('Silingi', 'PERSON'), ('Baetica', 'GPE')"
"He felt that his genius and
 his fortune were equal to the most arduous enterprises; and
 the enthusiasm which he communicated to the Goths insensibly
 removed the popular and almost superstitious reverence of
 the nations for the majesty of the Roman name.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"He had imprudently received into his
 service one of the followers of Sarus, a barbarian of a
 daring spirit, but of a diminutive stature, whose secret
 desire of revenging the death of his beloved patron was
 continually irritated by the sarcasms of his insolent
 master.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sarus', 'PERSON')"
"He had received from the court of Ravenna the
 important commission of extirpating rebellion in the
 provinces of the West; and the pretended emperor
 Constantine, after enjoying a short and anxious respite, was
 again besieged in his capital by the arms of a more
 formidable enemy.","('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"He is degraded by Alaric, A.D. 410.","('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('410', 'CARDINAL')"
"He marched in arms from Barcelona to the shores of the
 Atlantic Ocean, which the ancients revered and dreaded as
 the boundary of the world.","('Barcelona', 'GPE'), ('the\r\n Atlantic Ocean', 'LOC')"
"He readily accepted the proposal of turning his
 victorious arms against the barbarians of Spain; the troops
 of Constantius intercepted his communication with the
 seaports of Gaul, and gently pressed his march towards the
 Pyrenees:(159) he passed the mountains, and surprised, in the 
 name of the emperor, the city of Barcelona.","('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('159', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barcelona', 'GPE')"
"He refused to trust the faith of the
 Romans, unless Aetius and Jason, the sons of two great
 officers of state, were sent as hostages to his camp: but he
 offered to deliver in exchange several of the noblest youths
 of the Gothic nation.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Jason', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"He slew, in battle, the king of the
 Alani; and the remains of those Scythian wanderers who
 escaped from the field, instead of choosing a new leader,
 humbly sought a refuge under the standard of the Vandals,
 with whom they were ever afterwards confounded.","('Alani', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Vandals', 'PRODUCT')"
"He then condescended to fix the ransom which he would accept as the price of his retreat from the walls of Rome: all the gold and silver in the city, whether it were the property of the state, or of individuals; all the rich and precious moveables; and all the slaves who could prove their title to the name of barbarians.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"He was probably ignorant of the causes and events
 which preserved him from these impending dangers; and as
 Italy was no longer invaded by any foreign or domestic
 enemies, he peaceably existed in the palace of Ravenna,
 while the tyrants beyond the Alps were repeatedly vanquished
 in the name and by the lieutenants of the son of Theodosius.
 (150)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('150', 'CARDINAL')"
"Heraclian, count, of Africa, who under the most difficult
 and distressful circumstances had supported with active
 loyalty the cause of Honorius, was tempted in the year of
 his consulship to assume the character of a rebel and the
 title of emperor.","('Heraclian', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('the year', 'DATE')"
"His
 wife, a valiant friend of the nation of the Alani, and some
 faithful slaves, were still attached to his person; and he
 used with so much skill and resolution a large magazine of
 darts and arrows, that above three hundred of the assailants
 lost their lives in the attempt.","('Alani', 'NORP'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"His army, enriched by
 the contributions of the capital, slowly advanced into the
 fair and fruitful province of Tuscany, where he proposed to
 establish his winter-quarters; and the Gothic standard
 became the refuge of forty thousand barbarian slaves, who
 had broke their chains, and aspired, under the command of
 their great deliverer, to revenge the injuries and the
 disgrace of their cruel servitude.","('Tuscany', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('forty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"His death, A.D. 415, August  Adolphus was assassinated in the palace of Barcelona; the laws of the succession were violated by a tumultuous faction;(160) and a stranger to the royal race, Singeric, the brother of Sarus himself, was seated on the Gothic throne.","('A.D. 415', 'DATE'), ('Adolphus', 'PERSON'), ('Barcelona', 'GPE'), ('160', 'CARDINAL'), ('Singeric', 'PERSON'), ('Sarus', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"His immense estates were 
 scattered over the wide extent of the Roman world; and
 though the public might suspect or disapprove the methods by
 which they had been acquired, the generosity and
 magnificence of that fortunate statesman deserved the
 gratitude of his clients and the admiration of strangers.(21) 
 Such was the respect entertained for his memory, that the
 two sons of Probus, in their earliest youth and at the
 request of the senate, were associated in the consular
 dignity: a memorable distinction, without example in the
 annals of Rome.(22)
Wealth of Roman nobles.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"His indignation was kindled by the report
 that a rival chieftain, that Sarus, the personal enemy of
 Adolphus, and the hereditary foe of the house of Balti, had
 been received into the palace.","('Sarus', 'PERSON'), ('Adolphus', 'PERSON'), ('Balti', 'GPE')"
"His marriage with Placidia, A.D. 414","('Placidia', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 414', 'DATE')"
"His measures were conducted with so
 much skill and secrecy, that, while they engaged the
 infantry of Constantius in the front, they were suddenly
 attacked, surrounded, and destroyed by the cavalry of his
 lieutenant Ulphilas, who had silently gained an advantageous
 post in their rear.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Ulphilas', 'PERSON')"
"His slaves, when all the
 missile weapons were spent, fled at the dawn of day; and
 Gerontius, if he had not been restrained by conjugal
 tenderness, might have imitated their example; till the
 soldiers, provoked by such obstinate resistance, applied
 fire on all sides to the house.","('the dawn of day', 'DATE'), ('Gerontius', 'PERSON')"
"His title was acknowledged from the wall of
 Antoninus , to the Columns of Hercules, and, in the midst of
 the public disorder, he shared the dominion and the plunder
 of Gaul and Spain with the tribes of barbarians whose
 destructive progress was no longer checked by the Rhine or
 Pyrenees.","('Antoninus , to the Columns of Hercules', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC')"
"His troops,
 animated by the hopes of spoil, followed the course of the
 Flaminian way, occupied the unguarded passes of the
 Apennine,(4) descended into the rich plains of Umbria; and, as they lay encamped on the banks of the Clitumnus, might
 wantonly slaughter and devour the milk-white oxen which had
 been so long reserved for the use of Roman triumphs.(5) A 
 lofty situation and a seasonable tempest of thunder and
 lightning preserved the little city of Narni: but the king
 of the Goths, despising the ignoble prey, still advanced
 with unabated vigour; and after he had passed through the
 stately arches, adorned with the spoils of barbaric
 victories, he pitched his camp under the walls of Rome.(6)
Hannibal at the gates of Rome 
During a period of six hundred and nineteen years the seat
 of empire had never been violated by the presence of a
 foreign enemy.","('Flaminian', 'NORP'), ('Apennine', 'NORP'), ('4', 'CARDINAL'), ('Umbria', 'GPE'), ('Clitumnus', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('5', 'CARDINAL'), ('Narni', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Hannibal', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('six hundred and nineteen years', 'DATE')"
"His troops, either by force or agreement, immediately occupied the cities of Narbonne, Toulouse, and Bordeaux; and though they were repulsed by Count Boniface from the walls of Marseilles, they soon extended their quarters from the Mediterranean to the ocean.","('Narbonne', 'GPE'), ('Toulouse', 'GPE'), ('Bordeaux', 'GPE'), ('Count Boniface', 'PERSON'), ('Marseilles', 'GPE'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC')"
"His victorious
 Goths, forty-three years after they had passed the Danube,
 were established, according to the faith of treaties, in the
 possession of the second Aquitain, a maritime province
 between the Garonne and the Loire, under the civil and
 ecclesiastical jurisdiction of Bourdeaux.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('forty-three years', 'DATE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Aquitain', 'GPE'), ('Garonne', 'LOC'), ('Loire', 'LOC'), ('Bourdeaux', 'GPE')"
"Honorius excluded all
 persons who were adverse to the catholic church from holding
 any office in the state; obstinately rejected the service of
 all those who dissented from his religion; and rashly
 disqualified many of his bravest and most skilful officers
 who adhered to the Pagan worship or who had imbibed the
 opinions of Arianism.","('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('Arianism', 'NORP')"
"Honorius viewed with supine indifference
 the calamities of Rome and Italy, (149) but the rebellious 
 attempts of Attalus and Heraclian against his personal
 safety awakened for a moment the torpid instinct of his
 nature.","('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('149', 'CARDINAL'), ('Attalus', 'PERSON'), ('Heraclian', 'PERSON')"
Hospitality was formerly the virtue of the Romans; and every stranger who could plead either merit or misfortune was relieved or rewarded by their generosity.,"('Romans', 'NORP')"
"House-rent was therefore immoderately dear: the rich
 acquired, at an enormous expense, the ground, which they
 covered with palaces and gardens; but the body of the Roman
 people was crowded into a narrow space; and the different
 floors and apartments of the same house were divided, as it
 is still the custom of Paris and other cities, among several
 families of plebeians.","('House', 'ORG'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Paris', 'GPE')"
"I. When the capital of the empire was besieged by the Goths,
 the circuit of the walls was accurately measured by
 Ammonius, the mathematician, who found it equal to
 twenty-one miles.(67)","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Ammonius', 'PERSON'), ('twenty-one miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"If
 these modest terms should be rejected, Alaric showed a
 disposition to relinquish his pecuniary demands, and even to
 content himself with the possession of Norieum; an exhausted
 and impoverished country, perpetually exposed to the inroads
 of the barbarians of Germany.(82)","('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Norieum', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('82', 'CARDINAL')"
"If Alaric
 himself had been introduced into the council of Ravenna, he
 would probably have advised the same measures which were
 actually pursued by the ministers of Honorius.(1)","('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('1', 'CARDINAL')"
"If at any time, but more especially on a hot day, they have courage to sail in their painted galleys from the  Lucrine lake (40)  to their elegant villas on the seacoast of Puteoli and Caieta, (41) they compare their own expeditions to the marches of Caesar and Alexander.","('a hot day', 'DATE'), ('the  Lucrine lake', 'LOC'), ('40', 'CARDINAL'), ('Puteoli', 'LOC'), ('Caieta', 'LOC'), ('41', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON')"
"If such an institution, which gave the
 people an interest in their own government, had been
 universally established by Trajan or the Antonines, the
 seeds of public wisdom and virtue might have been cherished
 and propagated in the empire of Rome.","('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Antonines', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"If the princes of Britain relapsed into
 barbarism, while the cities studiously preserved the laws
 and manners of Rome, the whole island must have been
 gradually divided by the distinction of two national
 parties, again broken into a thousand subdivisions of war
 and faction by the various provocations of interest and
 resentment.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"If we adopt the
 same average which, under similar circumstances, has been
 found applicable to Paris,(72) and indifferently allow about 
 twenty-five persons for each house, of every degree, we may
 fairly estimate the inhabitants of Rome at twelve hundred
 thousand: a number which cannot be thought excessive for the
 capital of a mighty empire, though it exceeds the
 populousness of the greatest cities of modern Europe.(73)
First seige of Rome by the Goths, A.D. 408.","('Paris', 'GPE'), ('72', 'CARDINAL'), ('about \r\n twenty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('twelve hundred\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('73', 'CARDINAL'), ('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('408', 'CARDINAL')"
"In a large plain near Rimini, and in the
 presence of an innumerable multitude of Romans and
 barbarians, the wretched Attalus was publicly despoiled of
 the diadem and purple; and those ensigns of royalty were
 sent by Alaric as the pledge of peace and friendship to the
 son of Theodosius. (95)","('Rimini', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Attalus', 'PERSON'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('95', 'CARDINAL')"
"In a solemn edict,(190) filled with the 
 strongest assurances of that paternal affection which
 princes so often express, and so seldom feel, the emperor
 Honorius promulgated his intention of convening an annual
 assembly of the seven provinces: a name peculiarly
 appropriated to Aquitain and the ancient Narbonnese, which
 had long since exchanged their Celtic rudeness for the
 useful and elegant arts of Italy. (191)","('190', 'CARDINAL'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aquitain', 'NORP'), ('Narbonnese', 'NORP'), ('Celtic', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('191', 'CARDINAL')"
"In less than seven years the vestiges of the 
 Gothic invasion were almost obliterated, and the city
 appeared to resume its former splendour and tranquillity.","('less than seven years', 'DATE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"In such
 councils, where the princes and magistrates sat
 promiscuously with the bishops, the important affairs of the
 state, as well as of the church, might be freely debated,
 differences reconciled, alliances formed, contributions
 imposed, wise resolutions often concerted, and sometimes
 executed; and there is reason to believe, that, in moments
 of extreme danger, a Pendragon, or Dictator, was elected
 by the general consent of the Britons.","('Pendragon', 'PERSON'), ('Britons', 'NORP')"
"In the arts of negotiation, as well as in those of war, the
 Gothic king maintained his superior ascendant over an enemy
 whose seeming changes proceeded from the total want of
 counsel and design.","('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"In the beginning of the sixteenth century the
 manners of Italy exhibited a remarkable scene of the
 depravity of mankind.","('the beginning of the sixteenth century', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"In the beginning of the war the Roman
 people consisted of two hundred and fifty thousand citizens
 of an age to bear arms.(9) Fifty thousand had already died in 
 the defence of their country; and the twenty-three legions
 which were employed in the different camps of Italy, Greece,
 Sardinia, Sicily, and Spain, required about one hundred
 thousand men.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('two hundred and fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty-three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Sardinia', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('about one hundred\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the course of a busy and interesting narrative I 
 might possibly forget to mention the death of such a prince,
 and I shall therefore take the precaution of observing in
 this place that he survived the last siege of Rome about
 thirteen years.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('about\r\n thirteen years', 'DATE')"
"In the exercise of domestic jurisdiction the nobles of Rome express an exquisite sensibility for any personal injury, and a contemptuous indifference for the rest of the human species.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In the manners of antiquity the use of oil was indispensable for
 the lamp as well as for the bath, and the annual tax which
 was imposed on Africa for the benefit of Rome amounted to
 the weight of three millions of pounds, to the measure,
 perhaps, of three hundred thousand English gallons.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('three millions of pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('three hundred thousand English gallons', 'QUANTITY')"
"In the midst of his apparent prosperity,
 Alaric was conscious, perhaps, of some secret weakness, some
 internal defect; or perhaps the moderation which he
 displayed was intended only to deceive and disarm the easy
 credulity of the ministers of Honorius.","('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON')"
"In the name of their
 sovereign they consented to acknowledge the lawful election
 of his competitor, and to divide the provinces of Italy and
 the West between the two emperors.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the pillage of Rome a just preference was given
 to gold and jewels, which contain the greatest value in the
 smallest compass and weight, but, after these portable
 riches had been removed by the more diligent robbers, the
 palaces of Rome were rudely stripped of their splendid and
 costly furniture.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In the pride of
 victory, Wallia was faithful to his engagements: he restored
 his Spanish conquests to the obedience of Honorius; and the
 tyranny of the Imperial officers soon reduced an oppressed
 people to regret the time of their barbarian servitude.","('Wallia', 'PERSON'), ('Spanish', 'NORP'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"In the sack of Rome some rare and extraordinary examples of
 barbarian virtue have been deservedly applauded.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In the time of Jerom and Claudian the senators unanimously
 yielded the pre-eminence to the Anician line; and a slight
 view of their history will serve to appreciate the rank and
 antiquity of the noble families which contended only for the
 second place.(13) During the five first ages of the city the name of the Anicians was unknown; they appear to have derived their
 origin from Praeneste; and the ambition of those new
 citizens was long satisfied with the plebeian honours of
 tribunes of the people.(14)","('Jerom', 'PERSON'), ('Claudian', 'PERSON'), ('Anician', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('13', 'CARDINAL'), ('the five first ages', 'DATE'), ('Anicians', 'PERSON'), ('Praeneste', 'PERSON'), ('14', 'CARDINAL')"
In these journeys into the country (43) the whole body of the household marches with their master.,"('43', 'CARDINAL')"
"In this disposition, the successor of Adolphus no longer
 refused to listen to a Roman ambassador, whose proposals
 were enforced by the real, or supposed, approach of a
 numerous army, under the conduct of the brave Constantius.","('Adolphus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"Indefatigable in
 the pursuit of fame and riches, they had improved, by
 repeated practice, the most exquisite and effectual methods
 of torturing their prisoners: many of the Castilians who
 pillaged Rome were familiars of the holy inquisition; and
 some volunteers, perhaps, were lately returned from the
 conquest of Mexico.","('Castilians', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Mexico', 'GPE')"
Independence of Britain,"('Britain', 'GPE')"
"Instead of assaulting the capital he successfully directed
 his efforts against the Port of Ostia, one of the boldest
 and most stupendous works of Roman magnificence. (88)","('the Port of Ostia', 'FAC'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Instead of attempting the
 hopeless siege of Ravenna, the prudent leader of the Goths
 proceeded to Rimini, stretched his ravages along the
 sea-coast of the Hadriatic, and meditated the conquest of
 the ancient mistress of the world.","('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Rimini', 'GPE'), ('Hadriatic', 'NORP')"
"Instigated by the praefect Jovius, the guards
 rose in furious mutiny and demanded the heads of two
 generals and of the two principal eunuchs.","('Jovius', 'PRODUCT'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
Invasion of Italy by Alaric—Manners of the Roman Senate and People—,"('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Alaric—Manners', 'PERSON'), ('the Roman Senate', 'ORG')"
"Invasion of Spain by the Suevi, Vandals, Alani etc, A.D. 409, October 13.","('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Suevi', 'GPE'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Alani', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 409', 'DATE'), ('October 13', 'DATE')"
"It cannot be presumed that all the
 barbarians were at all times capable of perpetrating such
 amorous outrages; and the want of youth, or beauty, or
 chastity, protected the greatest part of the Roman women
 from the danger of a rape.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It consisted of the Praetorian praefect of the
 Gauls; of seven provincial governors, one consular, and six
 presidents; of the magistrates, and perhaps the bishops, of
 about sixty cities; and of a competent, though indefinite,
 number of the most honourable and opulent possessors of
 land, who might justly be considered as the representatives
 of their country.","('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('about sixty', 'CARDINAL')"
"It is said that the foolish curiosity of Elagabalus
 attempted to discover, from the quantity of spiders' webs,
 the number of the inhabitants of Rome.","('Elagabalus', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"It is somewhat remarkable, or rather it is extremely
 natural, that the revolt of Britain and Armorica should have
 introduced an appearance of liberty into the obedient
 provinces of Gaul.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Armorica', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"It was natural to expect that a brave and skilful general,
 at the head of a victorius army, would have asserted, in a
 field of battle, the justice of the cause of Honorius.","('Honorius', 'PERSON')"
"It was not without
 the utmost difficulty that Virgil escaped from the sword of
 the centurion who had usurped his farm in the neighbourhood
 of Mantua;(170) but Paulinus of Bourdeaux received a sum of 
 money from his Gothic purchaser, which he accepted with
 pleasure and surprise; and, though it was much inferior to
 the real value of his estate, this act of rapine was
 disguised by some colours of moderation and equity.(171)","('Virgil', 'PERSON'), ('Mantua', 'GPE'), ('170', 'CARDINAL'), ('Paulinus', 'PERSON'), ('Bourdeaux', 'ORG'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"It was the interest of the ministers of Honorius, who were now released from the obligation of their extravagant oath, to deliver Italy from the intolerable weight of the Gothic powers; and they readily accepted their service against the tyrants and barbarians who infested the
 provinces beyond the Alps. (131)","('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Alps.', 'ORG'), ('131', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was their
 favourite amusement to insult, or destroy, the consecrated
 objects of catholic superstition; they indulged, without
 pity or remorse, a devout hatred against the clergy of every
 denomination and degree who form so considerable a part of
 the inhabitants of modern Rome; and their fanatic zeal might
 aspire to subvert the throne of Antichrist, to purify, with
 blood and fire, the abominations of the spiritual Babylon.
 (117)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Antichrist', 'PERSON'), ('117', 'CARDINAL')"
"Juvenal 
 (70) laments, as it should seem from his own experience, the 
 hardships of the poorer citizens, to whom he addresses the
 salutary advice of emigrating, without delay, from the smoke
 of Rome, since they might purchase in the little towns of
 Italy a cheerful, commodious dwelling at the same price
 which they annually paid for a dark and miserable lodging.","('Juvenal', 'PERSON'), ('70', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Laws for the relief of Italy and Rome, A.D. 410-417","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 410-417', 'DATE')"
"Many curious and costly ornaments of pure gold, enriched
 with jewels, were found in their palace of Narbonne when it
 was pillaged in the sixth century by the Franks: sixty cups
 or chalices; fifteen patens, or plates, for the use of the
 communion; twenty boxes, or cases, to hold the books of the
 gospels: this consecrated wealth(139) was distributed by the 
 son of Clovis among the churches of his dominions, and his
 pious liberality seems to upbraid some former sacrilege of
 the Goths.","('Narbonne', 'GPE'), ('the sixth century', 'DATE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('139', 'CARDINAL'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"Many of 
 these stately mansions might almost excuse the exaggeration of the poet—that Rome contained a multitude of palaces, and that each palace was equal to a city, since it included within its own precincts everything which could be subservient either to use or luxury: markets, hippodromes,
 temples, fountains, baths, porticos, shady groves, and artificial aviaries.(25)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('25', 'CARDINAL')"
"Many thousands of the 
 inhabitants of Rome expired in their houses, or in the
 streets, for want of sustenance; and as the public
 sepulchres without the walls were in the power of the enemy,
 the stench which arose from so many putrid and unburied
 carcasses infected the air; and the miseries of famine were
 succeeded and aggravated by the contagion of a pestilential
 disease.","('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Most of those
 families, however, attacked by so many causes of external
 violence or internal decay, were gradually extirpated: and
 it would be more reasonable to seek for a lineal descent of
 twenty generations among the mountains of the Alps or in the
 peaceful solitude of Apulia, than on the theatre of Rome,
 the seat of fortune, of danger, and of perpetual
 revolutions.","('twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"No sooner had he reached the extreme land of Italy
 than he was attracted by the neighbouring prospect of a
 fertile and peaceful island.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Nola was not saved from the general
 devastation;(125) and the captive bishop was protected only 
 by the general opinion of his innocence and poverty.","('Nola', 'PERSON'), ('125', 'CARDINAL')"
"Olympius (84) might have continued to insult the just 
 resentment of a people who loudly accused him as the author
 of the public calamities, but his power was undermined by
 the secret intrigues of the palace.","('Olympius', 'PERSON'), ('84', 'DATE')"
"On this occasion Constantius behaved with
 the magnanimity of a genuine Roman.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"One hundred and sixty-eight years 
 before the Christian era the family was ennobled by the
 praetorship of Anicius, who gloriously terminated the
 Illyrian war by the conquest of the nation and the captivity
 of their king. (15)","('One hundred and sixty-eight years', 'DATE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Anicius', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n Illyrian war', 'EVENT'), ('15', 'CARDINAL')"
"One of the successors of Torismond purchased the
 aid of the French monarch by the promise of this magnificent
 gift.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Torismond', 'ORG'), ('French', 'NORP')"
"Peace was
 incompatible with the situation and temper of the king of
 the Goths.","('Goths', 'NORP')"
"Perhaps in the person of
 Serena the Romans might have respected the niece of
 Theodosius, the aunt, nay even the adoptive mother, of the
 reigning emperor; they abhorred the widow of Stilicho; and
 they listened with credulous passion to the tale of calumny
 which accused her of maintaining a secret and criminal
 correspondence with the Gothic invader.","('Serena', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Stilicho', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
Pillage and fire of Rome,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Placidia,(133) the 
 daughter of the great Theodosius, and of Galla, his second
 wife, had received a royal education in the palace of
 Constantinople; but the eventful story of her life is
 connected with the revolutions which agitated the Western
 empire under the reign of her brother Honorius.","('Placidia', 'PERSON'), ('133', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Galla', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON')"
"Pompeianus, praefect of the city, had been persuaded, by the
 art or fanaticism of some Tuscan diviners, that, by the
 mysterious force of spells and sacrifices, they could
 extract the lightning from the clouds, and point those
 celestial fires against the camp of the barbarians.(77)","('Tuscan', 'NORP'), ('77', 'CARDINAL')"
Populous of Rome,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Possesion of Italy by the Goths, A.D. 408-412.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 408-412', 'DATE')"
Respect of the Goths for the Christian religion,"('Respect of the Goths', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"Revolt and defeat of Heraclian, count of Africa, A.D. 413","('Heraclian', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('413', 'CARDINAL')"
"Revolt of Britain and Armorica, A.D. 409 
 Whilst Italy was ravaged by the Goths, and a Succession of
 feeble tyrants oppressed the provinces beyond the Alps, the
 British island separated itself from the body of the Roman
 empire.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Armorica', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 409', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('British', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Revolutions of Gaul and Spain, A.D. 409-413","('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 409-413', 'DATE')"
"Rome Is Thrice Besieged, and at Length Pillaged, by the Goths—Death of Alaric—","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Length Pillaged', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Death of Alaric', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
Sack of Rome by troops of Charles V,"('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Charles V', 'PERSON')"
"Second siege of Rome by the Goths, A.D. 409.","('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 409', 'DATE')"
"Secure of a favourable reception, he repeats his visit the ensuing day, and is mortified by the discovery that his person, his name, and his country are already forgotten.","('the ensuing day', 'DATE')"
"Serena was ignominiously strangled; and the
 infatuated multitude were astonished to find that this cruel
 act of injustice did not immediately produce the retreat of
 the barbarians and the deliverance of the city.","('Serena', 'PERSON')"
"Several examples are recorded in the age of Honorius of vain and popular nobles who celebrated the year of their
 praetorship by a festival which lasted seven days and cost above one hundred thousand pounds sterling.(27)","('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('the year', 'DATE'), ('seven days', 'DATE'), ('one hundred thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('27', 'CARDINAL')"
"Several of the gates were cautiously opened; the importation of provisions from the river and the adjacent country was no longer obstructed by the Goths; the citizens resorted in crowds to the free market which was held during three days in the suburbs; and while the merchants who undertook this gainful trade made a considerable profit, the future subsistence of the city was secured by the ample magazines which were deposited in the public and private granaries.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('three days', 'DATE')"
"Several of these
 British chiefs might be the genuine posterity of ancient
 kings; and many more would be tempted to adopt this
 honourable genealogy, and to vindicate there hereditary
 claims, which had been suspended by the usurpation of the
 Caesars.(185)","('British', 'NORP'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('185', 'CARDINAL')"
"Six thousand Dalmatians, the flower of the Imperial legions,
 were ordered to march from Ravenna to Rome, through an open
 country which was occupied by the formidable myriads of the
 barbarians.","('Six thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dalmatians', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"So desperate indeed 
 did the situation of the son of Theodosius appear to those
 who were the best acquainted with his strength and
 resources, that Jovius and Valens, his minister and his
 general, betrayed their trust, infamously deserted the
 sinking cause of their benefactor, and devoted their
 treacherous allegiance to the service of his more fortunate
 rival.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Jovius', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"Some portion of the 
 Gothic treasures .might be the gift of friendship or the
 tribute of obedience; but the far greater part had been the
 fruits of war and rapine, the spoils of the empire, and
 perhaps of Rome.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Some truth may possibly be concealed
 in his devout assertion, that the wrath of Heaven supplied
 the imperfections of hostile rage, and that the proud Forum
 of Rome, decorated with the statues of so many gods and
 heroes, was levelled in the dust by the stroke of lightning.
 (107)","('Forum\r\n of Rome', 'ORG'), ('107', 'CARDINAL')"
"Sometimes indeed these heroes undertake more arduous achievements: they visit their estates in Italy, and procure themselves, by the toil of servile hands, the amusements of the chase.
 (39)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('39', 'CARDINAL')"
"Stained with the blood of the kinsmen of Honorius,
 he extorted from the court of Ravenna, with which he
 secretly corresponded, the ratification of his rebellious
 claims.","('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
State and character of the Roman people,"('Roman', 'NORP')"
"State of Britain, A.D. 409-449","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 409-449', 'DATE')"
"State of the Barbarians in Gaul, A.D. 420 etc","('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('420', 'CARDINAL')"
"Subduing or suppressing
 every sentiment of jealousy, he publicly acknowledged the
 merit and services of Ulphilas; but he turned with horror
 from the assassin of Edobic, and sternly intimated his
 commands that the camp should no longer be polluted by the
 presence of an ungrateful wretch who had violated the laws
 of friendship and hospitality.","('Ulphilas', 'PERSON'), ('Edobic', 'PERSON')"
"Such a triumph might have been justly claimed by the ally of
 Rome, if Wallia, before he repassed the Pyrenees, had
 extirpated the seeds of the Spanish war.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Wallia', 'PERSON'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('the Spanish war', 'EVENT')"
"Such assiduous zeal secured the favour of the
 saint,(124) or at least of the people; and, after fifteen 
 years' retirement the Roman consul was compelled to accept
 the bishopric of Nola, a few months before the city was
 invested by the Goths.","('124', 'CARDINAL'), (""fifteen \r\n years'"", 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Nola', 'PERSON'), ('a few months', 'DATE'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"Such was the involuntary reverence which the Roman name 
 still impressed on the minds of those warriors who had borne
 away in triumph the spoils of the Capitol.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Capitol', 'ORG')"
"Such was the popular favour which they enjoyed,
 that, in a time of scarcity, when all strangers were
 banished from the city, the merit of contributing to the
 public pleasures exempted them from a law which was strictly
 executed against the professors of the liberal arts.(65)
Populous of Rome","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Such was the state of Rome under the reign of Honorius, at
 the time when the Gothic army formed the siege, or rather
 the blockade, of the city.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Honorius', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"That metropolis,
 advantageously situated for the trade of the ocean, was
 built in a regular and elegant form; and its numerous
 inhabitants were distinguished among the Gauls by their
 wealth, their learning, and the politeness of their manners.","('Gauls', 'NORP')"
"The
 British church might be composed of thirty or forty bishops,
 (187) with an adequate proportion of the inferior clergy; and 
 the want of riches (for they seem to have been poor)(188) 
 would compel them to deserve the public esteem by a decent
 and exemplary behaviour.","('British', 'NORP'), ('thirty or forty', 'CARDINAL'), ('187', 'CARDINAL'), ('188', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 anxiety of Augustus to provide the metropolis with
 sufficient plenty of corn was not extended beyond that
 necessary article of human subsistence; and when the popular
 clamour accused the dearness and scarcity of wine, a
 proclamation was issued by the grave reformer to remind his
 subjects that no man could reasonably complain of thirst,
 since the aqueducts of Agrippa had introduced into the city
 so many copious streams of pure and salubrious water.(56)","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Agrippa', 'PERSON')"
"The
 bride, attired and adorned like a Roman empress, was placed
 on a throne of state; and the king of the Goths, who assumed
 on this occasion the Roman habit, contented himself with a
 less honourable seat by her side.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The
 conduct of Gennerid in the important station to which he was
 promoted or restored, of master-general of Dalmatia,
 Pannonia, Noricum, and Rhaetia, seemed to revive the
 discipline and spirit of the republic.","('Gennerid', 'PERSON'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('Pannonia', 'PERSON'), ('Noricum', 'PERSON'), ('Rhaetia', 'PERSON')"
"The
 crowds that so lately fled before the sword of the
 barbarians were soon recalled by the hopes of plenty and
 pleasure and Albinus, praefect of Rome, informed the court,
 with some anxiety and surprise, that in a single day he had
 taken an account of the arrival of fourteen thousand
 strangers.(144)","('Albinus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('a single day', 'DATE'), ('fourteen thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('144', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 edifices of Rome, though the damage has been much
 exaggerated, received some injury from the violence of the
 Goths.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The
 faithful count of Africa transmitted a large sum of money,
 which fixed the attachment of the Imperial guards and his
 vigilance in preventing the exportation of corn and oil
 introduced famine, tumult and discontent into the walls of
 Rome.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The
 hasty retreat of Constantius might be justified by weighty
 reasons; but he resigned without a struggle the possession
 of Gaul; and Dardanus, the Praetorian praefect, is recorded
 as the only magistrate who refused to yield obedience to the
 usurper.(153)","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Dardanus', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('153', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 king of the Goths executed his promise without difficulty or
 delay: the helpless brothers, unsupported by any personal
 merit, were abandoned by their barbarian auxiliaries; and
 the short opposition of Valentia was expiated by the ruin of
 one of the oldest cities of Gaul.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Valentia', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'LOC')"
"The
 king of the Goths, who no longer dissembled his appetite for
 plunder and revenge, appeared in arms under the walls of the
 capital; and the trembling senate, without any hopes of
 relief, prepared by a desperate resistance to delay the ruin
 of their country.","('The\r\n king of the Goths', 'PERSON')"
"The
 ministers of Honorius were heard to declare that, if they
 had only invoked the name of the Deity, they would consult
 the public safety, and trust their souls to the mercy of
 Heaven: but they had sworn by the sacred head of the emperor
 himself; they had touched in solemn ceremony that august
 seat of majesty and wisdom; and the violation of their oath
 would expose them to the temporal penalties of sacrilege and
 rebellion.(86)
Second siege of Rome by the Goths, A.D. 409.","('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('Deity', 'PERSON'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 409', 'DATE')"
"The
 pre-eminence of birth and fortune must have been frequently
 violated by bold and popular citizens; and the haughty
 nobles, who complained that they were become the subjects of
 their own servants, (183) would sometimes regret the reign of 
 an arbitrary monarch.","('183', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 private revenge of forty thousand slaves was exercised
 without pity or remorse; and the ignominious lashes which
 they had formerly received were washed away in the blood of
 the guilty or obnoxious families.","('forty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 senate, who in this emergency assumed the supreme powers of
 government, appointed two ambassadors to negotiate with the
 enemy.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 unfortunate Attalus, who was left without subjects or
 allies, embarked in one of the ports of Spain, in search of
 some secure and solitary retreat; but he was intercepted at
 sea, conducted to the presence of Honorius, led in triumph
 through the streets of Rome or Ravenna, and publicly exposed
 to the gazing multitude, on the second step of the throne of
 his invincible conqueror.","('Attalus', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"The 
 important secret was communicated to Innocent, the bishop of
 Rome; and the successor of St. Peter is accused, perhaps
 without foundation, of preferring the safety of the republic
 to the rigid severity of the Christian worship.","('Innocent', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The 
 odious name of conquerors was softened into the mild and
 friendly appellation of the guests of the Romans; and the
 barbarians of Gaul, more especially the Goths, repeatedly
 declared that they were bound to the people by the ties of
 hospitality, and to the emperor by the duty of allegiance
 and military service.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
The Anician family,"('Anician', 'NORP')"
"The Britons, reduced to
 this extremity, no longer relied on the tardy and doubtful
 aid of a declining monarchy.","('Britons', 'NORP')"
"The Egyptian granite was beautifully encrusted with the
 precious green marble of Numidia; the perpetual stream of
 hot water was poured into the capacious basins through so
 many wide mouths of bright and massy silver; and the meanest
 Roman could purchase, with a small copper coin, the daily
 enjoyment of a scene of pomp and luxury which might excite
 the envy of the kings of Asia.(59)","('Egyptian', 'NORP'), ('Numidia', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('59', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Franks, the valiant and faithful allies of the Roman republic, were soon tempted to imitate the invaders whom
 they had so bravely resisted.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Germans were less corrupt than the
 Italians, less cruel than the Spaniards; and the rustic, or
 even savage aspect of those Tramontane warriors often
 disguised a simple and merciful disposition.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Italians', 'NORP'), ('Spaniards', 'NORP'), ('Tramontane', 'NORP')"
"The Gothic captain, struck with reverential awe, despatched a messenger to inform the king of the treasure which he had discovered, and received a
 peremptory order from Alaric, that all the consecrated plate
 and ornaments should be transported, without damage or
 delay, to the church of the apostle.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON')"
"The Gothic limits were enlarged by the additional gift of some neighbouring dioceses; and the
 successors of Alaric fixed their royal residence at Toulouse, which included five populous quarters, or cities, within the spacious circuit of its walls.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Toulouse', 'GPE'), ('five', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Gothic prince would have subscribed with
 pleasure the edict which the fanaticism of Olympius dictated
 to the simple and devout emperor.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Olympius', 'PERSON')"
The Gothic treasures,"('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"The Goths 
 evacuated the city at the end of six days, but Rome remained
 above nine months in the possession of the Imperialists; and
 every hour was stained by some atrocious act of cruelty,
 lust, and rapine.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('the end of six days', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('nine months', 'DATE'), ('Imperialists', 'NORP'), ('every hour', 'TIME')"
The Goths Evacuate Italy—,"('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The Goths conquer and restore Spain, A.D. 415-418.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('418', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Italian
 fugitives were dispersed through the provinces, along the
 coast of Egypt and Asia, as far as Constantinople and
 Jerusalem; and the village of Bethlehem, the solitary
 residence of St. Jerom and his female converts, was crowned
 with illustrious beggars, of either sex and every age, who
 excited the public compassion by the remembrance of their
 past fortune.","('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Bethlehem', 'GPE'), ('St. Jerom', 'LOC')"
"The Roman
 general, instead of expecting the attack in his lines,
 boldly, and perhaps wisely, resolved to pass the Rhone and
 to meet the barbarians.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Rhone', 'LOC')"
"The Roman Port insensibly swelled to the size of an episcopal city,(90) 
 where the corn of Africa was deposited in spacious granaries
 for the use of the capital.","('The Roman Port', 'FAC'), ('90', 'CARDINAL'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"The Roman general indeed
 refused to sully his laurels with the blood of Constantine;
 but the abdicated emperor and his son Julian were sent,
 under a strong guard, into Italy; and before they reached
 the palace of Ravenna they met the ministers of death.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"The Spanish 
 war was obstinately supported, during three campaigns, with
 desperate valour and various success; and the martial
 achievements of Wallia diffused through the empire the
 superior renown of the Gothic hero.","('The Spanish \r\n war', 'EVENT'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Wallia', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"The Triumvirs
 proscribed eighteen of the most flourishing colonies of
 Italy, and distributed their lands and houses to the
 veterans who revenged the death of Caesar, and oppressed the
 liberty of their country.","('Triumvirs', 'PERSON'), ('eighteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"The VENERABLE CITY, which had trampled on the necks of the fiercest nations, and established a system of laws, the perpetual guardians of justice and freedom, was content, like a wise and wealthy parent, to devolve on the Caesars, her favourite sons, the care of governing her ample patrimony. (35)","('The VENERABLE CITY', 'GPE'), ('Caesars', 'PERSON')"
"The Vandals
 themselves, and the Suevi, yielded to the efforts of the
 invincible Goths.","('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Suevi', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The accidents to which the precarious subsistence of the city
 was continually exposed in a winter navigation and an open
 road had suggested to the genius of the first Caesar the
 useful design which was executed under the reign of
 Claudius.","('winter', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Claudius', 'PERSON')"
"The accurate description of the city, which was composed in the Theodosian age, enumerates one thousand seven hundred and eighty houses, the residence of wealthy and honourable citizens. (24)","('Theodosian', 'GPE'), ('one thousand seven hundred and eighty', 'CARDINAL'), ('24', 'CARDINAL')"
"The acquisition of knowledge seldom engages the curiosity of the nobles, who abhor the fatigue and disdain the advantages of study; and the only books which they peruse are the Satires of Juvenal, and the verbose and fabulous histories of Marius Maximus. (47)","('the Satires of Juvenal', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Marius Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('47', 'CARDINAL')"
"The acquisition of riches served only
 to stimulate the avarice of the rapacious barbarians, who
 proceeded by threats, by blows, and by tortures, to force
 from their prisoners the confession of hidden treasure.(104)","('104', 'CARDINAL')"
"The adjacent province, which has been fondly compared to the
 garden of Eden, is blessed with a fruitful soil and a
 temperate climate; the face of the country displayed the
 arts and the rewards of industry; and the Goths, after their
 martial toils, luxuriously exhausted the rich vineyards of
 Aquitain. (167)","('Eden', 'LOC'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Aquitain', 'LOC'), ('167', 'CARDINAL')"
"The administration
 of the public cellars was delegated to a magistrate of
 honourable rank; and a considerable part of the vintage of
 Campania was reserved for the fortunate inhabitants of Rome.","('Campania', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The ample 
 patrimonies which many senatorian families possessed in
 Africa invited them, if they had time and prudence to escape
 from the ruin of their country, to embrace the shelter of
 that hospitable province.","('senatorian', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"The ancient Gallicia, whose limits included the kingdom of Old Castille, was divided between the Suevi and the Vandals: the Alani were scattered over the provinces of Carthagena and Lusitania, from the Mediterranean to the Atlantic Ocean; and the fruitful territory of Baetica was allotted to the Silingi, another branch of the Vandalic nation.","('Gallicia', 'NORP'), ('Old Castille', 'LOC'), ('Suevi', 'NORP'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Alani', 'NORP'), ('Carthagena', 'LOC'), ('Lusitania', 'LOC'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC'), ('the Atlantic Ocean', 'LOC'), ('Baetica', 'GPE'), ('Silingi', 'GPE'), ('Vandalic', 'LOC')"
"The ancients were
 destitute of many of the conveniences of life which have
 been invented or improved by the progress of industry; and
 the plenty of glass and linen has diffused more real
 comforts among the modern nations of Europe than the
 senators of Rome could derive from all the refinements of
 pompous or sensual luxury.(33) Their luxury and their manners 
 have been the subject of minute and laborious disquisition;
 but as such inquiries would divert me too long from the
 design of the present work, I shall produce an authentic
 state of Rome and its inhabitants which is more peculiarly
 applicable to the period of the Gothic invasion.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"The architect
 Vitruvius, who flourished in the Augustan age, and whose
 evidence, on this occasion, has peculiar weight and
 authority, observes that the innumerable habitations of the
 Roman people would have spread themselves far beyond the
 narrow limits of the city; and that the want of ground,
 which was probably contracted on every side by gardens and
 villas, suggested the common, though inconvenient, practice
 of raising the houses to a considerable height in the air.
 (68)","('Vitruvius', 'PERSON'), ('Augustan', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The artificial moles which formed the narrow
