Sentence,Entities
(3),"('3', 'CARDINAL')"
(32),"('32', 'CARDINAL')"
(35),"('35', 'CARDINAL')"
"(5) Alexander and Caesar, Augustus, 
 Trajan, and Constantine acknowledged, with a blush, that
 fame, or power, or pleasure, had been the important object
 of their labours; but the gods themselves beheld with
 reverence and love a virtuous mortal, who had practised on
 the throne the lessons of philosophy, and who, in a state of
 human imperfection, had aspired to imitate the moral
 attributes of the Deity.","('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"A
 flame arose on the opposite side; and Julian, who too
 clearly understood that his foremost vessels in attempting
 to land had been fired by the enemy, dexterously converted
 their extreme danger into a presage of victory.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"A
 simple, naked statue, finished by the hand of a Grecian
 artist, is of more genuine value than all these rude and
 costly monuments of barbaric labour; and, if we are more
 deeply affected by the ruin of a palace than by the
 conflagration of a cottage, our humanity must have formed a
 very erroneous estimate of the miseries of human life.(57)
Personal behaviour of Julian  
 Julian was an object of terror and hatred to the Persians;
 and the painters of that nation represented the invader of
 their country under the emblem of a furious lion, who
 vomited from his mouth a consuming fire.(58)","('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('57', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian  \r\n Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('58', 'CARDINAL')"
"A detachment of four thousand men was left at Circesium, which completed, to the number of ten thousand, the regular garrison of that important fortress.(43)
His march over the desert of Mesopotamia  
From the moment that the Romans entered the enemy's country,
 (44) the country of an active and artful enemy, the order of march was disposed in three columns.(45)","('four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Circesium', 'GPE'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mesopotamia', 'LOC'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('44', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('45', 'CARDINAL')"
"A formidable body of Scythian auxiliaries
 had been transported from another climate, and almost from
 another world, to invade a distant country of whose name and
 situation they were ignorant.","('Scythian', 'NORP')"
"A milder sentence might have deprived the capital of the East of its honours and privileges, and the courtiers, perhaps the subjects of Julian, would have applauded an act of justice which asserted the dignity of the supreme magistrate of the republic. (19)","('East', 'LOC'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('19', 'CARDINAL')"
"A multitude of
 artificial canals, dug without much labour in a soft and
 yielding soil, connected the rivers and intersected the
 plain of Assyria.","('Assyria', 'GPE')"
"A peace, or rather a long truce, of thirty
 years, was stipulated between the hostile nations; the faith
 of the treaty was ratified by solemn oaths and religious
 ceremonies; and hostages of distinguished rank were
 reciprocally delivered to secure the performance of the
 condition.","('thirty\r\n years', 'DATE')"
"A similar
 danger recalled the intrepid prince to the defence of the
 front; and, as he galloped between the columns, the centre
 of the left was attacked, and almost overpowered, by a
 furious charge of the Persian cavalry and elephants.","('Persian', 'NORP')"
"A small convoy of provisions advanced to meet
 the army as far as the castle of Ur; and the supply was the
 more grateful, since it declared the fidelity of Sebastian
 and Procopius.","('Sebastian', 'PERSON'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON')"
"A solemn sacrifice was offered to the god of war, but
 the appearances of the victims threatened the most
 inauspicious events; and Julian soon discovered, by less
 ambiguous signs, that he had now reached the term of his
 prosperity.(72)
Situation and obstinacy of Julian, A.D. 363.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('72', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('363', 'CARDINAL')"
"A strong dyke
 was constructed to interrupt the ordinary current of the
 NaharMalcha: a flood of waters rushed impetuously into their
 new bed; and the Roman fleet, steering their triumphant
 course into the Tigris, derided the vain and ineffectual
 barriers which the Persians of Ctesiphon had erected to
 oppose their passage.","('NaharMalcha', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Ctesiphon', 'GPE')"
"A supply of twenty days' provisions
 was preserved for the use of the soldiers; and the rest of
 the magazines, with a fleet of eleven hundred vessels, which
 rode at anchor in the Tigris, were abandoned to the flames
 by the absolute command of the emperor.","('twenty days', 'DATE'), ('eleven hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"A tyrant might have
 proscribed, without distinction, the lives and fortunes of
 the citizens of Antioch; and the unwarlike Syrians must have
 patiently submitted to the lust, the rapaciousness, and the cruelty of the faithful legions of Gaul.","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Syrians', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"A.D. 319-390, Ec  
Yet Antioch possessed one citizen whose genius and virtues
 might atone, in the opinion of Julian, for the vice and
 folly of his country.","('A.D. 319-390', 'DATE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
A.D. 363.,"('A.D. 363', 'DATE')"
"Above 
 sixteen years after the death of Julian, the charge was
 solemnly and vehemently urged in a public oration addressed
 by Libanius to the emperor Theodosius.","('sixteen years', 'DATE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Libanius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"After a
 laborious march of two days (29) he halted on the third at 
 Bercea, or Aleppo, where he had the mortification of finding
 a senate almost entirely Christian, who received with cold
 and formal demonstrations of respect the eloquent sermon of
 the apostle of Paganism.","('two days', 'DATE'), ('29', 'DATE'), ('the third', 'DATE'), ('Bercea', 'GPE'), ('Aleppo', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Paganism', 'NORP')"
"After the
 siege of Perisabor the firmness of the emperor was exercised
 by the insolent avarice of the army, who loudly complained
 that their services were rewarded by a trifling donative of
 one hundred pieces of silver.","('Perisabor', 'GPE'), ('one hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"After this discourse, which Julian pronounced in a firm and gentle tone of voice, he distributed, by a military testament, (97) the remains of his  private fortune; and making some inquiry why Anatolius was not present, he understood, from the answer of Sallust, that Anatolius was killed; and bewailed, with amiable inconsistency, the loss of his friend.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('97', 'CARDINAL'), ('Anatolius', 'PERSON'), ('Sallust', 'PERSON'), ('Anatolius', 'PERSON')"
"Alexander was
 transformed into Diogenes—the philosopher was degraded
 into a priest.","('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Diogenes', 'PERSON')"
"Ammianus has delineated in lively colours the scene of universal despair, which he seems to have viewed with an eye of compassion.(125)","('Ammianus', 'PERSON')"
"As far
 as the confines of India and Scythia, the satraps of the
 distant provinces were ordered to assemble their troops, and
 to march, without delay, to the assistance of their monarch.","('India', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'GPE')"
"As he examined the exterior fortifications of
 Maogamalcha, two Persians, devoting themselves for their
 country, suddenly rushed upon him with drawn scimitars: the
 emperor dexterously received their blows on his uplifted
 shield; and, with a steady and well-aimed thrust, laid one
 of his adversaries dead at his feet.","('Maogamalcha', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"As he had minutely studied the operations of Trajan
 in the same country, he soon recollected that his warlike
 predecessor had dug a new and navigable canal, which,
 leaving Coche on the right hand, conveyed the waters of the
 NaharMalcha into the river Tigris at some distance above the
 cities.","('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Coche', 'PERSON'), ('NaharMalcha', 'GPE'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"As it became necessary to transport the Roman army over the
 Tigris, another labour presented itself, of less toil, but
 of more danger, than the preceding expedition.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"As long as the Romans seemed to advance into the country,
 their march was observed and insulted from a distance by
 several bodies of Persian cavalry; who, showing themselves,
 sometimes in loose, and sometimes in closer order faintly
 skirmished with the advanced guards.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"As soon as the Persian monarch was 
 informed that the throne of Constantius was filled by a
 prince of a very different character, he condescended to
 make some artful or perhaps sincere overtures towards a
 negotiation of peace.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as the Romans had landed on the western bank, they
 were delivered from the hostile pursuit of the barbarians;
 but in a laborious march of two hundred miles over the
 plains of Mesopotamia they endured the last extremities of
 thirst and hunger.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('two hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Mesopotamia', 'LOC')"
"As soon as the feast was ended, the voice of Mercury proclaimed the will of Jupiter, that a celestial crown should be the reward of superior merit.","('Mercury', 'PERSON'), ('Jupiter', 'LOC')"
"As soon as they
 possessed a more equal field, Julian, who with his light
 infantry had led the attack,(69) darted through the ranks a  skilful and experienced eye; his bravest soldiers, according to the precepts of Homer,(70) were distributed in the front 
 and rear; and all the trumpets of the Imperial army sounded
 to battle.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('69', 'DATE'), ('Homer', 'PERSON'), ('70', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"As the
 Romans continued their march, their long array, which was
 forced to bend or divide, according to the varieties of the
 ground, afforded frequent and favourable opportunities to
 their vigilant enemies.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"As the price of his disgraceful concessions, the emperor
 might perhaps have stipulated that the camp of the hungry
 Romans should be plentifully supplied, (116) and that they 
 should be permitted to pass the Tigris on the bridge which
 was constructed by the hands of the Persians.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('116', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"As they exclaimed,(93) a cloud of darts and 
 arrows was discharged from the flying squadrons, and a
 javelin, after razing the skin of his arm, transpierced the
 ribs, and fixed in the inferior part of the liver.","('93', 'CARDINAL')"
"At
 length, as the only practicable measure, he embraced the
 resolution of directing his steps towards the banks of the
 Tigris, with the design of saving the army by a hasty march
 to the confines of Corduene, a fertile and friendly
 province, which acknowledged the sovereignty of Rome.","('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Corduene', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"At Thilsaphata (118) the emperor most 
 graciously received the generals of Mesopotamia, and the
 remains of a once flourishing army at length reposed
 themselves under the walls of Nisibis.","('Thilsaphata', 'GPE'), ('118', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mesopotamia', 'GPE'), ('Nisibis', 'PERSON')"
"At the 
 very time when he declined the siege of Ctesiphon, he
 rejected, with obstinacy and disdain, the most flattering
 offers of a negotiation of peace.","('Ctesiphon', 'GPE')"
"At the distance of fifty
 miles from the royal residence of Ctesiphon, Perisabor, or
 Anbar, held the second rank in the province: a city, large,
 populous, and well fortified, surrounded with a double wall,
 almost encompassed by a branch of the Euphrates, and
 defended by the valour of a numerous garrison.","('fifty\r\n miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Ctesiphon', 'GPE'), ('Perisabor', 'GPE'), ('Anbar', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"At the same time he reproved the immoderate grief of the spectators; and conjured them not to disgrace, by unmanly tears, the fate of a prince who in a few moments would be united with heaven and with the stars. (98)","('a few moments', 'TIME'), ('98', 'CARDINAL')"
August,"('August', 'DATE')"
"Babylon had been converted into a royal park, but near the
 ruins of the ancient capital new cities had successively
 arisen, and the populousness of the country was displayed in
 the multitudes of towns and villages, which were built of
 bricks dried in the sun and strongly cemented with bitumen,
 the natural and peculiar production of the Babylonian soil.","('Babylon', 'GPE'), ('Babylonian', 'NORP')"
"Before they were entirely
 consumed he might still have reached the wealthy and
 unwarlike cities of Ecbatana or Susa by the effort of a
 rapid and well-directed march; (86) but he was deprived of 
 this last resource by his ignorance of the roads and by the
 perfidy of his guides.","('Ecbatana', 'GPE'), ('Susa', 'PERSON'), ('86', 'DATE')"
"But as Julian was sensible that the
 hope of a safe and honourable peace might cool the ardour of
 his troops, he earnestly requested that Hormisdas would
 privately dismiss the minister of Sapor, and conceal this
 dangerous temptation from the knowledge of the camp.(76)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Hormisdas', 'PERSON'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON')"
"But as soon as an  Helepolis had been
 constructed, which could engage on equal terms with the
 loftiest ramparts, the tremendous aspect of a moving turret,
 that would leave no hope of resistance or of mercy,
 terrified the defenders of the citadel into an humble
 submission, and the place was surrendered only two days
 after Julian first appeared under the walls of Perisabor.","('Helepolis', 'PRODUCT'), ('only two days', 'DATE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Perisabor', 'PERSON')"
"But as the warlike emperor, instead of
 Constantius, had chosen Alexander for his model, he advanced
 without delay to Carrhae, (36) a very ancient city of 
 Mesopotamia, at the distance of four-score miles from
 Hierapolis.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Carrhae', 'PERSON'), ('36', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mesopotamia', 'GPE'), ('four-score miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Hierapolis', 'GPE')"
"But if Jovian
 presumed to solicit those equitable terms, they were sternly
 refused by the haughty tyrant of the East, whose clemency
 had pardoned the invaders of his country.","('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"But on the approach of
 the Romans this rich and smiling prospect was instantly
 blasted.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"But the
 impregnable fortress of Thilutha could scorn the menace of a
 siege, and the emperor was obliged to content himself with
 an insulting promise that, when he had subdued the interior
 provinces of Persia, Thilutha would no longer refuse to
 grace the triumph of the conqueror.","('Thilutha', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Thilutha', 'PERSON')"
"But the barbarians were finally repulsed, the
 country became every day less favourable to the operations
 of cavalry, and when the Romans arrived at Macepracta they
 perceived the ruins of the wall which had been constructed
 by the ancient kings of Assyria to secure their dominions
 from the incursions of the Medes.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Macepracta', 'GPE'), ('Assyria', 'GPE'), ('Medes', 'LOC')"
"But the event of the day was adverse to
 the barbarians.","('the day', 'DATE')"
"But the feeble Arsaces Tiranus,(38) king of Armenia, had degenerated still more shamefully than his father Chosroes from the manly virtues of the great Tiridates; and as the pusillanimous monarch was averse to any enterprise of danger and glory, he could disguise his timid indolence by the more decent excuses of religion and gratitude.","('Arsaces Tiranus', 'PERSON'), ('38', 'CARDINAL'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Tiridates', 'NORP')"
"But the most
 certain and irreparable loss of the Romans was that of time.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"But the pride of Sapor was astonished
 by the firmness of Julian, who sternly declared that he
 would never consent to hold a peaceful conference among the
 flames and ruins of the cities of Mesopotamia, and who
 added, with a smile of contempt, that it was needless to
 treat by ambassadors, as he himself had determined to visit
 speedily the court of Persia.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Mesopotamia', 'LOC'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"But the reduction, or even the siege, of the capital of
 Persia was still at a distance: nor can the military conduct
 of the emperor be clearly apprehended without a knowledge of
 the country which was the theatre of his bold and skilful
 operations.(65) Twenty miles to the south of Bagdad, and on 
 the eastern bank of the Tigris, the curiosity of travellers
 has observed some ruins of the palaces of Ctesiphon, which
 in the time of Julian was a great and populous city.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('65', 'CARDINAL'), ('Twenty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Ctesiphon', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"But the royal race of Constantius
 Chlorus was reduced to his own person; and if he entertained
 any serious thoughts of investing with the purple the most
 worthy among the Romans, he was diverted from his resolution
 by the difficulty of the choice, the jealousy of power, the
 fear of ingratitude, and the natural presumption of health,
 of youth, and of prosperity.","('Constantius\r\n Chlorus', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"But their preparations were dilatory, their motions slow;
 and before Sapor could lead an army into the field, he
 received the melancholy intelligence of the devastation of
 Assyria, the ruin of his palaces, and the slaughter of his
 bravest troops, who defended the passage of the Tigris.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Assyria', 'GPE'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"But this feeble relief served only to
 aggravate the sense of the public distress; and the Romans
 began to entertain the most gloomy apprehensions that,
 before they could reach the frontiers of the empire, they
 should all perish, either by famine or by the sword of the
 barbarians.(90)
Julian is mortally wounded.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"But we may rest
 assured, from the love of glory, and contempt of danger,
 which formed the character of Julian, that he was not
 discouraged by any trivial or imaginary obstacles.(75)","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"By the indefigable
 labour of the soldiers a broad and deep channel was speedily
 prepared for the reception of the Euphrates.","('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"Coche was situate on the
 western side of the Tigris; but it was naturally considered
 as a suburb of Ctesiphon, with which we may suppose it to
 have been connected by a permanent bridge of boats.","('Coche', 'PERSON'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Ctesiphon', 'GPE')"
"Conscious of their superiority over the barbarians in arms
 and discipline, they disdained to yield, they refused to
 capitulate: every obstacle was surmounted by their patience,
 courage, and military skill; and the memorable retreat of
 the ten thousand exposed and insulted the weakness of the
 Persian monarchy.(115)","('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('115', 'CARDINAL')"
"Dagalaiphus, and Secundinus duke of Osrhoene, conducted the troops of the rearguard; the baggage securely proceeded in the intervals of the columns; and the ranks, from a motive either of use or ostentation, were formed in such open order that the whole line of march extended almost ten miles.","('Dagalaiphus', 'GPE'), ('Secundinus', 'GPE'), ('Osrhoene', 'GPE'), ('almost ten miles', 'QUANTITY')"
Disaffection of the king of Armenia,"('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"During the licentious days of the
 Saturnalia, the streets of the city resounded with insolent
 songs, which derided the laws, the religion, the personal
 conduct, and even the  beard of the emperor; and the
 spirit of Antioch was manifested by the connivance of the
 magistrates and the applause of the multitude. (18)","('the licentious days', 'DATE'), ('Saturnalia', 'NORP'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('18', 'CARDINAL')"
"During the march the Surenas, or Persian
 general, and Malek Rodosaces, the renowned emir of the tribe
 of Gassan,(50) incessantly hovered round the army; every 
 straggler was intercepted, every detachment was attacked,
 and the valiant Hormisdas escaped with some difficulty from
 their hands.","('Surenas', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Malek Rodosaces', 'PERSON'), ('Gassan', 'PERSON'), ('50', 'DATE'), ('Hormisdas', 'PERSON')"
"Each of the candidates was allowed to
 display the merit of his own exploits; but, in the judgment
 of the gods, the modest silence of Marcus pleaded more
 powerfully than the elaborate orations of his haughty
 rivals.","('Marcus', 'PERSON')"
"Election
of Jovian.—","('Jovian', 'NORP')"
"Every day, every
 hour, as the supply diminished, the value and price of
 subsistence increased in the Roman camp. (89) Julian, who 
 always contented himself with such food as a hungry soldier
 would have disdained, distributed, for the use of the
 troops, the provisions of the Imperial household, and
 whatever could be spared from the sumpter-horses of the
 tribunes and generals.","('every\r\n hour', 'TIME'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"Fashion was the only
 law, pleasure the only pursuit, and the splendour of dress
 and furniture was the only distinction of the citizens of
 Antioch.","('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"Fifteen hundred enemies were already in
 the midst of the city.","('Fifteen hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"Four considerable villages were assigned for
 the subsistence of his Indian dogs; eight hundred stallions
 and sixteen thousand mares were constantly kept, at the
 expense of the country, for the royal stables; and as the
 daily tribute which was paid to the satrap amounted to one
 English bushel of silver, we may compute the annual revenue
 of Assyria at more than twelve hundred thousand pounds
 sterling. (56)
Invasion of Assyria.","('Four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Indian', 'NORP'), ('eight hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('sixteen thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('one\r\n English bushel', 'QUANTITY'), ('Assyria', 'GPE'), ('twelve hundred thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('56', 'CARDINAL'), ('Assyria', 'GPE')"
"From the hills, the archers of Persia
 insulted and annoyed the wearied legionaries; and a body of
 cavalry, which had penetrated with desperate courage through
 the Praetorian gate, was cut in pieces, after a doubtful
 conflict, near the Imperial tent.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"From the information of the peasants Julian
 ascertained the vestiges of this ancient work, which were
 almost obliterated by design or accident.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"From thence the emperor pursued his
 march, above ninety miles, along the winding stream of the
 Euphrates, till at length, about one month after his
 departure from Antioch, he discovered the towers of
 Circesium, the extreme limit of the Roman dominions.","('ninety miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('about one month', 'DATE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Circesium', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Had Jovian been capable
 of executing a bold and prudent measure, he would have
 continued his march with unremitting diligence; the progress
 of the treaty would have suspended the attacks of the
 barbarians; and, before the expiration of the fourth day, he
 might have safely reached the fruitful province of Corduene,
 at the distance only of one hundred miles. (110)","('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('the fourth day', 'DATE'), ('Corduene', 'GPE'), ('one hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('110', 'CARDINAL')"
"Had it been possible for Julian to maintain
 a bridge of communication on the Tigris, and to preserve the
 conquered places of Assyria, a desolated province could not
 afford any large or regular supplies in a season of the year
 when the lands were covered by the inundation of the
 Euphrates,(84) and the unwholesome air was darkened with 
 swarms of innumerable insects. (85)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Assyria', 'GPE'), ('a season of the year', 'DATE'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('84', 'CARDINAL'), ('85', 'CARDINAL')"
"Had the arms of Julian been victorious, we
 should now admire the conduct as well as the courage of a
 hero who, by depriving his soldiers of the hopes of a
 retreat, left them only the alternative of death or
 conquest.(82)
and marches against Sapor.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('82', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON')"
"He acquired, by a
 single article, the impregnable city of Nisibis, which had
 sustained, in three successive sieges, the effort of his
 arms.","('Nisibis', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
He continues his retreat to Nisibis,"('Nisibis', 'PERSON')"
"He despised the trophies of a Gothic victory,(8) and was 
 satisfied that the rapacious barbarians of the Danube would
 be restrained from any future violation of the faith of
 treaties by the terror of his name and the additional
 fortifications with which he strengthened the Thracian and
 Illyrian frontiers.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Thracian', 'NORP'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP')"
"He destroyed in a
 single hour the whole navy, which had been transported above
 five hundred miles,","('a\r\n single hour', 'TIME'), ('five hundred miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"He employed the awful
 moments with the firm temper of a hero and a sage; the
 philosophers who had accompanied him in this fatal
 expedition compared the tent of Julian with the prison of
 Socrates; and the spectators, whom duty, or friendship, or
 curiosity, had assembled round his couch, listened with
 respectful grief to the funeral oration of their dying
 emperor.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Socrates', 'PERSON')"
"He enacted that, in a time of scarcity, it should
 be sold at a price which had seldom been known in the most
 plentiful years; and that his own example might strengthen
 his laws, he sent into the market four hundred and
 twenty-two thousand modii, or measures, which were drawn
 by his order from the granaries of Hierapolis, of Chalcis,
 and even of Egypt.","('the most\r\n plentiful years', 'DATE'), ('four hundred and\r\n twenty-two thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hierapolis', 'GPE'), ('Chalcis', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"He excited their resentment by a lively picture of the insolence of the Persians and he exhorted them to imitate his firm resolution either to extirpate that perfidious nation, or to devote his life in the cause of the republic.","('Persians', 'NORP')"
"He expressed a pious attachment to the memory of Constantius, from whose hands he had received in marriage Olympias, the daughter of the praefect Ablavius; and the alliance of a female who had been educated as the destined wife of the emperor Constans exalted the dignity of a barbarian king. (39) Tiranus professed the Christian religion; he reigned over a nation of Christians; and he was restrained, by every principle of conscience and interest, from contributing to the victory which would consummate the ruin of the church.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Olympias', 'PERSON'), ('Ablavius', 'PERSON'), ('Constans', 'PERSON'), ('Tiranus', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"He had been insulted by satires and libels; in his turn he composed, under the title of the Enemy of the Beard, an ironical confession of his own faults, and a severe satire of the licentious and effeminate manners of Antioch.","('the Enemy of the Beard', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"He immediately
 detached the royal cavalry, perhaps the ten thousand
 Immortals, (104) to second and support the pursuit and discharged the whole weight of his united forces on the
 rearguard of the Romans.","('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Immortals', 'NORP'), ('104', 'CARDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"He informed Libanius of his 
 progress as far as Hierapolis by an elegant epistle,(33) 
 which displays the facility of his genius and his tender
 friendship for the sophist of Antioch.","('Libanius', 'PERSON'), ('Hierapolis', 'PERSON'), ('33', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"He punished
 with death, or ignominy, the misbehaviour of three troops of
 horse, who, in a skirmish with the Surenas, had lost their
 honour and one of their standards: and he distinguished with
 obsidional(62) crowns the valour of the foremost soldiers 
 who had ascended into the city of Maogamalcha.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Surenas', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('62', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maogamalcha', 'GPE')"
"He resolves to march against the Persians, A.D. 362","('Persians', 'NORP')"
He saves the Roman Army by a disgraceful Treaty.,"('the Roman Army', 'ORG'), ('Treaty', 'LAW')"
He transports his fleet from the Euphrates to the Tigris,"('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"He was a Persian prince, of the royal race of the Sassanides, who, in the troubles of the minority of Sapor, had escaped from prison to the hospitable court of
 the great Constantine.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Sassanides', 'NORP'), ('Sapor', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"He was accompanied by two of the king's sons and
 many of the principal satraps; and fame and expectation
 exaggerated the strength of the remaining powers, which
 slowly advanced under the conduct of Sapor himself.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON')"
"He was astonished by the inflexible firmness of a
 hero who remembered, most unfortunately for himself and for
 his country, that Alexander had uniformly rejected the
 propositions of Darius.","('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Darius', 'PERSON')"
"He was impatient to secure an empire at the
 expense of a few provinces, and the respectable names of
 religion and honour concealed the personal fears and the
 ambition of Jovian Notwithstanding the dutiful solicitations
 of the inhabitants, decency, as well as prudence, forbade
 the emperor to lodge in the palace of Nisibis; but the next
 morning after his arrival, Bineses, the ambassador of
 Persia, entered the place, displayed from the citadel the
 standard of the Great King, and proclaimed, in his name, the
 cruel alternative of exile or servitude.","('Nisibis', 'PERSON'), ('the next\r\n morning', 'TIME'), ('Bineses', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"He was persuaded, perhaps with truth, that the
 senators of Antioch, who possessed lands or were concerned
 in trade, had themselves contributed to the calamities of
 their country; and he imputed the disrespectful boldness
 which they assumed to the sense, not of public duty, but of
 private interest.","('Antioch', 'ORG')"
"His
 ardent desire to march into the heart of Persia was checked
 by the indispensable duty of regulating the state of the
 empire, by his zeal to revive the worship of the gods, and
 by the advice of his wisest friends, who represented the
 necessity of allowing the salutary interval of winter
 quarters to restore the exhausted strength of the legions of
 Gaul and the discipline and spirit of the Eastern troops.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('winter', 'DATE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"His
 expectations were disappointed by the treachery of the
 Armenian king, who permitted and most probably directed, the
 desertion of his auxiliary troops from the camp of the
 Romans;(74) and by the dissensions of the two generals, who 
 were incapable of forming or executing any plan for the
 public service.","('Armenian', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('74', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"His design of invading Persia  
 Hierapolis, situate almost on the banks of the Euphrates,(34) 
 had been appointed for the general rendezvous of the Roman
 troops, who immediately passed the great river on the bridge
 of boats which was previously constructed.","('Persia  \r\n Hierapolis', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('34', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"His just indignation was
 expressed in the grave and manly language of a Roman.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"His school was assiduously frequented by the Grecian youth;
 his disciples, who sometimes exceeded the number of eighty,
 celebrated their incomparable master; and the jealousy of
 his rivals, who persecuted him from one city to another,
 confirmed the favourable opinion which Libanius
 ostentatiously displayed of his superior merit.","('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('eighty', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Libanius', 'PERSON')"
"His subjects complained
 with superstitious indignation, that famine had pursued the
 emperor's steps from Constantinople to Antioch, and the
 discontent of a hungry people was exasperated by the
 injudicious attempt to relieve their distress.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
His successful Expedition against the Persians.—,"('Persians', 'NORP')"
"His suspicions are
 unsupported by fact or argument, and we can only esteem the
 generous zeal of the sophist of Antioch for the cold and
 neglected ashes of his friend.(135)
and funeral of Julian","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('135', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"His unexpected death left the
 empire without a master, and without an heir, in a state of
 perplexity and danger which, in the space of four-score
 years, had never been experienced, since the election of
 Diocletian.","('four-score\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"His wound began to bleed with fresh violence: his respiration was embarrassed by the swelling of the veins: he called for a draught of cold water, and, as soon as he had drunk it, expired without pain, about the hour of midnight.","('about the hour of midnight', 'TIME')"
"History has
 recorded the name of a private soldier, the first who
 ascended from the mine into a deserted tower.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Hormisdas and Arinthseus were appointed generals of the horse, and the singular adventures of Hormisdas (46) are not undeserving of our notice.","('Hormisdas', 'PERSON'), ('Arinthseus', 'PERSON'), ('Hormisdas', 'PERSON'), ('46', 'CARDINAL')"
"Hormisdas at first excited the compassion, and at length acquired the esteem, of his new masters; his valour and fidelity raised him to the military honours of the Roman service; and, though a Christian, he might indulge the secret satisfaction of convincing his
 ungrateful country that an oppressed subject may prove the most dangerous enemy.","('Hormisdas', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"If he
 had stretched as far as the Euphrates the claims of his
 ambition, he might have been secure, says Libanius, of not
 meeting with a refusal.","('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Libanius', 'PERSON')"
"If he had fixed, as the boundary of
 Persia, the Orontes, the Cydnus, the Sangarius, or even the
 Thracian Bosphorus, flatterers would not have been wanting
 in the court of Jovian to convince the timid monarch that
 his remaining provinces would still afford the most ample
 gratifications of power and luxury.(112)","('Persia', 'LOC'), ('Orontes', 'NORP'), ('Cydnus', 'NORP'), ('Sangarius', 'NORP'), ('the\r\n Thracian Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Jovian', 'GPE')"
"If the 
 inclinations of Julian had been similar to those of his
 predecessor, he might have wasted the active and important
 season of the year in the circus of Samosata or in the
 churches of Edessa.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('the active and important\r\n season of the year', 'DATE'), ('Samosata', 'EVENT'), ('Edessa', 'GPE')"
"If they had followed this royal
 canal, which bore the name of NaharMalcha, (66) the 
 intermediate situation of Coche would have separated the
 fleet and army of Julian; and the rash attempt of steering
 against the current of the Tigris, and forcing their way
 through the midst of a hostile capital, must have been
 attended with the total destruction of the Roman navy.","('NaharMalcha', 'GPE'), ('66', 'CARDINAL'), ('Coche', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"If, on the contrary, it was advisable to
 advance into the inland country, the destruction of the
 fleet and magazines was the only measure which could save
 that valuable prize from the hands of the numerous and
 active troops which might suddenly be poured from the gates
 of Ctesiphon.","('Ctesiphon', 'GPE')"
"In every useful
 labour the hand of Julian was prompt and strenuous; and the
 Imperial purple was wet and dirty, as the coarse garment of
 the meanest soldier.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"In his last moments he displayed, perhaps with some ostentation, the love of virtue and of fame, which had been the ruling passions of his life. (99)
Election of the emperor Jovian, A.D. 363, June 27.","('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 363', 'DATE'), ('June 27', 'DATE')"
"In the cool moments of reflection, Julian preferred the
 useful and benevolent virtues of Antoninus; but his
 ambitious spirit was inflamed by the glory of Alexander, and
 he solicited, with equal ardour, the esteem of the wise and
 the applause of the multitude.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Antoninus', 'PERSON'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON')"
"In the hurry of military preparation, and the
 careless confidence of a familiar correspondence, the zeal
 of Julian appears to have been lively and uniform.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"In the neighbourhood of the same 
 river, at no very considerable distance from the fatal
 station of Dura, (114) the ten thousand Greeks, without 
 generals, or guides, or provisions, were abandoned, above
 twelve hundred miles from their native country, to the
 resentment of a victorious monarch.","('Dura', 'ORG'), ('114', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('twelve hundred miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"In the obscure freedom of a private
 station, the son indulged his taste for wine and women; yet
 he supported, with credit, the character of a Christian(102)  and a soldier.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('102', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the season of life when
 the powers of the mind and body enjoy the most active
 vigour, the emperor, who was instructed by the experience
 and animated by the success of the German war, resolved to
 signalise his reign by some more splendid and memorable
 achievement.","('the German war', 'EVENT')"
"In the silence of the night they swam the Tigris,
 surprised an unguarded post of the enemy, and displayed at
 the dawn of day the signal of their resolution and fortune.","('the night', 'TIME'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('the dawn of day', 'DATE')"
"In the succeeding night
 the camp of Carche was protected by the lofty dykes of the
 river; and the Roman army, though incessantly exposed to the
 vexatious pursuit of the Saracens, pitched their tents near
 the city of Dura (106) four days after the death of Julian.","('the succeeding night', 'TIME'), ('Carche', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Dura', 'GPE'), ('106', 'CARDINAL'), ('four days', 'DATE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"In the warm climate of Assyria, which 
 solicited a luxurious people to the gratification of every
 sensual desire, (60) a youthful conqueror preserved his 
 chastity pure and inviolate: nor was Julian ever tempted,
 even by a motive of curiosity, to visit his female captives
 of exquisite beauty,(61) who, instead of resisting his power, 
 would have disputed with each other the honour of his
 embraces.","('Assyria', 'GPE'), ('60', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"In this fruitful and pleasant country the
 Romans were plentifully supplied with water and forage: and
 several forts, which might have embarrassed the motions of
 the army, submitted, after some resistance, to the efforts
 of their valour.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"In this hopeless situation, the fainting spirits of the
 Romans were revived by the sound of peace.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"In this scene of
 terror and distress, the body of the deceased prince,
 according to his own directions, was decently embalmed; and,
 at the dawn of day, the generals convened a military senate,
 at which the commanders of the legions, and the officers
 both of cavalry and infantry, were invited to assist.","('the dawn of day', 'DATE')"
"In this unequal contest, in which the produce of the land is claimed by one party as his exclusive property, is used by another as a lucrative object of trade, and is required by a third for the daily and necessary support of life, all the profits of the intermediate agents are accumulated on the head of the
 defenceless consumers.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL')"
"Instead of confining his servile march
 to the banks of the Euphrates and Tigris, he resolved to
 imitate the adventurous spirit of Alexander, and boldly to
 advance into the inland provinces, till he forced his rival
 to contend with him, perhaps in the plains of Arbela, for
 the empire of Asia.","('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Arbela', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"Instead of pressing, with the foremost of the
 crowd, into the palace of Constantinople, Libanius calmly
 expected his arrival at Antioch, withdrew from court on the
 first symptoms of coldness and indifference, required a
 formal invitation for each visit, and taught his sovereign
 an important lesson, that he might command the obedience of
 a subject, but that he must deserve the attachment of a
 friend.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Libanius', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Instead of tamely resigning
 themselves to the secret deliberations and private views of
 a single person, the united councils of the Greeks were
 inspired by the generous enthusiasm of a popular assembly,
 where the mind of each citizen is filled with the love of
 glory, the pride of freedom, and the contempt of death.","('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"It is
 not easy for us to conceive by what arts of fortification a
 city thrice besieged and taken by the predecessors of Julian
 could be rendered impregnable against an army of sixty
 thousand Romans, commanded by a brave and experienced
 general, and abundantly supplied with ships, provisions,
 battering engines, and military stores.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('sixty\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"It is the common calamity of old age
 (27) to lose whatever might have rendered it desirable; but 
 Libanius experienced the peculiar misfortune of surviving
 the religion and the sciences to which he had consecrated
 his genius.","('27', 'DATE'), ('Libanius', 'PERSON')"
"It was an ancient custom in the funerals, as well as in the
 triumphs of the Romans that the voice of praise should be
 corrected by that of satire and ridicule, and that, in the
 midst of the splendid pageants which displayed the glory of
 the living or of the dead, their imperfections should not be
 concealed from the eyes of the world.(136)","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('136', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was considered as an indulgence that the
 inhabitants of those fortresses were permitted to retire
 with their effects; but the conqueror rigorously insisted
 that the Romans should for ever abandon the king and kingdom
 of Armenia.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"Jovian alleged, with some confusion, the sanctity of oaths; and as the reluctance with which he accepted the present of a crown of gold convinced the citizens of their hopeless condition, the advocate Sylvanus was provoked to exclaim, ""O emperor!","('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('Sylvanus', 'PERSON')"
"Jovian, who in a few weeks had assumed the
 habits of a prince, (124) was displeased with freedom, and  offended with truth; and as he reasonably supposed that the discontent of the people might incline them to submit to the
 Persian government, he published an edict, under pain of death, that they should leave the city within the term of three days.","('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('a few weeks', 'DATE'), ('124', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('three days', 'DATE')"
"Julian
 attempted to draw the deadly weapon from his side; but his
 fingers were cut by the sharpness of the steel, and he fell
 senseless from his horse.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Julian
 led the van with the skill and attention of a consummate
 general; he was alarmed by the intelligence that his rear
 was suddenly attacked.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Julian
 marched over the same ground which had been trod above seven
 hundred years before by the footsteps of the younger Cyrus,
 and which is described by one of the companions of his
 expedition, the sage and heroic Xenophon.(47)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('seven\r\n hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Cyrus', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Xenophon', 'PERSON'), ('47', 'CARDINAL')"
"Julian checked their ardour, that he might
 ensure their success; and immediately diverted the attention
 of the garrison by the tumult and clamour of a general
 assault.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Julian composes a satire against Antioch  But instead of abusing or exerting the authority of the state to revenge his personal injuries, Julian contented himself with an inoffensive mode of retaliation, which it would be in the power of few princes to employ.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Julian disguised the silent anxiety of
 his own mind with smiles of confidence and joy; and amused
 the hostile nations with the spectacle of military games,
 which he insultingly celebrated under the walls of Coche.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Coche', 'PERSON')"
"Julian might expect that a conqueror who
 possessed the two forcible instruments of persuasion, steel
 and gold, would easily procure a plentiful subsistence from
 the fears or avarice of the natives.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Julian still
 continued to applaud his own policy, treated the complaints
 of the people as a vain and ungrateful murmur, and convinced
 Antioch that he had inherited the obstinacy, though not the
 cruelty, of his brother Gallus.(16)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'PERSON'), ('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('16', 'CARDINAL')"
"Julian was convinced
 that he had seen the menacing countenance of the god of war;
 (91) the council which he summoned, of Tuscan Haruspices,(92) 
 unanimously pronounced that he should abstain from action;
 but, on this occasion, necessity and reason were more
 prevalent than superstition; and the trumpets sounded at the
 break of day.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('91', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tuscan Haruspices', 'PERSON'), ('92', 'DATE')"
"Julian was persuaded to fix, till the ensuing spring, his
 residence at Antioch, among a people maliciously disposed to
 deride the haste and to censure the delays of their
 sovereign.(10)
Licentious manners of the people of Antioch  
 If Julian had flattered himself that his personal connection
 with the capital of the East would be productive of mutual
 satisfaction to the prince and people, he made a very false
 estimate of his own character and of the manners of Antioch.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('the ensuing spring', 'DATE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"Julian, on this occasion, showed himself ignorant
 or careless of the laws of civility, which the prudence and
 refinement of polished ages have established between hostile
 princes.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Julian, placing himself
 between them, attempted without success to inculcate the
 lesson and example of toleration, supported, with affected
 calmness, the indiscreet zeal of the aged Christian, who
 seemed to forget the sentiments of nature and the duty of a
 subject, and at length, turning towards the afflicted youth,  The emperor was received in a manner much more agreeable to his wishes at
 Batnae, a small town pleasantly seated in a grove of
 cypresses, about twenty miles from the city of Hierapolis.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Batnae', 'GPE'), ('about twenty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Hierapolis', 'GPE')"
"Julius Caesar,
 Augustus, Trajan, and Marcus Antoninus, were selected as the
 most illustrious candidates; the effeminate Constantine(4) was not excluded from this honourable competition; and the great Alexander was invited to dispute the prize of glory
 with the Roman heroes.","('Julius Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus, Trajan', 'ORG'), ('Marcus Antoninus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('4', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
July 1st,"('July 1st', 'DATE')"
July.,"('July', 'DATE')"
June 26.,"('June 26', 'DATE')"
June 27th—,"('June 27th', 'DATE')"
June.,"('June', 'DATE')"
"Many of these daring
 adventurers were swallowed by the waves; many others, who
 were carried along by the violence of the stream, fell an
 easy prey to the avarice or cruelty of the wild Arabs; and
 the loss which the army sustained in the passage of the
 Tigris was not inferior to the carnage of a day of battle.","('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('a day', 'DATE')"
May.,"('May', 'DATE')"
"Near the ruins of Seleucia the camp
 of Julian was fixed, and secured by a ditch and rampart
 against the sallies of the numerous and enterprising
 garrison of Coche.","('Seleucia', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Coche', 'PERSON')"
"On a sudden they wheeled to the right,
 traversed the level and naked plain of Carrhae, and reached,
 on the third day, the banks of the Euphrates, where the
 strong town of Nicephorium, or Callinicum, had been founded
 by the Macedonian kings.","('Carrhae', 'GPE'), ('the third day', 'DATE'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Nicephorium', 'GPE'), ('Callinicum', 'GPE'), ('Macedonian', 'NORP')"
"On the ensuing day 
 the barbarians, instead of harassing the march, attacked the
 camp of Jovian, which had been seated in a deep and
 sequestered valley.","('the ensuing day', 'DATE'), ('Jovian', 'GPE')"
"On the present occasion the zeal and obedience of
 the Persians seconded the commands of Sapor; and the emperor
 was soon reduced to the scanty stock of provisions which
 continually wasted in his hands.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON')"
"On the right, the brave Nevitta led a
 column of several legions along the banks of the Euphrates, and almost always in sight of the fleet.","('Nevitta', 'PERSON'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"On the second day after the battle the domestic guards, the
 Jovians and Herculians, and the remaining troops, which
 composed near two-thirds of the whole army, were securely
 wafted over the Tigris. (73)","('the second day', 'DATE'), ('Jovians', 'NORP'), ('Herculians', 'NORP'), ('near two-thirds', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"On their side the Romans acknowledged
 the loss of only seventy-five men; while they affirmed that
 the barbarians had left on the field of battle two thousand
 five hundred, or even six thousand, of their bravest
 soldiers.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('only seventy-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('two thousand\r\n five hundred, or even six thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"One party lamented the approaching ruin of their altars, the
 other celebrated the marvellous deliverance of the church.","('One', 'CARDINAL')"
"Passage of the Tigris, and victory of the Romans","('Passage of the Tigris', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
Passage of the Tigris.—,"('Passage of the Tigris', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Perhaps he
 would not have refused to purchase, with one half of his
 kingdom, the safety of the remainder; and he would have
 gladly subscribed himself, in a treaty of peace, the
 faithful and dependent ally of the Roman conqueror.","('one half', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Reflections on the death,  
After Jovian had performed those engagements which the voice
 of his people might have tempted him to violate, he hastened
 away from the scene of his disgrace, and proceeded with his
 whole court to enjoy the luxury of Antioch.(128)","('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('128', 'CARDINAL')"
Residence of Julian at Antioch—,"('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"Sapor enjoyed the glory and the fruits of his
 victory; and this ignominious peace has justly been
 considered as a memorable era in the decline and fall of the
 Roman empire.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Sapor, who had been so
 long accustomed to the tardy ostentation of Constantius, was
 surprised by the intrepid diligence of his successor.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"Siege of Perisabor,  Two cities of Assyria presumed to
 resist the arms of a Roman emperor; and they both paid the
 severe penalty of their rashness","('Perisabor', 'GPE'), ('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Assyria', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Similar orders were despatched by the 
 emperor for the evacuation of Singara and the castle of the
 Moors, and for the restitution of the five provinces beyond
 the Tigris.","('Singara', 'GPE'), ('Moors', 'LOC'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"Singara and the castle of the Moors, one of the
 strongest places of Mesopotamia, were likewise dismembered
 from the empire.","('Singara', 'GPE'), ('Moors', 'LOC'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mesopotamia', 'LOC')"
"Such imprudent declarations were 
 eagerly adopted by the malice or credulity of their
 adversaries, (133) who darkly insinuated or confidently 
 asserted that the governors of the church had instigated and
 directed the fanaticism of a domestic assassin.(134)","('133', 'CARDINAL'), ('134', 'CARDINAL')"
Such was the disposition of the three principal columns.,"('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such was the end of that extraordinary man, in the thirty-second year of his age, after a reign of one year and about eight months from the death of Constantius.","('the thirty-second year', 'DATE'), ('one year', 'DATE'), ('about eight months', 'DATE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The
 Assyrians maintained their loyalty by a skilful as well as
 vigorous defence, till the lucky stroke of a battering-ram
 having opened a large breach by shattering one of the angles
 of the wall, they hastily retired into the fortifications of
 the interior citadel.","('Assyrians', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 Persians derived some honour from the advantage which they
 obtained against the left wing, where Anatolius, master of
 the offices, was slain, and the praefect Sallust very
 narrowly escaped.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Anatolius', 'PERSON'), ('Sallust', 'PERSON')"
"The
 army of Julian, the most numerous that any of the Caesars
 had ever led against Persia, consisted of sixty-five
 thousand effective and well-disciplined soldiers.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('sixty-five\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 desponding troops obeyed the signal of retreat, only seventy
 days June 16after they had passed the Chaboras with the sanguine
 expectation of subverting the throne of Persia.(87)
Retreat and distress of the Roman army","('only seventy\r\n days June 16after', 'DATE'), ('Chaboras', 'NORP'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('87', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The
 exhortations of Hormisdas were repulsed with contempt; and
 the ears of the Persian prince were wounded by a just
 reproach, that, unmindful of his royal birth, he conducted
 an army of strangers against his king and country.","('Hormisdas', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The
 generals were named, a formidable army was destined for this
 important service, and Julian, marching from Constantinople
 through the provinces of Asia Minor, August  arrived at Antioch about eight months after the death of his predecessor.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Asia Minor', 'LOC'), ('August', 'DATE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('about eight months', 'DATE')"
"The
 generals, who were surprised and perplexed by his refusal,
 showed some disposition to adopt the salutary advice of an
 inferior officer,(100) that they should act as they would  have acted in the absence of the emperor; that they should exert their abilities to extricate the army from the present
 distress; and, if they were fortunate enough to reach the
 confines of Mesopotamia, they should proceed with united and
 deliberate counsels in the election of a lawful sovereign.","('100', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mesopotamia', 'GPE')"
"The
 majority of the people supported the glory of the Christian
 name, which had been first invented by their ancestors:(13) 
 they contented themselves with disobeying the moral
 precepts, but they were scrupulously attached to the
 speculative doctrines, of their religion.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('13', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 name and glory of the adjacent Seleucia were for ever
 extinguished; and the only remaining quarter of that Greek
 colony had resumed, with the Assyrian language and manners,
 the primitive appellation of Coche.","('Seleucia', 'LOC'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Assyrian', 'NORP'), ('Coche', 'PERSON')"
"The
 obscure domestic, exalted to the throne by fortune, rather
 than by merit, was impatient to escape from the hands of the
 Persians, that he might prevent the designs of Procopius,
 who commanded the army of Mesopotamia, and establish his
 doubtful reign over the legions and provinces which were
 still ignorant of the hasty and tumultuous choice of the
 camp beyond the Tigris.(113)","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Mesopotamia', 'GPE'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('113', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 preceptors of Julian had extorted a rash but solemn
 assurance that he would never attend the lectures of their
 adversary; the curiosity of the royal youth was checked and
 inflamed; he secretly procured the writings of this
 dangerous sophist, and gradually surpassed, in the perfect
 imitation of his style, the most laborious of his domestic
 pupils.(24) When Julian ascended the throne, he declared his 
 impatience to embrace and reward the Syrian sophist, who had
 preserved in a degenerate age the Grecian purity of taste,
 of manners, and of religion.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Syrian', 'NORP'), ('Grecian', 'NORP')"
"The
 savage insensibility of Jovian appears to have aggravated
 the hardships of these unhappy fugitives.","('Jovian', 'PERSON')"
"The
 united parts contributed to form the common epithet of Al
 Modain, THE CITIES, which the Orientals have bestowed on the
 winter residence of the Sassanides; and the whole
 circumference of the Persian capital was strongly fortified
 by the waters of the river, by lofty walls, and by
 impracticable morasses.","('Al\r\n Modain', 'LOC'), ('Orientals', 'NORP'), ('winter', 'DATE'), ('Sassanides', 'LOC'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The
 veteran bands of cavalry and infantry, of Romans and
 barbarians, had been selected from the different provinces,
 and a just pre-eminence of loyalty and valour was claimed by
 the hardy Gauls, who guarded the throne and person of their
 beloved prince.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Gauls', 'NORP')"
"The
 visionary conquests of Hyrcania and India, which had so long
 amused, now tormented, the mind of Julian.","('Hyrcania', 'GPE'), ('India', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The
 voluminous writings of Libanius still exist; for the most
 part they are the vain and idle compositions of an orator
 who cultivated the science of words—the productions of a
 recluse student, whose mind, regardless of his
 contemporaries, was incessantly fixed on the Trojan war and
 the Athenian commonwealth.","('Libanius', 'NORP'), ('the Trojan war', 'EVENT'), ('Athenian', 'NORP')"
"The
 welcome news of the death of Julian, which a deserter
 revealed to the camp of Sapor, inspired the desponding
 monarch with a sudden confidence of victory.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON')"
"The
 whole engagement lasted above twelve hours; till the gradual
 retreat of the Persians was changed into a disorderly
 flight, of which the shameful example was given by the
 principal leaders and the Surenas himself.","('twelve hours', 'TIME'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Surenas', 'PERSON')"
"The 
 disciple of Socrates was too deeply affected by these
 popular insults; but the monarch, endowed with quick
 sensibility and possessed of absolute power, refused his
 passions the gratification of revenge.","('Socrates', 'PERSON')"
"The Caesars of Julian  
 THE philosophical fable which Julian composed under the name
 of the Caesars (1) is one of the most agreeable and instructive productions of ancient wit.(2) During the freedom 
 and equality of the days of the Saturnalia, Romulus prepared
 a feast for the deities of Olympus, who had adopted him as a
 worthy associate, and for the Roman princes, who had reigned
 over his martial people and the vanquished nations of the
 earth.","('The Caesars of Julian', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Caesars', 'PERSON'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saturnalia', 'NORP'), ('Romulus', 'PERSON'), ('Olympus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Christian
 bishops, Gregory and Augustin, insult the madness of the
 apostate, who executed, with his own hands, the sentence of
 divine justice.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Augustin', 'PERSON')"
"The Christians applauded, in lofty and ambiguous strains,
 the stroke of divine vengeance which had been so long
 suspended over the guilty head of Julian.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The Imperial wheat was
 purchased by the rich merchants; the proprietors of land or
 of corn withheld from the city the accustomed supply; and
 the small quantities that appeared in the market were
 secretly sold at an advanced and illegal price.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The Pagans already placed their
 beloved hero in the rank of those gods whose worship he had
 restored while the invectives of the Christians pursued the
 soul of the apostate to hell, and his body to the grave.(130)","('Pagans', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('130', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Persians repeatedly charged with
 fury; they were repeatedly repulsed with firmness; and the
 action at Maronga, which almost deserved the name of a
 battle, was marked by a considerable loss of satraps and
 elephants, perhaps of equal value in the eyes of their
 monarch.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Maronga', 'GPE')"
"The Persians, who from their walls contemptuously
 beheld the progress of an impotent attack, celebrated with
 songs of triumph the glory of Sapor; and ventured to assure
 the emperor that he might ascend the starry mansion of
 Ormusd before he could hope to take the impregnable city of
 Maogamalcha.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Ormusd', 'PERSON'), ('Maogamalcha', 'GPE')"
The Retreat and Death of Julian.—,"('The Retreat and Death of Julian', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"The Romans wandered several days in
 the country to the eastward of Bagdad; the Persian deserter,
 who had artfully led them into the snare, escaped from their
 resentment; and his followers, as soon as they were put to
 the torture, confessed the secret of the conspiracy.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('several days', 'DATE'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The Romans, after sending up a military shout,
 advanced in measured steps to the animating notes of martial
 music; launched their formidable javelins, and rushed
 forwards with drawn swords to deprive the barbarians, by a
 closer onset, of the advantage of their missile weapons.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The Romans, who now
 aspired only to the permission of a safe and speedy retreat,
 endeavoured to persuade themselves that this formidable
 appearance was occasioned by a troop of wild asses, or
 perhaps by the approach of some friendly Arabs.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"The Saracens
 sometimes intercepted the stragglers on the march; but the
 generals and troops of Sapor respected the cessation of
 arms, and Jovian was suffered to explore the most convenient
 place for the passage of the river.","('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Jovian', 'PERSON')"
"The Sassanian prince, whether he listened to the
 voice of pride or humanity, whether he consulted the
 sentiments of his birth or the duties of his situation, was
 equally inclined to promote a salutary measure which would
 terminate the calamities of Persia, and secure the triumph
 of Rome.","('Sassanian', 'NORP'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The Surenas
 himself, accompanied by another satrap, appeared in the camp
 of Jovian,(109) and declared that the clemency of his 
 sovereign was not averse to signify the conditions on which
 he would consent to spare and to dismiss the Caesar with the
 relics of his captive army.","('Surenas', 'PERSON'), ('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('109', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"The Tigris was still on their left; their hopes and
 provisions were almost consumed; and the impatient soldiers,
 who had fondly persuaded themselves that the frontiers of
 the empire were not far distant, requested their new
 sovereign that they might be permitted to hazard the passage
 of the river.","('Tigris', 'PRODUCT')"
"The alienated mind of Tiranus was exasperated by the indiscretion of Julian, who treated the king of Armenia as his slave, and as the enemy of the gods.","('Tiranus', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"The ambassadors of the East, from the continent
 of India and the isle of Ceylon,(6) had respectfully saluted 
 the Roman purple. (7)","('East', 'LOC'), ('India', 'GPE'), ('Ceylon', 'GPE'), ('6', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('7', 'CARDINAL')"
"The ancient and magnificent temple, which
 had sanctified for so many ages the city of Hierapolis,(31) no longer subsisted, and the consecrated wealth, which afforded a liberal maintenance to more than three hundred
 priests, might hasten its downfall.","('Hierapolis', 'GPE'), ('31', 'CARDINAL'), ('more than three hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The army marched through a hilly country and
 the hills had been secretly occupied by the Persians.","('Persians', 'NORP')"
"The arts of luxury were honoured, the serious and
 manly virtues were the subject of ridicule, and the contempt
 for female modesty and reverent age announced the universal
 corruption of the capital of the East.","('East', 'LOC')"
"The barbarians fled: and Julian, who was
 foremost in every danger, animated the pursuit with his
 voice and gestures.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The battle was at length restored by the
 persevering valour of the Romans; the Persians were repulsed
 with a great slaughter of men and elephants; and the army,
 after marching and fighting a long summer's day, arrived, in
 the evening, at Samara, on the banks of the Tigris, about
 one hundred miles above Ctesiphon. (105)","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), (""a long summer's day"", 'DATE'), ('Samara', 'GPE'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('about\r\n one hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Ctesiphon', 'LOC'), ('105', 'CARDINAL')"
"The bloody and
 obstinate conflict was maintained by the two armies till
 they were separated by the total darkness of the night.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The broad channel of the Euphrates(41) was crowded by a fleet 
 of eleven hundred ships, destined to attend the motions and
 to satisfy the wants of the Roman army.","('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('41', 'CARDINAL'), ('eleven hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The church of
 Antioch was distracted by heresy and schism; but the Arians
 and the Athanasians, the followers of Meletius and those of
 Paulinus,(14) were actuated by the same pious hatred of their 
 common adversary.","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Arians', 'NORP'), ('Athanasians', 'NORP'), ('Meletius', 'PERSON'), ('Paulinus', 'NORP'), ('14', 'CARDINAL')"
"The city of Anah, or
 Anatho,(49) the actual residence of an Arabian emir, is composed of two long streets, which enclose, within a
 natural fortification, a small island in the midst, and two
 fruitful spots on either side, of the Euphrates.","('Anah', 'GPE'), ('Anatho', 'GPE'), ('49', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"The city, or rather fortress, of Maogamalcha, which was
 defended by sixteen large towers, a deep ditch,, and two
 strong and solid walls of brick and bitumen, appears to have
 been constructed at the distance of eleven miles, as the
 safeguard of the capital of Persia.","('Maogamalcha', 'GPE'), ('sixteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('eleven miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"The comedians, who
 resented his contempt and aversion for the theatre,
 exhibited, with the applause of a Christian audience, the
 lively and exaggerated representation of the faults and
 follies of the deceased emperor.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The conduct of the attack was assumed by Julian
 himself, who seemed to place his whole dependence in the
 military engines which he erected against the walls; while
 he secretly contrived a more efficacious method of
 introducing his troops into the heart of the city.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The contest was continued
 by an incessant and mutual discharge of missile weapons; and
 the superiority which the Romans might derive from the
 mechanical powers of their balistae and catapultae was
 counterbalanced by the advantage of the ground on the side
 of the besieged.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The corpse of Julian was transported
 from Nisibis to Tarsus, in a slow march of fifteen days,
 and, as it passed through the cities of the East, was
 saluted by the hostile factions with mournful lamentations
 and clamorous insults.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Nisibis', 'GPE'), ('Tarsus', 'GPE'), ('fifteen days', 'DATE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The country
 which they traversed from the Chaboras to the cultivated
 lands of Assyria may be considered as a part of the desert
 of Arabia, a dry and barren waste, which could never be
 improved by the most powerful arts of human industry.","('Chaboras', 'LOC'), ('Assyria', 'GPE'), ('Arabia', 'LOC')"
"The crafty Persian delayed,
 under various pretences, the conclusion of the agreement;
 started difficulties, required explanations, suggested
 expedients, receded from his concessions, increased his
 demands, and wasted four days in the arts of negotiation,
 till he had consumed the stock of provisions which yet
 remained in the camp of the Romans.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('four days', 'DATE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The cumbersome train of artillery and wagons, which retards
 the operations of a modern army, was in a great measure
 unknown in the camps of the Romans.(83)","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('83', 'CARDINAL')"
"The custom of ancient discipline required a military oration, and Julian embraced every opportunity of displaying his eloquence","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The day was consecrated to pleasure; but, as soon as the
 hour of supper was past, the emperor summoned the generals
 to his tent, and acquainted them that he had fixed that
 night for the passage of the Tigris.","('that\r\n night', 'TIME'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"The days of festivity, consecrated by
 ancient custom to the honour of the gods, were the only
 occasions in which Julian relaxed his philosophic severity,
 and those festivals were the only days in which the Syrians
 of Antioch could reject the allurements of pleasure.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Syrians', 'NORP'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"The death of Julian, A.D. 363.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 363', 'DATE')"
"The distance of the last-mentioned city from the 
 Roman camp was not very considerable; and Julian must soon
 have renounced the vain and impracticable attempt of forcing
 upwards a great fleet against the stream of a rapid river,
 (80) which in several places was embarrassed by natural or 
 artificial cataracts.(81) The power of sails and oars was 
 insufficient, it became necessary to tow the ships against
 the current of the river; the strength of twenty thousand
 soldiers was exhausted in this tedious and servile labour;
 and if the Romans continued to march along the banks of the
 Tigris, they could only expect to return home without
 achieving any enterprise worthy of the genius or fortune of
 their leader.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('80', 'CARDINAL'), ('81', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"The eloquence of Julian was enforced by a donative of one hundred and thirty pieces of silver to every soldier, and the bridge of the Chaboras was instantly cut away to convince the troops that they must place their hopes of safety in the success of their arms.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('one hundred and thirty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Chaboras', 'PRODUCT')"
"The emperor
 detached an army of thirty thousand men, under the command
 of his kinsman Procopius, and of Sebastian, who had been
 duke of Egypt.","('thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Sebastian', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"The emperor stood before
 the citadel of Perisabor, insensible of his extreme danger,
 and encouraged his troops to burst open the gates of iron,
 till he was almost overwhelmed under a cloud of missile
 weapons and huge stones that were directed against his
 person.","('Perisabor', 'PERSON')"
"The emperor,
 apprehensive of leaving such an important fortress in his
 rear, immediately formed the siege of Maogamalcha; and the
 Roman army was distributed for that purpose into three
 divisions.","('Maogamalcha', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"The esteem of a prince
 who possesses the virtues which he approves is the noblest
 recompense of a deserving subject; and the authority which
 Julian derived from his personal merit enabled him to revive
 and enforce the rigour of ancient discipline.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The extensive region
 that lies between the river Tigris and the mountains of
 Media was filled with villages and towns; and the fertile
 soils for the most part, was in a very improved state of
 cultivation.","('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Media', 'LOC')"
"The face of the country was interspersed with
 groves of innumerable palm-trees, (55) and the diligent 
 natives celebrated, either in verse or prose, the three
 hundred and sixty uses to which the trunk, the branches, the
 leaves, the juice, and the fruit were skilfully applied.","('three\r\n hundred and sixty', 'CARDINAL')"
"The father and the son
 were invited to the Imperial table.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The fertile province of Assyria (52) which stretched beyond 
 the Tigris, as far as the mountains of Media,(53) extended 
 about four hundred miles from the ancient wall of Macepracta
 to the territory of Basra, where the united streams of the
 Euphrates and Tigris discharge themselves into the Persian
 Gulf.(54)","('Assyria', 'GPE'), ('52', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Media', 'LOC'), ('53', 'CARDINAL'), ('about four hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Macepracta', 'GPE'), ('Basra', 'GPE'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('the Persian\r\n Gulf', 'LOC'), ('54', 'CARDINAL')"
"The fields of Assyria were devoted by Julian to the
 calamities of war; and the philosopher retaliated on a
 guiltless people the acts of rapine and cruelty which had
 been committed by their haughty master in the Roman
 provinces.","('Assyria', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The first words that Julian uttered, after his recovery from
 the fainting fit into which he had been thrown by loss of
 blood, were expressive of his martial spirit.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The five provinces beyond the
 Tigris, which had been ceded by the grandfather of Sapor,
 were restored to the Persian monarchy.","('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The fleet passed from the Euphrates into an
 artificial deviation of that river, which pours a copious
 and navigable stream into the Tigris at a small distance
 below the great city.","('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"The fortifications
 were razed to the ground; and not a vestige was left that
 the city of Maogamalcha had ever existed.","('Maogamalcha', 'GPE')"
"The friend of Julian was an indignant spectator
 of the triumph of Christianity, and his bigotry, which
 darkened the prospect of the visible world, did not inspire
 Libanius with any lively hopes of celestial glory and
 happiness.(28)
March of Julian to the Euphrates, A.D. 363, March 5","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Libanius', 'PERSON'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('363', 'CARDINAL'), ('March 5', 'DATE')"
"The friends of Julian had confidently announced the success
 of his expedition.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The front and flanks of the army were covered by Lucilianus with a flying detachment of fifteen hundred light-armed soldiers, whose active vigilance observed the most distant signs, and conveyed the earliest notice of any hostile approach.","('Lucilianus', 'GPE'), ('fifteen hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The governor, who had yielded on
 a promise of mercy, was burnt alive, a few days afterwards,
 on a charge of having uttered some disrespectful words
 against the honour of Prince Hormisdas.","('a few days afterwards', 'DATE'), ('Prince Hormisdas', 'PERSON')"
"The hardy veterans, accustomed to the cold climate of Gaul
 and Germany, fainted under the sultry heat of an Assyrian
 summer; their vigour was exhausted by the incessant
 repetition of march and combat; and the progress of the army
 was suspended by the precautions of a slow and dangerous
 retreat in the presence of an active enemy.","('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Assyrian', 'NORP')"
"The haughty and threatening style of the Imperial mandates (40) awakened the secret indignation of a prince who, in the humiliating state of dependence, was still conscious of his royal descent from the Arsacides, the lords of the East, and the rivals of the Roman power.","('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Arsacides', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The heat of the weather had tempted
 him to lay aside his cuirass; but he snatched a shield from
 one of his attendants, and hastened, with a sufficient
 reinforcement, to the relief of the rear guard.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The honour, as well as interest, of Julian, forbade him to
 consume his time under the impregnable walls of Ctesiphon;
 and as often as he defied the barbarians, who defended the
 city, to meet him on the open plain, they prudently replied
 that, if he desired to exercise his valour, he night seek
 the army of the Great King.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Ctesiphon', 'PERSON'), ('the Great King', 'PERSON')"
"The hopes of safety subdued the
 firmness of the Romans; the emperor was compelled, by the
 advice of his council and the cries of the soldiers, to
 embrace the offer of peace; and the praefect Sallust was
 immediately sent, with the general Arinthecus, to understand
 the pleasure of the Great King.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Sallust', 'PERSON'), ('Arinthecus', 'NORP'), ('the Great King', 'PERSON')"
"The immortals were placed in just order on their
 thrones of state, and the table of the Caesars was spread
 below the moon, in the upper region of the air.","('Caesars', 'FAC')"
"The inclemency of the season had affected the harvests of Syria, and the price of bread (15) in the markets of Antioch had  naturally risen in proportion to the scarcity of corn.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"The inflexible spirit of the Roman senate had
 always disclaimed the unequal conditions which were extorted
 from the distress of her captive armies; and, if it were
 necessary to satisfy the national honour by delivering the
 guilty general into the hands of the barbarians, the
 greatest part of the subjects of Jovian would have
 cheerfully acquiesced in the precedent of ancient times.(123)
Jovian evacuates Nisibis, and restores the five provinces to the Persians.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Jovian', 'NORP'), ('Jovian', 'NORP'), ('Nisibis', 'PERSON'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"The inhabitants of the
 open towns, unable to resist and unwilling to yield, fled
 with precipitation, and their houses, filled with spoil and
 provisions, were occupied by the soldiers of Julian, who
 massacred, without remorse and without punishment, some
 defenceless women.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The legions appeared to direct their march towards Nisibis
 and the Tigris.","('Nisibis', 'GPE'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"The loose sand of the desert was frequently raised by the wind into clouds of dust, and a great number of the soldiers of Julian, with their tents, were suddenly thrown to the ground by the violence of an unexpected hurricane.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The love of
 spectacles was the taste, or rather passion, of the Syrians;
 the most skilful artists were procured from the adjacent
 cities;(12) a considerable share of the revenue was devoted 
 to the public amusements, and the magnificence of the games
 of the theatre and circus was considered as the happiness
 and as the glory of Antioch.","('Syrians', 'NORP'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"The love of fame was the ardent passion of his soul: but it was not before he
 trampled on the ruins of Maogamalcha that he allowed himself to say, ""We have now provided some materials for the sophist of Antioch.""  (64)","('Maogamalcha', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('64', 'CARDINAL')"
"The love of rapine and war
 allured to the Imperial standard several tribes of Saracens,
 or roving Arabs, whose service Julian had commanded, while
 he sternly refused the payment of the accustomed subsidies.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The magnanimity of Julian was applauded
 and betrayed by the arts of a noble Persian, who, in the
 cause of his country, had generously submitted to act a part
 full of danger, of falsehood, and of shame.(77)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The martial impatience of Julian urged him to take the field
 in the beginning of the spring, and he dismissed, with
 contempt and reproach, the senate of Antioch, who
 accompanied the emperor beyond the limits of their own
 territory, to which he was resolved never to return.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('the beginning of the spring', 'DATE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"The messengers of
 Jovian had already proclaimed, in the language of flattery,
 his election, his treaty, and his return, and the new prince
 had taken the most effectual measures to secure the
 allegiance of the armies and provinces of Europe by placing
 the military command in the hands of those officers who,
 from motives of interest or inclination, would firmly
 support the cause of their benefactor.(119)
Universal clamour against the treaty of peace","('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('119', 'CARDINAL')"
"The messengers of Jovian 
 promulgated the specious tale of a prudent and necessary
 peace; the voice of fame, louder and more sincere, revealed
 the disgrace of the emperor and the conditions of the
 ignominious treaty.","('Jovian', 'NORP')"
"The military
 strength of the fleet was composed of fifty armed galleys,
 and these were accompanied by an equal number of
 flat-bottomed boats, which might occasionally be connected
 into the form of temporary bridges.","('fifty', 'CARDINAL')"
"The military dispositions of Julian were skilfully contrived
 to deceive the spies and to divert the attention of Sapor.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON')"
"The minds of the people were filled with
 astonishment and grief, with indignation and terror, when
 they were informed that the unworthy successor of Julian
 relinquished the five provinces which had been acquired by
 the victory of Galerius, and that he shamefully surrendered
 to the barbarians the important city of Nisibis, the firmest
 bulwark of the provinces of the East. (122)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Nisibis', 'GPE'), ('East.', 'LOC'), ('122', 'CARDINAL')"
"The modest resolution of Julian was answered by  the unanimous applause and cheerful obedience of the Romans, who declared their confidence of victory while they fought under the banners of their heroic prince.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The most rational grounds of suspicion were
 urged, without effect, by the wisdom and experience of
 Hormisdas; and the credulous Julian, receiving the traitor
 into his bosom, was persuaded to issue an hasty order,
 which, in the opinion of mankind, appeared to arraign his
 prudence and to endanger his safety.","('Hormisdas', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The nations of the West esteemed and 
 dreaded the personal virtues of Julian both in peace and
 war.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The navigation of the Euphrates
 never ascended above Babylon, nor that of the Tigris above
 Opis.(79)","('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Babylon', 'GPE'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('79', 'CARDINAL')"
"The neighbourhood
 of the capital of Persia was adorned with three stately
 palaces, laboriously enriched with every production that
 could gratify the luxury and pride of an Eastern monarch.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"The new prince, astonished with his own fortune, was
 hastily invested with the Imperial ornaments, and received
 an oath of fidelity from the generals, whose favour and
 protection he so lately solicited","('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"The ordinary post of Julian was at the head of the centre column, but, as he
 preferred the duties of a general to the state of a monarch, he rapidly moved, with a small escort of light cavalry, to the front, the rear, the flanks, wherever his presence could
 animate or protect the march of the Roman army.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The park-walls were broken down, the savage game was
 abandoned to the darts of the soldiers, and the palaces of
 Sapor were reduced to ashes, by the command of the Roman
 emperor.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The philosopher
 expressed a very reasonable wish that the disciple of Plato
 might have reposed amidst the groves of the Academy,(139) 
 while the soldier exclaimed, in bolder accents, that the
 ashes of Julian should have been mingled with those of
 Caesar, in the field of Mars, and among the ancient monuments of Roman virtue. (140)","('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('139', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Mars', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('140', 'CARDINAL')"
"The pleasant situation of the gardens along the banks of the
 Tigris was improved, according to the Persian taste, by the
 symmetry of flowers, fountains, and shady walks: and
 spacious parks were enclosed for the reception of the bears,
 lions, and wild boars, which were maintained at a
 considerable expense for the pleasure of the royal chase.","('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The predecessors of Jovian had sometimes
 relinquished the dominion of distant and unprofitable
 provinces; but, since the foundation of the city, the genius
 of Rome, the god Terminus, who guarded the boundaries of the
 republic, had never retired before the sword of a victorious
 enemy.(127)","('Jovian', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Terminus', 'PERSON'), ('127', 'CARDINAL')"
"The pressing voice of necessity was obeyed without
 delay; and the first orders issued by Jovian, a few hours
 after his predecessor had expired, were to prosecute a march
 which could alone extricate the Romans from their actual
 distress.(103)
Danger and difficulty of the retreat","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('a few hours', 'TIME'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('103', 'CARDINAL')"
"The pride of this unexpected
 elevation was moderated by the just apprehension that the
 same day might terminate the life and reign of the new
 emperor.","('the\r\n same day', 'DATE')"
"The principal
 citizens of Nisibis, who till that fatal moment, had
 confided in the protection of their sovereign, threw
 themselves at his feet.","('Nisibis', 'GPE')"
"The progress of the arms 
 of Julian interrupted his communication with the empire,
 and, from the moment that he passed the Tigris, his
 affectionate subjects were ignorant of the fate and fortunes
 of their prince.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"The rearguard was thrown into
 disorder; the renowned legions, which derived their title
 from Diocletian and his warlike colleague, were broke and
 trampled down by the elephants; and three tribunes lost
 their lives in attempting to stop the flight of their
 soldiers.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"The remains of Julian were interred at Tarsus
 in Cilicia; but his stately tomb, which arose in that city
 on the banks of the cold and limpid Cydnus, (138) was 
 displeasing to the faithful friends who loved and revered
 the memory of that extraordinary man.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Tarsus', 'GPE'), ('Cilicia', 'GPE'), ('Cydnus', 'LOC'), ('138', 'CARDINAL')"
"The report of the melancholy event passed from rank to
 rank; but the grief of the Romans inspired them with
 invincible valour, and the desire of revenge.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The rest of the Caesars successively
 advanced to their seats; and as they passed, the vices, the
 defects, the blemishes of their respective characters, were
 maliciously noticed by old Silenus, a laughing moralist, who
 disguised the wisdom of a philosopher under the mask of a
 Bacchanal.","('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Silenus', 'PERSON'), ('Bacchanal', 'NORP')"
"The river Chaboras falls into the Euphrates at Circesium, (42) and, as soon as the trumpet gave the signal of march, April 7th the Romans passed the little stream which separated two mighty and hostile empires.","('Chaboras', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Circesium', 'GPE'), ('42', 'CARDINAL'), ('April 7th', 'DATE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The roads were rendered
 impracticable; a flood of waters was poured into the camp;
 and, during several days, the troops of Julian were obliged
 to contend with the most discouraging hardships.","('several days', 'DATE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The rustic manners of a prince
 who disdained such glory, and was insensible of such
 happiness, soon disgusted the delicacy of his subjects, and
 the effeminate Orientals could neither imitate nor admire
 the severe simplicity which Julian always maintained and
 sometimes affected.","('Orientals', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The same
 grievances were still the subject of the same complaints,
 which were industriously circulated by the wit and levity of
 the Syrian Greeks.","('the Syrian Greeks', 'NORP')"
"The sandy plains of Mesopotamia were abandoned to the
 antelopes and wild asses of the desert, but a variety of
 populous towns and villages were pleasantly situated on the
 banks of the Euphrates and in the islands which are
 occasionally formed by that river.","('Mesopotamia', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"The secret of the expedition had hitherto remained in his
 own breast; but as Carrhae is the point of separation of the
 two great roads, he could no longer conceal whether it was
 his design to attack the dominions of Sapor on the side of
 the Tigris, or on that of the Euphrates.","('Carrhae', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"The signal was instantly
 given, and obeyed: the most impatient of the legionaries
 leaped into five vessels that lay nearest to the bank; and,
 as they plied their oars with intrepid diligence, they were
 lost after a few moments in the darkness of the night.","('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('a few moments', 'TIME'), ('the darkness of the night', 'TIME')"
"The soldiers of Julian rushed
 impetuously into the town, and, after the full gratification
 of every military appetite, Perisabor was reduced to ashes;
 and the engines which assaulted the citadel were planted on
 the ruins of the smoking houses.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Perisabor', 'GPE')"
"The solemn rites of sacrifice were decently prepared by the
 inhabitants of Batnae, who seemed attached to the worship of
 their tutelar deities, Apollo and Jupiter; but the serious
 piety of Julian was offended by the tumult of their
 applause, and he clearly discerned that the smoke which
 arose from their altars was the incense of flattery rather
 than of devotion.","('Batnae', 'GPE'), ('Apollo', 'PERSON'), ('Jupiter', 'LOC'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The son of one of the most
 illustrious citizens of Bercea, who had embraced, either
 from interest or conscience, the religion of the emperor,
 was disinherited by his angry parent.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bercea', 'GPE')"
"The sophist Libanius was born in the
 capital of the East, he publicly professed the arts of
 rhetoric and declamation at Nice, Nicomedia, Constantinople,
 Athens, and, during the remainder of his life, at Antioch.","('Libanius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Nice', 'GPE'), ('Nicomedia', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"The sophist of Antioch, who saw with indignation the sceptre
 of his hero in the feeble hand of a Christian successor,
 professes to admire the moderation of Sapor in contenting
 himself with so small a portion of the Roman empire.","('Antioch', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The sophists of every age, despising or affecting to
 despise the accidental distinctions of birth and fortune,(25) 
 reserve their esteem for the superior qualities of the mind,
 with which they themselves are so plentifully endowed Julian
 might disdain the acclamations of a venal court who adored
 the Imperial purple; but he was deeply flattered by the
 praise, the admonition, the freedom, and the envy of an
 independent philosopher, who refused his favours, loved his
 person, celebrated his fame, and protected his memory.","('25', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
The spectators were silent; and  Julian entered into a metaphysical argument with the philosophers Priscus and Maximus on the nature of the soul.,"('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Priscus', 'PERSON'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"The spoil was such as might be expected from the
 riches and luxury of an Oriental camp; large quantities of
 silver and gold, splendid arms and trappings, and beds and
 tables of massive silver.","('Oriental', 'NORP')"
"The stream
 was broad and rapid, the ascent steep and difficult; and the
 entrenchments which had been formed on the ridge of the
 opposite bank were lined with a numerous army of heavy
 cuirassiers, dexterous archers, and huge elephants; who
 (according to the extravagant hyperbole of Libanius) could
 trample with the same ease a field of corn or a legion of
 Romans.(67)","('Libanius', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('67', 'CARDINAL')"
"The strength of the infantry, and consequently of the whole army, was placed in the centre, under the peculiar command of their master-general Victor.","('Victor', 'PERSON')"
"The strongest
 recommendation of Jovian was the merit of his father, Count
 Varronian, who enjoyed, in honourable retirement, the fruit
 of his long services.","('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('Varronian', 'PERSON')"
"The strongest prejudice was entertained against the
 character of an apostate, the enemy and successor of a
 prince who had engaged the affections of a very numerous
 sect, and the removal of St. Babylas excited an implacable
 opposition to the person of Julian.","('St. Babylas', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The success of this trial disposed the emperor to listen to
 the promises of his architects, who proposed to construct a
 floating bridge of the inflated skins of sheep, oxen, and
 goats, covered with a floor of earth and fascines.(107)","('107', 'CARDINAL')"
"The success of this well-concerted plan depended, in a great measure, on the powerful and ready assistance of the king of Armenia, who, without exposing the safety of his own dominions, might detach an army of four thousand horse and twenty thousand foot to the assistance of the Romans. (37)","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty thousand foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('37', 'CARDINAL')"
"The successful valour of Julian had triumphed over all the
 obstacles that opposed his march to the gates of Ctesiphon.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Ctesiphon', 'GPE')"
"The successor of Cyrus and Artaxerxes
 was the only rival whom he deemed worthy of his arms, and he
 resolved, by the final conquest of Persia, to chastise the
 haughty nation which had so long resisted and insulted the
 majesty of Rome. (9)","('Cyrus', 'PERSON'), ('Artaxerxes', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The superior virtues of Sallust
 could alone reconcile their divisions and unite their
 suffrages; and the venerable praefect would immediately have
 been declared the successor of Julian, if he himself, with
 sincere and modest firmness, had not alleged his age and
 infirmities, so unequal to the weight of the diadem.","('Sallust', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The temple of the Moon attracted the devotion of
 Julian, but the halt of a few days was principally employed
 in completing the immense preparations of the Persian war.","('The temple of the Moon', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('a few days', 'DATE'), ('the Persian war', 'EVENT')"
"The transient
 presumption of Sapor had vanished: he observed, with serious
 concern, that, in the repetition of doubtful combats, he had
 lost his most faithful and intrepid nobles, his bravest
 troops, and the greatest part of his tram of elephants: and
 the experienced monarch feared to provoke the resistance of
 despair, the vicissitudes of fortune, and the unexhausted
 powers of the Roman empire, which might soon advance to
 relieve, or to revenge, the successor of Julian.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The trembling Assyrians summoned the rivers to
 their assistance; and completed with their own hands the
 ruin of their country.","('Assyrians', 'NORP')"
"The triumph of Christianity, and the calamities of the
 empire, may, in some measure, be ascribed to Julian himself,
 who had neglected to secure the future execution of his
 designs by the timely and judicious nomination of an
 associate and successor.","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The tumultuary acclamation was instantly repeated by the guards who surrounded the tent,
 and passed, in a few minutes, to the extremities of the
 line.","('a few minutes', 'TIME')"
"The two sieges allowed him some
 remarkable opportunities of signalising his personal valour,
 which, in the improved state of the military art, can seldom
