Sentence,Entities
"""Rather than abstain from adoring Christ and his Mother in their holy images, it would be better for you,"" replied the casuist, ""to enter every brothel, and visit every prostitute, in the
 city."" (80)","('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('80', 'CARDINAL')"
"""Romans,"" exclaimed the youth, ""once you were the masters of the world, and these Burgundians the most abject of your slaves.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP')"
(53),"('53', 'CARDINAL')"
(6),"('6', 'CARDINAL')"
(75),"('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 hundred princes bowed before his throne, and exalted their
 own dignity by the voluntary honours which they yielded to
 their chief or minister.","('A\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 new super structure of fable was raised on the popular basis
 of a Syrian legend, on the correspondence of Christ and
 Abgarus, so famous in the days of Eusebius, so reluctantly
 deserted by our modern advocates.","('Syrian', 'NORP'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Abgarus', 'PERSON'), ('Eusebius', 'PERSON')"
"A
 single question yet remained, whether they are endowed with
 any proper and inherent sanctity; it was agitated by the
 Greeks of the eleventh century; (81) and as this opinion has
 the strongest recommendation of absurdity, I am surprised
 that it was not more explicitly decided in the affirmative.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('the eleventh century', 'DATE'), ('81', 'DATE')"
"A
 torrent of Barbarians may pass over the earth, but an
 extensive empire must be supported by a refined system of
 policy and oppression; in the centre, an absolute power,
 prompt in action and rich in resources; a swift and easy
 communication with the extreme parts; fortifications to
 check the first effort of rebellion; a regular
 administration to protect and punish; and a well-disciplined
 army to inspire fear, without provoking discontent and
 despair.","('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"A
 treaty of peace and alliance was concluded between the two
 empires, and the limits of the East and West were defined by
 the right of present possession.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"A distant and dangerous
 station, amidst the Barbarians of the West, excited the
 spirit and freedom of the Latin bishops.","('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"A faint remembrance of
 their ancestors still tormented the Romans; and they beheld
 with pious indignation the succession of Saxons, Franks,
 Swabians, and Bohemians, who usurped the purple and
 prerogatives of the Caesars.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Swabians', 'NORP'), ('Bohemians', 'NORP'), ('Caesars', 'ORG')"
"A form of administration was preserved
 by the election of magistrates and governors; and so high
 was the public indignation, that the Italians were prepared
 to create an orthodox emperor, and to conduct him with a
 fleet and army to the palace of Constantinople.","('Italians', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"A memorable example of repentance
 and piety was exhibited by Liutprand, king of the Lombards.","('Liutprand', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"A monk had concluded a truce
 with the daemon of fornication, on condition of interrupting
 his daily prayers to a picture that hung in his cell.","('daily', 'DATE')"
"A more specious argument is drawn from present possession and recent practice the harmony of the Christian world supersedes the demand of a general council; and Gregory frankly confesses, than such assemblies can only be useful under the reign of an orthodox
 prince.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON')"
"A portion of Gaul, to the
 west of the Rhine, along the banks of the Meuse and the
 Moselle, was assigned to the Germans, by whose blood and
 language it has been tinged since the time of Caesar and
 Tacitus.","('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Meuse', 'FAC'), ('Moselle', 'LOC'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
A similar indulgence was requisite and propitious for the Virgin Mary: the place of her burial was unknown; and the assumption of her soul and body into heaven was adopted by the credulity of the Greeks and Latins.,"('the Virgin Mary', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Latins', 'NORP')"
A.D. 1347-1378 .,"('A.D. 1347-1378', 'DATE')"
A.D. 1355,"('A.D. 1355', 'DATE')"
A.D. 813.,"('813', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 814-887 in Italy; 911 in Germany; 987 in France .,"('A.D. 814-887', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('911', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('987', 'CARDINAL'), ('France', 'GPE')"
A.D. 967.,"('A.D. 967', 'DATE')"
A.D. 998.,"('A.D. 998', 'DATE')"
"According to the legend, the first of the Christian
 emperors was healed of the leprosy, and purified in the
 waters of baptism, by St. Silvester, the Roman bishop; and
 never was physician more gloriously recompensed.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('St. Silvester', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"According to the measure of their force, the governors, the bishops, and the lords, usurped the fragments of the falling empire; and some preference was shown to the female or illegitimate
 blood of Charlemagne.","('Charlemagne', 'PERSON')"
"After
 his just condemnation by the bishops of Sicily, the tyrant
 was cut off, in the fullness of his sins, by a domestic
 servant: the saint is still adored by the nations of
 Scythia, among whom he ended his banishment and his life.","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'PERSON')"
"After
 suffering from the winds and waves much loss and delay, the
 Greeks made their descent in the neighbourhood of Ravenna:
 they threatened to depopulate the guilty capital, and to
 imitate, perhaps to surpass, the example of Justinian the
 Second, who had chastised a former rebellion by the choice
 and execution of fifty of the principal inhabitants.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('fifty', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a
 servitude of three hundred years, the Palladium was yielded
 to the devotion of Constantinople, for a ransom of twelve
 thousand pounds of silver, the redemption of two hundred
 Mussulmans, and a perpetual truce for the territory of
 Edessa. (16)","('three hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Palladium', 'FAC'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('twelve\r\n thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('two hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mussulmans', 'NORP'), ('Edessa', 'GPE'), ('16', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a bloody conflict of
 eight years, the loss of some French generals was avenged by
 the slaughter of the most noble Huns: the relics of the
 nation submitted the royal residence of the chagan was left
 desolate and unknown; and the treasures, the rapine of two
 hundred and fifty years, enriched the victorious troops, or
 decorated the churches of Italy and Gaul. (111)","('eight years', 'DATE'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('two\r\n hundred and fifty years', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('111', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a contest of fifty years,
 the first of these designs was accomplished by the firm
 support of the ecclesiastical order, whose liberty was
 connected with that of their chief.","('fifty years', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"After a long and evasive contest, the
 rebellion of the dukes of Aquitain was punished by the
 forfeiture of their province, their liberty, and their
 lives.","('Aquitain', 'PERSON')"
"After a long series of
 scandal, the apostolic see was reformed and exalted by the
 austerity and zeal of Gregory VII.","('Gregory VII', 'PERSON')"
"After a serious deliberation of six months,
 the three hundred and thirty-eight bishops pronounced and
 subscribed a unanimous decree, that all visible symbols of
 Christ, except in the Eucharist, were either blasphemous or
 heretical; that image-worship was a corruption of
 Christianity and a renewal of Paganism; that all such
 monuments of idolatry should be broken or erased; and that
 those who should refuse to deliver the objects of their
 private superstition, were guilty of disobedience to the
 authority of the church and of the emperor.","('six months', 'DATE'), ('three hundred and thirty-eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Paganism', 'NORP')"
"After a tedious journey of circuit and
 delay, the ambassadors of Nicephorus found him in his camp,
 on the banks of the River Sala; and Charlemagne affected to
 confound their vanity by displaying, in a Franconian
 village, the pomp, or at least the pride, of the Byzantine
 palace. (122)","('Nicephorus', 'PERSON'), ('the River Sala', 'LOC'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Franconian', 'NORP'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('122', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a war, or battle, which
 consumed one hundred thousand Franks, the empire was divided
 by treaty between his three sons, who had violated every
 filial and fraternal duty.","('one hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"After soothing the public despair by litanies and
 orations, he undertook this laborious journey with the
 ambassadors of the French monarch and the Greek emperor.","('French', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"After the
 death of Theophilus, the final victory of the images was
 achieved by a second female, his widow Theodora, whom he
 left the guardian of the empire.","('Theophilus', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"After the
 recovery of Italy and Africa by the arms of Justinian, the
 importance and danger of those remote provinces required the
 presence of a supreme magistrate; he was indifferently
 styled the exarch or the patrician; and these governors of
 Ravenna, who fill their place in the chronology of princes,
 extended their jurisdiction over the Roman city.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"After the
 reduction of Pannonia, the empire of Charlemagne was bounded
 only by the conflux of the Danube with the Teyss and the
 Save: the provinces of Istria, Liburnia, and Dalmatia, were
 an easy, though unprofitable, accession; and it was an
 effect of his moderation, that he left the maritime cities
 under the real or nominal sovereignty of the Greeks.","('Pannonia', 'GPE'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Teyss', 'NORP'), ('Istria', 'GPE'), ('Liburnia', 'GPE'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"After the Spanish expedition, his rear-guard
 was defeated in the Pyrenaean mountains; and the soldiers,
 whose situation was irretrievable, and whose valour was
 useless, might accuse, with their last breath, the want of
 skill or caution of their general. (99)","('Spanish', 'NORP'), ('Pyrenaean', 'NORP')"
"After the celebration of the holy mysteries,
 Leo suddenly placed a precious crown on his head, (93) and
 the dome resounded with the acclamations of the people, 
 ""Long life and victory to Charles, the most pious Augustus,
 crowned by God the great and pacific emperor of the Romans!""","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('93', 'DATE'), ('Charles', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"After the celebration of the holy mysteries,
 Leo suddenly placed a precious crown on his head, (93) and
 the dome resounded with the acclamations of the people,   The head and body of Charlemagne were consecrated by the
 royal unction: after the example of the Caesars, he was
 saluted or adored by the pontiff: his coronation oath
 represents a promise to maintain the faith and privileges of
 the church; and the first-fruits were paid in his rich
 offerings to the shrine of his apostle.","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('93', 'CARDINAL'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Caesars', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"After the death of Frederic the Second,
 Germany was left a monster with a hundred heads.","('Frederic', 'PERSON'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the excommunication of Lewis of Bavaria, he received the gift or promise of the
 vacant empire from the Roman pontiffs, who, in the exile and
 captivity of Avignon, affected the dominion of the earth.","('Lewis', 'PERSON'), ('Bavaria', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Avignon', 'GPE')"
"After this decent salutation, the pope attempts the usual distinction between the idols of antiquity and the Christian images.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"After this double chastisement, the
 Lombards languished about twenty years in a state of languor
 and decay.","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('about twenty years', 'DATE')"
"After this important service, the image of Edessa was
 preserved with respect and gratitude; and if the Armenians
 rejected the legend, the more credulous Greeks adored the
 similitude, which was not the work of any mortal pencil, but
 the immediate creation of the divine original.","('Edessa', 'PERSON'), ('Armenians', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"Alexander conquered with the arms of Philip, but the two
 heroes who preceded Charlemagne bequeathed him their name,
 their examples, and the companions of their victories.","('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Philip', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON')"
"All the powers of royalty were exercised by Pepin, mayor of the palace; and nothing, except the regal title, was wanting to his ambition.","('Pepin', 'PERSON')"
"Ambitious of restoring the splendour of the purple, Frederic
 the First invaded the republics of Lombardy, with the arts
 of a statesman, the valour of a soldier, and the cruelty of a
 tyrant.","('Frederic', 'PERSON'), ('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Lombardy', 'GPE')"
"Amidst the tears of the city, Stephen the Third
 embraced the generous resolution of visiting in person the
 courts of Lombardy and France, to deprecate the injustice of
 his enemy, or to excite the pity and indignation of his
 friend.","('Stephen', 'PERSON'), ('Third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Lombardy', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE')"
"Amidst the triumph of the Catholic arms, the Roman
 pontiff convened a synod of ninety-three bishops against the
 heresy of the Iconoclasts.","('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('ninety-three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Iconoclasts', 'ORG')"
"Amidst their civil
 divisions, an Arabian emir of Saragossa implored his
 protection in the diet of Paderborn.","('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('Saragossa', 'PERSON'), ('Paderborn', 'PERSON')"
"Among them the worship of images advanced with a silent and insensible
 progress; but a large atonement is made for their hesitation
 and delay, by the gross idolatry of the ages which precede
 the reformation, and of the countries, both in Europe and
 America, which are still immersed in the gloom of
 superstition.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('America', 'GPE')"
"An
 angry book of controversy was composed and published in the
 name of Charlemagne: (82) under his authority a synod of
 three hundred bishops was assembled at Frankfort: (83) they
 blamed the fury of the Iconoclasts, but they pronounced a
 more severe censure against the superstition of the Greeks,
 and the decrees of their pretended council, which was long
 despised by the Barbarians of the West. (84)","('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('82', 'CARDINAL'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Frankfort', 'ORG'), ('83', 'CARDINAL'), ('Iconoclasts', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('84', 'CARDINAL')"
"An
 answer so agreeable to their wishes was accepted by the
 Franks as the opinion of a casuist, the sentence of a judge,
 or the oracle of a prophet: the Merovingian race disappeared
 from the earth; and Pepin was exalted on a buckler by the
 suffrage of a free people, accustomed to obey his laws and
 to march under his standard.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('Pepin', 'PERSON')"
"Are you ignorant that the popes are the bond of union, the mediators of peace, between the East and West?","('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"As John
 XII.","('John\r\n XII', 'PERSON')"
"As king of the Lombards, and patrician of Rome, he reigned over the greatest part of ITALY, (109) a
 tract of a thousand miles from the Alps to the borders of
 Calabria.","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('ITALY', 'GPE'), ('109', 'CARDINAL'), ('a thousand miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Calabria', 'GPE')"
"As often as the Franks or
 Lombards expressed their most bitter contempt of a foe, they
 called him a Roman;","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"As often as the Franks or
 Lombards expressed their most bitter contempt of a foe, they
 called him a Roman; 
""and in this name,"" says the bishop Liutprand, ""we include whatever is base, whatever is cowardly, whatever is perfidious, the extremes of avarice and luxury, and every vice that can prostitute the dignity
 of human nature."" (44)","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Liutprand', 'PERSON'), ('44', 'CARDINAL')"
"As soon as these qualities were
 separated in the person of his pious son, the Byzantine
 letters were inscribed, 
 ""To the king, or, as he styles himself, the emperor of the Franks and Lombards.""","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as these qualities were
 separated in the person of his pious son, the Byzantine
 letters were inscribed,   When both power and virtue were extinct, they despoiled Lewis the
 Second of his hereditary title, and with the barbarous
 appellation of rex or rega, degraded him among the crowd of
 Latin princes.","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Lewis', 'PERSON'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"As the worship of
 images had never been established by any general or positive
 law, its progress in the Eastern empire had been retarded,
 or accelerated, by the differences of men and manners, the
 local degrees of refinement, and the personal characters of
 the bishops.","('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"Astolphus with a sigh relinquished his prey; the
 keys and the hostages of the principal cities were delivered
 to the French ambassador; and, in his master's name, he
 presented them before the tomb of St. Peter.","('Astolphus', 'PERSON'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE')"
"At
 Constantinople, as in the former councils, the will of the
 prince was the rule of episcopal faith; but on this
 occasion, I am inclined to suspect that a large majority of
 the prelates sacrificed their secret conscience to the
 temptations of hope and fear.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"At Ravenna, (39) the several quarters of the city had long exercised a bloody and hereditary feud; in
 religious controversy they found a new aliment of faction:
 but the votaries of images were superior in numbers or
 spirit, and the exarch, who attempted to stem the torrent,
 lost his life in a popular sedition.","('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('39', 'CARDINAL')"
"At first, the experiment was made with caution and scruple; and the venerable pictures were discreetly allowed to instruct the ignorant, to awaken the cold, and to gratify the prejudices of the heathen proselytes.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"At the
 foot of these popular ramparts, the pride of the Caesars was
 overthrown; and the invincible genius of liberty prevailed
 over the two Frederics, the greatest princes of the middle
 age; the first, superior perhaps in military prowess; the
 second, who undoubtedly excelled in the softer
 accomplishments of peace and learning.","('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Frederics', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"At the aspect
 of the holy crosses, and ensigns of the saints, he
 dismounted from his horse, led the procession of his nobles
 to the Vatican, and, as he ascended the stairs, devoutly
 kissed each step of the threshold of the apostles.","('Vatican', 'FAC')"
"At the distance of one
 mile, the Flaminian way was lined with the schools, or
 national communities, of Greeks, Lombards, Saxons, etc.: the
 Roman youth were under arms; and the children of a more
 tender age, with palms and olive branches in their hands,
 chanted the praises of their great deliverer.","('one\r\n mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('Flaminian', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"At the head of a victorious army, he passed the
 Alps, subdued the kingdom of Italy, delivered the pope, and
 forever fixed the Imperial crown in the name and nation of
 Germany.","('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"At the head of his victorious legions, in his reign over the
 sea and land, from the Nile and Euphrates to the Atlantic
 Ocean, Augustus professed himself the servant of the state
 and the equal of his fellow-citizens.","('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('the Atlantic\r\n Ocean', 'LOC'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"At the head of this class, we may justly rank the worship of images, so fiercely disputed in the eighth and ninth centuries; since a question of popular superstition produced the revolt of Italy, the temporal power of the popes, and the restoration of the Roman empire in the West.","('the eighth and ninth centuries', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"At the royal banquet, the
 hereditary great officers, the seven electors, who in rank
 and title were equal to kings, performed their solemn and
 domestic service of the palace.","('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"At this signal, Ravenna,
 Venice, and the cities of the Exarchate and Pentapolis,
 adhered to the cause of religion; their military force by
 sea and land consisted, for the most part, of the natives;
 and the spirit of patriotism and zeal was transfused into
 the mercenary strangers.","('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('Exarchate', 'GPE'), ('Pentapolis', 'GPE')"
Authority of the emperors in Rome .,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Authority of the emperors in the elections of the popes, A.D. 800-1060 .","('800-1060', 'CARDINAL')"
"Before
 he repassed the Alps, the emperor chastised the revolt of
 the people and the ingratitude of John XII.","('Alps', 'LOC'), ('John XII', 'PERSON')"
"Before
 the end of the eighth century, some apostolic scribe,
 perhaps the notorious Isidore, composed the decretals, and
 spiritual and temporal monarchy of the popes.","('the end of the eighth century', 'DATE'), ('Isidore', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Before the end of the sixth century, these images, made without hands, (in Greek it is a single word, (11)) were propagated in the camps and cities of the Eastern empire: (12) they were the objects of worship, and the instruments of miracles; and in the hour of danger or tumult, their venerable presence could revive the hope, rekindle the courage, or repress the fury, of the Roman legions.","('the end of the sixth century', 'DATE'), ('Greek', 'LANGUAGE'), ('11', 'CARDINAL'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Before the ruin of Paganism in Rome, the competition for a
 wealthy bishopric had often been productive of tumult and
 bloodshed.","('Paganism', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Between the Rhine, the Rhone, and the Alps, the
 successors of Otho acquired a vain supremacy over the broken
 kingdoms of Burgundy and Arles.","('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Rhone', 'LOC'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Otho', 'PERSON'), ('Burgundy', 'GPE'), ('Arles', 'GPE')"
"Beyond the
 Elbe, the Slavi, or Sclavonians, of similar manners and
 various denominations, overspread the modern dominions of
 Prussia, Poland, and Bohemia, and some transient marks of
 obedience have tempted the French historian to extend the
 empire to the Baltic and the Vistula.","('Elbe', 'LOC'), ('Slavi', 'NORP'), ('Sclavonians', 'NORP'), ('Prussia', 'GPE'), ('Poland', 'GPE'), ('Bohemia', 'GPE'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Baltic', 'LOC'), ('Vistula', 'NORP')"
"But
 the north of Germany, from the Rhine and beyond the Elbe,
 was still hostile and Pagan; nor was it till after a war of
 thirty-three years that the Saxons bowed under the yoke of
 Christ and of Charlemagne.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Elbe', 'LOC'), ('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('thirty-three years', 'DATE'), ('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON')"
"But
 these distant possessions added more to the reputation than
 to the power of the Latin emperor; nor did he risk any
 ecclesiastical foundations to reclaim the Barbarians from
 their vagrant life and idolatrous worship.","('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"But Arrechis, the reigning duke, refused
 to be included in the slavery of his country; assumed the
 independent title of prince; and opposed his sword to the
 Carlovingian monarchy.","('Arrechis', 'PERSON'), ('Carlovingian', 'NORP')"
"But I have reviewed, with diligence and pleasure, the objects of ecclesiastical history, by which the decline and fall of the Roman empire were materially affected, the propagation of Christianity, the constitution of the Catholic church, the ruin of Paganism, and the sects that arose from the mysterious controversies concerning the Trinity and incarnation.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Paganism', 'NORP'), ('Trinity', 'ORG')"
"But Milan soon rose from her ashes; and the league of
 Lombardy was cemented by distress: their cause was espoused
 by Venice, Pope Alexander the Third, and the Greek emperor:
 the fabric of oppression was overturned in a day; and in the
 treaty of Constance, Frederic subscribed, with some
 reservations, the freedom of four-and-twenty cities.","('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Lombardy', 'GPE'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('Third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('a day', 'DATE'), ('Constance', 'PERSON'), ('Frederic', 'PERSON'), ('four-', 'CARDINAL'), ('-twenty', 'CARDINAL')"
"But a recent discovery (107) has
 proved that these unhappy princes were the last and lawful
 heirs of the blood and sceptre of Clovis, and younger
 branch, from the brother of Dagobert, of the Merovingian
 house.","('107', 'CARDINAL'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Dagobert', 'PERSON'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP')"
"But as soon as she reigned in her own
 name and that of her son, Irene more seriously undertook the
 ruin of the Iconoclasts; and the first step of her future
 persecution was a general edict for liberty of conscience.","('Irene', 'PERSON'), ('Iconoclasts', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But his successors only once in their lives
 appeared on the banks of the Tyber, to receive their crown
 in the Vatican. (140)","('Tyber', 'NORP'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('140', 'CARDINAL')"
"But in
 the quarrel of the investitures, they were deprived of their
 influence over the episcopal chapters; the freedom of
 election was restored, and the sovereign was reduced, by a
 solemn mockery, to his first prayers, the recommendation,
 once in his reign, to a single prebend in each church.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But in the beginning of the eighth century, in the
 full magnitude of the abuse, the more timorous Greeks were
 awakened by an apprehension, that under the mask of
 Christianity, they had restored the religion of their
 fathers: they heard, with grief and impatience, the name of
 idolaters; the incessant charge of the Jews and Mahometans,
 (15) who derived from the Law and the Koran an immortal
 hatred to graven images and all relative worship.","('the beginning of the eighth century', 'DATE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Mahometans', 'NORP'), ('15', 'DATE'), ('Law', 'PERSON'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"But in the eleventh and twelfth
 centuries, the Lombards rekindled the flame of industry and
 freedom; and the generous example was at length imitated by
 the republics of Tuscany.","('the eleventh and twelfth\r\n centuries', 'DATE'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Tuscany', 'GPE')"
"But in the outset of an
 unsettled reign, during ten years of toil and danger, Leo
 submitted to the meanness of hypocrisy, bowed before the
 idols which he despised, and satisfied the Roman pontiff
 with the annual professions of his orthodoxy and zeal.","('ten years', 'DATE'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But no sooner was
 Astolphus delivered from the presence of the French arms,
 than he forgot his promise and resented his disgrace.","('Astolphus', 'PERSON'), ('French', 'NORP')"
"But on the
 reception of his proscriptive edict, they trembled for their
 domestic deities: the images of Christ and the Virgin, of
 the angels, martyrs, and saints, were abolished in all the
 churches of Italy; and a strong alternative was proposed to
 the Roman pontiff, the royal favour as the price of his
 compliance, degradation and exile as the penalty of his
 disobedience.","('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Virgin', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But that he might not legally assume the
 titles of emperor and Augustus, till he had received the
 crown from the hands of the Roman pontiff. (119)
Transactions of the Western and Eastern empires .","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('119', 'CARDINAL'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"But the
 Italian cities and the French vassals were divided and
 destroyed, while the union of the Germans has produced,
 under the name of an empire, a great system of a federative
 republic.","('Italian', 'NORP'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"But the Greek prelate
 was a domestic slave under the eye of his master, at whose
 nod he alternately passed from the convent to the throne,
 and from the throne to the convent.","('Greek', 'NORP')"
"But the Greeks (123) soon
 forgot this humiliating equality, or remembered it only to
 hate the Barbarians by whom it was extorted.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"But the Romans were free to choose a master
 for themselves; and the powers which had been delegated to
 the patrician, were irrevocably granted to the French and
 Saxon emperors of the West.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Saxon', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"But the Saxon was imperious, the Romans were impatient, the
 festival of the coronation was disturbed by the secret conflict of prerogative and freedom, and Otho commanded his
 sword-bearer not to stir from his person, lest he should be
 assaulted and murdered at the foot of the altar. (138)of pope John XII.","('Saxon', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Otho', 'PERSON'), ('138', 'CARDINAL'), ('John XII', 'PERSON')"
"But the association of his
 son Lewis the Pious asserts the independent right of
 monarchy and conquest, and the emperor seems on this
 occasion to have foreseen and prevented the latent claims of
 the clergy.","('Lewis', 'PERSON'), ('Pious', 'PERSON')"
"But the danger
 was on the banks of the Tyber, the succour on those of the
 Seine, and our sympathy is cold to the relation of distant
 misery.","('Tyber', 'FAC'), ('Seine', 'LOC')"
"But the decrees of a general
 council could only be repealed by a similar assembly: (78)
 the Iconoclasts whom she convened were bold in possession,
 and averse to debate; and the feeble voice of the bishops
 was reechoed by the more formidable clamour of the soldiers
 and people of Constantinople.","('78', 'CARDINAL'), ('Iconoclasts', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"But the most essential gifts of the popes to the Carlovingian race were the dignities of king of France, (55) and of patrician of Rome.","('Carlovingian', 'NORP'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('55', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But the preparations of the
 ceremony must have disclosed the secret; and the journey of
 Charlemagne reveals his knowledge and expectation: he had
 acknowledged that the Imperial title was the object of his
 ambition, and a Roman synod had pronounced, that it was the
 only adequate reward of his merit and services. (94)
Reign and character of Charlemagne, A.D. 768-814 .","('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('814', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the second attempt,
 though it was crowned with some partial and apparent
 success, has been vigorously resisted by the secular power,
 and finally extinguished by the improvement of human reason.","('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"But the superstitious mind was more easily reconciled to paint and to worship the angels, and, above all, the Son of God, under the human shape, which, on earth, they have condescended to assume.","('the Son of God', 'PERSON')"
"But their
 rapid progress, the daily extension of their power and
 pretensions, were founded on the numbers and spirit of these
 rising communities. (143)","('143', 'CARDINAL')"
"But their minds were not yet humbled to their
 condition; and instead of affecting the pacific virtues of
 the feeble, they peevishly harassed the Romans with a
 repetition of claims, evasions, and inroads, which they
 undertook without reflection, and terminated without glory.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"But these clandestine
 or open attacks were repelled by the courage and vigilance
 of the Romans; the Greeks were overthrown and massacred,
 their leaders suffered an ignominious death, and the popes,
 however inclined to mercy, refused to intercede for these
 guilty victims.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"But they were now opposed by the murmurs of many
 simple or rational Christians, who appealed to the evidence
 of texts, of facts, and of the primitive times, and secretly
 desired the reformation of the church.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"But this
 religious fervour was the illusion, perhaps the artifice, of
 the moment; the sense of interest is strong and lasting; the
 love of arms and rapine was congenial to the Lombards; and
 both the prince and people were irresistibly tempted by the
 disorders of Italy, the nakedness of Rome, and the unwarlike
 profession of her new chief.","('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But this activity was a
 national, rather than a personal, virtue; the vagrant life
 of a Frank was spent in the chase, in pilgrimage, in
 military adventures; and the journeys of Charlemagne were
 distinguished only by a more numerous train and a more
 important purpose.","('Frank', 'PERSON'), ('Charlemagne', 'LOC')"
"But this mystic circle could have been traced
 only by the wand of a legislator and a sage: this pacific
 system was incompatible with the zeal and ambition of the
 popes the Romans were not addicted, like the inhabitants of
 Elis, to the innocent and placid labours of agriculture; and
 the Barbarians of Italy, though softened by the climate,
 were far below the Grecian states in the institutions of
 public and private life.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Elis', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Grecian', 'NORP')"
"But we
 read, with some surprise, that the worthy grandson of
 Marozia lived in public adultery with the matrons of Rome;
 that the Lateran palace was turned into a school for
 prostitution, and that his rapes of virgins and widows had
 deterred the female pilgrims from visiting the tomb of St.
 Peter, lest, in the devout act, they should be violated by
 his successor. (133)","('Marozia', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Lateran', 'NORP'), ('St.\r\n Peter', 'GPE'), ('133', 'CARDINAL')"
"By
 a second edict, he proscribed the existence as well as the
 use of religious pictures; the churches of Constantinople
 and the provinces were cleansed from idolatry; the images of
 Christ, the Virgin, and the saints, were demolished, or a
 smooth surface of plaster was spread over the walls of the
 edifice.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Virgin', 'PERSON')"
"By a reverse of fortune,
 Otho, after separating his troops, was besieged three days,
 without food, in his palace; and a disgraceful escape saved
 him from the justice or fury of the Romans.","('Otho', 'PERSON'), ('three days', 'DATE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"By a slow though inevitable progression, the honours of the original were transferred to the copy: the devout Christian prayed before the image of a saint; and the Pagan rites of genuflection, luminaries, and incense, again stole into the Catholic church.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"By the
 opportunities of death or removal, the episcopal seats were
 judiciously filled the most eager competitors for earthly or
 celestial favour anticipated and flattered the judgment of
 their sovereign; and the promotion of her secretary Tarasius
 gave Irene the patriarch of Constantinople, and the command
 of the Oriental church.","('Tarasius', 'PERSON'), ('Irene', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Oriental', 'NORP')"
"By the
 reunion of Aquitain, France was enlarged to its present
 boundaries, with the additions of the Netherlands and Spain,
 as far as the Rhine.","('Aquitain', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Netherlands', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"By the Caesars, the triumphs of the consuls had
 been annihilated: in the decline and fall of the empire, the
 god Terminus, the sacred boundary, had insensibly receded
 from the ocean, the Rhine, the Danube, and the Euphrates;
 and Rome was reduced to her ancient territory from Viterbo
 to Terracina, and from Narni to the mouth of the Tyber. (42)","('Caesars', 'PERSON'), ('Terminus', 'LOC'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Viterbo', 'GPE'), ('Terracina', 'GPE'), ('Narni', 'GPE'), ('Tyber', 'LOC')"
"By the failure of the collateral branches, the whole inheritance devolved to Charles the Fat, the last emperor of his family: his insanity authorized the
 desertion of Germany, Italy, and France: he was deposed in a diet, and solicited his daily bread from the rebels by whose contempt his life and liberty had been spared.","('Charles the Fat', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE')"
"By the necessity of their situation, the inhabitants of Rome were cast into the rough model of a republican government: they were compelled to
 elect some judges in peace, and some leaders in war: the
 nobles assembled to deliberate, and their resolves could not
 be executed without the union and consent of the multitude.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('republican', 'NORP')"
"By this decisive measure they would finally eradicate the
 claims of the Greeks; from the debasement of a provincial
 town, the majesty of Rome would be restored: the Latin
 Christians would be united, under a supreme head, in their
 ancient metropolis; and the conquerors of the West would
 receive their crown from the successors of St. Peter.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Latin\r\n Christians', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE')"
Character and Coronation of Charlemagne.,"('Coronation of Charlemagne', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Charlemagne pursued, and
 confined, the Britons on the shores of the ocean; and that
 ferocious tribe, whose origin and language are so different
 from the French, was chastised by the imposition of tribute,
 hostages, and peace.","('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Britons', 'NORP'), ('French', 'NORP')"
"Charlemagne undertook
 the expedition, restored the emir, and, without distinction
 of faith, impartially crushed the resistance of the
 Christians, and rewarded the obedience and services of the
 Mahometans.","('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Mahometans', 'NORP')"
"Charlemagne was the first who united GERMANY under the same
 sceptre.","('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('GERMANY', 'GPE')"
Conquest of Italy by the Franks.,"('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"Constantine flew for refuge
 to his paternal mountains; but he descended at the head of
 the bold and affectionate Isaurians; and his final victory
 confounded the arms and predictions of the fanatics.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Isaurians', 'NORP')"
"Constantine himself is accused of
 indulging a royal license to doubt, or deny, or deride the
 mysteries of the Catholics, (20) but they were deeply
 inscribed in the public and private creed of his bishops;
 and the boldest Iconoclast might assault with a secret
 horror the monuments of popular devotion, which were
 consecrated to the honour of his celestial patrons.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('20', 'DATE'), ('Iconoclast', 'ORG')"
"Constantinople was exasperated by the treason and sacrilege
 of ancient Rome: a proverb, ""That the Franks were good
 friends and bad neighbours,""  was in every one's mouth; but it
 was dangerous to provoke a neighbour who might be tempted to
 reiterate, in the church of St. Sophia, the ceremony of his
 Imperial coronation.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('St. Sophia', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
Constitution of the Germanic Body.,"('the Germanic Body', 'ORG')"
"Content with the titles of emperor
 and Augustus, the successors of Charlemagne neglected to
 assert this local jurisdiction.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON')"
Contrast of the power and modesty of Augustus .,"('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"Division of the empire, A.D. 888 .","('888', 'CARDINAL')"
"During
 sixty years, no emperor appeared in Italy, and the name was
 remembered only by the ignominious sale of the last relics
 of sovereignty.","('sixty years', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"During the
 short union of virtue and power, they respectfully saluted
 the august Charlemagne, with the acclamations of basileus,
 and emperor of the Romans.","('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"During the five succeeding reigns, a period of thirty-eight years, the contest was maintained, with unabated rage and various success, between the worshippers and the breakers of the images; but I am not inclined to pursue with minute diligence the repetition of the same events.","('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirty-eight years', 'DATE')"
"During the life of her husband, these sentiments
 were inflamed by danger and dissimulation, and she could
 only labor to protect and promote some favourite monks whom
 she drew from their caverns, and seated on the metropolitan
 thrones of the East.","('East', 'LOC')"
Epistles of Gregory II.,"('Gregory II', 'PERSON')"
Establishment of Images.,"('Establishment of Images', 'ORG')"
"Except an original and self-inherent claim of
 sovereignty, there was not any prerogative remaining, which
 the title of emperor could add to the patrician of Rome. (61)
Donations of Pepin and Charlemagne to the popes .","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Pepin', 'PERSON'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON')"
"Far different was the situation of the German
 Caesars, who were ambitious to enslave the kingdom of Italy.","('German', 'NORP'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Final establishment of images by the empress Theodora, A.D. 842","('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 842', 'DATE')"
"Final separation of the popes from the Eastern empire, A.D. 774-800.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 774-800', 'DATE')"
"For a while Edessa had braved the
 Persian assaults; but the chosen city, the spouse of Christ,
 was involved in the common ruin; and his divine resemblance
 became the slave and trophy of the infidels.","('Edessa', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"For the honour of orthodoxy, at least the orthodoxy of the Roman church, it is somewhat unfortunate, that the two princes who convened the two councils of Nice are both stained with the blood of their sons.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nice', 'GPE')"
Forgery of the donation of Constantine .,"('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
 the net of sacerdotal policy.","('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
Frederic the Second (148) was endowed with some personal and peculiar advantages.,"('Frederic', 'PERSON'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('148', 'CARDINAL')"
"Frederic the first, A.D. 1152-1190.","('Frederic', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('A.D. 1152-1190', 'DATE')"
"From
 the condition of a subject and an exile, he twice rose to
 the command of the city, oppressed, expelled, and created
 the popes, and formed a conspiracy for restoring the
 authority of the Greek emperors.","('Greek', 'NORP')"
"From his prison he escaped
 to the Vatican: the duke of Spoleto hastened to his rescue,
 Charlemagne sympathized in his injury, and in his camp of
 Paderborn in Westphalia accepted, or solicited, a visit from
 the Roman pontiff.","('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Spoleto', 'GPE'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Paderborn', 'PERSON'), ('Westphalia', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"From that memorable aera, two maxims of public
 jurisprudence were introduced by force and ratified by time.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"From this humiliating scene, let us turn to the apparent
 majesty of the same Charles in the diets of the empire.","('Charles', 'PERSON')"
Germany .,"('Germany', 'GPE')"
"Had
 they power to abolish his government of Rome?","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Had the pope and the Romans revived the primitive
 constitution, the titles of emperor and Augustus were
 conferred on Charlemagne for the term of his life; and his
 successors, on each vacancy, must have ascended the throne
 by a formal or tacit election.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON')"
"Happy would it
 have been for the Romans, if a similar privilege had guarded
 the patrimony of St. Peter from the calamities of war; if
 the Christians, who visited the holy threshold, would have
 sheathed their swords in the presence of the apostle and his
 successor.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"He
 retaliated on the Avars, or Huns of Pannonia, the same
 calamities which they had inflicted on the nations.","('Avars', 'NORP'), ('Huns of Pannonia', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"He maintained a more equal intercourse with the
 caliph Harun al Rashid, (114) whose dominion stretched from
 Africa to India, and accepted from his ambassadors a tent, a
 water-clock, an elephant, and the keys of the Holy
 Sepulchre.","('Harun al Rashid', 'PERSON'), ('114', 'CARDINAL'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('India', 'GPE'), ('the Holy\r\n Sepulchre', 'PERSON')"
"He must indeed have trusted to the ignorance of Leo, since he could assert the perpetual use of images, from the apostolic age, and their venerable presence in the six synods of the Catholic church.","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"He was himself
 provoked by resistance and invective; and his own party
 accused him of an imperfect discharge of his duty, and urged
 for his imitation the example of the Jewish king, who had
 broken without scruple the brazen serpent of the temple.","('Jewish', 'NORP')"
"He was ignorant of sacred and
 profane letters; but his education, his reason, perhaps his
 intercourse with the Jews and Arabs, had inspired the
 martial peasant with a hatred of images; and it was held to
 be the duty of a prince to impose on his subjects the
 dictates of his own conscience.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"He was ignorant, the
 profane historian, of the testimony which he is compelled to
 deliver in the ecclesiastical page of Evagrius, that the
 Palladium was exposed on the rampart, and that the water
 which had been sprinkled on the holy face, instead of
 quenching, added new fuel to the flames of the besieged.","('Evagrius, that the\r\n Palladium', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"He wished to improve the laws and the character of
 the Franks; and his attempts, however feeble and imperfect,
 are deserving of praise: the inveterate evils of the times
 were suspended or mollified by his government; (100) but in
 his institutions I can seldom discover the general views and
 the immortal spirit of a legislator, who survives himself
 for the benefit of posterity.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"Her ancient patrimony
 of farms and houses was transformed by their bounty into the
 temporal dominion of cities and provinces; and the donation
 of the Exarchate was the first-fruits of the conquests of
 Pepin. (62)","('Exarchate', 'PRODUCT'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Pepin', 'PERSON'), ('62', 'CARDINAL')"
"Her deliverance by Pepin, A.D. 754 .","('Pepin', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 754', 'DATE')"
"Her son by the first marriage, Alberic, was compelled to attend at the nuptial banquet; but his reluctant and ungraceful service was
 chastised with a blow by his new father.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Alberic', 'PERSON')"
"His
 alms, his sermons, his correspondence with the kings and
 prelates of the West, his recent services, their gratitude,
 and oath, accustomed the Romans to consider him as the first
 magistrate or prince of the city.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"His
 father, Henry the Fowler, was elected, by the suffrage of
 the nation, to save and institute the kingdom of Germany.","('Henry the Fowler', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"His
 grandson contended with their vigour and maturity; but
 Frederic II., A.D. 1198-1250.","('Frederic II.', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 1198-1250', 'DATE')"
"His
 long reign was distracted with clamour, sedition, conspiracy,
 and mutual hatred, and sanguinary revenge; the persecution
 of images was the motive or pretence, of his adversaries;
 and, if they missed a temporal diadem, they were rewarded by
 the Greeks with the crown of martyrdom.","('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"His best
 prerogative was the right of presiding and proposing in the
 national senate, which was convened at his summons; and his
 native kingdom of Bohemia, less opulent than the adjacent
 city of Nuremberg, was the firmest seat of his power and the
 richest source of his revenue.","('Bohemia', 'LOC'), ('Nuremberg', 'GPE')"
"His birth and education recommended
 him to the Italians; and in the implacable discord of the
 two factions, the Ghibelins were attached to the emperor,
 while the Guelfs displayed the banner of liberty and the
 church.","('Italians', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ghibelins', 'NORP'), ('Guelfs', 'PERSON')"
"His contemporaries of the fifteenth
 century were astonished at his sacrilegious boldness; yet
 such is the silent and irresistible progress of reason,
 that, before the end of the next age, the fable was rejected
 by the contempt of historians (73) and poets, (74) and the
 tacit or modest censure of the advocates of the Roman
 church.","('the fifteenth\r\n century', 'DATE'), ('73', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"His coronation was twice
 performed, with the sanction of the popes, by their most
 faithful servant St. Boniface, the apostle of Germany, and
 by the grateful hands of Stephen the Third, who, in the
 monastery of St. Denys placed the diadem on the head of his
 benefactor.","('St. Boniface', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Stephen the Third', 'PERSON'), ('St. Denys', 'GPE')"
"His enemies were crushed by his valour; his friends were
 multiplied by his liberality; his father had been the saviour of Christendom; and the claims of personal merit were repeated and ennobled in a descent of four generations.","('Christendom', 'NORP'), ('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"His esteem for the piety and knowledge of the
 clergy tempted him to intrust that aspiring order with
 temporal dominion and civil jurisdiction; and his son Lewis,
 when he was stripped and degraded by the bishops, might
 accuse, in some measure, the imprudence of his father.","('Lewis', 'PERSON')"
"His memory was revered; but in the next
 election, a priest of the Lateran, Leo the Third, was
 preferred to the nephew and the favourite of Adrian, whom he
 had promoted to the first dignities of the church.","('Lateran', 'PERSON'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Adrian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"His moderation was guarded by timidity; but his son Theophilus, alike ignorant of fear and pity, was the last and most cruel of the Iconoclasts.","('Theophilus', 'PERSON'), ('Iconoclasts', 'NORP')"
"His open simony might be the consequence of
 distress; and his blasphemous invocation of Jupiter and
 Venus, if it be true, could not possibly be serious.","('Jupiter', 'LOC'), ('Venus', 'LOC')"
"His ostentation, A.D. 1356 .","('A.D. 1356', 'DATE')"
"His own studies were
 tardy, laborious, and imperfect; if he spoke Latin, and
 understood Greek, he derived the rudiments of knowledge from
 conversation, rather than from books; and, in his mature
 age, the emperor strove to acquire the practice of writing,
 which every peasant now learns in his infancy. (102)","('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Greek', 'LANGUAGE'), ('102', 'CARDINAL')"
"His real merit is doubtless enhanced by the barbarism of the nation and the times from
 which he emerged: but the apparent magnitude of an object is
 likewise enlarged by an unequal comparison; and the ruins of
 Palmyra derive a casual splendour from the nakedness of the
 surrounding desert.","('Palmyra', 'LOC')"
"His reply (124) is expressive of his weakness: he proves, with some learning, that, both in sacred and profane history, the name of king is synonymous with the
 Greek word basileus: if, at Constantinople, it were assumed
 in a more exclusive and imperial sense, he claims from his
 ancestors, and from the popes, a just participation of the
 honours of the Roman purple.","('124', 'CARDINAL'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"His royal
 proselyte withdrew from the seat and patrimony of St. Peter;
 declared his resolution of founding a new capital in the
 East; and resigned to the popes the free and perpetual
 sovereignty of Rome, Italy, and the provinces of the West.
 (69)","('St. Peter', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('69', 'CARDINAL')"
"His royal prerogatives, in a
 less odious sense, were acknowledged in the diet of
 Roncaglia; and the revenue of Italy was fixed at thirty
 thousand pounds of silver, (146) which were multiplied to an
 indefinite demand by the rapine of the fiscal officers.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('thirty\r\n thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('146', 'CARDINAL')"
"His son Pepin, the heir of his power and
 virtues, assumed the office of champion of the Roman church;
 and the zeal of the French prince appears to have been
 prompted by the love of glory and religion.","('Pepin', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('French', 'NORP')"
"His son and heir Octavian assumed, with the pontificate, the name of John XII.: like
 his predecessor, he was provoked by the Lombard princes to seek a deliverer for the church and republic; and the services of Otho were rewarded with the Imperial dignity.","('Octavian', 'PERSON'), ('John XII', 'PERSON'), ('Lombard', 'PERSON'), ('Otho', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"His successor Astolphus declared himself the equal
 enemy of the emperor and the pope: Ravenna was subdued by
 force or treachery, (50) and this final conquest extinguished
 the series of the exarchs, who had reigned with a
 subordinate power since the time of Justinian and the ruin
 of the Gothic kingdom.","('Astolphus', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'PERSON'), ('50', 'CARDINAL'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"His treatment of the vanquished
 Saxons (98) was an abuse of the right of conquest; his laws
 were not less sanguinary than his arms, and in the
 discussion of his motives, whatever is subtracted from
 bigotry must be imputed to temper.","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('98', 'CARDINAL')"
"His youth and manhood were of a
 suitable complexion; and the nations of pilgrims could bear
 testimony to the charges that were urged against him in a
 Roman synod, and in the presence of Otho the Great.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Otho the Great', 'PERSON')"
"I shall be scarcely
 permitted to accuse the ambition of a conqueror; but in a
 day of equal retribution, the sons of his brother Carloman,
 the Merovingian princes of Aquitain, and the four thousand
 five hundred Saxons who were beheaded on the same spot,
 would have something to allege against the justice and
 humanity of Charlemagne.","('a\r\n day', 'DATE'), ('Carloman', 'PERSON'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('Aquitain', 'PERSON'), ('four thousand\r\n five hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON')"
"I touch with
 reverence the laws of Charlemagne, so highly applauded by a
 respectable judge.","('Charlemagne', 'PERSON')"
"I. Seven of
 the most powerful feudatories were permitted to assume, with
 a distinguished name and rank, the exclusive privilege of
 choosing the Roman emperor; and these electors were the king
 of Bohemia, the duke of Saxony, the margrave of
 Brandenburgh, the count palatine of the Rhine, and the three
 archbishops of Mentz, of Treves, and of Cologne.","('Seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Bohemia', 'GPE'), ('Saxony', 'GPE'), ('Brandenburgh', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mentz', 'PERSON'), ('Treves', 'GPE'), ('Cologne', 'GPE')"
"I. That the prince, who was elected in the German diet,
 acquired, from that instant, the subject kingdoms of Italy
 and Rome.","('German', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"I. The Roman province of Gaul had been transformed into the name
 and monarchy of France; but, in the decay of the Merovingian
 line, its limits were contracted by the independence of the
 Britons and the revolt of Aquitain.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Merovingian', 'GPE'), ('Britons', 'NORP'), ('Aquitain', 'ORG')"
"I. To
 fix in the college of cardinals the freedom and independence
 of election, and forever to abolish the right or usurpation
 of the emperors and the Roman people.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"I. Under the sacerdotal monarchy of St. Peter, the nations began to resume the practice of seeking, on the banks of the Tyber, their kings, their laws, and the oracles of their fate.","('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('Tyber', 'NORP')"
"If the dukes, margraves, and counts of Germany,
 were less audacious in their claims, the consequences of
 their success were more lasting and pernicious to the state.","('Germany', 'GPE')"
"If we annihilate the interval of time and space between
 Augustus and Charles, strong and striking will be the
 contrast between the two Caesars; the Bohemian who concealed
 his weakness under the mask of ostentation, and the Roman,
 who disguised his strength under the semblance of modesty.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Charles', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Bohemian', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"If we retrace the outlines of this geographical picture, it
 will be seen that the empire of the Franks extended, between
 east and west, from the Ebro to the Elbe or Vistula; between
 the north and south, from the duchy of Beneventum to the
 River Eyder, the perpetual boundary of Germany and Denmark.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Ebro', 'LOC'), ('Elbe', 'LOC'), ('Vistula', 'GPE'), ('Beneventum', 'GPE'), ('the\r\n River Eyder', 'LOC'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Denmark', 'GPE')"
"Ignorant of the arts of luxury, the primitive Romans had improved the science of government and war: the will of the community was absolute: the rights of individuals were
 sacred: one hundred and thirty thousand citizens were armed for defence or conquest; and a band of robbers and outlaws was moulded into a nation deserving of freedom and ambitious of glory.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('one hundred and thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"In
 the reformation of religion, his first steps were moderate
 and cautious: he assembled a great council of senators and
 bishops, and enacted, with their consent, that all the
 images should be removed from the sanctuary and altar to a
 proper height in the churches where they might be visible to
 the eyes, and inaccessible to the superstition, of the
 people.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"In a hard-fought day, as the two armies alternately
 yielded and advanced, a phantom was seen, a voice was heard,
 and Ravenna was victorious by the assurance of victory.","('a hard-fought day', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ravenna', 'PERSON')"
"In a rapid conquest of ten years, the
 Arabs subdued those cities and these images; and, in their
 opinion, the Lord of Hosts pronounced a decisive judgment
 between the adoration and contempt of these mute and
 inanimate idols.","('ten years', 'DATE'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('the Lord of Hosts', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"In arms, at the gate of the Vatican, the conqueror listened
 to the voice of Gregory the Second, (48) withdrew his troops,
 resigned his conquests, respectfully visited the church of
 St. Peter, and after performing his devotions, offered his
 sword and dagger, his cuirass and mantle, his silver cross,
 and his crown of gold, on the tomb of the apostle.","('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Gregory the Second', 'PERSON'), ('48', 'DATE'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE')"
"In ecclesiastical
 rank and jurisdiction, the patriarch of Constantinople and
 the pope of Rome were nearly equal.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In every age, such copies, so congenial to human feelings, have been cherished by the zeal
 of private friendship, or public esteem: the images of the Roman emperors were adored with civil, and almost religious, honours; a reverence less ostentatious, but more sincere, was applied to the statues of sages and patriots; and these 
profane virtues, these splendid sins, disappeared in the presence of the holy men, who had died for their celestial and everlasting country.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In his
 fourth and last pilgrimage, he was received at Rome with the
 due honours of king and patrician: Leo was permitted to purge
 himself by oath of the crimes imputed to his charge: his
 enemies were silenced, and the sacrilegious attempt against
 his life was punished by the mild and insufficient penalty
 of exile.","('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('last', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Leo', 'PERSON')"
"In his absence he instituted the Spanish march,
 (108) which extended from the Pyrenees to the River Ebro:
 Barcelona was the residence of the French governor: he
 possessed the counties of Rousillon and Catalonia; and the
 infant kingdoms of Navarre and Arragon were subject to his
 jurisdiction.","('Spanish', 'NORP'), ('108', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('the River Ebro', 'FAC'), ('Barcelona', 'GPE'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Rousillon', 'GPE'), ('Catalonia', 'GPE'), ('Navarre', 'GPE'), ('Arragon', 'GPE')"
"In his distress, the first  Gregory had implored the aid of the hero of the age, of Charles Martel, who governed the
 French monarchy with the humble title of mayor or duke; and
 who, by his signal victory over the Saracens, had saved his
 country, and perhaps Europe, from the Mahometan yoke.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Charles Martel', 'PERSON'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Mahometan', 'NORP')"
"In his dress, his domestics, (155)
 his titles, in all the offices of social life, Augustus
 maintained the character of a private Roman; and his most
 artful flatterers respected the secret of his absolute and
 perpetual monarchy.","('155', 'CARDINAL'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In his familiar
 conversation, the emperor protested the ignorance of the
 intentions of Leo, which he would have disappointed by his
 absence on that memorable day.","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('that memorable day', 'DATE')"
"In his first visit to the capital, he was received with all
 the honours which had formerly been paid to the exarch, the
 representative of the emperor; and these honours obtained
 some new decorations from the joy and gratitude of Pope
 Adrian the First. (60)","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Adrian', 'PERSON'), ('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('60', 'CARDINAL')"
"In his four pilgrimages or visits to the Vatican, he
 embraced the popes in the communion of friendship and piety;
 knelt before the tomb, and consequently before the image, of
 the apostle; and joined, without scruple, in all the prayers
 and processions of the Roman liturgy.","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In that
 palace, the Roman bishops, the second and third Gregory,
 were condemned as the authors of the revolt, and every
 attempt was made, either by fraud or force, to seize their
 persons, and to strike at their lives.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON')"
"In that schism the Romans had
 tasted of freedom, and the popes of sovereignty: their
 submission would have exposed them to the revenge of a
 jealous tyrant; and the revolution of Italy had betrayed the
 impotence, as well as the tyranny, of the Byzantine court.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"In the
 cathedral of St. Ambrose, Charles was crowned with the iron
 crown, which tradition ascribed to the Lombard monarchy; but
 he was admitted only with a peaceful train; the gates of the
 city were shut upon him; and the king of Italy was held a
 captive by the arms of the Visconti, whom he confirmed in
 the sovereignty of Milan.","('St. Ambrose', 'GPE'), ('Charles', 'PERSON'), ('Lombard', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Visconti', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"In the
 dissolution of the Lombard kingdom, the inhabitants of the
 duchy of Spoleto (64) sought a refuge from the storm, shaved
 their heads after the Roman fashion, declared themselves the
 servants and subjects of St. Peter, and completed, by this
 voluntary surrender, the present circle of the
 ecclesiastical state.","('Lombard', 'NORP'), ('Spoleto', 'GPE'), ('64', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE')"
"In the
 portico, Adrian expected him at the head of his clergy: they
 embraced, as friends and equals; but in their march to the
 altar, the king or patrician assumed the right hand of the
 pope.","('Adrian', 'PERSON')"
"In the
 reformation of the sixteenth century, freedom and knowledge
 had expanded all the faculties of man: the thirst of
 innovation superseded the reverence of antiquity; and the
 vigour of Europe could disdain those phantoms which terrified
 the sickly and servile weakness of the Greeks.","('the sixteenth century', 'DATE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"In the Christian
 aristocracy, the principal members of the clergy still
 formed a senate to assist the administration, and to supply
 the vacancy, of the bishop.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"In the Italian cities a
 municipal government had never been totally abolished; and
 their first privileges were granted by the favour and policy
 of the emperors, who were desirous of erecting a plebeian
 barrier against the independence of the nobles.","('Italian', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"In the North, Christianity
 was propagated by the sword of Otho, the conqueror and
 apostle of the Slavic nations of the Elbe and Oder: the
 marches of Brandenburgh and Sleswick were fortified with
 German colonies; and the king of Denmark, the dukes of
 Poland and Bohemia, confessed themselves his tributary
 vassals.","('North', 'LOC'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Otho', 'PERSON'), ('Slavic', 'NORP'), ('Elbe', 'LOC'), ('Oder', 'NORP'), ('Brandenburgh', 'LOC'), ('Sleswick', 'LOC'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('Denmark', 'GPE'), ('Poland', 'GPE'), ('Bohemia', 'GPE')"
"In the Vatican he was again
 crowned with the golden crown of the empire; but, in
 obedience to a secret treaty, the Roman emperor immediately
 withdrew, without reposing a single night within the walls
 of Rome.","('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('a single night', 'TIME'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In the West, Pope Adrian the First accepted and announced
 the decrees of the Nicene assembly, which is now revered by
 the Catholics as the seventh in rank of the general
 councils.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Adrian', 'PERSON'), ('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Nicene', 'PERSON'), ('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('seventh', 'ORDINAL')"
"In the change of manners and language the patricians of
 Rome (58) were far removed from the senate of Romulus, on the palace of Constantine, from the free nobles of the republic,
 or the fictitious parents of the emperor.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('58', 'DATE'), ('Romulus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"In the church of Diospolis, in Palestine, the features of the Mother of God (13) were deeply inscribed in a marble column; the East and West have been decorated by the pencil of St. Luke; and the Evangelist, who was perhaps a physician, has been forced to exercise the occupation of a painter, so profane and odious in the eyes of the primitive Christians.","('Diospolis', 'GPE'), ('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('13', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('St. Luke', 'LOC'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"In the conquest of Italy, the champions of the Roman church obtained a favourable
 occasion, a specious title, the wishes of the people, the prayers and intrigues of the clergy.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the first age of the monarchy, the appointment of
 the son to the duchy or county of his father, was solicited
 as a favour; it was gradually obtained as a custom, and
 extorted as a right: the lineal succession was often
 extended to the collateral or female branches; the states of
 the empire (their popular, and at length their legal,
 appellation) were divided and alienated by testament and
 sale; and all idea of a public trust was lost in that of a
 private and perpetual inheritance.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"In the fortress of St.
 Angelo, he maintained an obstinate siege, till the
 unfortunate consul was betrayed by a promise of safety: his
 body was suspended on a gibbet, and his head was exposed on
 the battlements of the castle.","('St.\r\n Angelo', 'GPE')"
"In the frequent and at last the perpetual
 institution of diets, a national spirit was kept alive, and
 the powers of a common legislature are still exercised by
 the three branches or colleges of the electors, the princes,
 and the free and Imperial cities of Germany.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"In the hour of prosperity,
 their ambition was diverted by more alluring objects; and in
 the decay and division of the empire, they were oppressed by
 the defence of their hereditary provinces.","('the hour', 'TIME')"
"In the long night of superstition, the Christians had wandered far away from the
 simplicity of the gospel: nor was it easy for them to
 discern the clue, and tread back the mazes, of the
 labyrinth.","('the long night', 'TIME'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"In the minority of his son Otho the Third,
 Rome made a bold attempt to shake off the Saxon yoke, and
 the consul Crescentius was the Brutus of the republic.","('Otho', 'PERSON'), ('Third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Saxon', 'NORP'), ('Crescentius', 'PERSON'), ('Brutus', 'PERSON')"
"In the partition of his share, Lorraine and Arles,
 two recent and transitory kingdoms, were bestowed on the
 younger children; Lewis II. A.D. 856-875 and Lewis the Second, his eldest son, was content with the realm of Italy, the proper and sufficient patrimony of a Roman emperor.","('Lorraine', 'PERSON'), ('Arles', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Lewis II', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 856-875', 'DATE'), ('Lewis the Second', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the purple, Leo the Fifth asserted the name and religion of an Armenian; and the idols, with their seditious adherents, were condemned to a second exile.","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Fifth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Armenian', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"In the quarrels of ancient Greece, the holy people of Elis
 enjoyed a perpetual peace, under the protection of Jupiter,
 and in the exercise of the Olympic games. (47)","('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Elis', 'GPE'), ('Jupiter', 'LOC'), ('Olympic', 'EVENT'), ('47', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the restoration of the monks, a thousand images were
 exposed to the public veneration; a thousand legends were
 inverted of their sufferings and miracles.","('a thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('a thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the revival of letters
 and liberty, this fictitious deed was transpierced by the
 pen of Laurentius Valla, the pen of an eloquent critic and a
 Roman patriot. (72)","('Laurentius Valla', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('72', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the revival of the empire of empire of Rome, neither the
 bishop nor the people could bestow on Charlemagne or Otho
 the provinces which were lost, as they had been won, by the
 chance of arms.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Otho', 'PERSON')"
"In the school of adversity the priest insensibly
 imbibed the virtues and the ambition of a prince; the same
 character was assumed, the same policy was adopted, by the
 Italian, the Greek, or the Syrian, who ascended the chair of
 St. Peter; and, after the loss of her legions and provinces,
 the genius and fortune of the popes again restored the
 supremacy of Rome.","('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Syrian', 'NORP'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In the time of Charles Martel and of
 Pepin, the interposition of the Lombard kingdom covered the
 freedom, while it threatened the safety, of Rome; and the
 patriciate represented only the title, the service, the
 alliance, of these distant protectors.","('Charles Martel', 'PERSON'), ('Pepin', 'PERSON'), ('Lombard', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In the twenty-six years that
 elapsed between the conquest of Lombardy and his Imperial
 coronation, Rome, which had been delivered by the sword, was
 subject, as his own, to the sceptre of Charlemagne.","('the twenty-six years', 'DATE'), ('Lombardy', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON')"
"In this season of distress and dismay, the
 eloquence of the monks was exercised in the defence of
 images; and they attempted to prove, that the sin and schism
 of the greatest part of the Orientals had forfeited the
 favour, and annihilated the virtue, of these precious
 symbols.","('this season', 'DATE'), ('Orientals', 'NORP')"
"Incapable as you are of defending your Roman subjects, the maritime situation of the city may perhaps expose it to your depredation but we can remove to the distance of four-and-twenty stadia, (34) to the first fortress of the Lombards, and then - you may pursue the winds.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('four-and-twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('34', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Lombards', 'NORP')"
Independence of Italy.,"('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Independence of the princes of Germany, A.D. 814-1250,etc .","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 814-1250', 'DATE')"
Introduction of images into the Christian church.,"('Christian', 'NORP')"
"It is agreed, that in the eighth
 century, their dominion was founded on rebellion, and that
 the rebellion was produced, and justified, by the heresy of
 the Iconoclasts; but the conduct of the second and third
 Gregory, in this memorable contest, is variously interpreted
 by the wishes of their friends and enemies.","('the eighth\r\n century', 'DATE'), ('Iconoclasts', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON')"
"It is in the fourteenth century that we may view in the
 strongest light the state and contrast of the Roman empire
 of Germany, which no longer held, except on the borders of
 the Rhine and Danube, a single province of Trajan or
 Constantine.","('the fourteenth century', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Trajan', 'GPE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"It is not easy to conceive the private
 friendship of a Frank and an Arab, who were strangers to
 each other's person, and language, and religion: but their
 public correspondence was founded on vanity, and their
 remote situation left no room for a competition of interest.","('Frank', 'PERSON'), ('Arab', 'NORP')"
"It is true,
 indeed, that the text of Procopius ascribes the double
 deliverance of Edessa to the wealth and valour of her
 citizens, who purchased the absence and repelled the
 assaults of the Persian monarch.","('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Edessa', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"It was after the Nycene synod, and under the reign of the
 pious Irene, that the popes consummated the separation of
 Rome and Italy, by the translation of the empire to the less
 orthodox Charlemagne.","('Nycene', 'PERSON'), ('Irene', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON')"
"It was not in the cause
 of the Iconoclast that Pepin has exposed his person and army
 in a double expedition beyond the Alps: he possessed, and
 might lawfully alienate, his conquests: and to the
 importunities of the Greeks he piously replied that no human
 consideration should tempt him to resume the gift which he
 had conferred on the Roman Pontiff for the remission of his
 sins, and the salvation of his soul.","('Iconoclast', 'NORP'), ('Pepin', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('the Roman Pontiff', 'PERSON')"
"It was the design of Leo the Isaurian to pronounce
 the condemnation of images as an article of faith, and by
 the authority of a general council: but the convocation of
 such an assembly was reserved for his son Constantine; (19)
 and though it is stigmatized by triumphant bigotry as a
 meeting of fools and atheists, their own partial and
 mutilated acts betray many symptoms of reason and piety.","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Isaurian', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('19', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was the design of Otho the Third to
 abandon the ruder countries of the North, to erect his
 throne in Italy, and to revive the institutions of the Roman
 monarchy.","('Otho', 'PERSON'), ('Third', 'ORDINAL'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
Italy .,"('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Its
 first and most glorious exploit was the deliverance of the
 city from the arms of Chosroes Nushirvan; and it was soon
 revered as a pledge of the divine promise, that Edessa
 should never be taken by a foreign enemy.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Chosroes Nushirvan', 'PERSON'), ('Edessa', 'PERSON')"
"Its limits (118) were enlarged on every side by his son, the
 first and greatest of the Othos.","('118', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Othos', 'NORP')"
"Leo repassed the Alps with a commission
 of counts and bishops, the guards of his safety and the
 judges of his innocence; and it was not without reluctance,
 that the conqueror of the Saxons delayed till the ensuing
 year the personal discharge of this pious office.","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('the ensuing\r\n year', 'DATE')"
"Leo the Fourth maintained with less rigour the religion
 of his father and grandfather; but his wife, the fair and
 ambitious Irene, had imbibed the zeal of the Athenians, the
 heirs of the Idolatry, rather than the philosophy, of their
 ancestors.","('Leo the Fourth', 'PERSON'), ('Irene', 'PERSON'), ('Athenians', 'NORP'), ('Idolatry', 'NORP')"
"Leo the Iconoclast, and his successors, A.D. 726-840.","('Leo the Iconoclast', 'PERSON'), ('726-840', 'CARDINAL')"
"Leo was left for dead on the ground: on his revival
 from the swoon, the effect of his loss of blood, he
 recovered his speech and sight; and this natural event was
 improved to the miraculous restoration of his eyes and
 tongue, of which he had been deprived, twice deprived, by
 the knife of the assassins. (91)","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('91', 'CARDINAL')"
"Lewis the Pious, A.D. 814-840 .","('Lewis the Pious', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 814-840', 'DATE')"
Lothaire I A.D. 840-856 .,"('A.D. 840-856', 'DATE')"
"Many large congregations of Gnostics and Arians maintained,
 after their conversion, the simple worship which had
 preceded their separation; and the Armenians, the most
 warlike subjects of Rome, were not reconciled, in the
 twelfth century, to the sight of images. (17)","('Gnostics', 'NORP'), ('Arians', 'NORP'), ('Armenians', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('the\r\n twelfth century', 'DATE'), ('17', 'CARDINAL')"
"Neither zeal nor policy allowed him to
 hesitate; and the haughty strain in which Gregory addressed
 the emperor displays his confidence in the truth of his
 doctrine or the powers of resistance.","('Gregory', 'PERSON')"
"Nicephorus
 allowed a general liberty of speech and practice; and the only virtue of his reign is accused by the monks as the cause of his temporal and eternal perdition.","('Nicephorus', 'PERSON')"
"No more than
 eighteen days were allowed for the consummation of this
 important work: the Iconoclasts appeared, not as judges, but
 as criminals or penitents: the scene was decorated by the
 legates of Pope Adrian and the Eastern patriarchs, (79) the
 decrees were framed by the president Taracius, and ratified
 by the acclamations and subscriptions of three hundred and
 fifty bishops.","('No more than\r\n eighteen days', 'DATE'), ('Iconoclasts', 'NORP'), ('Pope', 'PERSON'), ('Adrian', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('79', 'CARDINAL'), ('Taracius', 'PERSON'), ('three hundred and\r\n fifty', 'CARDINAL')"
"No sooner had they confirmed their own safety, the worship of images, and the freedom of Rome and Italy, than the popes appear to have relaxed of their severity, and to have spared the relics of the Byzantine dominion.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"No sooner was he informed of the
 sudden approach of the monarch, than he despatched the
 magistrates and nobles of Rome to meet him, with the banner,
 about thirty miles from the city.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('about thirty miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"Nor was the Frank content with these vain and empty
 demonstrations of respect.","('Frank', 'PERSON')"
"Nor was the supremacy of the emperor confined to Germany alone: the hereditary
 monarchs of Europe confessed the preeminence of his rank and
 dignity: he was the first of the Christian princes, the
 temporal head of the great republic of the West: (153) to his
 person the title of majesty was long appropriated; and he
 disputed with the pope the sublime prerogative of creating
 kings and assembling councils.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('153', 'CARDINAL')"
"Of his moral virtues,
 chastity is not the most conspicuous: (96) but the public
 happiness could not be materially injured by his nine wives
 or concubines, the various indulgence of meaner or more
 transient amours, the multitude of his bastards whom he
 bestowed on the church, and the long celibacy and licentious
 manners of his daughters, (97) whom the father was suspected
 of loving with too fond a passion.","('96', 'CARDINAL'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('97', 'DATE')"
"Of such adventurers, the most fortunate was the emperor Leo
 the Third, (18) who, from the mountains of Isauria, ascended
 the throne of the East.","('Leo\r\n the Third', 'PERSON'), ('18', 'DATE'), ('Isauria', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"Of the
 Archipelago, or Holy Sea, the numerous islands were filled
 with images and monks: their votaries abjured, without
 scruple, the enemy of Christ, his mother, and the saints;
 they armed a fleet of boats and galleys, displayed their
 consecrated banners, and boldly steered for the harbour of
 Constantinople, to place on the throne a new favourite of God
 and the people.","('Archipelago', 'LOC'), ('Holy Sea', 'LOC'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
Of the consul Crescentius.,"('Crescentius', 'PERSON')"
"Of this second Nicene council the acts
 are still extant; a curious monument of superstition and
 ignorance, of falsehood and folly.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Nicene council', 'ORG')"
"On
 the death of the pope, these bishops recommended a successor
 to the suffrage of the college of cardinals, (126) and their
 choice was ratified or rejected by the applause or clamour of
 the Roman people.","('126', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"On either side, their expiring monarchy was pressed by the
 zeal and prudence of Pope Adrian the First, the genius, the
 fortune, and greatness of Charlemagne, the son of Pepin;
 these heroes of the church and state were united in public
 and domestic friendship, and while they trampled on the
 prostrate, they varnished their proceedings with the fairest
 colours of equity and moderation.","('Adrian', 'PERSON'), ('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Pepin', 'PERSON')"
"On his death without any male issue, the vacant throne was disputed by his uncles and
 cousins, and the popes most dexterously seized the occasion of judging the claims and merits of the candidates, and of bestowing on the most obsequious, or most liberal, the Imperial office of advocate of the Roman church.","('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"On the festival of Christmas, the last year of
 the eighth century, Charlemagne appeared in the church of
 St. Peter; and, to gratify the vanity of Rome, he had
 exchanged the simple dress of his country for the habit of a
 patrician. (92)","('Christmas', 'EVENT'), ('the last year of\r\n the eighth century', 'DATE'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"On the first edicts of the
 emperor, they declared themselves the champions of the holy
 images: Liutprand invaded the province of Romagna, which had
 already assumed that distinctive appellation; the Catholics
 of the Exarchate yielded without reluctance to his civil and
 military power; and a foreign enemy was introduced for the
 first time into the impregnable fortress of Ravenna.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Liutprand', 'PERSON'), ('Romagna', 'GPE'), ('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('Exarchate', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"On this occasion the effects of
 love and hatred are the same; and the zealous Protestants,
 who seek to kindle the indignation, and to alarm the fears,
 of princes and magistrates, expatiate on the insolence and
 treason of the two Gregories against their lawful sovereign.
 (29)","('Protestants', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gregories', 'NORP')"
"Otho king of Germany restores and appropriates the Western empire, A.D. 962 . 
 Otho (117) was of the noble race of the dukes of Saxony; and
 if he truly descended from Witikind, the adversary and
 proselyte of Charlemagne, the posterity of a vanquished
 people was exalted to reign over their conquerors.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('962', 'CARDINAL'), ('Otho', 'PERSON'), ('117', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saxony', 'GPE'), ('Witikind', 'PERSON'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON')"
"Otho the First imposed a treaty on the
 senate and people, who engaged to prefer the candidate most
 acceptable to his majesty: (127) his successors anticipated
 or prevented their choice: they bestowed the Roman benefice,
 like the bishoprics of Cologne or Bamberg, on their
 chancellors or preceptors; and whatever might be the merit
 of a Frank or Saxon, his name sufficiently attests the
 interposition of foreign power.","('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('127', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Cologne', 'GPE'), ('Bamberg', 'GPE'), ('Frank', 'PERSON'), ('Saxon', 'PERSON')"
"Patricians of Rome. 
 II.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Perhaps
 in his connection with Irene he aspired to the name of
 husband: his embassy to Constantinople spoke the language of
 peace and friendship, and might conceal a treaty of marriage
 with that ambitious princess, who had renounced the most
 sacred duties of a mother.","('Irene', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Perhaps a faithful subject,
 or even a generous enemy, would have been less impatient to
 divide the spoils of the Barbarian; and if the emperor had
 intrusted Stephen to solicit in his name the restitution of
 the Exarchate, I will not absolve the pope from the reproach
 of treachery and falsehood.","('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('Stephen', 'PERSON'), ('Exarchate', 'PERSON')"
"Perhaps some recent and imperfect converts of the Gnostic tribe might crown the statues of Christ and St. Paul with the profane honours which they paid to those of Aristotle and Pythagoras;
 (3) but the public religion of the Catholics was uniformly simple and spiritual; and the first notice of the use of 
pictures is in the censure of the council of Illiberis, three hundred years after the Christian aera.","('Gnostic', 'NORP'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('St. Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Aristotle', 'PERSON'), ('Pythagoras', 'PERSON'), ('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Illiberis', 'GPE'), ('three hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"Perhaps the humility of a
 Christian priest should have rejected an earthly kingdom,
 which it was not easy for him to govern without renouncing
 the virtues of his profession.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"Perhaps, in his expeditions beyond the Rhine and the
 Elbe, he aspired to save his monarchy from the fate of the
 Roman empire, to disarm the enemies of civilized society,
 and to eradicate the seed of future emigrations.","('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Elbe', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Reformation and claims of the church, A.D. 1073, etc.","('A.D. 1073', 'DATE')"
"Reluctance of the Franks and Charlemagne, A.D. 794, etc .","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('794', 'CARDINAL')"
Restoration and Decay of the Roman Empire in the West.,"('the Roman Empire', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"Restoration of images in the East by the empress Irene, A.D. 780, etc .","('East', 'LOC'), ('Irene', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 780', 'DATE')"
"Revolt of Alberic, A.D. 932 Amidst the ruins of Italy, the famous Marozia invited one of the usurpers to assume the character of her third husband; and Hugh, king of Burgundy was introduced by her faction into the mole of Hadrian or Castle of St. Angelo, which commands the principal bridge and entrance of Rome.","('Alberic', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 932', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Marozia', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Hugh', 'PERSON'), ('Burgundy', 'PERSON'), ('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('Castle', 'PERSON'), ('St. Angelo', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
Revolt of Italy and Rome.,"('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Revolt of Italy, A.D. 728, etc.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 728', 'DATE')"
"Rome
 was again encompassed by his arms; and Stephen, apprehensive
 of fatiguing the zeal of his Transalpine allies enforced his
 complaint and request by an eloquent letter in the name and
 person of St. Peter himself. (52)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Stephen', 'PERSON'), ('Transalpine', 'NORP'), ('St. Peter', 'PERSON'), ('52', 'CARDINAL')"
"Rome and Italy were docile to the voice of their
 father; but the greatest part of the Latin Christians were
 far behind in the race of superstition.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('the Latin Christians', 'NORP')"
"Rome attacked by the Lombards, A.D. 730-752 .","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"Rome was divided into
 twenty-eight parishes, and each parish was governed by a
 cardinal priest, or presbyter, a title which, however common
 or modest in its origin, has aspired to emulate the purple
 of kings.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('twenty-eight', 'CARDINAL')"
"Rome was summoned to acknowledge the
 victorious Lombard as her lawful sovereign; the annual
 tribute of a piece of gold was fixed as the ransom of each
 citizen, and the sword of destruction was unsheathed to
 exact the penalty of her disobedience.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Lombard', 'PERSON')"
"Since the
 revolt of Italy and the loss of the Exarchate, the distress
 of the Romans had exacted some sacrifice of their
 independence.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Exarchate', 'ORG'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
 among the decrees of the canon law. (70)","('Greece', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE')"
"Some canals of
 communication between the rivers, the Saone and the Meuse,
 the Rhine and the Danube, were faintly attempted.","('Saone', 'LOC'), ('Meuse', 'FAC'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
Spain . II.,"('Spain', 'GPE')"
"Stephen was entertained
 as the visible successor of the apostle; at the next
 assembly, the field of March or of May, his injuries were
 exposed to a devout and warlike nation, and he repassed the
 Alps, not as a suppliant, but as a conqueror, at the head of
 a French army, which was led by the king in person.","('Stephen', 'PERSON'), ('March or of May', 'DATE'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('French', 'NORP')"
"Such anarchy was the
 inevitable consequence of the laws and manners of Europe;
 and the kingdoms of France and Italy were shivered into
 fragments by the violence of the same tempest.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Superstition and weakness formed the character of Michael the First, but the saints and images were incapable of supporting their votary on the throne.","('Michael', 'PERSON'), ('First', 'ORDINAL')"
Temporal Dominion of the Popes.,"('Temporal Dominion of the Popes', 'PERSON')"
"That
 city and fortress were speedily recovered by the active
 diligence and maritime forces of the Venetians; and those
 faithful subjects obeyed the exhortation of Gregory himself,
 in separating the personal guilt of Leo from the general
 cause of the Roman empire. (49)","('Venetians', 'NORP'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"That ambitious monk
 devoted his life to the execution of two projects.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"That empire was not unworthy of its title; (105) and some of
 the fairest kingdoms of Europe were the patrimony or
 conquest of a prince, who reigned at the same time in
 France, Spain, Italy, Germany, and Hungary. (106)
France.","('105', 'CARDINAL'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('106', 'CARDINAL'), ('France', 'GPE')"
"That mysterious circle was enlarged
 to an indefinite extent, by the verbal or written donation
 of Charlemagne, (65) who, in the first transports of his
 victory, despoiled himself and the Greek emperor of the
 cities and islands which had formerly been annexed to the
 Exarchate.","('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('65', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Exarchate', 'ORG')"
"That name, with the addition of saint, is inserted in
 the Roman calendar; and the saint, by a rare felicity, is
 crowned with the praises of the historians and philosophers
 of an enlightened age. (95)","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The
 German emperor was no more than the elective and impotent
 magistrate of an aristocracy of princes, who had not left
 him a village that he might call his own.","('German', 'NORP')"
"The
 Lombards, after a weak resistance, obtained an ignominious
 peace, and swore to restore the possessions, and to respect
 the sanctity, of the Roman church.","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The
 Roman church would acquire a zealous and respectable
 advocate; and, under the shadow of the Carlovingian power,
 the bishop might exercise, with honour and safety, the
 government of the city. (88)
Coronation of Charlemagne as emperor of Rome and of the West, A.D. 800, Dec. 25 .","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Carlovingian', 'NORP'), ('88', 'CARDINAL'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('800', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dec. 25', 'DATE')"
"The
 ambassadors of the pope were received by Charles with decent
 reverence; but the greatness of his occupations, and the
 shortness of his life, prevented his interference in the
 affairs of Italy, except by a friendly and ineffectual
 mediation.","('Charles', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The
 college of princes and prelates purged themselves of a
 promiscuous multitude: they reduced to four representative
 votes the long series of independent counts, and excluded
 the nobles or equestrian order, sixty thousand of whom, as
 in the Polish diets, had appeared on horseback in the field
 of election.","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Polish', 'NORP')"
"The
 fiercest of the Saxon idolaters escaped from the Christian
 tyrant to their brethren of the North; the Ocean and
 Mediterranean were covered with their piratical fleets; and
 Charlemagne beheld with a sigh the destructive progress of
 the Normans, who, in less than seventy years, precipitated
 the fall of his race and monarchy.","('Saxon', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('Ocean', 'LOC'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('less than seventy years', 'DATE')"
"The
 first hostilities of Leo were directed against a lofty
 Christ on the vestibule, and above the gate, of the palace.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Leo', 'PERSON')"
"The
 golden bull, which fixes the Germanic constitution, is
 promulgated in the style of a sovereign and legislator.","('Germanic', 'NORP')"
"The
 grammar and logic, the music and astronomy, of the times,
 were only cultivated as the handmaids of superstition; but
 the curiosity of the human mind must ultimately tend to its
 improvement, and the encouragement of learning reflects the
 purest and most pleasing lustre on the character of
 Charlemagne. (103)","('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('103', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 leaders of a powerful nation would have disdained a servile
 title and subordinate office; but the reign of the Greek
 emperors was suspended; and, in the vacancy of the empire,
 they derived a more glorious commission from the pope and
 the republic.","('Greek', 'NORP')"
"The
 legislative authority was inherent in the general assembly;
 but the executive powers were intrusted to three consuls,
 annually chosen from the three orders of captains,
 valvassors, (144) and commons, into which the republic was divided.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('144', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 obstinate cities were reduced by the terror or the force of
 his arms: his captives were delivered to the executioner, or
 shot from his military engines; and. after the siege and
 surrender of Milan, the buildings of that stately capital
 were razed to the ground, three hundred hostages were sent
 into Germany, and the inhabitants were dispersed in four
 villages, under the yoke of the inflexible conqueror. (147)","('Milan', 'GPE'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('147', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 servitude of the Jews might curb their zeal, and depreciate
 their authority; but the triumphant Mussulmans, who reigned
 at Damascus, and threatened Constantinople, cast into the
 scale of reproach the accumulated weight of truth and
 victory.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Mussulmans', 'PERSON'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The
 strangers retreated to their ships, but the populous
 sea-coast poured forth a multitude of boats; the waters of
