Sentence,Entities
"(111)
Privileges of the Romans of Gaul.","('111', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
(2),"('2', 'CARDINAL')"
(53),"('53', 'CARDINAL')"
(72),"('72', 'CARDINAL')"
"A Greek historian of that age has 
 praised the private and public virtues of the Franks, with a
 partial enthusiasm which cannot be sufficiently justified by
 their domestic annals. (61)","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"A bloody and complete
 victory has sometimes yielded no more than the possession of
 the field; and the loss of ten thousand men has sometimes
 been sufficient to destroy, in a single day, the work of
 ages.","('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('a single day', 'DATE')"
"A crowd of impatient
 warriors, presumptuous in their strength, and disdaining to
 fly before the robbers of Germany, excited Alaric to assert
 in arms the name and blood of the conqueror of Rome.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"A devouring host of one hundred and twenty thousand Germans
 had formerly passed the Rhine under the command of
 Ariovistus.","('one hundred and twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Ariovistus', 'PRODUCT')"
"A large portion of their lands was exacted for
 the use of the Franks: but they enjoyed the remainder exempt
 from tribute; (112) and the same irresistible violence which 
 swept away the arts and manufactures of Gaul destroyed the
 elaborate and expensive system of Imperial despotism.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('112', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"A long siege and an artful negotiation
 admonished the king of the Franks of the danger and
 difficulty of his enterprise.","('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"A monk, who in the profound ignorance of human life has
 presumed to exercise the office of historian, strangely
 disfigures the state of Britain at the time of its
 separation from the Western empire.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"A province, improved and adorned by the arts
 of Rome, was again reduced to a savage wilderness, and some
 vestige of the stately Vindonissa may still be discovered in
 the fertile and populous valley of the Aar. (23)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Vindonissa', 'GPE'), ('23', 'CARDINAL')"
"A select band of noble youths, the sons of the
 principal senators, was delivered to the conqueror as the hostages of the faith of Childebert and of their countrymen.","('Childebert', 'PERSON')"
"A sufficient number of Latin or Celtic words
 might be assumed by the Germans to express their new wants
 and ideas; (144) but those illiterate Pagans preserved and established the use of their national dialect. (145)","('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Celtic', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('144', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pagans', 'NORP'), ('145', 'CARDINAL')"
"A vain conference
 was agitated between the two factions.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"About forty years after the dissolution of the Roman
 government Vortigern appears to have obtained the supreme,
 though precarious, command of the princes and cities of
 Britain.","('About forty years', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Vortigern', 'PERSON'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"According to the maxims of ancient war, the conqueror became
 the lawful master of the enemy whom he had subdued and
 spared: (96) and the fruitful cause of personal slavery, which 
 had been almost suppressed by the peaceful sovereignty of
 Rome, was again revived and multiplied by the perpetual
 hostilities of the independent barbarians.","('96', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"According to the most rational account, he
 defeated, in twelve successive battles, the Angles of the
 North and the Saxons of the West; but the declining age of
 the hero was embittered by popular ingratitude and domestic
 misfortunes.","('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Angles of the\r\n North', 'PERSON'), ('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"According to the weight of the charge this legal
 number of 'compurgators' was multiplied: seventy-two voices
 were required to absolve an incendiary or assassin; and when
 the chastity of a queen of France was suspected, three
 hundred gallant nobles swore, without hesitation, that the
 infant prince had been actually begotten by her deceased
 husband. (78)","('seventy-two', 'CARDINAL'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('three\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"After Clovis had passed the
 ford, as it is still named, of the Hart, he advanced with
 bold and hasty steps to prevent the escape of the enemy.","('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Hart', 'PERSON')"
"After a painful search he was discovered in this unworthy occupation, by the emissaries of his grandfather, Gregory bishop of Langres; but his offers of ransom were sternly rejected by the avarice of the barbarian, who required an exorbitant sum of ten pounds of gold for the freedom of his noble captive.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Langres', 'PERSON'), ('ten pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"After a war of an hundred years the independent Britons
 still occupied the whole extent of the western coast, from
 the wall of Antoninus to the extreme promontory of Cornwall;
 and the principal cities of the inland country still opposed
 the arms of the barbarians.","('an hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Britons', 'NORP'), ('Antoninus', 'GPE'), ('Cornwall', 'GPE')"
"After each successful battle or expedition the
 spoils were accumulated in one common mass; every warrior
 received his proportionable share, and the royal prerogative
 submitted to the equal regulations of military law.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"After his restoration
 Bafina escaped from her husband's bed to the arms of her
 lover, freely declaring that, if she had known a man wiser,
 stronger, or more beautiful than Childeric, that man should
 have been the object of her preference.","('Bafina', 'PERSON'), ('Childeric', 'PERSON')"
"After the
 conversion of Recared had removed the prejudices of the
 catholics, the coasts both of the Ocean and Mediterranean
 were still possessed by the Eastern emperors, who secretly
 excited a discontented people to reject the yoke of the
 barbarians, and to assert the name and dignity of Roman
 citizens.","('Recared', 'PERSON'), ('Ocean', 'LOC'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"After the baptism
 of Clovis, he reformed several articles that appeared
 incompatible with Christianity: the Salic law was again
 amended by his sons; and at length, under the reign of
 Dagobert, the code was revised and promulgated in its actual
 form, one hundred years after the establishment of the
 French monarchy.","('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Salic', 'PERSON'), ('Dagobert', 'PERSON'), ('one hundred years', 'DATE'), ('French', 'NORP')"
"After the conquest of Gaul they still
 delighted in the rustic simplicity of their ancestors; the
 cities were abandoned to solitude and decay; and their
 coins, their charters, and their synods, are still inscribed
 with the names of the villas or rural palaces in which they
 successively resided.","('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"After the conquest of the
 Western provinces, the Franks alone maintained their ancient
 habitations beyond the Rhine.","('Western', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"After the destruction of the principal churches, the bishops
 who had declined the crown of martyrdom retired with the
 holy relics into Wales and Armorica; the remains of their
 flocks were left destitute of any spiritual food; the
 practice, and even the remembrance, of Christianity were
 abolished; and the British clergy might obtain some comfort
 from the damnation of the idolatrous strangers.","('Wales', 'GPE'), ('Armorica', 'GPE'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('British', 'NORP')"
"After the event of an unsuccessful battle, Sigismond, who
 wished to protract his life that he might prolong his
 penance, concealed himself in the desert in a religious
 habit till he was discovered and betrayed by his subjects,
 who solicited the favour of their new masters.","('Sigismond', 'PERSON')"
"After the loss of a
 battle, the captive Radiger implored the mercy of his
 victorious bride, who generously pardoned his offence,
 dismissed her rival, and compelled the king of the Varni to
 discharge with honour and fidelity the duties of a husband.","('Radiger', 'PERSON'), ('Varni', 'PERSON')"
"After the patient expectation of a whole year, he cautiously whispered his design to Attalus, and exhorted him to prepare for flight in the ensuing night.","('a whole year', 'DATE'), ('Attalus', 'PERSON'), ('the ensuing night', 'TIME')"
"After the success of the Gothic war, Clovis accepted the
 honours of the Roman consulship.","('the Gothic war', 'EVENT'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"After their conversion from idolatry or heresy, the Franks
 and the Visigoths were disposed to embrace, with equal
 submission, the inherent evils and the accidental benefits
 of superstition.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP')"
"After this dream of fancy, we read with
 astonishment that the name of this island is 'Brittia'; that
 it lies in the ocean, against the mouth of the Rhine, and
 less than thirty miles from the continent; that it is
 possessed by three nations, the Frisians, the Angles, and
 the Britons; and that some Angles had appeared at
 Constantinople in the train of the French ambassadors.","('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('less than thirty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Frisians', 'NORP'), ('Angles', 'NORP'), ('Britons', 'NORP'), ('Angles', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('French', 'NORP')"
"Alaric had left behind him an infant
 son, a bastard competitor, factious nobles and a disloyal
 people and the remaining forces of the Goths were oppressed
 by the general consternation, or opposed to each other in
 civil discord","('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"All the
 subjects of the empire, who, by the use of the Latin
 language, more particularly deserved the name and privileges
 of Romans, were oppressed by the disgrace and calamities of
 foreign conquest; and the victorious nations of Germany
 established a new system of manners and government in the
 western countries of Europe.","('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"Almost 
 every name, conspicuous either in the church or state,
 reveals its Teutonic origin; (146) and the geography of 
 England was universally inscribed with foreign characters
 and appellations.","('Teutonic', 'NORP'), ('146', 'CARDINAL'), ('England', 'GPE')"
"Ambrosius
 Aurelian was descended from a noble family of Romans; (138) 
 his modesty was equal to his valour, and his valour, till
 the last fatal action, (139) was crowned with splendid 
 success.","('Ambrosius\r\n Aurelian', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('138', 'CARDINAL'), ('139', 'CARDINAL')"
"An
 impartial stranger, instructed by their discoveries, their
 disputes, and even their faults, may describe, from the same
 original materials, the state of the Roman provincials,
 after Gaul had submitted to the arms and laws of the
 Merovingian kings. (64)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('64', 'CARDINAL')"
Anarchy of the Franks.,"('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"Another detachment penetrated as far as Brivas, or Brioude, where the inhabitants, with their valuable effects, had taken refuge in the sanctuary of St. Julian.","('Brivas', 'NORP'), ('Brioude', 'LOC'), ('St. Julian', 'LOC')"
"Arles and
 Marseilles surrendered to his arms: he oppressed the freedom
 of Auvergne, and the bishop condescended to purchase his
 recall from exile by a tribute of just but reluctant praise.","('Arles', 'PERSON'), ('Marseilles', 'GPE'), ('Auvergne', 'GPE')"
"As a Roman, he had been educated in the liberal 
 studies of rhetoric and jurisprudence; but he was engaged by
 accident and policy in the familiar use of the Germanic
 idiom.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Germanic', 'NORP')"
"As long as the Visigoths themselves were
 satisfied with the rude customs of their ancestors, they
 indulged their subjects of Aquitain and Spain in the
 enjoyment of the Roman law.","('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Aquitain', 'PERSON'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"As soon as Odoacer had extinguished the Western empire, he
 sought the friendship of the most powerful of the
 barbarians.","('Odoacer', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"As the common 
 offspring of Troy, they claimed a fraternal alliance with
 the Romans; (101) and if each province had imitated the 
 courage and loyalty of Auvergne, the fall of the Western
 empire might have been prevented or delayed.","('Troy', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('101', 'CARDINAL'), ('Auvergne', 'GPE'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"As the manners
 of the Franks became less ferocious, their laws were
 rendered more severe; and the Merovingian kings attempted to
 imitate the impartial rigour of the Visigoths and
 Burgundians. (75)","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('Visigoths', 'PERSON'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"As they lay concealed in a dark thicket, they heard the noise of horses; they were terrified by the angry countenance of their master, and they anxiously listened to his declaration that, if he could seize the guilty fugitives, one of them he would cut in pieces with his sword, and would expose the other on a gibbet.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"At Bordeaux, which had submitted without resistance, Clovis established his winter quarters and his
 prudent economy transported from Toulouse the royal
 treasures, which were deposited in the capital of the
 monarchy.","('Bordeaux', 'GPE'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('winter', 'DATE'), ('Toulouse', 'GPE')"
"At Paris, which he already
 considered as his royal seat, Clovis declared to an assembly
 of the princes and warriors the pretence and the motive of a
 Gothic war.","('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"At a distance from their sovereign the
 barbarians might indeed be tempted to exercise such
 arbitrary depredation; but the firm and artful policy of
 Clovis must curb a licentious spirit which would aggravate
 the misery of the vanquished whilst it corrupted the union
 and discipline of the conquerors.","('Clovis', 'GPE')"
"At length Attalus and his faithful Leo reached the friendly habitation of a presbyter of Rheims, who recruited their fainting strength with bread and wine, concealed them from the search of their enemy, and safely conducted them beyond the limits of the Austrasian kingdom to the episcopal palace of Langres.","('Attalus', 'PERSON'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Rheims', 'NORP'), ('Austrasian', 'NORP'), ('Langres', 'GPE')"
"At length the eye of 
 criticism and philosophy was directed to the antiquities of
 France but even philosophers have been tainted by the
 contagion of prejudice and passion.","('France', 'GPE')"
"At length the light of science and
 reason was rekindled; the talisman was broken; the visionary
 fabric melted into air; and by a natural, though unjust,
 reverse of the public opinion, the severity of the present
 age is inclined to question the existence of Arthur. (141)
Desolation of Britain.","('Arthur', 'PERSON'), ('141', 'CARDINAL'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"At that
 unhappy period the Saxons fiercely struggled with the
 natives for the possession of Britain: Gaul and Spain were
 divided between the powerful monarchies of the Franks and
 Visigoths and the dependent kingdoms of the Suevi and
 Burgundians: Africa was exposed to the cruel persecution of
 the Vandals and the savage insults of the Moors: Rome and
 Italy, as far as the banks of the Danube, were afflicted by
 an army of barbarian mercenaries, whose lawless tyranny was
 succeeded by the reign of Theodoric the Ostrogoth.","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Suevi', 'NORP'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Moors', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Theodoric the Ostrogoth', 'PERSON')"
"At the annual 
 review of the month of March their arms were diligently
 inspected, and when they traversed a peaceful territory they
 were prohibited from touching a blade of grass.","('annual', 'DATE'), ('the month of March', 'DATE')"
"At the distance of five hundred years the Visigoths 
 and Burgundians, who revenged the defeat of Ariovistus,
 usurped the same unequal proportion of two-thirds of the
 subject lands.","('five hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Ariovistus', 'NORP'), ('two-thirds', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the end of ten centuries the reign of legal violence was not totally extinguished; and the ineffectual censures of saints, of popes, and of synods, may seem to prove that the influence of superstition is weakened by its unnatural alliance with reason and humanity","('the end of ten centuries', 'DATE')"
"At the hour of midnight the intemperate guests retired from table, and the Frank's son-in-law, whom Leo attended to his apartment with a nocturnal potation, condescended to jest on the facility with which he might betray his trust.","('the hour of midnight', 'TIME'), ('Frank', 'PERSON'), ('Leo', 'PERSON')"
"At the sound of his
 trumpets the walls of the city imitated the example of
 Jericho, and instantly fell to the ground; a splendid
 miracle, which may be reduced to the supposition that some
 clerical engineers had secretly undermined the foundations
 of the rampart.","('Jericho', 'GPE')"
"At the third hour
 of the day, about ten miles beyond Poitiers, Clovis
 overtook, and instantly attacked, the Gothic army, whose
 defeat was already prepared by terror and confusion.","('the third hour\r\n of the day', 'TIME'), ('about ten miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Poitiers', 'GPE'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"Auvergne had formerly maintained a just pre-eminence
 among the independent states and cities of Gaul.","('Auvergne', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'GPE')"
"Before the Austrasian army retreated from Auvergne, Theodoric exacted some pledges of the future loyalty of a people whose just hatred could be restrained only by their fear.","('Austrasian', 'NORP'), ('Auvergne, Theodoric', 'GPE')"
"Before the election of the Merovingian 
 kings, the most powerful tribe, or nation, of the Franks,
 appointed four venerable chieftains to compose the Salic
 laws; (66) and their labours were examined and approved in 
 three successive assemblies of the people.","('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Salic', 'ORG'), ('66', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"Besides these royal and beneficiary estates, a large
 proportion had been assigned, in the division of Gaul, of
 allodial and Salic lands: they were exempt from tribute, and
 the Salic lands were equally shared among the male
 descendants of the Franks. (91)","('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Salic', 'LOC'), ('Salic', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"Beyond the Severn the Britons still asserted
 their national freedom, which survived the heptarchy, and
 even the monarchy of the Saxons.","('Severn', 'LOC'), ('Britons', 'NORP'), ('Saxons', 'NORP')"
"But
 the careless barbarians, secure of their personal
 independence, disdained the labour of government: the annual
 assemblies of the month of March were silently abolished,
 and the nation was separated and almost dissolved by the
 conquest of Gaul. (120)","('the month of March', 'DATE'), ('Gaul.', 'GPE'), ('120', 'CARDINAL')"
"But earth as well as heaven rejoiced in the
 conversion of the Franks.","('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"But every British name is effaced by the
 illustrious name of ARTHUR, (140) the hereditary prince of the 
 Silures, in South Wales and the elective king or general of
 the nation.","('British', 'NORP'), ('140', 'CARDINAL'), ('Silures', 'NORP'), ('South Wales', 'GPE')"
"But in the loose society
 of the Germans, revenge was always honourable, and often
 meritorious: the independent warrior chastised, or
 vindicated, with his own hand, the injuries which he had
 offered or received; and he had only to dread the resentment
 of the sons and kinsmen of the enemy whom he had sacrificed
 to his selfish or angry passions.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"But on the morning of the fourth day the doors
 were thrown open for the entrance of the great officers of
 the palace, the dukes and counts of the provinces, the
 judges of the cities, and the Gothic nobles; and the decrees
 of Heaven were ratified by the consent of the people.","('the morning of the fourth day', 'TIME'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"But such an artificial scheme of policy is repugnant to the
 rude and turbulent spirit of the Saxons: their laws are
 silent, and their imperfect annals afford only a dark and
 bloody prospect of intestine discord. (131)","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('131', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the
 national strength was increased by these powerful and
 voluntary accessions; and the neighbouring kingdoms dreaded
 the numbers as well as the spirit of the Franks.","('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"But the
 strength of the Roman government could not always guard the
 maritime province against the pirates of Germany: the
 independent and divided states were exposed to their
 attacks, and the Saxons might sometimes join the Scots and
 the Picts in a tacit or express confederacy of rapine and
 destruction.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Scots', 'NORP'), ('Picts', 'NORP')"
"But the
 subjects of the Merovingian kings might alienate their
 personal freedom; and this act of legal suicide, which was
 familiarly practised, is expressed in terms most disgraceful
 and afflicting to the dignity of human nature. (99)","('Merovingian', 'NORP')"
"But the 
 courage and numbers of the Gallic youth were long since
 exhausted, and the loose bands of volunteers or mercenaries
 who marched under the standard of Syagrius were incapable of
 contending with the national valour of the Franks.","('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Syagrius', 'ORG'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"But the Franks of
 Austrasia soon yielded to the persuasive eloquence of their
 king.","('the Franks of\r\n Austrasia', 'ORG')"
"But the Germans, who obeyed in peace the
 hereditary jurisdiction of their chiefs, were free to follow
 the standard of a popular and victorious general; and the
 superior merit of Clovis attracted the respect and
 allegiance of the national confederacy.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON')"
"But the Roman captives who were destitute of art, but
 capable of labour, were condemned, without regard to their
 former rank, to tend the cattle and cultivate the lands of
 the barbarians.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But the Romans were disposed to revere, in
 the person of their master, that antique title which the
 emperors condescended to assume: the barbarian himself
 seemed to contract a sacred obligation to respect the
 majesty of the republic; and the successors of Theodosius,
 by soliciting his friendship, tacitly forgave, and almost
 ratified, the usurpation of Gaul.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"But the Visigoths were protected by
 the wise and powerful monarch of Italy.","('Visigoths', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"But the battle was restored by the valour, the
 conduct, and perhaps by the piety, of Clovis; and the event
 of the bloody day decided for ever the alternative of empire
 or servitude.","('Clovis', 'PERSON')"
"But the national inequality established by the
 Franks in their criminal proceedings was the last insult and
 abuse of conquest.","('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"But the prelates of France, long before the
 extinction of the Merovingian race, had degenerated into
 fighting and hunting barbarians.","('France', 'GPE'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP')"
"But the sagacious monarch dreaded the rising empire of Clovis, and he was firmly engaged to support the national and religious cause of the Goths.","('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"But the savage 
 conqueror of Gaul was incapable of examining the proofs of a
 religion which depends on the laborious investigation of
 historic evidence and speculative theology.","('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"But their conquest of Gaul was followed by
 ten centuries of anarchy and ignorance.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('ten centuries', 'DATE')"
"But their retreat was intercepted,
 and their communication was impracticable: they were
 abandoned by the Greek princes of Constantinople, and they
 piously disclaimed all connection with the Arian usurpers of
 Gaul.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
But this act of impiety was severely chastised by the devout son of Clovis,"('Clovis', 'PERSON')"
"But this dependent tenure was gradually abolished (89) by the 
 independent and rapacious nobles of France, who established
 the perpetual property and hereditary succession of their
 benefices; a revolution salutary to the earth, which had
 been injured or neglected by its precarious masters. (90)","('France', 'GPE'), ('90', 'CARDINAL')"
"By such prevailing arguments, the absurd and cruel practice of judicial duels, which had been peculiar to some tribes of Germany, was propagated and established in all the monarchies of Europe, from Sicily to the Baltic.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Baltic', 'LOC')"
By the execution of this promise Theodoric justly forfeited the allegiance of a people whom he devoted to destruction.,"('Theodoric', 'PERSON')"
"By the revolution of Britain the limits of science as well
 as of empire were contracted.","('Britain', 'GPE')"
"Childebert enjoyed this clandestine victory;
 and the free subjects of Theodoric threatened to desert his
 standard if he indulged his private resentment while the
 nation was engaged in the Burgundian war.","('Childebert', 'PERSON'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('the Burgundian war', 'EVENT')"
"Christianity was 
 still professed in the mountains of Wales; but the rude
 schismatics, in the form of the clerical tonsure, and in the
 day of the celebration of Easter, obstinately resisted the
 imperious mandates of the Roman pontiffs.","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Wales', 'LOC'), ('Easter', 'EVENT'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Clovis encountered
 the invaders of Gaul in the plain of Tolbiac, about
 twenty-four miles from Cologne, and the two fiercest nations
 of Germany were mutually animated by the memory of past
 exploits and the prospect of future greatness.","('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Tolbiac', 'GPE'), ('about\r\n twenty-four miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Cologne', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"Clovis no longer possessed those advantages which had
 assured the success of the preceding war; and his rival,
 instructed by adversity, had found new resources in the
 affections of his people.","('Clovis', 'PERSON')"
"Clovis was the 
 offspring of this voluntary union, and when he was no more
 than fifteen years of age he succeeded, by his father's
 death, to the command of the Salian tribe.","('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('no more\r\n than fifteen years of age', 'DATE'), ('Salian', 'NORP')"
"Clovis, king of the Franks, A.D. 481-511.","('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('511', 'CARDINAL')"
"Conversion of Clovis, A.D. 496.","('Clovis', 'GPE'), ('496', 'CARDINAL')"
"Defeat and submission of the Alemanni, A.D. 496.","('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('496', 'CARDINAL')"
"Delay must be always dangerous
 to barbarians, who consume the country through which they
 march; and had Clovis possessed leisure and materials, it
 might have been impracticable to construct a bridge, or to
 force a passage, in the face of a superior enemy.","('Clovis', 'PERSON')"
"Descent of the Saxons, A.D. 449.","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('449', 'CARDINAL')"
Division of the lands by the Barbarians.,"('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"During a period
 of five hundred years the tradition of his exploits was
 preserved, and rudely embellished, by the obscure bards of
 Wales and Armorica, who were odious to the Saxons, and
 unknown to the rest of mankind.","('five hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Wales', 'GPE'), ('Armorica', 'PERSON'), ('Saxons', 'NORP')"
"During the first three days of the convocation, as long as
 they agitated the ecclesiastical questions of doctrine and
 discipline, the profane laity was excluded from their
 debates, which were conducted, however, with decent
 solemnity.","('the first three days', 'DATE')"
"Each in his turn is
 summoned, at the hour of midnight, to hear the voices, and
 even the names, of the ghosts: he is sensible of their
 weight, and he feels himself impelled by an unknown, but
 irresistible, power.","('the hour of midnight', 'TIME')"
"Each intrepid chieftain, according to the measure of
 his fame and fortunes, assembled his followers; equipped a
 fleet of three, or perhaps of sixty, vessels; chose the
 place of the attack, and conducted his subsequent operations
 according to the events of the war and the dictates of his
 private interest.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('sixty', 'CARDINAL')"
Establishment of the French Monarchy in Gaul—Laws of the Barbarians—,"('French', 'NORP'), ('Gaul—Laws of the Barbarians', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Euric was the first
 of the Gothic princes who expressed in writing the manners
 and customs of his people; and the composition of the
 Burgundian laws was a measure of policy rather than of
 justice, to alleviate the yoke and regain the affections of
 their Gallic subjects. (68)","('Euric', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Burgundian', 'NORP'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('68', 'CARDINAL')"
"Every
 nation embraced and adorned the popular romance of Arthur
 and the Knights of the Round Table: their names were
 celebrated in Greece and Italy; and the voluminous tales of
 Sir Lancelot and Sir Tristram were devoutly studied by the
 princes and nobles who disregarded the genuine heroes and
 historians of antiquity.","('Arthur\r\n and the Knights of the Round Table', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Lancelot', 'PERSON'), ('Tristram', 'PERSON')"
Example of Auvergne.,"('Auvergne', 'GPE')"
"Fairies and giants,
 flying dragons and enchanted palaces, were blended with the
 more simple fictions of the West; and the fate of Britain
 depended on the art, or the predictions, of Merlin.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Merlin', 'PERSON')"
Fall of the Roman empire in the West.,"('Roman', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"Final conquest of Burgundy, by the Franks, A.D. 532.","('Burgundy', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('532', 'CARDINAL')"
"Final establishment of the French monarchy in Gaul, A.D. 536.","('French', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('536', 'CARDINAL')"
"From
 these ambassadors Procopius might be informed of a singular,
 though not improbable, adventure, which announces the
 spirit, rather than the delicacy, of an English heroine.","('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('English', 'LANGUAGE')"
"From that era they enjoyed the right of celebrating at 
 Arles the games of the circus; and by a singular privilege,
 which was denied even to the Persian monarch, the gold coin,
 impressed with their name and image, obtained a legal
 currency in the empire. (60)","('Arles', 'GPE'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"From the 
 source of the Rhine to its conflux with the Main and the
 Moselle, the formidable swarms of the Alemanni commanded
 either side of the river by the right of ancient possession
 or recent victory.","('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Main', 'FAC'), ('Moselle', 'PRODUCT'), ('Alemanni', 'NORP')"
"From the monarchy of the Goths, which soon involved the Suevic kingdom of Gallicia, the modern Spaniards still derive some national vanity, but the historian of the Roman empire is neither invited nor compelled to pursue the obscure and barren series of their annals. (122)","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Suevic', 'NORP'), ('Gallicia', 'GPE'), ('Spaniards', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('122', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the reign of Clovis, during
 five successive centuries, the laws and manners of Gaul
 uniformly tended to promote the increase, and to confirm the
 duration, of personal servitude.","('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('five successive centuries', 'DATE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"From the reign of Recared, the
 first catholic king, to that of Witiza, the immediate
 predecessor of the unfortunate Roderic, sixteen national
 councils were successively convened.","('Recared', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Witiza', 'PERSON'), ('Roderic', 'PERSON'), ('sixteen', 'CARDINAL')"
"From thence he proceeded on
 horseback to the cathedral of Tours; and, as he passed
 through the streets, profusely scattered, with his own hand,
 a donative of gold and silver to the joyful multitude, who
 incessantly repeated their acclamations of Consul and
 Augustus.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"Gaul was again overspread with woods; and the animals, who
 were reserved for the use or pleasure of the lord, might
 ravage with impunity the fields of his industrious vassals.","('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"Gildas (132) describes in 
 florid language the improvements of agriculture, the foreign
 trade which flowed with every tide into the Thames and the
 Severn, the solid and lofty construction of public and
 private edifices: he accuses the sinful luxury of the
 British people; of a people, according to the same writer,
 ignorant of the most simple arts, and incapable, without the
 aid of the Romans, of providing walls of stone or weapons of
 iron for the defence of their native land. (133)","('Gildas', 'PERSON'), ('132', 'CARDINAL'), ('Thames', 'LOC'), ('Severn', 'LOC'), ('British', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('133', 'CARDINAL')"
"Goths were intimidated by the menaces of 
 Clovis: and the Roman king, after a short confinement, was
 delivered into the hands of the executioner.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Gregory embraced his grandson with tears of joy, gratefully delivered Leo with his whole family from the yoke of servitude, and bestowed on him the property of a farm, where he might end his days in happiness and freedom.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Leo', 'PERSON')"
"Gregory of Tours (110) was born about sixty years after the death of Sidonius Apollinaris; and their situation was almost similar, since each of them was a native of Auvergne, a senator, and a bishop.","('Gregory of Tours', 'PERSON'), ('110', 'CARDINAL'), ('about sixty years', 'DATE'), ('Sidonius Apollinaris', 'PERSON'), ('Auvergne', 'GPE')"
"He celebrates their politeness and 
 urbanity, their regular government, and orthodox religion;
 and boldly asserts that these barbarians could be
 distinguished only by their dress and language from the
 subjects of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"He consented (perhaps such terms had been
 previously stipulated) to the baptism of his eldest on; and
 though the sudden death of the infant excited some
 superstitious fears, he was persuaded a second time to
 repeat the dangerous experiment.","('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"He distrusted the strength of Dijon, a quadrangular
 fortress, encompassed by two rivers and by a wall thirty
 feet high and fifteen thick, with four gates and
 thirty-three towers: (40) he abandoned to the pursuit of 
 Clovis the important cities of Lyons and Vienne, and
 Gundobald still fled with precipitation till he had reached
 Avignon, at the distance of two hundred and fifty miles from
 the field of battle.","('Dijon', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirty\r\n feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('fifteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirty-three', 'CARDINAL'), ('40', 'CARDINAL'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Lyons', 'GPE'), ('Vienne', 'PERSON'), ('Gundobald', 'PERSON'), ('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('two hundred and fifty miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"He imposed a tribute on the
 Burgundian prince, compelled him to pardon and reward his
 brother's treachery, and proudly returned to his own
 dominions with the spoils and captives of the southern
 provinces.","('Burgundian', 'NORP')"
"He marched
 from Paris, and as he proceeded with decent reverence
 through the holy diocese of Tours, his anxiety tempted him
 to consult the shrine of St Martin, the sanctuary, and the
 oracle of Gaul.","('Paris', 'GPE'), ('St Martin', 'FAC'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"He punished with death the most atrocious offenders; left their secret accomplices to the vengeance of St. Julian; released the captives; restored the plunder; and extended the rights of sanctuary five miles round the sepulchre of the holy martyr. (106)
Story of Attalus.","('St. Julian', 'PERSON'), ('five miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('106', 'CARDINAL'), ('Story of Attalus', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"He released them at once from spiritual and temporal
 bond-age; and two hundred and fifty slaves of both sexes
 were baptised by their indulgent master.","('two hundred and fifty', 'CARDINAL')"
"He was intercepted in the career of
 victory, since he died in the forty-fifth year of his age:
 but he had already accomplished, in a reign of thirty years,
 the establishment of the French monarchy in Gaul.","('forty-fifth year', 'DATE'), ('thirty years', 'DATE'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"He was still
 more incapable of feeling the mild influence of the Gospel,
 which persuades and purifies the heart of a genuine convert.","('Gospel', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Hengist and Horsa, as they ranged along
 the eastern coast with three ships, were engaged by the
 promise of an ample stipend to embrace the defence of
 Britain, and their intrepid valour soon delivered the
 country from the Caledonian invaders.","('Hengist', 'PERSON'), ('Horsa', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Caledonian', 'NORP')"
"Hengist might hope to achieve the conquest
 of Britain; but his ambition, in an active reign of
 thirty-five years, was confined to the possession of Kent;
 and the numerous colony which he had planted in the North
 was extirpated by the sword of the Britons.","('Hengist', 'PERSON'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('thirty-five years', 'DATE'), ('Kent', 'PERSON'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('Britons', 'NORP')"
"Hengist, who boldly aspired to the conquest of Britain,
 exhorted his countrymen to embrace the glorious opportunity:
 he painted in lively colours the fertility of the soil, the
 wealth of the cities, the pusillanimous temper of the
 natives, and the convenient situation of a spacious solitary
 island, accessible on all sides to the Saxon fleets.","('Hengist', 'PERSON'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Saxon', 'NORP')"
"Her warlike subjects
 are said to have been ignorant of the use, and even of the
 form, of a horse; but she boldly sailed from Britain to the
 mouth of the Rhine, with a fleet of four hundred ships and
 an army of one hundred thousand men.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('four hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"His
 nocturnal march was directed by a flaming meteor suspended
 in the air above the cathedral of Poitiers; and this signal,
 which might be previously concerted with the orthodox
 successor of St. Hilary, was compared to the column of fire
 that guided the Israelites in the desert.","('Poitiers', 'GPE'), ('St. Hilary', 'GPE'), ('Israelites', 'NORP')"
"His
 visible or invisible aid promoted the cause of a liberal and
 orthodox prince; and the profane remark of Clovis himself,
 that St. Martin was an expensive friend, (33) need not be 
 interpreted as the symptom of any permanent or rational
 scepticism.","('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('St. Martin', 'PERSON'), ('33', 'CARDINAL')"
"His Victories over the Alemanni, Burgundians, and Visigoths—","('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP')"
"His ambassadors are despatched by
 the gravest historians to the coast of Germany: they address
 a pathetic oration to the general assembly of the Saxons,
 and those warlike barbarians resolve to assist with a fleet
 and army the suppliants of a distant and unknown island.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Saxons', 'NORP')"
"His ambitious reign was a perpetual violation of moral and
 Christian duties: his hands were stained with blood in peace
 as well as in war; and, as soon as Clovis had dismissed a
 synod of the Gallician church, he calmly assassinated all
 the princes of the Merovingian race. (32)","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Gallician', 'NORP'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('32', 'CARDINAL')"
"His deliverance was effected by the hardy stratagem of Leo, a slave belonging to the kitchens of the bishop of Langres. (108)","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Langres', 'ORG'), ('108', 'CARDINAL')"
"His disbelief, or 
 rather disregard of Christianity, might encourage him to
 pillage with less remorse the churches of an hostile
 territory: but his subjects of Gaul enjoyed the free
 exercise of religious worship, and the bishops entertained a
 more favourable hope of the idolater than of the heretics.","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"His messengers were instructed to remark the
 words of the Psalm which should happen to be chanted at the
 precise moment when they entered the church.","('Psalm', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"His prayer
 was heard: the avengers were at hand; and the provinces of
 Burgundy were overwhelmed by an army of victorious Franks.","('Burgundy', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"His romance, transcribed in the Latin of
 Jeffrey of Monmouth, and afterwards translated into the
 fashionable idiom of the times, was enriched with the
 various, though incoherent, ornaments which were familiar to
 the experience, the learning, or the fancy of the twelfth
 century.","('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('of\r\n Jeffrey of Monmouth', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('the twelfth\r\n century', 'DATE')"
"His savage character and the virtues of Henry
 IV.","('Henry\r\n IV', 'PERSON')"
"His troops, reinforced by the fiercest barbarians of Germany, (104) spread desolation over the fruitful face of Auvergne; and two places only, a strong castle and a holy shrine, were saved or redeemed from their licentious fury.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('104', 'CARDINAL'), ('Auvergne', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"His trophies were decorated with captive provinces
 and Imperial titles; and his Danish victories avenged the
 recent injuries of his country.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Danish', 'NORP')"
"His victory of Syagrius, A.D. 486.","('Syagrius', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 486', 'DATE')"
"I
 shall not attempt to enumerate the generals and magistrates
 whose names (113) attest the liberal policy of the 
 Merovingians.","('113', 'CARDINAL'), ('Merovingians', 'NORP')"
"I am impatient to pursue the final ruin of that kingdom,
 which was accomplished under the reign of Sigismond, the son
 of Gundobald.","('Sigismond', 'PERSON'), ('Gundobald', 'PERSON')"
I have anticipated in the preceding chapter the most important of their ecclesiastical events — the fall of Arianism and the persecution of the Jews: and it only remains to observe some interesting circumstances which relate to the civil and ecclesiastical constitution of the Spanish kingdom.,"('Arianism', 'NORP'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Spanish', 'NORP')"
"I have now accomplished the laborious narrative of the
 decline and fall of the Roman empire, from the fortunate age
 of Trajan and the Antonines to its total extinction in the
 West, about five centuries after the Christian era.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Trajan', 'LOC'), ('Antonines', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('about five centuries', 'DATE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"If
 Britain had indeed been unknown to the Saxons, the measure
 of its calamities would have been less complete.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Saxons', 'NORP')"
"In Wales and Armorica,
 the Celtic tongue, the native idiom of the West, was
 preserved and propagated; and the Bards, who had been the
 companions of the Druids, were still protected, in the
 sixteenth century, by the laws of Elizabeth.","('Wales', 'GPE'), ('Armorica', 'GPE'), ('Celtic', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Bards', 'PERSON'), ('Druids', 'NORP'), ('the\r\n sixteenth century', 'DATE'), ('Elizabeth', 'PERSON')"
"In a century of perpetual, or at least implacable, war, much
 courage, and some skill, must have been exerted for the
 defence of Britain.","('a century', 'DATE'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"In all his transactions with mankind he calculated the
 weight of interest, of passion, and of opinion; and his
 measures were sometimes adapted to the sanguinary manners of
 the Germans, and sometimes moderated by the milder genius of
 Rome and Christianity.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Christianity', 'NORP')"
"In all temporal affairs the 
 Theodosian Code was the universal law of the clergy; but the
 barbaric jurisprudence had liberally provided for their
 personal safety: a subdeacon was equivalent to two Franks;
 the antrustion and priest were held in similar estimation;
 and the life of a bishop was appreciated far above the
 common standard, at the price of nine hundred pieces of
 gold.","('the \r\n Theodosian Code', 'LAW'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('nine hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"In every religion the Deity has been
 invoked to confirm the truth, or to punish the falsehood, of
 human testimony; but this powerful instrument was misapplied
 and abused by the simplicity of the German legislators.","('German', 'NORP')"
"In the Lower
 Auvergne, the river Allier flows through the fair and
 spacious plain of Limagne; and the inexhaustible fertility
 of the soil supplied, and still supplies, without any
 interval of repose, the constant repetition of the same
 harvests. (103)","('the Lower\r\n Auvergne', 'LOC'), ('Allier', 'GPE'), ('Limagne', 'GPE'), ('103', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the Salic laws, and the Pandects of
 Justinian, we may compare the first rudiments, and the full
 maturity, of civil wisdom; and whatever prejudices may be
 suggested in favour of barbarism, our calmer reflections
 will ascribe to the Romans the superior advantages, not only
 of science and reason, but of humanity and justice.","('Salic', 'GPE'), ('the Pandects of\r\n Justinian', 'LAW'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"In the bloody discord and silent decay of the Merovingian
 line a new order of tyrants arose in the provinces, who,
 under the appellation of Seniors or Lords, usurped a right
 to govern and a licence to oppress the subjects of their
 peculiar territory.","('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('Lords', 'ORG')"
"In the calm moments of legislation 
 they solemnly pronounced that the life of a Roman was of
 smaller value than that of a barbarian.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the distress of the
 battle of Tolbiac, Clovis loudly invoked the God of Clotilda
 and the Christians; and victory disposed him to hear with
 respectful gratitude the eloquent (27) Remigius, ((28) bishop of 
 Rheims, who forcibly displayed the temporal and spiritual
 advantages of his conversion.","('Tolbiac', 'PERSON'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Clotilda', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('27', 'CARDINAL'), ('Remigius', 'PERSON'), ('28', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rheims', 'PERSON')"
"In the invasion of Britain many heroes
 vanquished and fell; but only seven victorious leaders
 assumed, or at least maintained, the title of Kings.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the midst 
 of these peaceful occupations Syagrius received, and boldly
 accepted, the hostile defiance of Clovis, who challenged his
 rival in the spirit, and almost in the language of chivalry,
 to appoint the day and the field (17) of battle.","('Syagrius', 'PERSON'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('the day', 'DATE'), ('17', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the space of four hundred years the hardy Gauls, who had
 encountered the arms of Caesar, were imperceptibly melted
 into the general mass of citizens and subjects: the Western
 empire was dissolved; and the Germans who had passed the
 Rhine fiercely contended for the possession of Gaul, and
 excited the contempt or abhorrence of its peaceful and
 polished inhabitants.","('the space of four hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"In the subsequent
 battle of Marlborough, (134) his British enemies displayed 
 their military science.","('Marlborough', 'GPE'), ('134', 'CARDINAL'), ('British', 'NORP')"
"In the time 
 of Caesar, Soissons would have poured forth a body of fifty
 thousand horse; and such an army might have been plentifully
 supplied with shields, cuirasses, and military engines from
 the three arsenals or manufactures of the city.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Soissons', 'PERSON'), ('fifty\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"In these districts each barbarian was connected by
 the ties of hospitality with some Roman provincial.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It was
 a name, a shadow, an empty pageant; and if the conqueror had
 been instructed to claim the ancient prerogatives of that
 high office, they must have expired with the period of its
 annual duration.","('annual', 'DATE')"
"It was her interest as
 well as her duty to achieve the conversion (26) of a Pagan 
 husband; and Clovis insensibly listened to the voice of love
 and religion.","('26', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON')"
"It was the duty and the
 interest of Clovis to provide rewards for a successful army,
 and settlements for a numerous people, without inflicting
 any wanton or superfluous injuries on the loyal catholics of
 Gaul.","('Clovis', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"It would
 be ungenerous, without some more accurate knowledge of his
 strength and resources, to condemn the rapid flight of
 Syagrius, who escaped after the loss of a battle to the
 distant court of Toulouse.","('Syagrius', 'PERSON'), ('Toulouse', 'GPE')"
"It would be
 superfluous to praise the valour of a Frank, but the valour
 of Clovis was directed by cool and consummate prudence.","('Frank', 'PERSON'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON')"
"Kenric, his valiant
 son, advanced into Wiltshire; besieged Salisbury, at that
 time seated on a commanding eminence; and vanquished an army
 which advanced to the relief of the city.","('Kenric', 'PERSON'), ('Wiltshire', 'GPE'), ('Salisbury', 'PERSON')"
Legislative Assemblies of Spain.,"('Legislative Assemblies of Spain', 'ORG')"
"Leo assured him that, if he would provide a sufficient quantity of poultry, his wishes should be satisfied.","('Leo', 'PERSON')"
"Liberty had peopled the mountains of Wales and the morasses
 of Armorica: but their populousness has been maliciously
 ascribed to the loose practice of polygamy; and the houses
 of these licentious barbarians have been supposed to contain
 ten wives, and perhaps fifty children. (158)","('Wales', 'GPE'), ('Armorica', 'LOC'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('158', 'CARDINAL')"
"Martin, the most popular of the saints, had filled
 the Western world with the fame of those miracles which were
 incessantly performed at his holy sepulchre of Tours.","('Martin', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
Obscure or fabulous state of Britain.,"('Britain', 'GPE')"
"On the false report that their lawful 
 sovereign had been slain in Germany, the city and diocese of
 Auvergne were betrayed by the grandson of Sidonius
 Apollinaris.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Auvergne', 'GPE'), ('Sidonius\r\n Apollinaris', 'PERSON')"
"On the first rumour of war or conspiracy these guiltless youths were reduced to a state of servitude; and one of them, Attalus, (107) whose adventures are more particularly related, kept his master's horses in the diocese of Treves.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Attalus', 'PERSON'), ('107', 'CARDINAL'), ('Treves', 'GPE')"
"On the memorable day when Clovis
 ascended from the baptismal font, he alone in the Christian
 world deserved the name and prerogatives of a catholic king.","('the memorable day', 'DATE'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"On the revival of
 learning, the students who had been formed in the schools of
 Athens and Rome disdained their barbarian ancestors; and a
 long period elapsed before patient labour could provide the
 requisite materials to satisfy, or rather to excite, the
 curiosity of more enlightened times.","('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"On the solemn day, the monarch of Gaul, placing a diadem on his
 head, was invested, in the church of St. Martin, with a
 purple tunic and mantle.","('the solemn day', 'DATE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('St. Martin', 'GPE')"
"One hundred and fifty years
 after the reign of Honorius the gravest historian of the
 times (161) describes the wonders of a remote isle, whose 
 eastern and western parts are divided by an antique wall,
 the boundary of life and death, or, more properly, of truth
 and fiction.","('One hundred and fifty years', 'DATE'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('161', 'CARDINAL')"
"One hundred and sixty of these
 palaces, a title which need not excite any unseasonable
 ideas of art or luxury, were scattered through the provinces
 of their kingdom; and if some might claim the honours of a
 fortress, the far greater part could be esteemed only in the
 light of profitable farms.","('One hundred and sixty', 'CARDINAL')"
"One of the greatest of the English monarchs was
 requested to satisfy the curiosity of a Greek emperor
 concerning the state of Britain; and Henry II.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('English', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Henry II', 'PERSON')"
"One of these legislative councils of Toledo examined and
 ratified the code of laws which had been compiled by a
 succession of Gothic kings, from the fierce Euric to the
 devout Egica.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Toledo', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Euric', 'NORP'), ('Egica', 'ORG')"
"One-third part of the fertile lands of the
 Sequani was appropriated to their use; and the conqueror
 soon repeated his oppressive demand of another third, for
 the accommodation of a new colony of twenty-four thousand
 barbarians whom he had invited to share the rich harvest of
 Gaul. (85)","('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Sequani', 'GPE'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('twenty-four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('85', 'CARDINAL')"
"Orleans  secured to the Franks a bridge on the Loire; but, at the distance of forty miles from Poitiers, their progress was intercepted by an extraordinary swell of the river Vigenna
 or Vienne; and the opposite banks were covered by the
 encampment of the Visigoths.","('Orleans', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Loire', 'LOC'), ('forty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Poitiers', 'GPE'), ('Vigenna', 'GPE'), ('Vienne', 'GPE'), ('Visigoths', 'PRODUCT')"
"Perhaps Agathias, and the Greeks, were
 dazzled by the rapid progress of their arms, and the
 splendour of their empire.","('Agathias', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"Perhaps the Franks already displayed the
 social disposition, and lively graces, which, in every age,
 have disguised their vices, and sometimes concealed their
 intrinsic merit.","('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"Perhaps these suspected catholics had been
 maliciously exposed to the blind assault of the enemy; and
 perhaps the influence of religion was superseded by personal
 attachment or military honour. (52) Conquest of Aquitain by the Franks, A.D. 508.","('Conquest of Aquitain', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('508', 'CARDINAL')"
"Perhaps this singular adventure, which is marked with so many circumstances of truth and nature, was related by Attalus himself to his cousin or nephew, the first historian of the Franks.","('Attalus', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"Pilgrimage, and the holy wars, introduced into Europe the
 specious miracles of Arabian magic.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Arabian', 'NORP')"
"Plebeian transgressors were legally
 chastised with stripes and imprisonment; (94) but in an age 
 which admitted a slight composition for the life of a
 citizen, it was a capital crime to destroy a stag or a wild
 bull within the precincts of the royal forests. (95)
Personal servitude.","('94', 'DATE'), ('95', 'CARDINAL')"
"Resistance, if it cannot avert, must increase the miseries
 of conquest; and conquest has never appeared more dreadful
 and destructive than in the hands of the Saxons, who hated
 the valour of their enemies, disdained the faith of
 treaties, and violated, without remorse, the most sacred
 objects of the Christian worship.","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"Separated by their enemies from
 the rest of mankind, they soon became an object of scandal
 and abhorrence to the catholic world. (156)","('156', 'CARDINAL')"
"Seven independent kingdoms were agitated
 by perpetual discord; and the British world was seldom
 connected, either in peace or war, with the nations of the
 continent. (164)","('Seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('British', 'NORP'), ('164', 'CARDINAL')"
"Seven independent thrones, the Saxon Heptarchy, were founded by the conquerors; and seven families, one of which has been
 continued, by female succession, to our present sovereign,
 derived their equal and sacred lineage from Woden, the god
 of war.","('Seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Woden', 'PERSON')"
"Seventy-five years after the death of Clovis, his
 grandson Gontran, king of Burgundy, sent an army to invade
 the Gothic possessions of Septimania, or Languedoc.","('Seventy-five years', 'DATE'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Gontran', 'PERSON'), ('Burgundy', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Septimania', 'GPE'), ('Languedoc', 'LOC')"
"She
 had been betrothed to Radiger, king of the Varni, a tribe of
 Germans who touched the ocean and the Rhine; but the
 perfidious lover was tempted, by motives of policy, to
 prefer his father's widow, the sister of Theodebert, king of
 the Franks. (162)","('Radiger', 'PERSON'), ('Varni', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Theodebert', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('162', 'CARDINAL')"
"She reminded her husband how
 effectually some pious foundation would propitiate the Deity
 and his servants: and the Christian hero, darting his
 battleaxe with a skilful and nervous hand, This ostentatious piety confirmed and justified the attachment of the Catholics, with whom he secretly corresponded; and their devout wishes were gradually ripened into a formidable conspiracy.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Catholics', 'NORP')"
"Sidonius waited before the gates of the palace among a crowd
 of ambassadors and suppliants, and their various business at
 the court of Bordeaux attested the power and the renown of
 the king of the Visigoths.","('Sidonius', 'PERSON'), ('Bordeaux', 'GPE'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP')"
"Since Britain was already separated
 from the Roman empire, I might without reproach decline a
 story familiar to the most illiterate, and obscure to the
 most learned, of my readers.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Since the conquest of Burgundy,
 Gaul, except the Gothic province of Septimania, was subject,
 in its whole extent, to the sons of Clovis.","('Burgundy', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Septimania', 'GPE'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON')"
"Some disputes inevitably
 arose on the edge of their contiguous dominions; and after
 the delays of fruitless negotiation a personal interview of
 the two kings was proposed and accepted.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Some families of
 fishermen, the subjects of the Franks, are excused from
 tribute, in consideration of the mysterious office which is
 performed by these Charons of the ocean.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Charons', 'NORP')"
State of the Britons.,"('Britons', 'NORP')"
State of the Romans—,"('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Such an indulgence would abolish the partial distinctions of
 victory: and the Roman provincials might patiently acquiesce
 in the hardships of their condition, since it depended on
 themselves to assume the privilege, if they dared to assert
 the character, of free and warlike barbarians.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Such an outrage might have exasperated the patience
 of the most peaceful sovereign; yet the conqueror of Gaul
 dissembled the injury, released the tribute, and accepted
 the alliance and military service of the king of Burgundy.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Burgundy', 'GPE')"
"Such gentle treatment might secure the 
 allegiance of a fierce people, who had been recently subdued
 on the confines of Wales and Cornwall.","('Wales', 'GPE'), ('Cornwall', 'GPE')"
"Such imperfect population might 
 have been supplied, in some generations, by the English
 colonies; but neither reason nor facts can justify the
 unnatural supposition that the Saxons of Britain remained
 alone in the desert which they had subdued.","('English', 'NORP'), ('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"Such is the empire of Fortune (if we may still disguise our
 ignorance under that popular name), that it is almost
 equally difficult to foresee the events of war, or to
 explain their various consequences.","('Fortune', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Such miracles
 were readily provided by fraud and credulity; the most
 intricate causes were determined by this easy and infallible
 method; and the turbulent barbarians, who might have
 disdained the sentence of the magistrate, submissively
 acquiesced in the judgment of God. (79)
Judicial Combats.","('79', 'CARDINAL')"
"Syagrius inherited, as a patrimonial estate, the
 city and diocese of Soissons: the desolate remnant of the
 second Belgic, Rheims and Troyes, Beauvais and Amiens, would
 naturally submit to the count or patrician; (14) and after the 
 dissolution of the Western empire he might reign with the
 title, or at least with the authority, of king of the
 Romans. (15)","('Syagrius', 'PERSON'), ('Soissons', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Belgic', 'NORP'), ('Rheims', 'NORP'), ('Troyes', 'NORP'), ('Beauvais', 'PERSON'), ('Amiens', 'PERSON'), ('14', 'CARDINAL'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('15', 'CARDINAL')"
"That fortunate district, from the lake to Avenche and 
 Mount Jura, was occupied by the Burgundians. (22)","('Avenche', 'GPE'), ('Mount Jura', 'GPE'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"That unfortunate monarch has been almost
 unanimously condemned for the weak and mischievous policy of
 inviting (128) a formidable stranger to repel the vexatious 
 inroads of a domestic foe.","('128', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 Jutes, who fought under the peculiar banner of Hengist,
 assumed the merit of leading their countrymen in the paths
 of glory, and of erecting in Kent the first independent
 kingdom.","('Jutes', 'PERSON'), ('Hengist', 'PERSON'), ('Kent', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The
 North (such are the lofty strains of the poet) was agitated
 or appeased by the nod of Euric, the great king of Persia
 consulted the oracle of the West, and the aged god of the
 Tiber was protected by the swelling genius of the Garonne. (6)","('North', 'LOC'), ('Euric', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Tiber', 'PERSON'), ('Garonne', 'PERSON'), ('6', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 advice of the graver chieftains pressed him to elude the
 first ardour of the Franks; and to expect, in the southern
 provinces of Gaul, the veteran and victorious Ostrogoths,
 whom the king of Italy had already sent to his assistance.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The
 barbarians, who followed the hopes of rapine either on the
 land or sea, were insensibly blended with this triple
 confederacy; the Frisians, who had been tempted by their
 vicinity to the British shores, might balance during a short
 space the strength and reputation of the native Saxons; the
 Danes, the Prussians, the Rugians, are faintly described;
 and some adventurous Huns, who had wandered as far as the
 Baltic, might embark on board the German vessels for the
 conquest of a new world. (130)","('Frisians', 'NORP'), ('British', 'NORP'), ('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Danes', 'NORP'), ('Prussians', 'NORP'), ('Rugians', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Baltic', 'LOC'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('130', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 great Theodoric congratulated the victory of Clovis, whose
 sister Albofleda the king of Italy had lately married; but
 he mildly interceded with his brother in favour of the
 suppliants and fugitives who had implored his protection.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Albofleda', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The
 harsh sound of the Teutonic appellations was mollified into
 the Latin titles of Duke, of Count, or of Praefect; and the
 same officer assumed, within his district, the command of
 the troops and the administration of justice. (77)","('Teutonic', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Duke', 'PERSON'), ('Praefect', 'PERSON')"
"The
 king of Paris, Childebert, was tempted by the neighbourhood
 and beauty of Auvergne. (102)","('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Childebert', 'GPE'), ('Auvergne', 'LOC'), ('102', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 language of science, of business, and of conversation, which
 had been introduced by the Romans, was lost in the general
 desolation.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The
 lawful pretensions of Euric were justified by ambition and
 success, and the Gothic nation might aspire under his
 command to the monarchy of Spain and Gaul.","('Euric', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The
 progress of superstition and barbarism was rapid and
 universal: the worship of the saints concealed from vulgar
 eyes the God of the Christians, and the rustic dialect of
 peasants and soldiers was corrupted by a Teutonic idiom and
 pronunciation.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Teutonic', 'NORP')"
"The
 provincials must frequently deplore the savage jurisprudence
 of the Salic or Ripuarian laws but their private life, in
 the important concerns of marriage, testaments, or
 inheritance, was still regulated by the Theodosian Code; and
 a discontented Roman might freely aspire or descend to the
 title and character of a barbarian.","('Salic', 'NORP'), ('Ripuarian', 'NORP'), ('the Theodosian Code', 'LAW'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The
 provincials were long separated from their Arian masters by
 the irreconcilable difference of religion.","('Arian', 'NORP')"
"The
 reduction of the northern provinces of Gaul, instead of
 being decided by the chance of a single battle, appears to
 have been slowly effected by the gradual operation of war
 and treaty; and Clovis acquired each object of his ambition
 by such efforts or such concessions as were adequate to its
 real value.","('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON')"
"The
 same rules .were observed in the provincial assemblies, the
 annual synods, which were empowered to hear complaints and
 to redress grievances; and a legal government was supported
 by the prevailing influence of the Spanish clergy.","('Spanish', 'NORP')"
"The
 subjects of Honorius contemplated their new freedom with
 surprise and terror, they were left destitute of any civil
 or military constitution; and their uncertain rulers wanted
 either skill, or courage, or authority to direct the public
 force against the common enemy.","('Honorius', 'PERSON')"
"The
 successive colonies which issued in the period of a century
 from the mouths of the Elbe, the Weser, and the Rhine, were
 principally composed of three valiant tribes or nations of
 Germany; the Jutes, the old Saxons, and the Angles.","('the period of a century', 'DATE'), ('Elbe', 'LOC'), ('Weser', 'LOC'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Jutes', 'PERSON'), ('Saxons', 'NORP')"
"The
 troops of Burgundy, Berry, Auvergne, and the adjacent
 territories were excited by the hopes of spoil.","('Burgundy', 'GPE'), ('Berry, Auvergne', 'GPE')"
"The 
 bishops of Spain respected themselves, and were respected by
 the public: their indissoluble union disguised their vices,
 and confirmed their authority; and the regular discipline of
 the church introduced peace, order, and stability into the
 government of the state.","('Spain', 'GPE')"
"The Alemanni and Bavarians, who had
 occupied the Roman provinces of Rhaetia and Noricum, to the
 south of the Danube, confessed themselves the humble vassals
 of the Franks; and the feeble barrier of the Alps was
 incapable of resisting their ambition.","('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Bavarians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Rhaetia', 'GPE'), ('Noricum', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC')"
"The Angles were
 distinguished by their numbers and their success; and they
 claimed the honour of fixing a perpetual name on the country
 of which they occupied the most ample portion.","('Angles', 'PERSON')"
"The Antrustion, (74) a 
 name expressive of the most illustrious birth or dignity
 among the Franks, was appreciated at the sum of six hundred
 pieces of gold; while the noble provincial, who was admitted
 to the king's table, might be legally murdered at the
 expense of three hundred pieces.","('Antrustion', 'PERSON'), ('74', 'CARDINAL'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('six hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Arian
 monarch was justly alarmed by the satisfaction and the hopes
 which seemed to animate his clergy and people after the
 conversion of Clovis; and Gundobald convened at Lyons an
 assembly of his bishops, to reconcile, if it were possible,
 their religious and political discontents.","('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Gundobald', 'PERSON'), ('Lyons', 'PERSON')"
"The Arians upbraided
 the catholics with the worship of three Gods: the catholics
 defended their cause by theological distinctions; and the
 usual arguments, objections, and replies were reverberated
 with obstinate clamour, till the king revealed his secret
 apprehensions by an abrupt but decisive question, which he
 addressed to the orthodox bishops:","('Arians', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Belgic
 cities surrendered to the king of the Franks, and his
 dominions were enlarged towards the east by the ample
 diocese of Tongres, (20) which Clovis subdued in the tenth 
 year of his reign.","('Belgic', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Tongres', 'GPE'), ('20', 'CARDINAL'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('the tenth \r\n year', 'DATE')"
"The Burgundian war, A.D. 499.","('The Burgundian war', 'EVENT'), ('499', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Franks
 after an obstinate struggle gave way, and the Alemanni,
 raising a shout of victory, impetuously pressed their
 retreat.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON')"
"The Franks
 esteemed the valour of the Armoricans; (35) and the Armoricans 
 were reconciled by the religion of the Franks.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Armoricans', 'NORP'), ('35', 'CARDINAL'), ('Armoricans', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"The Franks beheld with envy and despair this impregnable fortress: but they surprised a party of fifty stragglers; and, as they were oppressed by the number of their captives, they fixed at a trifling ransom the alternative of life or death for these wretched victims, whom the cruel barbarians were prepared to massacre on the refusal of the garrison.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('fifty', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Franks, after they mingled with their Gallic subjects,
 might have imparted the most valuable of human gifts, a
 spirit and system of constitutional liberty.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP')"
"The Franks, or French, are the only people of Europe who can
 deduce a perpetual succession from the conquerors of the
 Western empire.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"The Franks, who were inspired by hereditary 
 valour and recent zeal, applauded the generous design of
 their monarch; expressed their resolution to conquer or die,
 since death and conquest would be equally profitable; and
 solemnly protested that they would never shave their beards
 till victory should absolve them from that inconvenient vow.","('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"The Gallic territories which were possessed by the Alemanni
 became the prize of their conqueror; and the haughty nation,
 invincible or rebellious to the arms of Rome, acknowledged
 the sovereignty of the Merovingian kings, who graciously
 permitted them to enjoy their peculiar manners and
 institutions under the government of official, and, at
 length, of hereditary dukes.","('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP')"
"The Gauls or Romans applauded the
 mild and impartial laws of Gundobald, which almost raised
 them to the same level with their conquerors.","('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Gundobald', 'GPE')"
"The Gauls were endowed with all the
 advantages of art and nature, but, as they wanted courage to
 defend them, they were justly condemned to obey, and even to
 flatter, the victorious barbarians by whose clemency they
 held their precarious fortunes and their lives. (4)Euric, king of the Visigoths, A.D. 476-485.","('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('Euric', 'PERSON'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('476-485', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Goth, the
 Burgundian, or the Frank, who returned from a successful
 expedition, dragged after him a long train of sheep, of
 oxen, and of human captives, whom he treated with the same
 brutal contempt.","('The Goth', 'PERSON'), ('Burgundian', 'NORP'), ('Frank', 'PERSON')"
"The Gothic war, A.D. 507.","('The Gothic war', 'EVENT'), ('507', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Goths of Spain were separated from the rest of mankind by the lofty ridge of the Pyrenaean mountains: their manners and institutions, as far as they were common to the Germanic tribes, have been already explained.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('the Pyrenaean mountains', 'LOC'), ('Germanic', 'NORP')"
"The Heruli of the distant ocean,
 who painted their naked bodies with its caerulean colour,
 implored his protection; and the Saxons respected the
 maritime provinces of a prince who was destitute of any
 naval force.","('Heruli', 'PERSON'), ('Saxons', 'NORP')"
"The Isle of Thanet, a
 secure and fertile district, was alloted for the residence
 of these German auxiliaries, and they were supplied
 according to the treaty with a plentiful allowance of
 clothing and provisions.","('The Isle of Thanet', 'GPE'), ('German', 'NORP')"
"The Merovingian prince had contracted a fortunate alliance
 with the fair Clotilda, the niece of the king of Burgundy,
 who in the midst of an Arian court was educated in the
 profession of the catholic faith.","('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('Clotilda', 'PERSON'), ('Burgundy', 'PERSON'), ('Arian', 'NORP')"
"The Merovingians, instead of
 imposing a uniform rule of conduct on their various
 subjects, permitted each people, and each family, of their
 empire freely to enjoy their domestic institutions; (69) nor 
 were the Romans excluded from the common benefits of this
 legal toleration. (70)","('Merovingians', 'NORP'), ('69', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The Ostrogoths of Italy,
 unable to defend their distant acquisitions, had resigned to
 the Franks the cities of Arles and Marseilles: of Arles,
 still adorned with the seat of a Praetorian praefect, and of
 Marseilles, enriched by the advantages of trade and
 navigation.","('The Ostrogoths of Italy', 'ORG'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Arles', 'GPE'), ('Marseilles', 'GPE'), ('Arles', 'GPE'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Marseilles', 'GPE')"
"The Romans communicated to their conquerors the use of the Christian religion and Latin language; (118) but 
 their language and their religion had alike degenerated from
 the simple purity of the Augustan and Apostolic age.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('118', 'CARDINAL'), ('Augustan', 'NORP'), ('Apostolic', 'NORP')"
"The Saxon kingdoms displayed
 the face of recent discovery and cultivation: the towns were
 small, the villages were distant; the husbandry was languid
 and unskilful; four sheep were equivalent to an acre of the
 best land; (149) an ample space of wood and morass was 
 resigned to the vague dominion of nature; and the modern
 bishopric of Durham, the whole territory from the Tyne to
 the Tees, had returned to its primitive state of a savage
 and solitary forest. (150)","('Saxon', 'NORP'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('an acre', 'QUANTITY'), ('149', 'CARDINAL'), ('Durham', 'GPE'), ('Tyne', 'LOC'), ('Tees', 'LOC'), ('150', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Saxons
 charged in one weighty column, boldly encountered with their
 short swords the long lances of the Britons, and maintained
 an equal conflict till the approach of night.","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Britons', 'NORP'), ('night', 'TIME')"
"The Saxons flew to arms; and if they perpetrated a
 treacherous massacre during the security of a feast, they
 destroyed the reciprocal confidence which sustains the
 intercourse of peace and war. (129)
Establishment of the Saxon heptarchy, A.D. 455-582.","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('129', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saxon', 'NORP')"
"The Saxons magnified all that they had done and
 suffered in the cause of an ungrateful people; while the
 Britons regretted the liberal rewards which could not
 satisfy the avarice of those haughty mercenaries.","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Britons', 'NORP')"
"The Saxons, who excelled in the
 use of the oar or the battleaxe, were ignorant of the art
 which could alone perpetuate the fame of their exploits; the
 provincials, relapsing into barbarism, neglected to describe
 the ruin of their country; and the doubtful tradition was
 almost extinguished before the missionaries of Rome restored
 the light of science and Christianity.","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Christianity', 'NORP')"
"The Vandals of Africa cultivated his useful friendship, and
 the Ostrogoths of Pannonia were supported by his powerful
 aid against the oppression of the neighbouring Huns.","('The Vandals of Africa', 'PERSON'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP'), ('Pannonia', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"The Visigoths
 and Burgundians, whose conquests in Gaul preceded those of
 the Franks, showed less impatience to attain one of the
 principal benefits of civilised society.","('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
The Visigoths had resigned to Clovis the greatest part of their Gallic possessions; but their loss was amply compensated by the easy conquest and secure enjoyment of the provinces of Spain.,"('Visigoths', 'PERSON'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE')"
The Visigoths of Spain.,"('Visigoths', 'PERSON'), ('Spain', 'GPE')"
The Visigoths of Spain—Conquest of Britain by the Saxons,"('The Visigoths of Spain', 'PERSON'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Saxons', 'NORP')"
"The Visigoths resumed the exercise of arms, which they had neglected in a long and luxurious peace; (49) a select band of valiant and robust slaves attended their masters to the field; (50) and the cities of Gaul were compelled to furnish their doubtful and reluctant aid.","('Visigoths', 'ORG'), ('49', 'CARDINAL'), ('50', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'GPE')"
"The Visigoths were suffered to retain the possession of
 Septimania, a narrow tract of seacoast, from the Rhone to
 the Pyrenees; but the ample province of Aquitain, from those
 mountains to the Loire, was indissolubly united to the
 kingdom of France. (56) Consulship of Clovis, A.D. 510.","('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Septimania', 'GPE'), ('Rhone', 'LOC'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('Aquitain', 'GPE'), ('Loire', 'LOC'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('56', 'CARDINAL'), ('Clovis', 'GPE'), ('510', 'CARDINAL')"
"The accidental or artificial prodigies which adorned the
 expedition of Clovis were accepted, by a superstitious age,
 as the manifest declaration of the Divine favour.","('Clovis', 'LOC')"
"The actual or legal authority of Clovis could not
 receive any new accessions from the consular dignity.","('Clovis', 'GPE')"
"The allegiance of doubtful subjects is indeed most
 effectually secured by their own persuasion that they hazard
 more in a revolt than they can hope to obtain by a
 revolution; but it has appeared so natural to oppress those
 whom we hate and fear, that the contrary system well
 deserves the praise of wisdom and moderation. (125)
Revolution of Britain.","('125', 'CARDINAL'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"The allegiance of his brother was already seduced; and the
 obedience of Godegesil, who joined the royal standard with
 the troops of Geneva, more effectually promoted the success
 of the conspiracy.","('Godegesil', 'PERSON'), ('Geneva', 'GPE')"
"The ample fund which he might lawfully acquire of the
 Imperial patrimony, vacant lands, and Gothic usurpations,
 would diminish the cruel necessity of seizure and
 confiscation, and the humble provincials would more
 patiently acquiesce in the equal and regular distribution of
 their loss. (87)
Domain and benefices of the Merovingians.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Merovingians', 'NORP')"
"The answer of Avitus,  bishop of Vienne, who spoke in the name of his brethren, was delivered with the voice and countenance of an angel.","('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('Vienne', 'PERSON')"
"The arts and religion, the laws
 and language, which the Romans had so carefully planted in
 Britain, were extirpated by their barbarous successors.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"The arts of navigation, by
 which they had acquired the empire of Britain and of the
 sea, were soon neglected by the indolent barbarians, who
 supinely renounced all the commercial advantages of their
 insular situation.","('Britain', 'GPE')"
The barbarian purchased Leo for the price of twelve pieces of gold; and was pleased to learn that he was deeply skilled in the luxury of an episcopal table:,"('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL')"
"The bishops
 were reconciled and flattered by the hopes which he artfully
 suggested of his approaching conversion; and though he
 eluded their accomplishment to the last moment of his life,
 his moderation secured the peace and suspended the ruin of
 the kingdom of Burgundy. (42)","('Burgundy', 'GPE'), ('42', 'CARDINAL')"
"The brave
 and numerous inhabitants displayed a singular trophy—the
 sword of Caesar himself, which he had lost when he was
 repulsed before the walls of Gergovia. (100)","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Gergovia', 'PRODUCT'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"The bravest warriors, who
 preferred exile to slavery, found a secure refuge in the
 mountains of Wales: the reluctant submission of Cornwall was
 delayed for some ages; (135) and a band of fugitives acquired 
 a settlement in Gaul, by their own valour, or the liberality
 of the Merovingian kings. (136)","('Wales', 'GPE'), ('Cornwall', 'GPE'), ('135', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('136', 'CARDINAL')"
"The captive
 monarch, with his wife and two children, was transported to
 Orleans, and buried alive in a deep well by the stern
 command of the sons of Clovis, whose cruelty might derive
 some excuse from the maxims and examples of their barbarous
 age.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Orleans', 'GPE'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON')"
"The castle of Meroliac (105) was seated on a lofty rock, which rose an hundred feet above the surface of the plain; and a large reservoir of fresh water was enclosed with some arable lands within the circle of its fortifications.","('Meroliac', 'GPE'), ('105', 'CARDINAL'), ('an hundred feet', 'QUANTITY')"
"The catholic Sigismond has acquired the
 honours of a saint and martyr; (43) but the hands of the royal 
 saint were stained with the blood of his innocent son, whom
 he inhumanly sacrificed to the pride and resentment of a
 stepmother.","('Sigismond', 'PERSON')"
"The cavalry of Armorica, the spearmen of
 Gwent, and the archers of Merioneth, were equally
 formidable; but their poverty could seldom procure either
 shields or helmets; and the inconvenient weight would have
 retarded the speed and agility of their desultory
 operations.","('Armorica', 'GPE'), ('Gwent', 'GPE'), ('Merioneth', 'GPE')"
"The cities, which had been
 fortified with skill, were defended with resolution; the
 advantages of ground, hills, forests, and morasses, were
 diligently improved by the inhabitants; the conquest of each
 district was purchased with blood and the defeats of the
 Saxons are strongly attested by the discreet silence of
 their annalist.","('Saxons', 'NORP')"
"The civil and military professions, which had been separated
 by Constantine, were again united by the barbarians.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The clergy and people, the sacred and the profane spoils, were rudely torn from the altar; and the sacrilegious division was made at a small distance from the town of Brioude.","('Brioude', 'GPE')"
"The clergy of 
 Gaul consisted almost entirely of native provincials; the
 haughty Franks fell prostrate at the feet of their subjects
 who were dignified with the episcopal character; and the
 power and riches which had been lost in war were insensibly
 recovered by superstition.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"The common or public rights of nature, such as
 they had always been deemed by the Roman jurisprudence, (93) 
 were severely restrained by the German conquerors, whose
 amusement, or rather passion, was the exercise of hunting.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('93', 'DATE'), ('German', 'NORP')"
"The conqueror penetrated as far as the confines of
 Spain; (54) restored the honours of the catholic church; fixed 
 in Aquitain a colony of Franks (55) and delegated to his 
 lieutenants the easy task of subduing or extirpating the
 nation of the Visigoths.","('Spain', 'GPE'), ('54', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aquitain', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('55', 'DATE'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP')"
"The cornfields, the villages, the
 churches themselves, were consumed by fire; the inhabitants
 were massacred or dragged into captivity; and, in the
 disorderly retreat, five thousand of these inhuman savages
 were destroyed by hunger or intestine discord.","('five thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The counsels of the Visigoths
 were irresolute and distracted.","('Visigoths', 'PERSON')"
"The crafty barbarian suggested to Vortigern
 the obvious advantage of fixing, in the neighbourhood of the
 Picts, a colony of faithful allies: a third fleet, of forty
 ships, under he command of his son and nephew, sailed from
 Germany, ravaged the Orkneys, and disembarked a new army on
 the coast of Northumberland or Lothian, at the opposite
 extremity of the devoted land.","('Vortigern', 'PERSON'), ('Picts', 'NORP'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('forty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Orkneys', 'NORP'), ('Northumberland', 'GPE'), ('Lothian', 'GPE')"
"The dark cloud which had been
 cleared by the Phoenician discoveries, and finally dispelled
 by the arms of Caesar, again settled on the shores of the
 Atlantic, and a Roman province was again lost among the
 fabulous islands of the Ocean.","('Phoenician', 'NORP'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Atlantic', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Ocean', 'LOC')"
"The decisive battle of Poitiers was followed by the
 conquest of Aquitain.","('Poitiers', 'GPE'), ('Aquitain', 'PERSON')"
"The decisive moments were wasted in idle deliberation; the
 Goths too hastily abandoned, perhaps, an advantageous post;
 and the opportunity of a secure retreat was lost by their
 slow and disorderly motions.","('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The declamations of
 Gildas, the fragments or fables of Nennius, the obscure
 hints of the Saxon laws and chronicles, and the
 ecclesiastical tales of the venerable Bede, (126) have been 
 illustrated by the diligence, and sometimes embellished by
 the fancy, of succeeding writers, whose works I am not
 ambitious either to censure or to transcribe. (127)","('Gildas', 'PERSON'), ('Nennius', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Saxon', 'NORP'), ('Bede', 'PERSON'), ('126', 'CARDINAL')"
"The difference of their style and sentiments may, therefore, express the decay of Gaul; and clearly ascertain how much, in so short a space, the human mind had lost of its energy and refinement.","('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The diligence and affability of their judge
 rendered him popular, the impartial wisdom of his decrees
 obtained their voluntary obedience, and the reign of
 Syagrius over the Franks and Burgundians seemed to revive
 the original institution of civil society.","('Syagrius', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP')"
"The eldest, or rather the only son of
 the church, was acknowledged by the clergy as their lawful
 sovereign or glorious deliverer; and the arms of Clovis were
 strenuously supported by the zeal and favour of the catholic
 faction. (34) Submission of the Amoricans and the Roman troops, A.D. 497 etc.","('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('34', 'CARDINAL'), ('Amoricans', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 497', 'DATE')"
"The emperor Anastasius
 ambitiously bestowed on the most powerful rival of Theodoric
 the title and ensigns of that eminent dignity; yet, from
 some unknown cause, the name of Clovis has not been
 inscribed in the Fasti either of the East or West. (57)","('Anastasius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Fasti', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('57', 'CARDINAL')"
"The emperor Anastasius entertained some dangerous errors
 concerning the nature of the divine incarnation; and the
 barbarians of Italy, Africa, Spain, and Gaul were involved
 in the Arian heresy.","('Anastasius', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Arian', 'NORP')"
"The enterprise was promoted by the public or private
 exhortations of Clotilda.","('Clotilda', 'ORG')"
"The example of a revolution so rapid and
 so complete may not easily be found; but it will excite a
 probable suspicion that the arts of Rome were less deeply
 rooted in Britain than in Gaul or Spain; and that the native
 rudeness of the country and its inhabitants was covered by a
 thin varnish of Italian manners.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
The fame of Arthur.,"('Arthur', 'PERSON')"
"The fame of the enterprise was attributed to the
 primitive Saxons, and the common laws and language of the
 conquerors are described by the national appellation of a
 people which, at the end of four hundred years, produced the
 first monarchs of South Britain.","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('the end of four hundred years', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('South Britain', 'GPE')"
"The feeble minority of Alaric
 could not assist or protect an unfortunate fugitive; the
 pusillanimous (19)","('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('19', 'CARDINAL')"
"The fields of battle might
 be traced, almost in every district, by monuments of bones;
 the fragments of falling towers were stained with blood; the
 last of the Britons, without distinction of age or sex, was
 massacred, (142) in the ruins of Anderida; (143) and the 
 repetition of such calamities was frequent and familiar
 under the Saxon heptarchy.","('Britons', 'NORP'), ('142', 'CARDINAL'), ('Anderida', 'GPE'), ('143', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saxon', 'NORP')"
"The fierce spirit of the Franks would have opposed 
 a more rigorous sentence; the same fierceness despised these
 ineffectual restraints; and, when their simple manners had
 been corrupted by the wealth of Gaul, the public peace was
 continually violated by acts of hasty or deliberate guilt.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The first exploit of Clovis was the defeat of Syagrius, the
 son of Aegidius, and the public quarrel might on this
 occasion be inflamed by private resentment.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Syagrius', 'PERSON'), ('Aegidius', 'PERSON')"
"The first victory of Clovis had insulted the honour of the
 Goths.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The forsaken princess of the Angles, instead 
 of bewailing, revenged her disgrace.","('Angles', 'PERSON')"
"The fortune of nations has often depended on accidents; and
 France may ascribe her greatness to the premature death of
 the Gothic king at a time when his son Alaric was a helpless
 infant, and his adversary Clovis (7) an ambitious and valiant 
 youth.","('France', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('7', 'CARDINAL')"
"The gallantry and
 superstition of the British hero, his feasts and
 tournaments, and the memorable institution of his Knights of
 the Round Table, were faithfully copied from the reigning
 manners of chivalry; and the fabulous exploits of Uther's
 son appear less incredible than the adventures which were
 achieved by the enterprising valour of the Normans.","('British', 'NORP'), ('Knights of\r\n the Round Table', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Uther', 'PERSON'), ('Normans', 'NORP')"
"The general state and revolutions of France, a name which
 was imposed by the conquerors, may be illustrated by the
 particular example of a province, a diocese, or a senatorial
 family.","('France', 'GPE')"
"The glory of the
 father still insulted the Merovingian race; the power of the
 son might excite the jealous ambition of the king of the
 Franks.","('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"The honours of the state
 were accessible to his ambition: the education and temper of
 the Romans more peculiarly qualified them for the offices of
 civil government; and as soon as emmulation had rekindled
 their military ardour, they were permitted to march in the
 ranks, or even at the head, of the victorious Germans.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"The important ceremony was performed in the
 cathedral of Rheims with every circumstance of magnificence
 and solemnity hat could impress an awful sense of religion
 on he minds of its rude proselytes. (29)","('Rheims', 'PERSON')"
"The independent Britons appear to have relapsed into the state of original barbarism from whence they had
 been imperfectly reclaimed.","('Britons', 'NORP')"
"The indigent
 barbarians were often tempted to sell their children or
 themselves into perpetual, and even foreign, bondage; (152) 
 yet the special exemptions which were granted to national
 slaves (153) sufficiently declare that they were much less 
 numerous than the strangers and captives who had lost their
 liberty, or changed their masters, by the accidents of war.","('152', 'CARDINAL'), ('153', 'CARDINAL')"
"The intrepid slave, after sustaining this dangerous raillery, entered his master's bedchamber; removed his spear and shield; silently drew the fleetest horses from the stable; unbarred the ponderous gates; and excited Attalus to save his life and liberty by incessant diligence.","('Attalus', 'PERSON')"
"The introduction of the
 Saxons betrayed their internal weakness, and degraded the
 character both of the prince and people.","('Saxons', 'NORP')"
"The justice
 of Clovis was inexorable, and his careless or disobedient
 soldiers were punished with instant death.","('Clovis', 'PERSON')"
"The kindred tribes of the
 Franks who had seated themselves along the Belgic rivers,
 the Scheldt, the Meuse, the Moselle, and the Rhine, were
 governed by their independent kings of the Merovingian race
 the equals, the allies, and sometimes the enemies, of the
 Salic prince.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Belgic', 'NORP'), ('Scheldt', 'NORP'), ('Meuse', 'FAC'), ('Moselle', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('Salic', 'NORP')"
"The king declared himself
 satisfied of the truth of the catholic faith and the
 political reasons which might have suspended his public
 profession were removed by the devout or loyal acclamations
 of the Franks, who showed themselves alike prepared to
 follow their heroic leader to the field of battle or to the
 baptismal font.","('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"The king of Burgundy, who was not prepared to accept the
 condition which the catholics considered as essential to the
 treaty, delayed and dismissed the ecclesiastical conference,
 after reproaching his bishops, that Clovis, their friend and
 proselyte, had privately tempted the allegiance of his
 brother. (39) Victory of Clovis, A.D. 500.","('Burgundy', 'GPE'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('500', 'CARDINAL')"
"The kingdom of
 Sussex, which spread from the sea to the Thames, contained
 seven thousand families: twelve hundred were ascribed to the
 Isle of Wight; and, if we multiply this vague computation,
 it may seem probable that England was cultivated by a
 million of servants, or villains, who were attached to the
 estates of their arbitrary landlords.","('Sussex', 'GPE'), ('Thames', 'LOC'), ('seven thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('twelve hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('the\r\n Isle of Wight', 'GPE'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('a\r\n million', 'CARDINAL')"
"The kingdom of the Burgundians, which was defined by the
 course of two Gallic rivers, the Saone and the Rhone,
 extended from the forest of Vosges to the Alps and the sea
 of Marseilles. (37)","('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Saone', 'LOC'), ('Rhone', 'LOC'), ('Vosges', 'LOC'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Marseilles', 'LOC'), ('37', 'CARDINAL')"
"The kings of
 France maintained the privileges of their Roman subjects;
 but the ferocious Saxons trampled on the laws of Rome and of
 the emperors.","('France', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The last king of the Alemanni was slain in the
 field, and his people were slaughtered and pursued till they
 threw down their arms and yielded to the mercy of the
 conqueror.","('Alemanni', 'PERSON')"
"The last retreats of 
 Celtic freedom, the extreme territories of Gaul and Britain,
 were less adapted to agriculture than to pasturage: the
 wealth of the Britons consisted in their flocks and herds;
 milk and flesh were their ordinary food; and bread was
 sometimes esteemed, or rejected, as a foreign luxury.","('Celtic', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Britons', 'NORP')"
"The liberal studies were still
 cultivated in the schools of Autun and Bordeaux, and the
 language of Cicero and Virgil was familiar to the Gallic
 youth.","('Autun', 'LOC'), ('Bordeaux', 'GPE'), ('Cicero', 'PERSON'), ('Virgil', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP')"
"The life of Cerdic,
 one of the bravest of the children of Woden, was consumed in
 the conquest of Hampshire and the Isle of Wight, and the
 loss which he sustained in the battle of Mount Badon reduced
 him to a state of inglorious repose.","('Cerdic', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Woden', 'PERSON'), ('Hampshire', 'GPE'), ('the Isle of Wight', 'GPE'), ('Mount Badon', 'LOC')"
"The majesty of 
 the Roman laws protected the liberty of each citizen against
 the rash effects of his own distress or despair.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The majesty of Rome was faintly
