Sentence,Entities
"(1) But it 
 would soon appear that the vain attempt to blend such
 discordant colours, and to reconcile such inconsistent
 qualities, must produce a figure monstrous rather than
 human, unless it is viewed in its proper and distinct lights
 by a careful separation of the different periods of the
 reign of Constantine.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"(15) In the midst of 
 the festival the unfortunate Crispus was apprehended by
 order of the emperor, who laid aside the tenderness of a
 father without assuming the equity of a judge.","('Crispus', 'PERSON')"
"(3) In the life of Augustus we behold the tyrant of the republic converted almost by imperceptible degrees into the father of his country and of
(43),"('43', 'CARDINAL')"
(44),"('44', 'CARDINAL')"
(51),"('51', 'CARDINAL')"
"(55) 
 If any credit can be given to this marvellous tale, which
 seems, however, to be countenanced by the manners of the
 people and by the extraordinary duration of his reign, we
 must admire not only the fortune but the genius of Sapor.","('55', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON')"
"(76)
Deposes Vetranio, A.D. 350, Dec. 25.","('350', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dec. 25', 'DATE')"
"A more
 numerous band retired beyond the Carpathian mountains, among
 the Quadi, their German allies, and were easily admitted to
 share a superfluous waste of uncultivated land.","('Carpathian', 'NORP'), ('Quadi', 'NORP'), ('German', 'NORP')"
"A perpetual exemption from
 all duties was stipulated for their vessels which traded to
 the ports of the Black Sea.","('the Black Sea', 'LOC')"
"A royal bed, on which the queen lay in state,
 was exhibited in the midst of the palace; the diadem was
 placed on the spot which might be supposed to conceal the
 future heir of Artaxerxes, and the prostrate satraps adored
 the majesty of their invisible and insensible sovereign.","('Artaxerxes', 'NORP')"
"A tale so moral and so interesting would deserve to be supported by less exceptionable
 authority; but if we consult the more ancient and authentic
 writers, they will inform us that the repentance of
 Constantine was manifested only in acts of blood and
 revenge, and that he atoned for the murder of an innocent
 son by the execution, perhaps, of a guilty wife.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"A treble enclosure of
 brick walls was defended by a deep ditch; (65) and the 
 intrepid resistance of Count Lucilianus and his garrison was
 seconded by the desperate courage of the people.","('65', 'CARDINAL'), ('Lucilianus', 'PERSON')"
"A.D. 324, October 10.","('A.D. 324', 'DATE'), ('October 10', 'DATE')"
"A.D. 325, October 1","('A.D. 325', 'DATE'), ('October 1', 'DATE')"
A.D. 350..,"('A.D. 350', 'DATE')"
"According to the
 maxims adopted by Probus and his successors, the offers of
 this barbarian colony were eagerly accepted; and a competent
 portion of lands in the provinces of Pannonia, Thrace,
 Macedonia, and Italy, were immediately assigned for the
 habitation and subsistence of three hundred thousand
 Sarmatians.(46)
Death and funeral of Constantine, A.D. 335, July 25.","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Pannonia', 'GPE'), ('Thrace', 'GPE'), ('Macedonia', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('three hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('46', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 335', 'DATE'), ('July 25', 'DATE')"
"According to the various accidents of peace and war, of
 alliance or conquest, the Sarmatians were sometimes confined
 to the banks of the Tanais, and they sometimes spread
 themselves over the immense plains which lie between the
 Vistula and the Volga.(36)","('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Tanais', 'NORP'), ('Vistula', 'NORP'), ('Volga', 'LOC'), ('36', 'CARDINAL')"
"After
 the troubles had continued about three years, Antiochus, one
 of the officers of the household, executed with success the
 Imperial commission of restoring Chosroes, the son of
 Tiridates, to the throne of his fathers, of distributing
 honours and rewards among the faithful servants of the house
 of Arsaces, and of proclaiming a general amnesty, which was
 accepted by the greater part of the rebellious satraps.","('about three years', 'DATE'), ('Antiochus', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Tiridates', 'PERSON'), ('Arsaces', 'PERSON')"
"After some experience of the superior
 strength and numbers of their adversaries, the Sarmatians
 implored the protection of the Roman monarch, who beheld
 with pleasure the discord of the nations, but who was justly
 alarmed by the progress of the Gothic arms.","('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"After the partition of the empire three years had scarcely
 elapsed before the sons of Constantine seemed impatient to
 convince mankind that they were incapable of contenting
 themselves with the dominions which they were unqualified to
 govern.","('three years', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Alarmed 
 by this intelligence, he hastily relinquished the siege, and
 marched with rapid diligence from the banks of the Tigris to
 those of the Oxus.","('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Oxus', 'PERSON')"
"Although Sapor was in the thirtieth year of his long reign,
 he was still in the vigour of youth, as the date of his
 accession, by a very strange fatality, had preceded that of
 his birth.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('the thirtieth year', 'DATE')"
"An Imperial fleet acquired the easy
 possession of Africa and Spain, confirmed the wavering faith
 of the Moorish nations, and landed a considerable force,
 which passed the Pyrenees, and advanced towards Lyons, the
 last and fatal station of Magnentius.(94)","('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Moorish', 'NORP'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('Lyons', 'GPE'), ('Magnentius', 'GPE'), ('94', 'CARDINAL')"
"An edict of Constantine, published about this time, manifestly indicates his real or affected suspicions that a secret conspiracy had been formed against his person and government.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Arming a desperate troop of slaves and
 gladiators, he overpowered the feeble guard of the domestic
 tranquillity of Rome, received the homage of the senate,
 and, assuming the title of Augustus, precariously reigned
 during a tumult of twenty eight days.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('twenty eight days', 'DATE')"
"As soon as
 Constantine had declared himself in favour of the weaker
 party, the haughty Araric, king of the Goths, instead of
 expecting the attack of the legions, boldly passed the
 Danube, and spread terror and devastation through the
 province of Maesia.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Araric', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Maesia', 'GPE')"
"As soon as he had taken
 possession of the palace of Constantinople, his first care
 was to remove the apprehensions of his kinsmen, by a solemn
 oath which he pledged for their security.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"As soon as the death of Constans had decided this easy but
 important revolution, the example of the court of Autun was
 imitated by the provinces of the West.","('Constans', 'PERSON'), ('Autun', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"As soon as the legions gave way, the lighter and more active squadrons of the second line rode sword in hand into the intervals and completed the disorder.","('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"As they advanced in years and experience,
 the limits of their authority were insensibly enlarged: but
 the emperor always reserved for himself the title of
 Augustus; and while he showed the Caesars to the armies and
 provinces, he maintained every part of the empire in equal
 obedience to its supreme head.","('years', 'DATE'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Caesars', 'PERSON')"
"At the age of 
 seventeen Crispus was invested with the title of Caesar, and
 the administration of the Gallic provinces, where the
 inroads of the Germans gave him an early occasion of
 signalising his military prowess.","('the age of \r\n seventeen', 'DATE'), ('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"At the decease of Constantine, the throne of
 the East was filled by Sapor, son of Hormouz, or Hormisdas,
 and grandson of Narses, who, after the victory of Galerius,
 had humbly confessed the superiority of the Roman power.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Hormouz', 'PERSON'), ('Hormisdas', 'PERSON'), ('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"At the head of a tumultuary
 band, suited for rapine rather than for conquest, he
 suddenly broke into the dominions of Constans, by the way of
 the Julian Alps, and the country round Aquileia felt the
 first effects of his resentment.","('Constans', 'NORP'), ('the Julian Alps', 'LOC'), ('Aquileia', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"At the stated season of the
 melting of the snows in Armenia, the river Mygdonius, which
 divides the plain and the city of Nisibis, forms, like the
 Nile,(67) an inundation over the adjacent country.","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Mygdonius', 'GPE'), ('Nisibis', 'GPE'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('67', 'CARDINAL')"
"Attached by habit, by duty, and by gratitude to 
 the house of Constantine, he immediately gave the strongest
 assurances to the only surviving son of his late master that
 he would expose, with unshaken fidelity, his person and his
 troops to inflict a just revenge on the traitors of Gaul.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"Battle of Mursa, A.D. 351, Sept. 28.","('Mursa', 'PERSON'), ('351', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sept. 28', 'DATE')"
"Before he
 could reach a seaport in Spain, where he intended to embark,
 he was overtaken near Helena, (72) at the foot of the 
 Pyrenees, by a party of light cavalry, whose chief,
 regardless of the sanctity of a temple, executed his
 commission by the murder of the son of Constantine.(73)
Magnentius and Vetranio assume the purple, A.D. 350, March 1.","('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Helena', 'GPE'), ('72', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Vetranio', 'ORG'), ('350', 'CARDINAL'), ('March 1', 'DATE')"
"Besides the females and the allies of the
 Flavian house, ten or twelve males, to whom the language of
 modern courts would apply the title of princes of the blood,
 seemed, according to the order of their birth, to be
 destined either to inherit or to support the throne of
 Constantine.","('Flavian', 'NORP'), ('ten or twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"But
 Constantius, though he granted fair terms of pardon and
 reconciliation to all who abandoned the standard of
 rebellion,(93) avowed his inflexible resolution to inflict a 
 just punishment on the crimes of an assassin whom he
 prepared to overwhelm on every side by the effort of his
 victorious arms.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('93', 'DATE')"
"But
 the Romans derived more honour than advantage from this
 revolution.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"But
 the conclusion of his reign (according to the moderate and
 indeed tender sentence of a writer of the same age) degraded
 him from the rank which he had acquired among the most
 deserving of the Roman princes.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But
 the haughty usurper, careless of the remonstrances of his
 friends, gave orders that Philip should be detained as a
 captive, or at least as an hostage; while he despatched an
 officer to reproach Constantius with the weakness of his
 reign, and to insult him by the promise of a pardon if he
 would instantly abdicate the purple.","('Philip', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"But Helena, the aged mother of Constantine,
 lamented and revenged the untimely fate of her grandson
 Crispus; nor was it long before a real or pretended
 discovery was made that Fausta herself entertained a
 criminal connection with a slave belonging to the Imperial
 stables.(23) Her condemnation and punishment were the instant 
 consequences of the charge, and the adulteress was
 suffocated by the steam of a bath, which, for that purpose,
 had been heated to an extraordinary degree.(24)","('Helena', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('Fausta', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('23', 'CARDINAL'), ('24', 'CARDINAL')"
"But as many of the
 Armenian nobles still refused to abandon the plurality of
 their gods and of their wives, the public tranquillity was
 disturbed by a discontented faction, which insulted the
 feeble age of their sovereign, and impatiently expected the
 A.D. 342.","('Armenian', 'NORP'), ('342', 'CARDINAL')"
"But as soon as
 Sapor attained the age of manhood the presumptuous Thair,
 his nation, and his country, fell beneath the first effort
 of the young warrior, who used his victory with so judicious
 a mixture of rigour and clemency that he obtained from the
 fears and gratitude of the Arabs the title of Dhoulacnaf,
 or protector of the nation.(56)
State of Mesopotamia and Armenia.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Thair', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Dhoulacnaf', 'PERSON'), ('56', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mesopotamia', 'GPE'), ('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"But as soon as Constantius, after the battle of Mursa, became master of the
 seacoast of Dalmatia, a band of noble exiles, who had
 ventured to equip a fleet in some harbour of the Adriatic,
 sought protection and revenge in his victorious camp.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Mursa', 'PERSON'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC')"
"But in less than thirty years this numerous and
 increasing family was reduced to the persons of Constantius
 and Julian, who alone had survived a series of crimes and
 calamities such as the tragic poets have deplored in the
 devoted lines of Pelops and of Cadmus.","('less than thirty years', 'DATE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Pelops', 'PERSON'), ('Cadmus', 'PERSON')"
"But it was thought that the
 Sarmatians were sufficiently rewarded by their deliverance
 from impending ruin and the emperor, perhaps with too strict
 an economy, deducted some part of the expenses of the war
 from the customary gratifications which were allowed to that
 turbulent nation.","('Sarmatians', 'NORP')"
"But of
 the whole series of Roman princes in any age of the empire
 Hannibalianus alone was distinguished by the title of KING,
 a name which the subjects of Tiberius would have detested as
 the profane and cruel insult of capricious tyranny.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Hannibalianus', 'PERSON'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON')"
"But the Romans of the West soon rallied by the habits of discipline; and the barbarians of Germany
 supported the renown of their national bravery.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"But the far
 greater part of the distressed nation turned their eyes
 towards the fruitful provinces of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But the genius of Constantine
 himself had been formed by adversity and experience.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"But the legions of Vetranio were seduced, rather than
 provoked, by the example of rebellion; their leader soon
 betrayed a want of firmness or a want of sincerity, and his
 ambition derived a specious pretence from the approbation of
 the princess Constantina.","('Vetranio', 'NORP'), ('Constantina', 'PERSON')"
"But the memory of the cruelties exercised by his 
 ministers, after the unsuccessful revolt of Nepotian, had
 left a deep impression of horror and resentment on the minds
 of the Romans.","('Nepotian', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"But the prudent Sapor had watched
 the moment of victory.","('Sapor', 'PERSON')"
"But the royalty of the Flavian
 line, which had been first ennobled by the Gothic Claudius,
 descended through several generations; and Constantine
 himself derived from his royal father the hereditary honours
 which he transmitted to his children.","('Flavian', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Claudius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"But the vigilant citizens improved the
 opportunity of the night, and the return of day discovered a
 new wall of six feet in height rising every moment to fill
 up the interval of the breach.","('six feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('every moment', 'TIME')"
"By
 their secret intelligence with their countrymen, Rome and
 the Italian cities were persuaded to display the banners of
 Constantius on their walls.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'ORG')"
"By Fausta, the daughter of Maximian, he
 had three daughters, and three sons known by the kindred
 names of Constantine, Constantius, and Constans.","('Fausta', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Constans', 'PERSON')"
"By all the allurements of honours and
 rewards he invites informers of every degree to accuse,
 without exception, his magistrates or ministers, his friends
 or his most intimate favourites, protesting, with a solemn
 asseveration, that he himself will listen to the charge,
 that he himself will revenge his injuries; and concluding
 with a prayer, which discovers some apprehension of danger,
 that the providence of the Supreme Being may still continue
 to protect the safety of the emperor and of the empire.(12)
Disgrace and death of Crispus, A.D. 326, July","('the Supreme Being', 'ORG'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 326', 'DATE'), ('July', 'DATE')"
"By chastising the pride of the Goths, and by accepting the
 homage of a suppliant nation, Constantine asserted the
 majesty of the Roman empire; and the ambassadors of
 Aethiopia, Persia, and the most remote countries of India,
 congratulated the peace and prosperity of his government.(47)","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Aethiopia', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('India', 'GPE')"
"By his
 secrecy and diligence he entertained some hopes of
 surprising the person of Constans, who was pursuing in the
 adjacent forest his favourite amusement of hunting, or
 perhaps some pleasures of a more private and criminal
 nature.","('Constans', 'PERSON')"
"By some it 
 will perhaps be thought that the remembrance of a Conjugal
 union of twenty years, and the honour of their common
 offspring, the destined heirs of the throne, might have
 softened the obdurate heart of Constantine, and persuaded
 him to suffer his wife, however guilty she might appear, to
 expiate her offences in a solitary prison.","('Conjugal', 'NORP'), ('twenty years', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"By the
 grateful zeal of the Christians the deliverer of the church
 has been decorated with every attribute of a hero, and even
 of a saint; while the discontent of the vanquished party has
 compared Constantine to the most abhorred of those tyrants
 who, by their vice and weakness, dishonoured the Imperial
 purple.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"By the 
 labour of the Persians the course of the river was stopped
 below the town, and the waters were confined on every side
 by solid mounds of earth.","('Persians', 'NORP')"
"By the artful
 appearances of flight, Constantine was betrayed into an
 ambuscade, which had been concealed in a wood, where the
 rash youth, with a few attendants, was surprised,
 surrounded, and slain.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"By the death of Crispus the inheritance of the empire seemed
 to devolve on the three sons of Fausta, who have been
 already mentioned under the names of Constantine,
 Constantius, and of Constans.","('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Fausta', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Constans', 'PERSON')"
"By the prudence of Constantius, who,
 from the interview with his brothers in Pannonia,
 immediately hastened to the banks of the Euphrates, the
 legions were gradually restored to a sense of duty and
 discipline; but the season of anarchy had permitted Sapor to
 form the siege of Nisibis, and to occupy several of the most
 important fortresses of Mesopotamia. (58)","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Pannonia', 'GPE'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Nisibis', 'GPE'), ('Mesopotamia', 'LOC'), ('58', 'CARDINAL')"
"Character of Constantine 
 THE character of the prince who removed the seat of empire,
 and introduced such important changes into the civil and
 religious constitution of his country, has fixed the
 attention, and divided the opinions of mankind","('Constantine \r\n THE', 'PERSON')"
Character of Constantine— Gothic War—Death of Constantine— Division of the Empire among His Three Sons— Persian War— Tragic Deaths of Constantine the Younger and Constans— Usurpation of Magnentius— Civil War— Victory of Constantius.,"('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic War', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Death of Constantine', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persian War', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Tragic Deaths of Constantine the Younger and Constans— Usurpation of Magnentius— Civil War— Victory of Constantius', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Chosroes was a prince of a puny stature and a
 pusillanimous spirit.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON')"
"Civil war and death of Constantine, A.D. 340,March.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 340', 'DATE'), ('March', 'DATE')"
"Constantine survived that solemn
 festival about ten months; and, at the mature age of
 A.D. 337, May 22.sixty-four, after a short illness, he ended his memorable life at the palace of Aquyrion, in the suburbs of Nicomedia, whither he had retired for the benefit of the air, and with
 the hope of recruiting his exhausted strength by the use of
 the warm baths.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('about ten months', 'DATE'), ('A.D. 337', 'DATE'), ('May 22.sixty-four', 'DATE'), ('Aquyrion', 'FAC'), ('Nicomedia', 'GPE')"
"Constantine, the eldest of
 the Caesars, obtained, with a certain pre-eminence of rank,
 the possession of the new capital, which bore his own name
 and that of his father.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Caesars', 'ORG')"
"Constantius acknowledged him as a
 legitimate and equal colleague in the empire, on condition
 that he would renounce his disgraceful alliance with
 Magnentius, and appoint a place of interview on the
 frontiers of their respective provinces, where they might
 pledge their friendship by mutual vows of fidelity, and
 regulate by common consent the future operations of the
 civil war.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Magnentius', 'PERSON')"
"Constantius used his victory with
 prudence and moderation; and raising from the ground the aged suppliant, whom he affected to style by the endearing name of Father, he gave him his hand to descend from the throne.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"Constantius, who was
 hurried along in the pursuit, attempted, without effect, to
 restrain the ardour of his troops, by representing to them
 the dangers of the approaching night, and the certainty of
 completing their success with the return of day.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"Crispus soon had
 reason to complain that, while his infant brother
 Constantius was sent with the title of Caesar to reign over
 his peculiar department of the Gallic provinces,(11) he, a prince of mature years, who had performed such recent and
 signal services, instead of being raised to the superior
 rank of Augustus, was confined almost a prisoner to his
 father's court, and exposed, without power or defence, to
 every calumny which the malice of his enemies could suggest.","('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('11', 'CARDINAL'), ('years', 'DATE'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"During the greater part of the summer the tyrant of
 Gaul showed himself master of the field.","('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"During the long period of the reign of Constantius the
 provinces of the East were afflicted by the calamities of
 the Persian war.","('Constantius', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('the Persian war', 'EVENT')"
"Enraged by their former
 servitude, elated by their present glory, the slaves, under
 the name of Limigantes, claimed and usurped the possession
 of the country which they had saved.","('Limigantes', 'PERSON')"
"Every day, at the appointed hours,
 the principal officers of the state, the army, and the
 household, approaching the person of their sovereign with
 bended knees and a composed countenance, offered their
 respectful homage as seriously as if he had been still
 alive.","('the appointed hours', 'TIME')"
"Exasperated by this apparent neglect, the Sarmatians soon
 forgot, with the levity of barbarians, the services which
 they had so lately received, and the dangers which still
 threatened their safety.","('Sarmatians', 'NORP')"
"Expulsion of the Sarmatians, A.D. 334","('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('334', 'CARDINAL')"
"From motives of policy, this theatrical
 representation was for some time continued; nor could
 flattery neglect the opportunity of remarking that
 Constantine alone, by the peculiar indulgence of Heaven, had
 reigned after his death.(48)
Factions of the court.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('48', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the hands of the
 bishop of Nicomedia, Constantius received a fatal scroll,
 affirmed to be the genuine testament of his father; in which
 the emperor expressed his suspicions that he had been
 poisoned by his brothers; and conjured his sons to revenge
 his death, and to consult their own safety, by the
 punishment of the guilty.","('Nicomedia', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"Gallus and Julian afterwards became
 the most illustrious of the children of Julius Constantius,
 the Patrician.","('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Julius Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Patrician', 'NORP')"
"He
 fixed Dalmatius on the Gothic frontier, to which he annexed
 the government of Thrace, Macedonia, and Greece.","('Dalmatius', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Thrace', 'GPE'), ('Macedonia', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE')"
"He carried by assault the
 important town of Siscia; made an attack on the city of
 Sirmium, which lay in the rear of the Imperial camp;
 attempted to force a passage over the Save into the eastern
 provinces of Illyricum; and cut in pieces a numerous
 detachment which he had allured into the narrow passes of
 Adarne.","('Siscia', 'GPE'), ('Sirmium', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Illyricum', 'GPE'), ('Adarne', 'PERSON')"
"He contributed at least to improve this advantage by his
 negotiations with the free and warlike people of
 Chersonesus,(45) whose capital, situated on the western coast 
 of the Tauric or Crimaean peninsula, still retained some
 vestiges of a Grecian colony, and was governed by a
 perpetual magistrate, assisted by a council of senators,
 emphatically styled the Fathers of the City.","('Chersonesus', 'GPE'), ('45', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tauric', 'LOC'), ('Crimaean peninsula', 'LOC'), ('Grecian', 'NORP')"
"He died at length, after a reign of fifty-six years, and the fortune of the Armenian monarchy expired with Tiridates.","('fifty-six years', 'DATE'), ('Armenian', 'NORP'), ('Tiridates', 'PRODUCT')"
"He displayed, with some
 complacency, the glories of his Imperial race, and recalled
 to the memory of the troops the valour, the triumphs, the
 liberality of the great Constantine, to whose sons they had
 engaged their allegiance by an oath of fidelity, which the
 ingratitude of his most favoured servants had tempted them
 to violate.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"He first
 despatched a senator, in whose abilities he confided, and
 afterwards several bishops, whose holy character might
 obtain a more favourable audience, with the offer of
 resigning the purple, and the promise of devoting the
 remainder of his life to the services of the emperor.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"He often expressed his grateful sense of the goodness of Constantius, and, with a very amiable simplicity, advised his benefactor to resign the sceptre of the world, and to seek for content (where alone it could be found) in the peaceful obscurity of a private condition.(79)
Makes war against Magnentius, A.D. 351.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('79', 'CARDINAL'), ('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('351', 'CARDINAL')"
"He recommended the care of
 the East to his lieutenants, and afterwards to his cousin
 Gallus, whom he raised from a prison to a throne, and
 marched towards Europe, with a mind agitated by the conflict
 of hope and fear, of grief and indignation.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"He seems to have displayed the virtues of a general and of a soldier till the day was irrecoverably lost, and his camp in the possession of the enemy.","('the day', 'DATE')"
"He was unable to bring 
 another army into the field; the fidelity of his guards was
 corrupted; and when he appeared in public to animate them by
 his exhortations, he was saluted with an unanimous shout of
 ""Long live the emperor Constantius!""","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"His
 fond partiality towards some German captives, distinguished
 only by the charms of youth, was an object of scandal to the
 people;(70) and Magnentius, an ambitious soldier, who was 
 himself of barbarian extraction, was encouraged by the
 public discontent to assert the honour of the Roman name.(71)","('German', 'NORP'), ('70', 'CARDINAL'), ('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('71', 'CARDINAL')"
"His army, of which the greater part,
 securely posted on the heights, had been spectators of the
 action, advanced in silence and under the shadow of the
 night, and his Persian archers, guided by the illumination
 of the camp, poured a shower of arrows on a disarmed and
 licentious crowd.","('Persian', 'NORP')"
"His body, after it had been found in
 the obscure stream of the Alsa, obtained the honours of an
 Imperial sepulchre, but his provinces transferred their
 allegiance to the conqueror, who, refusing to admit his
 elder brother Constantius to any share in these new
 acquisitions, maintained the undisputed possession of more
 than two-thirds of the Roman empire.(69)
Murder of Constans, A.D. 350, February.","('Alsa', 'PRODUCT'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('more\r\n than two-thirds', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('69', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constans', 'PERSON'), ('350', 'CARDINAL'), ('February', 'DATE')"
"His cuirassiers are described as so many massy statues of steel, glittering with their scaly armour, and breaking with their ponderous lances the firm array of the Gallic legions.","('Gallic', 'NORP')"
"His destined
 successors had the misfortune of being born and educated in
 the Imperial purple.","('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"His formidable host, when it
 was drawn out in order of battle, covered the banks of the
 river, the adjacent heights, and the whole extent of a plain
 of above twelve miles which separated the two armies.","('above twelve miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"His lawful heir was driven into
 exile, the Christian priests were either murdered or
 expelled from their churches, the barbarous tribes of
 Albania were solicited to descend from their mountains, and
 two of the most powerful governors, usurping the ensigns or
 the powers of royalty, implored the assistance of Sapor, and
 opened the gates of their cities to the Persian garrisons.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Albania', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sapor', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"His minority was exposed to the almost inevitable calamities
 of domestic discord; his capital was surprised and plundered
 by Thair, a powerful king of Yemen or Arabia, and the
 majesty of the royal family was degraded by the captivity of
 a princess, the sister of the deceased king.","('Thair', 'PERSON'), ('Yemen', 'GPE'), ('Arabia', 'GPE')"
"His third sister, Constantia, was
 distinguished by her pre-eminence of greatness and of
 misery.","('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantia', 'PERSON')"
"His two elder brothers obtained in marriage the
 daughters of wealthy senators, and propagated new branches
 of the Imperial race.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"His unworthy favourites,  enriched by the boundless liberality of their master, usurped with impunity the privilege of rapine and
 corruption.(5) A secret but universal decay was felt in every  part of the public administration, and the emperor himself, though he still retained the obedience, gradually lost the
 esteem, of his subjects.","('5', 'CARDINAL')"
"If he reckoned among the favours of fortune the death of his
 eldest son, of his nephew, and perhaps of his wife, he
 enjoyed an uninterrupted flow of private as well as public
 felicity till the thirtieth year of his reign; a period
 which none of his predecessors; since Augustus, had been
 permitted to celebrate.","('the thirtieth year', 'DATE'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"If it were necessary to
 aggravate the horrors of this bloody scene, we might add
 that Constantius himself had espoused the daughter of his
 uncle Julius, and that he had bestowed his sister in
 marriage on his cousin Hannibalianus.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Julius', 'PERSON'), ('Hannibalianus', 'PERSON')"
"In
 the soft sequestered education of a Persian harem the royal
 youth could discover the importance of exercising the vigour
 of his mind and body, and by his personal merit deserved a
 throne on which he had been seated while he was yet
 unconscious of the duties and temptations of absolute power.","('Persian', 'NORP')"
"In Armenia the 
 renowned Tiridates had long enjoyed the peace and glory
 which he deserved by his valour and fidelity to the cause of
 Rome.","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Tiridates', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In consequence of this agreement, Vetranio
 advanced to the city of Sardica,(77) at the head of twenty 
 thousand horse, and of a more numerous body of infantry; a
 power so far superior to the forces of Constantius, that the
 Illyrian emperor appeared to command the life and fortunes
 of his rival, who, depending on the success of his private
 negotiations, had seduced the troops and undermined the
 throne of Vetranio.","('Vetranio', 'ORG'), ('Sardica', 'GPE'), ('77', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty \r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP'), ('Vetranio', 'PERSON')"
"In favour of the
 latter, Constantine invented the new and singular
 appellation of Nobilissimus, (30) to which he annexed the flattering distinction of a robe of purple and gold.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Nobilissimus', 'PERSON'), ('30', 'CARDINAL')"
"In his civil wars against Maxentius
 and Licinius he had engaged on his side the inclinations of
 the people, who compared the undissembled vices of those
 tyrants with the spirit of wisdom and justice which seemed
 to direct the general tenor of the administration of
 Constantine.(2)
His vices 
 Had Constantine fallen on the banks of the Tiber.","('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Had Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Tiber', 'LOC')"
"In his pathetic, but
 sometimes unmanly lamentations, (40) he describes in the most 
 lively colours the dress and manners, the arms and inroads;
 of the Getae and Sarmatians, who were associated for the
 purposes of destruction; and from the accounts of history
 there is some reason to believe that these Sarmatians were
 the Jazygae, one of the most numerous and warlike tribes of
 the nation.","('40', 'DATE'), ('Getae', 'NORP'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Jazygae', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"In such apparel, scarcely to be excused by
 the youth and folly of Elagabalus, we are at a loss to
 discover the wisdom of an aged monarch and the simplicity of
 a Roman veteran. (6)","('Elagabalus', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('6', 'CARDINAL')"
"In that of Constantine we may contemplate a
 hero, who had so long inspired his subjects with love and
 his enemies with terror, degenerating into a cruel and
 dissolute monarch, corrupted by his fortune, or raised by
 conquest above the necessity of dissimulation.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"In the
 free intercourse of private life, and amidst the dangers of
 the court of Galerius, he had learned to command his own
 passions, to encounter those of his equals, and to depend
 for his present safety and future greatness on the prudence
 and firmness of his personal conduct.","('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"In the
 presence of this formidable assembly the two emperors were
 called upon to explain the situation of public affairs: the
 precedency of rank was yielded to the royal birth of
 Constantius; and though he was indifferently skilled in the
 arts of rhetoric, he acquitted himself, under these
 difficult circumstances, with firmness, dexterity, and
 eloquence.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"In the civil war which
 broke out soon afterwards, the father and son divided their
 powers; and this history has already celebrated the valour
 as well as conduct displayed by the latter in forcing the
 straits of the Hellespont, so obstinately defended by the
 superior fleet of Licinius.","('the civil war', 'EVENT'), ('Hellespont', 'GPE'), ('Licinius', 'PRODUCT')"
"In the expressions of his gratitude towards the
 faithful Chersonites, the emperor was still more
 magnificent.","('Chersonites', 'PERSON')"
"In the meantime the Imperial troops 
 forced the passages of the Cottian Alps, and in the bloody
 combat of Mount Seleucus irrevocably fixed the title of
 rebels on the party of Magnentius.(98)","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('the Cottian Alps', 'LOC'), ('Mount Seleucus', 'LOC'), ('Magnentius', 'ORG'), ('98', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the meanwhile, the huge bodies of the Germans were exposed almost naked to the dexterity of the Oriental archers; and whole troops of those barbarians were urged by anguish and despair to precipitate
 themselves into the broad and rapid stream of the Drave.(86)","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('Drave', 'PRODUCT'), ('86', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the space of twelve years Nisibis, which,
 since the time of Lucullus, had been deservedly esteemed the
 bulwark of the East, sustained three memorable sieges A.D. 338,346,350.","('the space of twelve years', 'DATE'), ('Nisibis', 'PERSON'), ('Lucullus', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('338,346,350', 'CARDINAL')"
"In this advantageous position they watched or suspended the
 moment of attack, as they were provoked by injuries or
 appeased by presents; they gradually acquired the skill of
 using more dangerous weapons; and although the Sarmatians
 did not illustrate their name by any memorable exploits,
 they occasionally assisted their eastern and western
 neighbours, the Goths and the Germans, with a formidable
 body of cavalry.","('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"It was
 the object of Magnentius to tempt or to compel his adversary
 to relinquish this advantageous position; and he employed
 with that view the various marches, evolutions, and
 stratagems which the knowledge of the art of war could
 suggest to an experienced officer.","('Magnentius', 'PERSON')"
"It was an easy task
 to deceive the frankness and simplicity of Vetranio, who,
 fluctuating some time between the opposite views of honour
 and interest, displayed to the world the insincerity of his
 temper, and was insensibly engaged in the snares of an
 artful negotiation.","('Vetranio', 'PERSON')"
"Italy, the Western Illyricum, and
 Africa, were accustomed to revere Constans, the third of his
 sons, as the representative of the great Constantine.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Western Illyricum', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Constans', 'PERSON'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Like the 
 daughter of Minos, the daughter of Maximian accused her
 son-in-law of an incestuous attempt on the chastity of his
 father's wife and easily obtained, from the jealousy of the
 emperor, a sentence of death against a young prince whom she
 considered with reason as the most formidable rival of her
 own children.","('Minos', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"Magnentius had fixed his
 residence in the city of Aquileia, and showed a seeming
 resolution to dispute the passage of the mountains and
 morasses which fortified the confines of the Venetian
 province.","('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('Aquileia', 'GPE'), ('Venetian', 'NORP')"
"Magnentius then consulted his safety, and, throwing away the Imperial ornaments, escaped with some difficulty from the pursuit of the light horse, who incessantly followed his rapid flight from the banks of
 the Drave to the foot of the Julian Alps.(89)
Conquest of Italy, A.D. 352.","('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Drave', 'FAC'), ('the Julian Alps', 'LOC'), ('89', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('352', 'CARDINAL')"
"Magnentius, directing his march towards Mursa, set fire to the gates, and, by a sudden assault, had almost scaled the walls of the town.","('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('Mursa', 'PERSON')"
"Manners of the Sarmatians 
 Among the different branches of the human race, the
 Sarmatians form a very remarkable shade; as they seem to
 unite the manners of the Asiatic barbarians with the figure
 and complexion of the ancient inhabitants of Europe.","('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"Marcellinus, under the pretence of celebrating
 his son's birthday, gave a splendid entertainment to the
 illustrious and honourable persons of the court of Gaul,
 which then resided in the city of Autun.","('Marcellinus', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Autun', 'GPE')"
"Medals
 were struck with the customary vows for the long and
 auspicious reign of the young Caesar;(13) and as the people 
 who was not admitted into the secrets of the palace, still
 loved his virtues and respected his dignity, a poet, who
 solicits his recall from exile adores with equal devotion
 the majesty of the father and that of the son.(14)","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('13', 'CARDINAL'), ('14', 'CARDINAL')"
"Minervina, the obscure but lawful object of
 his youthful attachment, (7) had left him only one son, who 
 was called Crispus.","('Minervina', 'PERSON'), ('7', 'CARDINAL'), ('only one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Crispus', 'PERSON')"
"Notwithstanding the
 disappointment of his hopes and the loss of more than twenty
 thousand men, Sapor still pressed the reduction of Nisibis
 with an obstinate firmness which could have yielded only to
 the necessity of defending the eastern provinces of Persia
 against a formidable invasion of the Massagetae.(68)","('more than twenty\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Nisibis', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Massagetae', 'PERSON'), ('68', 'CARDINAL')"
"Notwithstanding the claims of the
 senate and people of ancient Rome, the corpse of the
 deceased emperor, according to his last request, was
 transported to the city which was destined to preserve the
 name and memory of its founder.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Notwithstanding the positive testimony of several writers of
 the Pagan as well as of the Christian religion, there may
 still remain some reason to believe, or at least to suspect,
 that Fausta escaped the blind and suspicious cruelty of her
 husband.","('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Fausta', 'PERSON')"
"Obedient to the
 requisition of Constantine, they prepared under the conduct
 of their magistrate Diogenes, a considerable army, of which
 the principal strength consisted in cross-bows and military
 chariots.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Diogenes', 'PERSON')"
"Obedient to the voice of superstition,
 the Persians prepared, without delay, the ceremony of his
 coronation.","('Persians', 'NORP')"
"Of so numerous a family, Gallus and Julian alone,
 the two youngest children of Julius Constantius, were saved
 from the hands of the assassins, till their rage, satiated
 with slaughter, had in some measure subsided.","('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julius Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"On a sudden the doors were thrown open, and
 Magnentius, who had retired for a few moments, returned into
 the apartment, invested with the diadem and purple.","('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('a few moments', 'TIME')"
"On his arrival
 at Heraclea in Thrace, the emperor gave audience to the
 ambassadors of Magnentius and Vetranio.","('Heraclea', 'GPE'), ('Thrace', 'GPE'), ('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('Vetranio', 'PERSON')"
"On the news of his brother's invasion he
 detached a select and disciplined body of his Illyrian
 troops, proposing to follow them in person with the
 remainder of his forces.","('Illyrian', 'NORP')"
"On this artificial lake a fleet of
 armed vessels, filled with soldiers, and with engines which
 discharged stones of five hundred pounds weight, advanced in
 order of battle, and engaged, almost upon a level, the
 troops which defended the ramparts","('five hundred pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"One of the ambassadors of the tyrant was dismissed with the haughty answer of Constantius; his colleagues, as unworthy of the privileges of the law of nations, were put in irons; and the contending powers prepared to wage an implacable war.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"Paul, surnamed Catena from his superior skill in
 the judicial exercise of tyranny, was sent to explore the
 latent remains of the conspiracy in the remote province of
 Britain.","('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Catena', 'PERSON'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"Peace was at length granted to their humble supplications;
 the eldest son of Araric was accepted as the most valuable
 hostage; and Constantine endeavoured to convince their
 chiefs, by a liberal distribution of honours and rewards,
 how far the friendship of the Romans was preferable to their
 enmity.","('Araric', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Perhaps it was without the consent of
 Constantina that the new emperor formed a necessary, though
 dishonourable, alliance with the usurper of the West, whose
 purple was so recently stained with her brother's blood.(75)
Constantius refuses to treat.","('Constantina', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"She remained the widow of the vanquished Licinius;
 and it was by her entreaties that an innocent boy, the
 offspring of their marriage, preserved, for sometime, his
 life, the title of Caesar, and a precarious hope of the
 succession.","('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"Should
 pride and mistaken piety urge him to refuse these equitable
 conditions, the ambassadors were ordered to expatiate on the
 inevitable ruin which must attend his rashness, if he
 ventured to provoke the sovereigns of the West to exert
 their superior strength, and to employ against him that
 valour, those abilities, and those legions, to which the
 house of Constantine had been indebted for so many triumphs.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Some of the fugitive Sarmatians solicited a less ignominious
 dependence under the hostile standard of the Goths.","('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"Soon
 after the reign of Augustus they obliged the Dacians, who
 subsisted by fishing on the banks of the river Theiss or
 Tibiscus, to retire into the hilly country, and to abandon
 to the victorious Sarmatians the fertile plains of the Upper
 Hungary, which are bounded by the course of the Danube and
 the semicircular enclosure of the Carpathian mountains.(41)","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Dacians', 'NORP'), ('Theiss', 'LOC'), ('Tibiscus', 'GPE'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('the Upper\r\n Hungary', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('the Carpathian mountains', 'LOC'), ('41', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such propositions and such arguments appeared to deserve the
 most serious attention; the answer of Constantius was
 deferred till the next day; and as he had reflected on the
 importance of justifying a civil war in the opinion of the
 people, he thus addressed his council, who listened with
 real or affected credulity:","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('the next day', 'DATE')"
"Such was the conduct, and such perhaps was the duty, of the
 brother of Constans towards the perfidious usurper of Gaul.","('Constans', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"That cruel and aspiring woman, who
 had obtained from the great Constantine, her father, the
 rank of Augusta, placed the diadem with her own hands on the
 head of the Illyrian general, and seemed to expect from his
 victory the accomplishment of those unbounded hopes of which
 she had been disappointed by the death of her husband
 Hannibalianus.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Augusta', 'GPE'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP'), ('Hannibalianus', 'PERSON')"
"That rash youth, the son of the princess
 Eutropia, and the nephew of Constantine, had seen with
 indignation the sceptre of the West usurped by a perfidious
 barbarian.","('Eutropia', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"The
 author of the conspiracy, Marcellinus, had long since
 disappeared in the battle of Mursa, (100) and the public 
 tranquillity was confirmed by the execution of the surviving
 leaders of a guilty and unsuccessful faction.","('Marcellinus', 'PERSON'), ('Mursa', 'PERSON'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 broken army of the Goths abandoned the field of battle, the
 wasted province, and the passage of the Danube: and although
 the eldest of the sons of Constantine was permitted to
 supply the place of his father, the A.D. 332, April 20.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('the A.D. 332', 'DATE'), ('April 20', 'DATE')"
"The
 citizens of Nisibis were animated by the exhortations of
 their bishop,(66) inured to arms by the presence of danger, 
 and convinced of the intentions of Sapor to plant a Persian
 colony in their room, and to lead them away into distant and
 barbarous captivity.","('Nisibis', 'GPE'), ('66', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The
 conspirators instantly saluted him with the titles of
 Augustus and Emperor.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 examination was short and private;(16) and as it was thought 
 decent to conceal the fate of the young prince from the eyes
 of the Roman people, he was sent under a strong guard to
 Pola, in Istria, where, soon afterwards, he was put to
 death, either by the hand of the executioner or by the more
 gentle operation of poison.(17) The Caesar Liciniuss, a youth 
 of amiable manners, was involved in the ruin of Crispus,(18) 
 and the stern jealousy of Constantine was unmoved by the
 prayers and tears of his favourite sister, pleading for the
 life of a son whose rank was his only crime, and whose loss
 she did not long survive.","('16', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Pola', 'LOC'), ('Istria', 'GPE'), ('The Caesar Liciniuss', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('18', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The
 experienced merit of a reigning monarch is acknowledged by
 his subjects with reluctance, and frequently denied with
 partial and discontented murmurs; while, from the opening
 virtues of his successor, they fondly conceive the most
 unbounded hopes of private as well as public felicity.(10)
Jealousy of Constantine.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The
 indulgence of Constantine admitted them, at a very tender
 age, to share the administration of the empire; and they
 studied the art of reigning, at the expense of the people
 intrusted to their care.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The
 ministers and generals who were placed about their persons
 were such as Constantine could trust to assist, and even to
 control, these youthful sovereigns in the exercise of their
 delegated power.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The
 most innocent subjects of the West were exposed to exile and
 confiscation, to death and torture; and as the timid are
 always cruel, the mind of Constantius was inaccessible to
 mercy.(101)","('West', 'LOC'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The
 pernicious tendency of the system introduced by Constantine
 was displayed in the feeble administration of his sons, who,
 by their vices and weakness, soon lost the esteem and
 affections of their people.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The
 unambitious brothers of the Great Constantine, Julius
 Constantius, Dalmatius, and Hannibalanus, (8) were permitted 
 to enjoy the most honourable rank and the most affluent
 fortune that could be consistent with a private station.","('the Great Constantine', 'ORG'), ('Julius\r\n Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Dalmatius', 'PERSON'), ('Hannibalanus', 'PERSON'), ('8', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 youngest of the three lived without a name and did without
 posterity.","('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"The 
 same assiduous cultivation was bestowed, though not perhaps
 with equal success, to improve the minds of the sons and
 nephews of Constantine.(33) The most celebrated professors of 
 the Christian faith, of the Grecian philosophy, and of the
 Roman jurisprudence, were invited by the liberality of the
 emperor, who reserved for himself the important task of
 instructing the royal youths in the science of government
 and the knowledge of mankind.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The 
 younger Dalmatius, who was united with his collateral
 relations by the ties of friendship and interest, is allowed
 to have inherited a considerable share of the abilities of
 the great Constantine; but, on this occasion, he does not
 appear to have concerted any measures for supporting by arms
 the just claims which himself and his royal brother derived
 from the liberality of their uncle.","('Dalmatius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The Asiatic pomp which had been adopted by the pride of Diocletian assumed an
 air of softness and effeminacy in the person of Constantine.","('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The Chersonites
 were animated against the Goths by the memory of the wars
 which, in the preceding century, they had maintained with
 unequal forces against the invaders of their country.","('Chersonites', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('the preceding century', 'DATE')"
"The Christian party, under the guidance of the archbishop of
 Artaxata, the immediate successor of St. Gregory the
 Illuminator, had recourse to the piety of Constantius.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Artaxata', 'GPE'), ('St. Gregory the\r\n Illuminator', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The Czar Peter, in the full possession of despotic
 power, submitted to the judgment of Russia, of Europe, and
 of posterity, the reasons which had compelled him to
 subscribe the condemnation of a criminal, or at least of a
 degenerate, son. (20)","('The Czar Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Russia', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('20', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Gothic war, A.lD. 331.","('The Gothic war', 'EVENT'), ('331', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Goths,
 vanquished on every side, were driven into the mountains,
 where, in the course of a severe campaign, above an hundred
 thousand were computed to have perished by cold and hunger.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('an hundred\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Great
 King, who, from an exalted throne, beheld the misfortunes of
 his arms, sounded, with reluctant indignation, the signal of
 the retreat, and suspended for some hours the prosecution of
 the attack.","('The Great\r\n King', 'PERSON'), ('some hours', 'TIME')"
"The Persian war, A.D. 337-360.","('The Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('337-360', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Persians were
 instantly driven to the assault, and the fate of Nisibis
 depended on the event of the day.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Nisibis', 'PERSON'), ('the day', 'DATE')"
"The Vandal princes were
 stimulated by fear and revenge; the Gothic kings aspired to
 extend their dominion from the Euxine to the frontiers of
 Germany; and the waters of the Maros, a small river which
 falls into the Theiss, were stained with the blood of the
 contending barbarians.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Euxine', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Maros', 'GPE'), ('Theiss', 'GPE')"
"The accumulated treasures
 found in the palaces of Maxentius and Licinius were lavishly
 consumed; the various innovations introduced by the
 conqueror were attended with an increasing expense, the cost
 of his buildings, his court, and his festivals required an
 immediate and plentiful supply; and the oppression of the
 people was the only fund which could support the
 magnificence of the sovereign.","('Maxentius', 'LOC'), ('Licinius', 'LOC')"
"The ambition of the Persian, to whom his enemies ascribe the
 virtues of a soldier and a statesman, was animated by the
 desire of revenging the disgrace of his fathers, and of
 wresting from the hands of the Romans the five provinces
 beyond the Tigris.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"The apprehensions of civil
 war were at length removed by the positive assurance of the
 Magi that the widow of Hormouz had conceived, and would
 safely produce a son.","('Magi', 'PERSON'), ('Hormouz', 'PERSON')"
"The approach of winter supplied the indolence of Constantius
 with specious reasons for referring the prosecution of the
 war till the ensuing spring.","('winter', 'DATE'), ('Constantius', 'GPE'), ('the ensuing spring', 'DATE')"
"The arguments by which they
 solicited the concurrence of the soldiers and people are of
 a more obvious nature: and they might with decency, as well
 as truth, insist on the superior rank of the children of
 Constantine, the danger of multiplying the number of
 sovereigns, and the impending mischiefs which threatened the
 republic, from the discord of so many rival princes who were
 not connected by the tender sympathy of fraternal affection.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The armies submitted to their
 hereditary right, and they condescended, after some delay,
 to accept from the Roman senate the title of Augustus.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"The authority of
 Magnentius was acknowledged through the whole extent of the
 two great praefectures of Gaul and Italy; and the usurper
 prepared, by every act of oppression, to collect a treasure
 which might discharge the obligation of an immense donative
 and supply the expenses of a civil war.","('Magnentius', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The behaviour of Constantius on this memorable occasion was
 celebrated with some appearance of justice; and his
 courtiers compared the studied orations which a Pericles or
 a Demosthenes addressed to the populace of Athens with the
 victorious eloquence which had persuaded an armed multitude
 to desert and depose the object of their partial choice.(80) 
 The approaching contest with Magnentius was of a more
 serious and bloody kind.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Pericles', 'PERSON'), ('Demosthenes', 'NORP'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('80', 'CARDINAL'), ('Magnentius', 'PERSON')"
"The body of Constantine,
 adorned with the vain symbols of greatness, the purple and
 diadem, was deposited on a golden bed in one of he
 apartments of the palace, which for that purpose had been
 splendidly furnished and illuminated.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The boundless ambition which, from the moment of his
 accepting the purple at York, appears as the ruling passion
 of his soul, may be justified by the dangers of his own
 situation, by the character of his rivals, by the
 consciousness of superior merit, and by the prospect that
 his success would enable him to restore peace and order to
 the distracted empire.","('York', 'GPE')"
"The care of his
 education, or at least of his studies, was intrusted to
 Lactantius, the most eloquent of the Christians; a preceptor
 admirably qualified to form the taste and to excite the
 virtues of his illustrious disciple.","('Lactantius', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"The care of their numerous flocks 
 and herds, the pursuit of game, and the exercise of war, or
 rather of rapine, directed the vagrant motions of the
 Sarmatians.","('Sarmatians', 'NORP')"
"The cavalry, the legions, and the
 auxiliaries of Italy, renewed their oath of allegiance to
 Constantius; and the usurper, alarmed by the general
 desertion, was compelled, with the remains of his faithful
 troops, to retire beyond the Alps into the provinces of
 Gaul.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'LOC')"
"The chiefs, who had secretly embraced
 the party of Constantius, prepared in his favour a public
 spectacle, calculated to discover and inflame the passions
 of the multitude. (78)","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('78', 'CARDINAL')"
"The chosen bands of Jovians and Herculians, who acknowledged
 Magnentius as their leader, maintained the most respectable
 and important station in the Imperial camp.","('Jovians', 'NORP'), ('Herculians', 'NORP'), ('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The city of
 Caesarea was chosen for the residence of Hannibalianus; and
 the provinces of Pontus, Cappadocia, and the Lesser Armenia,
 were designed to form the extent of his new kingdom.","('Caesarea', 'GPE'), ('Hannibalianus', 'GPE'), ('Pontus', 'LOC'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE'), ('the Lesser Armenia', 'LOC')"
"The city of Mursa, or Essek, celebrated in modern times for a bridge of boats, five miles in length, over the river Drave, and the adjacent morasses, (83) has been always  considered as a place of importance in the wars of Hungary.","('Mursa', 'GPE'), ('Essek', 'GPE'), ('five miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Drave', 'FAC'), ('83', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hungary', 'GPE')"
"The city of Prusa was assigned for the exile or
 retirement of the abdicated monarch, who lived six years in the enjoyment of ease and affluence.","('Prusa', 'GPE'), ('six years', 'DATE')"
"The contagion of loyalty and repentance
 was communicated from rank to rank, till the plain of
 Sardica resounded with the universal acclamation of The shout of thousands, their menacing gestures, the fierce clashing of their arms, astonished and subdued the courage of Vetranio, who stood, amidst the defection of his followers, in anxious and silent suspense.","('Sardica', 'PERSON'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('Vetranio', 'PERSON')"
"The danger and difficulties of the
 Scythian war engaged him soon afterwards to conclude, or at
 least to observe, a truce with the Roman emperor, which was
 equally grateful to both princes, as Constantius himself,
 after the deaths of his two brothers, was involved, by the
 revolutions of the West, in a civil contest which required
 and seemed to exceed the most vigorous exertion of his
 undivided strength.","('the\r\n Scythian war', 'EVENT'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"The death of Constantine was the signal
 of war,(57) and the actual condition of the Syrian and 
 Armenian frontier seemed to encourage the Persians by the
 prospect of a rich spoil and an easy conquest.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('57', 'CARDINAL'), ('Syrian', 'NORP'), ('Armenian', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"The deaths of
 Maximian and Licinius may perhaps be justified by the maxims
 of policy as they are taught in the schools of tyrants; but
 an impartial narrative of the executions, or rather murders,
 which sullied the declining age of Constantine, will suggest
 to our most candid thoughts the idea of a prince who could
 sacrifice, without reluctance, the laws of justice and the
 feelings of nature to the dictates either of his passions or
 of his interest.","('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The deaths of a son and of a nephew, with the
 execution of a great number of respectable and perhaps
 innocent friends,(27) who were involved in their fall, may be 
 sufficient, however, to justify the discontent of the Roman
 people, and to explain the satirical verses affixed to the
 palace gate, comparing the splendid and bloody reigns of
 Constantine and Nero.(28)","('27', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('28', 'CARDINAL')"
"The detachments, however, which were ordered either to
 press or to intercept the flight of Magnentius, conducted
 themselves with the usual imprudence of success; and allowed
 him, in the plains of Pavia, an opportunity of turning on
 his pursuers, and gratifying his despair by the carnage of a
 useless victory.(92)
Last defeat and death of Magnentius, A.D. 353, August 10..","('Magnentius', 'ORG'), ('Pavia', 'GPE'), ('92', 'CARDINAL'), ('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 353', 'DATE'), ('August 10', 'DATE')"
"The disadvantage of an illiterate education had
 not prevented him from forming a just estimate of the value
 of learning; and the arts and sciences derived some
 encouragement from the munificent protection of Constantine.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The eldest of those princes soon complained that he
 was defrauded of his just proportion of the spoils of their
 murdered kinsmen; and though he might yield to the superior
 guilt and merit of Constantius, he exacted from Constans the
 cession of the African provinces, as an equivalent for the
 rich countries of Macedonia and Greece which his brother had
 acquired by the death of Dalmatius.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('African', 'NORP'), ('Macedonia', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Dalmatius', 'PERSON')"
"The elephants,
 made furious by their wounds, increased the disorder, and
 trampled down thousands of the Persian archers.","('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The emperor
 Constantius, who, in the absence of his brothers, was the
 most obnoxious to guilt and reproach, discovered, on some
 future occasions, a faint and transient remorse for those
 cruelties which the perfidious counsels of his ministers and
 the irresistible violence of the troops, had extorted from
 his inexperienced youth.(53)
Division of the empire, A.D. 337, Sept. 11","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('53)\r\nDivision', 'ORG'), ('337', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sept. 11', 'DATE')"
The empress Fausta,"('Fausta', 'PERSON')"
"The event of a second and more 
 successful action retrieved the honour of the Roman name;
 and the powers of art and discipline prevailed, after an
 obstinate contest, over the efforts of irregular valour.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The event of the day was most commonly adverse to the Romans, but in
 A.D. 348 the battle of Singara their imprudent valour had almost achieved a signal and decisive victory.","('the day', 'DATE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 348', 'DATE'), ('Singara', 'PERSON')"
"The event of the two former sieges
 elated their confidence and exasperated the haughty spirit
 of the Great King, who advanced a third time towards
 Nisibis, at the head of the united forces of Persia and
 India.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Great King', 'PERSON'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Nisibis', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('India', 'GPE')"
"The example
 of the massacres of the palace diffused a spirit of
 licentiousness and sedition among the troops of the East,
 who were no longer restrained by their habits of obedience
 to a veteran commander.","('East', 'LOC')"
"The example of suicide was imitated by Decentius, who
 strangled himself on the news of his brother's death.","('Decentius', 'PERSON')"
"The fate of Constans himself was delayed about ten years
 longer, and the revenge of his brother's death was reserved
 for the more ignoble hand of a domestic traitor.","('Constans', 'PERSON'), ('about ten years\r\n longer', 'DATE')"
"The fertile plains
 (81) of the Lower Pannonia, between the Drave, the Save, and 
 the Danube, presented a spacious theatre; and the operations
 of the civil war were protracted during the summer months by
 the skill or timidity of the combatants.(82) Constantius had 
 declared his intention of deciding the quarrel in the fields
 of Cibalis, a name that would animate his troops by the
 remembrance of the victory which, on the same auspicious
 ground, had been obtained by the arms of his father
 Constantine Yet, by the impregnable fortifications with
 which the emperor encompassed his camp, he appeared to
 decline rather than to invite a general engagement.","('81', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Lower Pannonia', 'LOC'), ('Drave', 'FAC'), ('Save', 'FAC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('the summer months', 'DATE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Cibalis', 'GPE'), ('Constantine Yet', 'PERSON')"
"The field of battle round Mursa was a naked and level plain: on this ground the army of Constantius formed, with the Drave on their right; while their left, either from the nature of their disposition, or
 from the superiority of their cavalry, extended far beyond the right flank of Magnentius. (84)","('Mursa', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'GPE'), ('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('84', 'CARDINAL')"
"The firm alliance which he maintained with Constantine
 was productive of spiritual as well as of temporal benefits;
 by the conversion of Tiridates the character of a saint was
 applied to that of a hero, the Christian faith was preached
 and established from the Euphrates to the shores of the
 Caspian, and Armenia was attached to the empire by the
 double ties of policy and of religion.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Caspian', 'LOC'), ('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"The first author of
 the conspiracy, Marcellinus, who in some measure had
 bestowed the purple on his new master, boldly accepted this
 dangerous commission; and his three colleagues were selected
 from the illustrious personages of the state and army.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Marcellinus', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"The first part of his oration seemed to be
 pointed only against the tyrant of Gaul; but while he
 tragically lamented the cruel murder of Constans, he
 insinuated that none, except a brother, could claim a right
 to the succession of his brother.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Constans', 'PERSON')"
"The former celebrates the virtues, the
 beauty, and the fortune of the empress Fausta, the daughter,
 wife, sister, and mother of so many princes.(25)","('Fausta', 'PERSON'), ('25', 'CARDINAL')"
"The former was raised, by the title of
 Caesar, to an equality with his cousins.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"The friendship
 of Marcellinus, count of the sacred largesses, supplied with
 a liberal hand the means of seduction.","('Marcellinus', 'PERSON')"
"The general
 peace which he maintained during the last fourteen years of
 his A.D. 323-337 reign was a period of apparent splendour rather than of real prosperity; and the old age of Constantine was
 disgraced by the opposite yet reconcilable vices of
 rapaciousness and prodigality.","('the last fourteen years', 'DATE'), ('A.D. 323-337', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The guards hastened to
 take the oath of fidelity, the gates of the town were shut,
 and before the dawn of day Magnentius became master of the
 troops and treasure of the palace and city of Autun.","('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('Autun', 'GPE')"
"The honest indignation expressed by Martin,
 vice-praefect of the island, was interpreted as an evidence
 of his own guilt; and the governor was urged to the
 necessity of turning against his breast the sword with which
 he had been provoked to wound the Imperial minister.","('Martin', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The informers who complied with so liberal an invitation
 were sufficiently versed in the arts of courts to select the
 friends and adherents of Crispus as the guilty persons; nor
 is there any reason to distrust the veracity of the emperor
 who had promised an ample measure of revenge and punishment.","('Crispus', 'PERSON')"
"The innocence of Crispus was so universally acknowledged
 that the modern Greeks, who adore the memory of their
 founder, are reduced to palliate the guilt of a parricide
 which the common feelings of human nature forbade them to
 justify.","('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"The intelligence of these important events, which so deeply
 affected the honour and safety of the Imperial house,
 recalled the arms of Constantius from the inglorious
 prosecution of the Persian war.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'GPE'), ('the Persian war', 'EVENT')"
"The intemperance of
 the feast was artfully protracted till a very late hour of
 the night, and the unsuspecting guests were tempted to
 indulge themselves in a dangerous and guilty freedom of
 conversation.","('a very late hour of\r\n the night', 'TIME')"
"The intrigue was conducted with zeal and secrecy, till a
 loud and unanimous declaration was procured from the troops
 that they would suffer none except the sons of their
 lamented monarch to reign over the Roman empire.(49)","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The irregular incursions of the light
 troops alternately spread terror and devastation beyond the
 Tigris and beyond the Euphrates, from the gates of Ctesiphon
 to those of Antioch; and this active service was performed
 by the Arabs of the desert, who were divided in their
 interest and affections, some of their independent chiefs
 being enlisted in the party of Sapor, whilst others had
 engaged their doubtful fidelity to the emperor.(60)","('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Ctesiphon', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('60', 'CARDINAL')"
"The irresistible force of
 the waters was alternately fatal to the contending parties,
 till at length a portion of the walls, unable to sustain the
 accumulated pressure, gave way at once, and exposed an ample
 breach of one hundred and fifty feet.","('one hundred and fifty feet', 'QUANTITY')"
"The latter 
 asserts, in explicit terms, that the mother of the younger
 Constantine, who was slain three years after his father's
 death, survived to weep over the fate of her son. (26)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('three years', 'DATE')"
"The march of some
 regular forces put an end to his ambitious hopes: the
 rebellion was extinguished in the blood of Nepotian, of his
 mother Eutropia, and of his adherents; and the proscription
 was extended to all who had contracted a fatal alliance with
 the name and family of Constantine. (91)","('Nepotian', 'NORP'), ('Eutropia', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The martial
 countries of Illyricum, from the Danube to the extremity of
 Greece, had long obeyed the government of Vetranio, an aged
 general, beloved for the simplicity of his manners, and who
 had acquired some reputation by his experience and services
 in war.(74)","('Illyricum', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Vetranio', 'PERSON')"
"The massacre of the Flavian race was succeeded by a new
 division of the provinces, which was ratified in a personal
 interview of the three brothers.","('Flavian', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"The measures of Constans,
 who then resided in Dacia, were directed with more prudence
 and ability.","('Constans', 'PERSON'), ('Dacia', 'GPE')"
"The military fame of Constantine, and the
 real or apparent strength of his government, suspended the
 attack, and, while the hostile conduct of Sapor provoked the
 resentment, his artful negotiations amused the patience of
 the Imperial court.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The military strength of the nation was composed of
 cavalry; and the custom of their warriors to lead in their
 hand one or two spare horses enabled them to advance and to
 retreat with a rapid diligence, which surprised the
 security, and eluded the pursuit, of a distant enemy.(37)","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('37', 'CARDINAL')"
"The more 
 grave and important operations of the war were conducted
 with equal vigour; and the armies of Rome and Persia
 encountered each other in nine bloody fields, in two of
 which Constantius himself commanded in person. (61)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The negotiation of Philip was not, however, ineffectual, since he determined Sylvanus the Frank, a general of merit and reputation, to desert with a
 considerable body of cavalry a few days before the battle of Mursa.","('Philip', 'PERSON'), ('Sylvanus', 'PERSON'), ('Frank', 'PERSON'), ('a few days', 'DATE'), ('Mursa', 'PERSON')"
"The number of the slain was computed at fifty-four thousand men, and the slaughter of the conquerors was more
 considerable than that of the vanquished;(87) a circumstance  which proves the obstinacy of the contest, and justifies the observation of an ancient writer, that the forces of the empire were consumed in the fatal battle of Mursa, by the
 loss of a veteran army, sufficient to defend the frontiers, or to add new triumphs to the glory of Rome. (88)","('fifty-four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('87', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mursa', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('88', 'CARDINAL')"
"The offensive arms of the 
 Sarmatians were short daggers, long lances, and a weighty
 bow with a quiver of arrows.","('Sarmatians', 'NORP')"
"The officers, who surrounded the tribunal, and
 were instructed to act their parts in this extraordinary
 scene, confessed the irresistible power of reason and
 eloquence, by saluting the emperor Constantius as their
 lawful sovereign.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The ordinary machines, invented to batter or
 undermine the walls, were rendered ineffectual by the
 superior skill of the Romans, and many days had vainly
 elapsed when Sapor embraced a resolution worthy of an
 eastern monarch who believed that the elements themselves
 were subject to his power.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('many days', 'DATE'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON')"
"The person, as well as the mind, of Constantine had been
 enriched by nature with her choicest endowments.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The policy of Constantine maintained, however, the same
 appearances of regard and confidence towards a son whom he
 began to consider as his most irreconcilable enemy.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The pride assumed by Constans
 from the unmerited success of his arms was rendered more
 contemptible by his want of abilities and application.","('Constans', 'PERSON')"
"The pride of Magnentius was reduced, by repeated
 misfortunes, to sue, and to sue in vain, for peace.","('Magnentius', 'GPE')"
"The public favour,
 which seldom accompanies old age, diffused its lustre over
 the youth of Crispus.","('Crispus', 'PERSON')"
"The same fortune which so invariably followed the standard
 of Constantine seemed to secure the hopes and comforts of
 his domestic life.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The same ministers and generals who bowed with
 such reverential awe before the inanimate corpse of their
 deceased sovereign were engaged in secret consultations to
 exclude his two nephews, Dalmatius and Hannialianus, from
 the share which he had assigned them in the succession of
 the empire.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dalmatius', 'PERSON'), ('Hannialianus', 'PERSON')"
"The same passions have, in some degree, been
 perpetuated to succeeding generations, and the character of
 Constantine is considered, even in the present age, as an
 object either of satire or of panegyric.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
The signal victory which Constantius obtained is attributed to the arms of his cavalry.,"('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The sincerity of history(62) declares that 
 the Romans were vanquished with a dreadful slaughter, and
 that the flying remnant of the legions was exposed to the
 most intolerable hardships.","('62', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The situation and character of Vetranio admitted of milder
 measures; and the policy of the Eastern emperor was directed
 to disunite his antagonists, and to separate the forces of
 Illyricum from the cause of rebellion.","('Vetranio', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Illyricum', 'NORP')"
"The son of Sapor, the heir of his crown, had been made
 a captive in the Persian camp.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
The sons and nephews of Constantine,"('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The speedy march and intrepid attack of the
 Chersonites, by diverting the attention of the Goths,
 assisted the operations of the Imperial generals.","('Chersonites', 'PRODUCT'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The spirit, and even the forms, of
 legal proceedings were repeatedly violated in a promiscuous
 massacre; which involved the two uncles of Constantius,
 seven of his cousins, of whom Dalmatius and Hannibalianus
 were the most illustrious, the Patrician Optatus, who had
 married a sister of the late emperor, and the praefect
 Ablavius, whose power and riches had inspired him with some
 hopes of obtaining the purple.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dalmatius', 'PERSON'), ('Hannibalianus', 'PERSON'), ('Patrician', 'NORP'), ('Ablavius', 'PERSON')"
"The stationary troops of Singara retired on the approach of Sapor, who
 passed the Tigris over three bridges, and occupied near the
 village of Hilleh an advantageous camp, which, by the labour
 of his numerous pioneers, he surrounded in one day with a
 deep ditch and a lofty rampart.","('Singara', 'GPE'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hilleh', 'GPE'), ('one day', 'DATE')"
"The story of these unhappy
 princes, the nature and evidence of their guilt, the forms
 of their trial, and the circumstances of their death, were
 buried in mysterious obscurity, and the courtly bishop, who
 has celebrated in an elaborate work the virtues and piety of
 his hero, observes a prudent silence on the subject of these
 tragic events.(19) Such haughty contempt for the opinion of 
 mankind, whilst it imprints an indelible stain on the memory
 of Constantine, must remind us of the very different
 behaviour of one of the greatest monarchs of the present
 age.","('19', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The surprisal of a castle in the Alps by the
 secret march of the imperialists could scarcely have
 determined him to relinquish the possession of Italy, if the
 inclinations of the people had supported the cause of their
 tyrant.(90)","('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The temper of the 
 tyrant, which was never inclined to clemency, was urged by
 distress to exercise every act of oppression which could
 extort an immediate supply from the cities of Gaul.(95)","('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('95', 'CARDINAL')"
"The tender Ovid, after a youth spent in the enjoyment of
 fame and luxury, was condemned to an hopeless exile on the
 frozen banks of the Danube, where he was exposed, almost
 without defence, to the fury of these monsters of the
 desert, with whose stern spirits he feared that his gentle
 shade might hereafter be confounded.","('Ovid', 'PERSON'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"The time 
 was now arrived for celebrating the august ceremony of the
 twentieth year of the reign of Constantine and the emperor,
 for that purpose, removed his court from Nicomedia to Rome,
 where the most splendid preparations had been made for his
 reception.","('the\r\n twentieth year', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Nicomedia', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The tranquillity of the 
 last fourteen years of his reign was scarcely interrupted by
 the contemptible insurrection of a camel-driver in the
 island of Cyprus, (35) or by the active part which the policy 
 of Constantine engaged him to assume in the wars of the
 Goths and Sarmatians.","('the \r\n last fourteen years', 'DATE'), ('Cyprus', 'GPE'), ('35', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP')"
"The troops of
 Constantius were harassed and dispirited; his reputation
 declined in the eye of the world; and his pride condescended
 to solicit a treaty of peace, which would have resigned to
 the assassin of Constans the sovereignty of the provinces
 beyond the Alps.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Constans', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC')"
"The troops on both sides  remained under arms in anxious expectation during the greatest part of the morning; and the son of Constantine, after animating his soldiers by an eloquent speech, retired into a church at some distance from the field of battle, and committed to his generals the conduct of this decisive day.","('the morning', 'TIME'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The two sisters of the great
 Constantine, Anastasia and Eutropia, were bestowed on
 Optatus and Nepotianus, two senators of noble birth and of
 consular dignity.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Anastasia', 'PERSON'), ('Eutropia', 'PERSON'), ('Optatus', 'NORP'), ('Nepotianus', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The two sons of Dalmatius, who had been
 decorated with the vain title of Censor, were named
 Dalmatius and Hannibalianus.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dalmatius', 'PERSON'), ('Censor', 'ORG'), ('Dalmatius', 'PERSON'), ('Hannibalianus', 'PERSON')"
"The tyrant advanced by rapid
 marches to encounter Constantius, at the head of a numerous
 army, composed of Gauls and Spaniards, of Franks and Saxons;
 of those provincials who supplied the strength of the
 legions, and of those barbarians who were dreaded as the
 most formidable enemies of the republic.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('Spaniards', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Saxons', 'NORP')"
"The tyrant, who
 perceived that they were preparing to deserve pardon and
 rewards by the sacrifice of the most obnoxious criminal,
 prevented their design by falling on his sword;(99) a death 
 more easy and more honourable than he could hope to obtain
 from the hands of an enemy whose revenge would have been
 coloured with the specious pretence of justice and fraternal
 piety.","('99', 'CARDINAL')"
"The unhappy youth, who might
 have excited the compassion of the most savage enemy, was
 scourged, tortured, and publicly executed by the inhuman
 Romans.(63)
Siege of Nisbis.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('63', 'CARDINAL'), ('Siege of Nisbis', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"The use
 of such a title, even as it appears under the reign of
 Constantine, is a strange and unconnected fact, which can
 scarcely be admitted on the joint authority of Imperial
 medals and contemporary writers.(31)
Their education","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The vigilance of the garrison extinguished the flames; the approach of Constantius left him no time to continue the operations of the siege; and the emperor soon removed the only obstacle that could embarrass his motions, by forcing a body of troops which had taken post in an adjoining amphitheatre.","('Constantius', 'GPE')"
"The voice of the dying emperor had recommended the care of
 his funeral to the piety of Constantius; and that prince, by
 the vicinity of his eastern station, could easily prevent
 the diligence of his brothers, who resided in their distant
 governments of Italy and Gaul.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The want of sincerity
 which Constantine experienced in a tedious and fruitless
 negotiation exasperated the fierceness of his temper, and he
 eagerly listened to those favourites who suggested to him
 that his honour, as well as his interest.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The well-ordered ranks of Romans and
 barbarians, with drawn swords, or with erected spears, the
 squadrons of cavalry, and the cohorts of infantry,
 distinguished by the variety of their arms and ensigns,
 formed an immense circle around the tribunal; and the
 attentive silence which they preserved was sometimes
 interrupted by loud bursts of clamour or of applause.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The whole empire was deeply interested in the education of
 these five youths, the acknowledged successors of
 Constantine.","('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The wife of Hormouz remained pregnant at the time
 of her husband's death, and the uncertainty of the sex, as
 well as of the event, excited the ambitious hopes of the
 princes of the house of Sassan.","('Hormouz', 'PERSON'), ('Sassan', 'PERSON')"
"The younger Constantine was
 appointed to hold his court in Gaul; and his brother
 Constantius exchanged that department, the ancient patrimony
 of their father, for the more opulent, but less martial,
 countries of the East.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"Their 
 patience was at length exhausted; and Treves, the seat of
 Praetorian government, gave the signal of revolt, by
 shutting her gates against Decentius, who had been raised by
 his brother to the rank of either Caesar or of Augustus.(96) 
 From Treves, Decentius was obliged to retire to Sens, where
 he was soon surrounded by an army of Germans, whom the
 pernicious arts of Constantius had introduced into the civil
 dissensions of Rome. (97)","('Treves', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Decentius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Treves', 'PERSON'), ('Decentius', 'PERSON'), ('Sens', 'ORG'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'ORG'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('97', 'CARDINAL')"
"Their fate was
 suspended till the arrival of Constantius, the second,(50) 
 and perhaps the most favoured, of the sons of Constantine.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('50', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Their inroads on the territory of
 the empire provoked the indignation of Constantine to leave
 them to their fate; and he no longer opposed the ambition of
 Geberic, a renowned warrior, who had recently ascended the
 Gothic throne.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Geberic', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
Their settlement near the Danube.,"('Danube', 'LOC')"
"These
 deputies were instructed to soothe the resentment, and to
 alarm the fears, of Constantius.","('Constantius', 'ORG')"
"These alliances, which
 the policy of Constantine, regardless of the public
 prejudice,(52) had formed between the several branches of the 
 Imperial house, served only to convince mankind that these
 princes were as cold to the endearments of conjugal
 affection, as they were insensible to the ties of
 consanguinity and the moving entreaties of youth and
 innocence.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('52', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"These offers were enforced by the eloquence
 of Philip the Imperial ambassador; and the council as well
 as the army of Magnentius were disposed to accept them.","('Philip', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Magnentius', 'GPE')"
"These young princes were
 successively invested with the title of Caesar, and the
 dates of their promotion may be referred to the tenth, the
 twentieth, and the thirtieth years of the reign of their
 father.(29)","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('the tenth, the\r\n twentieth', 'DATE'), ('the thirtieth years', 'DATE'), ('29', 'CARDINAL')"
"They
 ascribe the misfortunes of Crispus to the arts of his
 stepmother, Fausta, whose implacable hatred or whose
 disappointed love renewed in the palace of Constantine the
 ancient tragedy of Hippolytus and of Phaedra.(22)","('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('Fausta', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Hippolytus', 'PERSON'), ('Phaedra', 'PERSON'), ('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"They
 were connected with the Romans by the mutual benefits of
 commerce; as they were supplied from the provinces of Asia
 with corn and manufactures, which they purchased with their
 only productions, salt, wax, and hides.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"They lived under the irregular aristocracy
 of their chieftains, (42) but after they had received into 
 their bosom the fugitive Vandals who yielded to the pressure
 of the Gothic power, they seem to have chosen a king from
 that nation, and from the illustrious race of the Astingi,
 who had formerly dwelt on the shores of the northern ocean.","('42', 'DATE'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Astingi', 'NORP')"
"They pretend that, as soon as the afflicted father
 discovered the falsehood of the accusation by which his
 credulity had been so fatally misled, he published to the
 world his repentance and remorse; that he mourned forty
 days, during which he abstained from the use of the bath and
 all the ordinary comforts of life; and that, for the lasting
 instruction of posterity, he erected a golden statue of
 Crispus, with this memorable inscription, - TO MY SON, WHOM
 I UNJUSTLY CONDEMNED. (21)","('forty\r\n days', 'DATE'), ('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('21', 'CARDINAL')"
"They were empowered to
 offer him the friendship and alliance of the western
 princes, to cement their union by a double marriage, - of
 Constantius with the daughter of Magnentius, and of
 Magnentius himself with the ambitious Constantina, - and to
 acknowledge in the treaty the pre-eminence of rank which
 might justly be claimed by the emperor of the East.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantina', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"They were reduced to the
 necessity of employing fish-bones for the points of their
 weapons; but the custom of dipping them in a venomous
 liquor, that poisoned the wounds which they inflicted, is
 alone sufficient to prove the most savage manners; since a
 people impressed with a sense of humanity would have
 abhorred so cruel a practice, and a nation skilled in the
 arts of war would have disdained so impotent a resource.(39) 
 Whenever these barbarians issued from their deserts in quest
 of prey, their shaggy beards, uncombed locks, the furs with
 which they were covered from head to foot, and their fierce
 countenancess which seemed to express the innate cruelty of
 their minds, inspired the more civilised provincials of Rome
 with horror and dismay.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"This conduct, though it tended to multiply the 
 future masters of the Roman world, might be excused by the
 partiality of paternal affection; but it is not so easy to
 understand the motives of the emperor, when he endangered
 the safety both of his family and of his people by the
 unnecessary elevation of his two nephews, Dalmatius and
 Hannibalianus.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dalmatius', 'PERSON'), ('Hannibalianus', 'PERSON')"
"This dangerous popularity soon excited the attention of
 Constantine, who, both as a father and as a king, was
 impatient of an equal.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"This large and populous city was situate about two days' journey from the Tigris, in the midst of a pleasant and fertile plain at the foot of Mount Masius.","(""about two days'"", 'DATE'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Mount Masius', 'LOC')"
"This naval victory contributed
 to determine the event of the war, and the names of
 Constantine and of Crispus were united in the joyful
 acclamations of their eastern subjects, who loudly
 proclaimed that the world had been subdued, and was now
 governed, by an emperor endowed with every virtue, and by
 his illustrious son, a prince beloved of Heaven, and the
 lively image of his father's perfections.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Crispus', 'PERSON')"
"Those among his predecessors who had
 enjoyed the longest and most prosperous reigns, Augustus,
 Trajan, and Diocletian, had been disappointed of posterity;
 and the frequent revolutions had never allowed sufficient
 time for any imperial family to grow up and multiply under
 the shade of the purple.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Those who
 occasionally mention the education or talents of Constantius
 allow that he excelled in the gymnastic arts of leaping and
 running; that he was a dexterous archer, a skilful horseman,
 and a master of all the different weapons used in the
 service either of the cavalry or of the infantry.(32)","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('32', 'CARDINAL')"
"Those who have attacked, and those who have defended, the
 character of Constantine, have alike disregarded two very
 remarkable passages of two orations pronounced under the
 succeeding reign.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Thrace and the countries of the East
 were allotted for the patrimony of Constantius; and Constans
 was acknowledged as the lawful sovereign of Italy, Africa,
 and the western Illyricum.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Constantius', 'LOC'), ('Constans', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Illyricum', 'LOC')"
"To secure this inglorious ease, he submitted to the
 conditions of peace which Sapor condescended to impose: the
 payment of an annual tribute, and the restitution of the
 fertile province of Atropatene, which the courage of
 Tiridates and the victorious arms of Galerius had annexed to
 the Armenian monarchy.(59)","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Atropatene', 'GPE'), ('Tiridates', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Armenian', 'NORP')"
"Unequal to the fatigues of war, averse
 to the society of mankind, he withdrew from his capital to a
 retired palace which he built on the banks of the river
 Eleutherus, and in the centre of a shady grove, where he
 consumed his vacant hours in the rural sports of hunting and
 hawking.","('Eleutherus', 'LOC'), ('hours', 'TIME')"
"Virtues of Crispus 
Crispus, the eldest son of Constantine, and the presumptive
 heir of the empire, is represented by impartial historians
 as an amiable and accomplished youth.","('Crispus \r\nCrispus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"We are too imperfectly acquainted with the court
 of Constantine to form any judgment of the real motives
 which influenced the leaders of the conspiracy; unless we
 should suppose that they were actuated by a spirit of
 jealousy and revenge against the praefect Ablavius, a proud
 favourite, who had long directed the counsels and abused the
 confidence of the late emperor.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Ablavius', 'PERSON')"
"Whatever advantages might attend the arms of Sapor in the
 field, though nine repeated victories diffused among the
 nations the fame of his valour and conduct, he could not
 hope to succeed in the execution of his designs while the
 fortified towns of Mesopotamia, and, above all, the strong
 and ancient city of Nisibis, remained in the possession of
 the Romans.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mesopotamia', 'GPE'), ('Nisibis', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"When
 they first assumed the reins of government, the eldest of
 these princes was twenty-one, the second twenty, and the
 third only seventeen, years of age.(54)
Sapor king of Persia, A.D. 310.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('twenty-one', 'CARDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('seventeen, years of age.(54', 'DATE'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('310', 'CARDINAL')"
