Sentence,Entities
(17),"('17', 'CARDINAL')"
(51),"('51', 'CARDINAL')"
(75),"('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 disgraceful treaty had resigned Armenia to the ambition of
 Sapor; and the scale of Persia appeared to preponderate.","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"A bishop and a deacon accused the archbishop of
 Constantinople; but the frivolous or improbable nature of
 the forty-seven articles which they presented against him
 may justly be considered as a fair and unexceptionable
 panegyric.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('forty-seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"A cruel and unjust law of treason, A.D. 397, September 4.","('A.D. 397', 'DATE'), ('September 4', 'DATE')"
"A light and active body of barbarian horse, disengaged
 from their infantry and baggage, might perform in eight or
 ten days a march of three hundred miles from the Hellespont
 to the Danube; (38) the garrisons of that important frontier 
 had been gradually annihilated; the river in the month of
 December would be deeply frozen; and the unbounded prospect
 of Scythia was open to the ambition of Gainas.","('eight or\r\n ten days', 'DATE'), ('three hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Hellespont', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('38', 'CARDINAL'), ('the month of\r\n December', 'DATE'), ('Scythia', 'ORG'), ('Gainas', 'PERSON')"
"A numerous council of the Eastern prelates, who were guided from a distance by the advice of Theophilus, confirmed the validity, without examining the justice, of the former sentence; and a detachment of barbarian troops was introduced into the city, to suppress the emotions of the people.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Theophilus', 'PERSON')"
"A private order was 
 despatched to the governor of Syria; and as the people might
 be unwilling to resign their favourite preacher, he was
 transported, with speed and secrecy, in a postchariot, from
 Antioch to Constantinople.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"A regular course of study and exercise was
 judiciously instituted; of the military exercises of riding,
 and shooting with the bow; of the liberal studies of
 grammar, rhetoric, and philosophy: the most skilful masters
 of the East ambitiously solicited the attention of their
 royal pupil, and several noble youths were introduced into
 the palace to animate his diligence by the emulation of
 friendship.","('East', 'LOC')"
"A seasonable 
 earthquake justified the interposition of Heaven; the
 torrent of sedition rolled forwards to the gates of the
 palace; and the empress, agitated by fear or remorse, threw
 herself at the feet of Arcadius, and confessed that the
 public safety could be purchased only by the restoration of
 Chrysostom.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('Chrysostom', 'PERSON')"
"A secret hope was
 entertained that the archbishop might perish in a difficult
 and dangerous march of seventy days in the heat of summer,
 through the provinces of Asia Minor, where he was
 continually threatened by the hostile attacks of the
 Isaurians, and the more implacable fury of the monks.","('seventy days', 'DATE'), ('summer', 'DATE'), ('Asia Minor', 'LOC'), ('Isaurians', 'NORP')"
"A truce of one hundred
 years was solemnly ratified; and although the revolutions of
 Armenia might threaten the public tranquillity, the
 essential conditions of this treaty were respected near
 four-score years by the successors of Constantine and
 Artaxerxes.","('one hundred\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('four-score years', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Artaxerxes', 'ORG')"
"About thirty years afterwards,
 Artasires, the nephew and successor of Chosroes, fell under
 the displeasure of the haughty and capricious nobles of
 Armenia; and they unanimously desired a Persian governor in
 the room of an unworthy king.","('About thirty years afterwards', 'DATE'), ('Artasires', 'PERSON'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"Abundantius was stripped of his ample fortunes by an Imperial rescript, and banished to Pityus, on the Euxine, the last frontier of the Roman world; where he subsisted by the precarious mercy of the barbarians till he could obtain, after the fall of Eutropius, a milder exile at Sidon in Phoenicia.","('Abundantius', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Pityus', 'NORP'), ('Euxine', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Eutropius', 'EVENT'), ('Sidon', 'GPE'), ('Phoenicia', 'GPE')"
"Administration and character of Eutropius, A.D. 395-399","('A.D. 395-399', 'DATE')"
"Administration of Anthemius, A.D. 408-415.","('Administration of Anthemius', 'ORG'), ('408-415', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a full experience of the vicissitudes of human
 life, the daughter of the philosopher Leontius expired at
 Jerusalem, in the sixty-seventh year of her age; protesting
 with her dying breath that she had never transgressed the
 bounds of innocence and friendship. (79)","('Leontius', 'PERSON'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('the sixty-seventh year', 'DATE')"
"After claiming for 
 himself the privilege of a veteran soldier, the eunuch
 intrusted the guard of Thrace and the Hellespont to Gainas
 the Goth, and the command of the Asiatic army to his
 favourite Leo; two generals who differently but effectually
 promoted the cause of the rebels.","('Thrace', 'PERSON'), ('Hellespont', 'NORP'), ('Gainas\r\n the Goth', 'PERSON'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the death of Arsaces, the Romans suppressed
 the regal government, and imposed on their allies the
 condition of subjects.","('Arsaces', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"After the destruction of his hopes and
 the loss of many thousands of his bravest soldiers, Gainas,
 who could no longer aspire to govern or to subdue the
 Romans, determined to resume the independence of a savage
 life.","('many thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gainas', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Although he struggled, according to the precepts of the
 Gospel, to love his private enemies, he indulged himself in
 the privilege of hating the enemies of God and of the
 church; and his sentiments were sometimes delivered with too
 much energy of countenance and expression.","('Gospel', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Among the generals and consuls of the East, Abundantius (12) had reason to dread the first effects  of the resentment of Eutropius.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Abundantius', 'PERSON'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Eutropius', 'ORG')"
"An order was despatched for the instant removal of Chrysostom to the extreme desert of Pityus: and his guards so faithfully obeyed their cruel instructions, that, before he reached the seacoast of the Euxine,  His death, A.D. 407, September 14.","('Chrysostom', 'PERSON'), ('Pityus', 'PERSON'), ('Euxine', 'PRODUCT'), ('A.D. 407', 'DATE'), ('September 14', 'DATE')"
Arcadius Emperor of the East.—,"('Arcadius Emperor of the East.', 'PERSON')"
"Arcadius and Honorius had been assisted by the guardian care
 of a parent, whose lessons were enforced by his authority
 and example.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON')"
"Arcadius considered, with anxious
 foresight, the helpless condition of his son Theodosius, who
 was no more than seven years of age, the dangerous factions
 of a minority, and the aspiring spirit of Jezdegerd, the
 Persian monarch.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('more than seven years of age', 'DATE'), ('Jezdegerd', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"Armenia divided between the Persians and the Romans, A.D. 431-440.","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('431-440', 'CARDINAL')"
Arsacius occupied the church of St. Sophia and the archiepiscopal throne.,"('Arsacius', 'PERSON'), ('St. Sophia', 'FAC')"
"As long as he despoiled the oppressors who 
 had enriched themselves with the plunder of the people,
 Eutropius might gratify his covetous disposition without
 much envy or injustice: but the progress of his rapine soon
 invaded the wealth which had been acquired by lawful
 inheritance or laudable industry.","('Eutropius', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as 
 the empress perceived that the affection of Theodosius was
 irretrievably lost, she requested the permission of retiring
 to the distant solitude of Jerusalem.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
"As soon as they had gained the middle
 of the stream, the Roman galleys, (37) impelled by the full 
 force of oars, of the current, and of a favourable wind,
 rushed forwards in compact order and with irresistible
 weight, and the Hellespont was covered with the fragments of
 the Gothic shipwreck.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('37', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hellespont', 'PRODUCT'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"At length, in
 the thirty-first year of his age, after a reign (if we may
 abuse that word) of thirteen years, three months, and
 fifteen days, Arcadius expired in the palace of
 Constantinople.","('the thirty-first year', 'DATE'), ('thirteen years', 'DATE'), ('three months', 'DATE'), ('fifteen days', 'DATE'), ('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"At the distance of one hundred and fifty years, this
 political question might be debated in the court of
 Justinian; but a prudent historian will refuse to examine
 the propriety, till he has ascertained the truth, of the
 testament of Arcadius.","('one hundred and fifty years', 'DATE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Arcadius', 'PERSON')"
"At the pious solicitation of the clergy and people of Constantinople,  His relics transported to Constantinople, A.D. 438, January 27 his relics, thirty years after his death, were transported from their obscure sepulchre to the royal city.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 438', 'DATE'), ('January 27', 'DATE'), ('thirty years', 'DATE')"
"Athenais, who
 was easily persuaded to renounce the errors of Paganism,
 received at her baptism the Christian name of Eudocia but
 the cautious Pulcheria withheld the title of Augusta till
 the wife of Theodosius had approved her fruitfulness by the
 birth of a daughter, who espoused fifteen years afterwards
 the emperor of the West.","('Athenais', 'PERSON'), ('Paganism', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Eudocia', 'PERSON'), ('Pulcheria', 'PERSON'), ('Augusta', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('fifteen years', 'DATE'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"Boldly declaring that vases of gold and silver
 are useless to a God who neither eats nor drinks, the
 generous prelate sold the plate of the church of Amida;
 employed the price in the redemption of seven thousand
 Persian captives; supplied their wants with affectionate
 liberality; and dismissed them to their native country, to
 inform their king of the true spirit of the religion which
 he persecuted.","('Amida', 'GPE'), ('seven thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"Born of a noble and opulent
 family in the capital of Syria, Chrysostom had been
 educated, by the care of a tender mother, under the tuition
 of the most skilful masters.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Chrysostom', 'PERSON')"
"But
 the desertion of his confederates, who were privately
 convinced of the justice and liberality of the Imperial
 ministers, obliged Uldin to repass the Danube: the tribe of
 the Scyrri, which composed his rearguard, was almost
 extirpated; and many thousand captives were dispersed, to
 cultivate, with servile labour, the fields of Asia. (66)","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Uldin', 'PERSON'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Scyrri', 'NORP'), ('many thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('66', 'CARDINAL')"
"But
 the royal race of Arsaces impatiently submitted to the house
 of Sassan; the turbulent nobles asserted, or betrayed, their
 hereditary independence; and the nation was still attached
 to the Christian princes of Constantinople.","('Arsaces', 'PERSON'), ('Sassan', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"But Fravitta attentively watched the progress
 of their undertaking.","('Fravitta', 'PERSON')"
"But Theodosius (72) was never 
 excited to support the weight and glory of an illustrious
 name; and, instead of aspiring to imitate his ancestors, he
 degenerated (if we may presume to measure the degrees of
 incapacity) below the weakness of his father and his uncle.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('72', 'DATE')"
"But a formidable ally appeared in arms to
 vindicate the majesty of the empire, and to guard the peace
 and liberty of Scythia. (39)","('Scythia', 'PERSON'), ('39', 'CARDINAL')"
"But as
 the pyramid rose towards the summit, it insensibly
 diminished to a point; and the magistrates, the ministers,
 the favourite eunuchs, the ladies of the court, (43) the 
 empress Eudoxia herself, had a much larger share of guilt to
 divide among a smaller proportion of criminals.","('43', 'DATE'), ('Eudoxia', 'PERSON')"
"But as this form of trial might be deemed partial and arbitrary, the further inquiry into the crimes of Timasius was delegated to Saturnius and Procopius; the former of consular rank, the latter still respected as the father-in-law of the emperor Valens.","('Timasius', 'PERSON'), ('Saturnius', 'PERSON'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"But the Romans had so long been accustomed to the authority of a monarch, that the first, even among the females of the Imperial family, who displayed any courage or capacity, was permitted to ascend the vacant throne of Theodosius.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"But the unfortunate prince who is born in the
 purple must remain a stranger to the voice of truth; and the
 son of Arcadius was condemned to pass his perpetual infancy
 encompassed only by a servile train of women and eunuchs.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON')"
"But the ungrateful Bargus, instead of being suffered to possess the reward of guilt, was soon afterwards circumvented and destroyed by the more powerful villainy of the minister himself, who retained sense and spirit enough to abhor the instrument of his own crimes.","('Bargus', 'PERSON')"
"But the weakness of Honorius, and the
 calamities of his reign, disqualified him from prosecuting
 this natural claim; and such was the absolute separation of
 the two monarchies, both in interest and affection, that
 Constantinople would have obeyed with less reluctance the
 orders of the Persian, than those of the Italian court.","('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
"But the whole body of Imperial dependents claimed a privilege, or rather impunity, which screened them in the loosest moments of their lives from the hasty, perhaps the justifiable, resentment of their fellow-citizens: and, by a strange perversion of the laws, the same degree of guilt and punishment was applied to a private quarrel and to a deliberate conspiracy against the emperor and the empire.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"But their implacable revenge still envied him the last
 moments of a miserable life, and Eutropius had no sooner
 touched the shores of Cyprus than he was hastily recalled.","('Eutropius', 'PERSON'), ('Cyprus', 'GPE')"
"But this pilgrimage was the fatal term of the glories of
 Eudocia.","('Eudocia', 'PERSON')"
"By the private 
 invitation of the empress, Theophilus landed at
 Constantinople, with a stout body of Egyptian mariners, to
 encounter the populace; and a train of dependent bishops, to
 secure by their voices the majority of a synod.","('Theophilus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP')"
"Careless of the dignity of their 
 sovereign, the new ministers of the palace immediately
 published an edict, to declare that his late favourite had
 disgraced the names of consul and patrician, to abolish his
 statues, to ,confiscate his wealth, and to inflict a
 perpetual exile in the island of Cyprus. (31)","('Cyprus', 'GPE'), ('31', 'CARDINAL')"
"Character and adventures of the empress Eudocia, A.D. 421-460.","('Eudocia', 'PERSON'), ('421-460', 'CARDINAL')"
"Chosroes, the Persian vassal, reigned over the eastern and most extensive portion of the country; while the western province acknowledged the
 jurisdiction of Arsaces, and the supremacy of the emperor
 Arcadius.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Arsaces', 'GPE'), ('Arcadius', 'PERSON')"
"Chrysostom is persecuted by the empress Eudocia, A.D. 403.","('Chrysostom', 'PERSON'), ('Eudocia', 'PERSON'), ('403', 'CARDINAL')"
Chrysostom was naturally of a choleric disposition. (44),"('Chrysostom', 'PERSON')"
"Cicero might claim some merit if his voluntary banishment
 preserved the peace of the republic; (53) but the submission 
 of a Chrysostom was the indispensable duty of a Christian
 and a subject.","('Cicero', 'PERSON'), ('53', 'CARDINAL'), ('Chrysostom', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"Conscious of the
 purity of his intentions, and perhaps of the superiority of
 his genius, the archbishop of Constantinople extended the
 jurisdiction of the Imperial city, that he might enlarge the
 sphere of his pastoral labours; and the conduct which the
 profane imputed to an ambitious motive, appeared to
 Chrysostom himself in the light of a sacred and
 indispensable duty.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Chrysostom', 'PERSON')"
"Conspiracy and fall of Gainas, A.D. 400","('Gainas', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 400', 'DATE')"
December 23.,"('December 23', 'DATE')"
"During the
 absence of Gainas his troops were surprised and oppressed;
 seven thousand barbarians perished in this bloody massacre.","('Gainas', 'PERSON'), ('seven thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Ecclesiastical history describes the splendid churches which were built at the expense of Pulcheria in all the provinces of the East, her charitable foundations for the benefit of strangers and the poor, the ample donations which she assigned for the perpetual maintenance of monastic societies, and the active severity with which she laboured to suppress the opposite heresies of Nestorius and Eutyches.","('Pulcheria', 'LOC'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Nestorius', 'PERSON'), ('Eutyches', 'PERSON')"
Education and character of Theodosius the younger.,"('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Election and merit of Chrysostom, A.D. 398, February 26
 After the death of the indolent Nectarius, the successor of
 Gregory Nazianzen, the church of Constantinople was
 distracted by the ambition of rival candidates, who were not
 ashamed to solicit, with gold or flattery, the suffrage of
 the people or of the favourite.","('Chrysostom', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 398', 'DATE'), ('February 26', 'DATE'), ('Nectarius', 'PERSON'), ('Gregory Nazianzen', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Eleven days
 after the naval victory of the Hellespont, the head of
 Gainas, the inestimable gift of the conqueror, was received
 at Constantinople with the most liberal expressions of
 gratitude; and the public deliverance was celebrated by
 festivals and illuminations.","('Eleven days', 'DATE'), ('Hellespont', 'PERSON'), ('Gainas', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Eudocia composed a poetical paraphrase of the first eight
 books of the Old Testament and of the prophecies of Daniel
 and Zechariah; a cento of the verses of Homer, applied to
 the life and miracles of Christ, the legend of St. Cyprian,
 and a panegyric on the Persian victories of Theodosius; and
 her writings, which were applauded by a servile and
 superstitious age, have not been disdained by the candour of
 impartial criticism.","('Eudocia', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Old Testament', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Daniel', 'PERSON'), ('Zechariah', 'PERSON'), ('Homer', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('St. Cyprian', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Eudocia instantly revenged them by the assassination of the
 count: the furious passions which she indulged on this
 suspicious occasion seemed to justify the severity of
 Theodosius; and the empress, ignominiously stripped of the
 honours of her rank, (78) was disgraced, perhaps unjustly, in 
 the eyes of the world.","('Eudocia', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('78', 'DATE')"
"Eudoxia was a young and beautiful woman, who
 indulged her passions and despised her husband: Count John
 enjoyed, at least, the familiar confidence of the empress;
 and the public named him as the real father of Theodosius
 the younger. (59)","('Eudoxia', 'PERSON'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
Eutropius was the first of his artificial sex who dared to assume the character of a Roman magistrate and general.,"('Eutropius', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Every quarter of Constantinople was filled with tumult 
 and disorder; and the barbarians gazed with such ardour on
 the rich shops of the jewellers and the tables of the
 bankers which were covered with gold and silver, that it was
 judged prudent to remove those dangerous temptations from
 their sight.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Fall of Eutropius, A.D. 399","('A.D. 399', 'DATE')"
"Four successive summons were signified to
 Chrysostom; but he still refused to trust either his person
 or his reputation in the hands of his implacable enemies,
 who, prudently declining the examination of any particular
 charges, condemned his contumacious disobedience, and
 hastily pronounced a sentence of deposition.","('Four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Chrysostom', 'PERSON')"
"From a motive either of prudence or religion, she embraced a life of celibacy; and notwithstanding some aspersions on the chastity of Pulcheria, (69) this resolution, which she communicated to her sisters Arcadia and Marina, was celebrated by the Christian world as the sublime effort of heroic piety.","('Pulcheria', 'PERSON'), ('69', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arcadia', 'PERSON'), ('Marina', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"From that solitude the
 archbishop, whose active mind was invigorated by
 misfortunes, maintained a strict and frequent correspondence
  (54) with the most distant provinces; exhorted the separate 
 congregation of his faithful adherents to persevere in their
 allegiance; urged the destruction of the temples of
 Phoenicia, and the extirpation of heresy in the isle of
 Cyprus; extended his pastoral care to the missions of Persia
 and Scythia; negotiated, by his ambassadors, with the Roman
 pontiff and the emperor Honorius; and boldly appealed, from
 a partial synod, to the supreme tribunal of a free and
 general council.","('Phoenicia', 'GPE'), ('Cyprus', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON')"
"From these panegyrics the historians (81) of the 
 age might borrow their extraordinary, and perhaps fabulous,
 tales of the proud challenge of a Persian hero, who was
 entangled by the net, and despatched by the sword, of
 Areobindus the Goth; of the ten thousand Immortals, who
 were slain in the attack of the Roman camp; and of the
 hundred thousand Arabs, or Saracens, who were impelled by a
 panic terror to throw themselves headlong into the
 Euphrates.","('81', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Areobindus', 'NORP'), ('Goth', 'NORP'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Immortals', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('the\r\n hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"Gainas bowed with reverence at the feet of the emperor,
 whilst he required the sacrifice of Aurelian and Saturninus,
 two ministers of consular rank and their naked necks were
 exposed by the haughty rebel to the edge of the sword, till
 he condescended to grant them a precarious and disgraceful
 respite.","('Gainas', 'PERSON'), ('Aurelian', 'NORP'), ('Saturninus', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Gainas was either
 innocent of the design or too confident of his success; he
 was astonished by the intelligence that the flower of his
 army had been ingloriously destroyed; that he himself was
 declared a public enemy; and that his countryman Fravitta, a
 brave and loyal confederate, had assumed the management of
 the war by sea and land.","('Gainas', 'PERSON'), ('Fravitta', 'PERSON')"
"He
 deplored the manifest and inexcusable vices of Artasires;
 and declared that he should not hesitate to accuse him
 before the tribunal of a Christian emperor, who would
 punish, without destroying, the sinner Exasperated by the firmness of Isaac, the factious nobles accused both the king and the archbishop as the secret adherents of the emperor; and absurdly rejoiced in the sentence of condemnation, which, after a partial hearing, was solemnly pronounced by Bahram himself.","('Artasires', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Isaac', 'PERSON'), ('Bahram', 'PERSON')"
"He had
 condemned from the pulpit the domestic females of the clergy
 of Constantinople, who, under the name of servants or
 sisters, afforded a perpetual occasion either of sin or of
 scandal.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
He had been guilty of the unpardonable crime of introducing that abject slave to the palace of Constantinople; and some degree of praise must be allowed to a powerful and ungrateful favourite who was satisfied with the disgrace of his benefactor.,"('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"He still
 maintained, from some considerations of health or
 abstinence, his former habits of taking his repasts alone;
 and this inhospitable custom, (45) which his enemies imputed 
 to pride, contributed at least to nourish the infirmity of a
 morose and unsocial humour.","('45', 'CARDINAL')"
"He studied the art of rhetoric
 in the school of Libanius; and that celebrated sophist, who
 soon discovered the talents of his disciple, ingenuously
 confessed that John would have deserved to succeed him had
 he not been stolen away by the Christians.","('Libanius', 'NORP'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"He was destitute of vessels, but the
 woods of the Chersonesus afforded materials for rafts, and
 his intrepid barbarians did not refuse to trust themselves
 to the waves.","('Chersonesus', 'PRODUCT')"
"He was promoted to the rank of patrician, which began to signify, in a popular and even legal acceptation, the father of the emperor: and the last year of the fourth century was polluted by the consulship of an eunuch and a slave.","('the last year of the fourth century', 'DATE')"
"Her
 ostentatious progress through the East may seem inconsistent
 with the spirit of Christian humility: she pronounced from a
 throne of gold and gems an eloquent oration to the senate of
 Antioch, declared her royal intention of enlarging the walls
 of the city, bestowed a donative of two hundred pounds of
 gold to restore the public baths, and accepted the statues
 which were decreed by the gratitude of Antioch.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('two hundred pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
His Sister Pulcheria.—,"('Pulcheria', 'PERSON')"
"His administration and defects, A.D. 398-403.","('398-403', 'CARDINAL')"
"His character was consecrated by
 absence and persecution; the faults of his administration
 were no longer remembered; but every tongue repeated the
 praises of his genius and virtue: and the respectful
 attention of the Christian world was fixed on a desert spot
 among the mountains of Taurus.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Taurus', 'LOC')"
"His former habits of life had not introduced him to the study of the laws or the exercises of the field; his awkward and unsuccessful attempts provoked the secret contempt of the spectators; the Goths expressed their wish that such a general might always command the armies of Rome; and the name of the minister was branded with ridicule, more pernicious, perhaps, than hatred to a public character.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"His immense riches were confiscated in the name of the emperor and for the benefit of the favourite; and he was doomed to perpetual exile at Oasis, a solitary spot in the midst of the sandy deserts of Libya. (14)","('Oasis', 'LOC'), ('Libya', 'GPE'), ('14', 'CARDINAL')"
"His imprudence tempted his enemies to inflame the haughty Spirit of Eudoxia, by reporting, or perhaps inventing, the famous exordium of a sermon, ""Herodias is again furious; Herodias again dances; she once more requires the head of John:""  an insolent allusion, which, as a woman and a sovereign, it was impossible for her to forgive.","('Spirit of Eudoxia', 'ORG'), ('Herodias', 'PERSON'), ('Herodias', 'PERSON'), ('John', 'PERSON')"
"His infirmities compelled him to return to the society of
 mankind; and the authority of Meletius devoted his talents
 to the service of the church: but in the midst of his
 family, and afterwards on the archiepiscopal throne,
 Chrysostom still persevered in the practice of the monastic
 virtues.","('Meletius', 'PERSON'), ('Chrysostom', 'PERSON')"
"His national dislike to the rising greatness of
 a city which degraded him from the second to the third rank
 in the Christian world was exasperated by some personal
 disputes with Chrysostom himself. (48)","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Chrysostom', 'PERSON')"
"His piety soon
 disposed him to receive the sacrament of baptism; to
 renounce the lucrative and honourable profession of the law;
 and to bury himself in the adjacent desert, where he subdued
 the lusts of the flesh by an austere penance of six years.","('six years', 'DATE')"
"His rapid progress
 was checked by the resistance of the peasants of Pamphylia;
 and the Ostrogoths, attacked in a narrow pass between the
 city of Selgae (24) a deep morass, and the craggy cliffs of 
 Mount Taurus, were defeated with the loss of their bravest
 troops.","('Pamphylia', 'GPE'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP'), ('Selgae', 'GPE'), ('24', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mount Taurus', 'LOC')"
"His sister Pulcheria, (68) who was only two years older than himself, received at the age of sixteen the title of
  Augusta; and though her favour might be sometimes clouded by caprice or intrigue, she continued to govern the Eastern empire near forty years; during the long minority of her brother, and after his death in her own name, and in the name of Marcian, her nominal husband.","('Pulcheria', 'PERSON'), ('68', 'DATE'), ('two years', 'DATE'), ('sixteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Augusta', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('forty years', 'DATE'), ('Marcian', 'PERSON')"
"His zeal and obstinacy were revenged on his 
 brethren: the Magi excited a cruel persecution; and the
 intolerant zeal of Jezdegerd was imitated by his son
 Varahes, or Bahram, who soon afterwards ascended the throne.","('Magi', 'PERSON'), ('Jezdegerd', 'PERSON'), ('Varahes', 'PERSON'), ('Bahram', 'PERSON')"
"Hunting was the only
 active pursuit that could tempt him beyond the limits of the
 palace; but he most assiduously laboured, sometimes by the
 light of a midnight lamp, in the mechanic occupations of
 painting and carving; and the elegance with which he
 transcribed religious books entitled the Roman emperor to
 the singular epithet of Calligraphes, or a fair writer.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Calligraphes', 'PERSON')"
"If he descended towards the sea, they
 imputed, and perhaps suggested, to the Gothic chief the more
 dangerous project of arming a fleet in the harbours of
 Ionia, and of extending his depredations along the maritime
 coast, from the mouth of the Nile to the port of
 Constantinople.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Ionia', 'GPE'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"If they
 were guilty, the numerous associates of their guilt would
 soon discover that their own safety depended on the ruin of
 the archbishop, whom they studied to represent as the tyrant
 of the Eastern church.","('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"Ignorant, or careless, of the impending danger, Chrysostom indulged his zeal, or perhaps his resentment; declaimed with peculiar asperity against female vices; and condemned the profane honours which were addressed, almost in the precincts of St. Sophia, to the statue of the empress.","('Chrysostom', 'PERSON'), ('St. Sophia', 'GPE')"
"In 
 the midst of the public triumph, Constantinople was
 protected by a strong enclosure of new and more extensive
 walls; the same vigilant care was applied to restore the
 fortifications of the Illyrian cities; and a plan was
 judiciously conceived, which, in the space of seven years,
 would have secured the command of the Danube, by
 establishing on that river a perpetual fleet of two hundred
 and fifty armed vessels. (67)
Character and administration of Pulcheria, A.D. 414-453.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP'), ('seven years', 'DATE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('two hundred\r\n and fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('67', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pulcheria', 'PRODUCT'), ('414-453', 'CARDINAL')"
"In a late journey into the East he had
 admired the sermons of John, a native and presbyter of
 Antioch, whose name has been distinguished by the epithet of
 Chrysostom, or the Golden Mouth. (41)","('East', 'LOC'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Chrysostom', 'PERSON'), ('the Golden Mouth', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('41', 'CARDINAL')"
"In his early youth Gainas had passed
 the Danube as a suppliant and a fugitive: his elevation had
 been the work of valour and fortune, and his indiscreet or
 perfidious conduct was the cause of his rapid downfall.","('Gainas', 'PERSON'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"In his visitation through the Asiatic
 provinces he deposed thirteen bishops of Lydia and Phrygia;
 and indiscreetly declared that a deep corruption of simony
 and licentiousness had infected the whole episcopal order.
 (46)","('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('thirteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Lydia', 'PERSON'), ('Phrygia', 'PERSON')"
"In less
 than four years afterwards, Eudoxia, in the bloom of youth,
 was destroyed by the consequences of a miscarriage; and this
 untimely death confounded the prophecy of a holy bishop, (60) 
 who, amidst the universal joy, had ventured to foretell that
 she should behold the long and auspicious reign of her
 glorious son.","('less\r\n than four years afterwards', 'DATE'), ('Eudoxia', 'GPE'), ('60', 'DATE')"
"In the Holy
 Land her alms and pious foundations exceeded the munificence
 of the great Helena; and though the public treasure might be
 impoverished by this excessive liberality, she enjoyed the
 conscious satisfaction of returning to Constantinople with
 the chains of St. Peter, the right arm of St. Stephen, and
 the undoubted picture of the Virgin, painted by St. Luke. (76)","('Helena', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('St. Peter', 'ORG'), ('St. Stephen', 'GPE'), ('Virgin', 'PERSON'), ('St. Luke', 'GPE')"
"In the beginning
 of the fifth century Armenia was divided by the progress of
 war and faction; (83) and the unnatural division precipitated the downfall of that ancient monarchy.","('the beginning\r\n of the fifth century', 'DATE'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('83', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the conference
 which was held on the limits of the two empires, the Roman
 ambassadors degraded the personal character of their
 sovereign, by a vain attempt to magnify the extent of his
 power, when they seriously advised the Persians to prevent,
 by a timely accommodation, the wrath of a monarch who was
 yet ignorant of this distant war.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"In the fury of the pursuit the catholics uncovered the roof,
 and continued to throw down flaming logs of wood till they
 overwhelmed their adversaries, who had retreated to the
 church or conventicle of the Arians.","('Arians', 'NORP')"
"In the last
 years of his peaceful life Europe was indeed afflicted by
 the arms of Attila; but the more extensive provinces of Asia
 still continued to enjoy a profound and permanent repose.","('the last\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"In the last year of the reign of Jezdegerd, the
 supposed guardian of Theodosius, a bishop, who aspired to
 the crown of martyrdom, destroyed one of the fire-temples of
 Susa. (80)","('the last year', 'DATE'), ('Jezdegerd', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Susa', 'PERSON'), ('80', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the presence of the clergy and people the three daughters of Arcadius (70)  dedicated their virginity to God; and the obligation of their solemn vow was inscribed on a tablet of gold and gems, which they publicly offered in the great church of Constantinople.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('70', 'DATE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"In the senate, in the capital, in the provinces, the statues of Eutropius were erected, in brass or marble, decorated with the symbols of his civil and military virtues, and inscribed with the pompous title of the third founder of Constantinople.","('Eutropius', 'NORP'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"In this hour
 of distress and despair his only refuge was in the sanctuary
 of the church, whose privileges he had wisely, or profanely,
 attempted to circumscribe; and the most eloquent of the
 saints, John Chrysostom, enjoyed the triumph of protecting a
 prostrate minister, whose choice had raised him to the
 ecclesiastical throne of Constantinople.","('this hour', 'TIME'), ('John Chrysostom', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"In this state 
 of mutual and suspicious hostility, the guards and the
 people of Constantinople shut the gates, and rose in arms to
 prevent or to punish the conspiracy of the Goths.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"Instead of listening to his humble prayer
 that he might be permitted to reside at Cyzicus or
 Nicomedia, the inflexible empress assigned for his exile the
 remote and desolate town of Cucusus, among the ridges of
 Mount Taurus, in the Lesser Armenia.","('Cyzicus', 'GPE'), ('Nicomedia', 'GPE'), ('Cucusus', 'GPE'), ('Mount Taurus', 'LOC'), ('the Lesser Armenia', 'LOC')"
"Instead of tempting the allegiance of an
 ambitious subject by the participation of supreme power, he
 boldly appealed to the magnanimity of a king, and placed, by
 a solemn testament, the sceptre of the East in the hands of
 Jezdegerd himself.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Jezdegerd', 'PERSON')"
"It has already been observed that
 Eutropius, (3) one of the principal eunuchs of the palace of  Constantinople, succeeded the haughty minister whose ruin he had accomplished and whose vices he soon imitated.","('Eutropius', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"It has been asserted with more confidence 
 that his son Syagrius, after successfully eluding the pursuit of the agents and emissaries of the court, collected a band of African robbers that he rescued Timasius from the place of his exile; and that both the father and the son disappeared from the knowledge of mankind.","('Syagrius', 'PERSON'), ('African', 'NORP'), ('Timasius', 'PERSON')"
"It is enacted, in the name and by the authority of Arcadius, that all those who shall conspire,either with subjects or with strangers, against the lives of any of the persons whom the emperor considers as the members of his own body, shall be punished with death and confiscation.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON')"
"It is impossible to delineate his character;
 since, in a period very copiously furnished with historical
 materials, it has not been possible to remark one action
 that properly belongs to the son of the great Theodosius.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
It is insinuated that Eutropius despatched a private order for his secret execution.,"('Eutropius', 'PERSON')"
"It was reported that in  attempting to escape from Oasis he perished in the desert of thirst and hunger, and that his dead body was found on the sands of Libya. (16)","('Oasis', 'LOC'), ('Libya', 'GPE'), ('16', 'CARDINAL')"
"Leo, (26) who from the bulk 
 of his body and the dullness of his mind was surnamed the
 Ajax of the East, had deserted his original trade of a
 woolcomber, to exercise with much less skill and success the
 military profession; and his uncertain operations were
 capriciously framed and executed with an ignorance of real
 difficulties and a timorous neglect of every favourable
 opportunity.","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('26', 'DATE'), ('Ajax', 'PRODUCT'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"Notwithstanding the vigorous opposition of the archbishop,
 he importunately claimed for his Arian sectaries the
 possession of a peculiar church, and the pride of the
 catholics was offended by the public toleration of heresy.
 (35)","('Arian', 'NORP')"
"On the vigil of Easter the solemn administration of baptism was rudely interrupted by the soldiers, who alarmed the modesty of the naked catechumens, and violated, by their presence, the awful mysteries of the Christian worship.","('Easter', 'DATE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"On this occasion Eutropius
 seems to have deviated from his ordinary maxims; and his
 uncorrupted judgment was determined only by the superior
 merit of a stranger.","('Eutropius', 'PERSON')"
Persecution of St. John Chrysostom.—,"('St. John Chrysostom', 'PERSON')"
Popular tumult at Constantinople.,"('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Pulcheria alone discharged the important task of
 instructing her brother in the arts of government; but her
 precepts may countenance some suspicion of the extent of her
 capacity or of the purity of her intentions.","('Pulcheria', 'PERSON')"
"Pulcheria, her two sisters, and a chosen train of favourite damsels, formed a religious community: they renounced the vanity of dress, interrupted by frequent fasts their simple and frugal diet, allotted a portion of their time to works of embroidery, and devoted several hours of the day and night to the exercises of prayer and psalmody.","('Pulcheria', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('several hours', 'TIME')"
Revolt of Gainas.—,"('Gainas', 'PERSON')"
"Ruin of Abundantius,","('Abundantius', 'GPE')"
"Satiated with empty pomp, and unmindful perhaps of
 her obligations to Pulcheria, she ambitiously aspired to the
 government of the Eastern empire: the palace was distracted
 by female discord; but the victory was at last decided by
 the superior ascendant of the sister of Theodosius.","('Pulcheria', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Secluded from all  human converse, the master-general of the Roman armies was lost for ever to the world; but the circumstances of his fate have been related in a various and contradictory manner.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Separated from that familiar
 intercourse which facilitates the knowledge and the despatch
 of business, he reposed an unsuspecting confidence in his
 deacon Serapion; and seldom applied his speculative
 knowledge of human nature to the particular characters
 either of his dependents or of his equals.","('Serapion', 'PERSON')"
"Separated from the world by an impenetrable veil, Theodosius
 trusted the persons whom he loved; he loved those who were
 accustomed to amuse and flatter his indolence, and as he
 never perused the papers that were presented for the royal
 signature, the acts of injustice the most repugnant to his
 character were frequently perpetrated in his name.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"She easily excited the curiosity of her brother by an
 interesting picture of the charms of Athenais: large eyes, a
 well-proportioned nose, a fair complexion, golden locks, a
 slender person, a graceful demeanour, an understanding
 improved by study, and a virtue tried by distress.","('Athenais', 'PERSON')"
"She obtained her
 request, but the jealousy of Theodosius, or the vindictive
 spirit of Pulcheria, pursued her in her last retreat; and
 Saturninus, count of the domestics, was directed to punish
 with death two ecclesiastics, her most favoured servants.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Pulcheria', 'PERSON'), ('Saturninus', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"She taught him
 to maintain a grave and majestic deportment; to walk, to
 hold his robes, to seat himself on his throne in a manner
 worthy of a great prince; to abstain from laughter, to
 listen with condescension, to return suitable answers; to
 assume by turns a serious or a placid countenance; in a
 word, to represent with grace and dignity the external
 figure of a Roman emperor.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Since the Roman and Parthian standards first encountered on
 the banks of the Euphrates, the kingdom of Armenia (82) was 
 alternately oppressed by its formidable protectors; and in
 the course of this History, several events which inclined
 the balance of peace and war, have been already related.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Parthian', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('82', 'CARDINAL'), ('History', 'EVENT')"
"Some
 engagements were fought, some towns were besieged, with
 various and doubtful success: and if the Romans failed in
 their attempt to recover the long-lost possession of
 Nisibis, the Persians were repulsed from the walls of a
 Mesopotamian city by the valour of a martial bishop, who
 pointed his thundering engine in the name of St. Thomas the
 Apostle.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Nisibis', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Mesopotamian', 'NORP'), ('St. Thomas the\r\n Apostle', 'PERSON')"
"Some Christian fugitives, who escaped to the Roman frontier,
 were sternly demanded, and generously refused; and the
 refusal, aggravated by commercial disputes, soon kindled a
 war between the rival monarchies.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Some of the noblest regulations of Roman jurisprudence have been suffered to expire; but this edict, a convenient and forcible engine of ministerial tyranny, was carefully inserted in the codes of Theodosius and Justinian; and the same maxims have been revived in modern ages to protect the electors of Germany and the cardinals of the church of Rome. (20)
Rebellion of Tribigild, A.D. 399","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('20', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tribigild', 'GPE'), ('399', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such a domestic
 misfortune afflicted him more deeply than the public
 calamities of the East (61)—the licentious excursions, from 
 Pontus to Palestine, of the Isaurian robbers, whose impunity
 accused the weakness of the government; and the earthquakes,
 the conflagrations, the famine, and the flights of locusts,
  (62) which the popular discontent was equally disposed to 
 attribute to the incapacity of the monarch.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Pontus', 'GPE'), ('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('Isaurian', 'NORP'), ('62', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such events may be disbelieved or disregarded;
 but the charity of a bishop, Acacius of Amida, whose name
 might have dignified the saintly calendar, shall not be lost
 in oblivion.","('Acacius', 'PERSON'), ('Amida', 'PERSON')"
"Such is the singular narrative of
 Procopius; and his veracity is not disputed by Agathias, (64) 
 while he presumes to dissent from his judgment, and to
 arraign the wisdom of a Christian emperor, who so rashly,
 though so fortunately, committed his son and his dominions
 to the unknown faith of a stranger, a rival, and a heathen.","('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Agathias', 'PERSON'), ('64', 'DATE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"Such virtues were supposed to deserve the peculiar favour of the Deity: and the relics of martyrs, as well as the knowledge of future events, were communicated in visions and revelations to the Imperial saint. (71)","('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"That great officer, the master-general of the armies of Theodosius, had signalised his valour by a decisive victory which he obtained over the Goths of Thessaly but he was too prone, after the example of his sovereign, to enjoy the luxury of peace and to abandon his confidence to wicked and designing flatterers.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"That sagacious princess listened to her eloquent
 complaint, and secretly destined the daughter of the
 philosopher Leontius for the future wife of the emperor of
 the East, who had now attained the twentieth year of his
 age.","('Leontius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('the twentieth year of his\r\n age', 'DATE')"
"The
 Goths advanced by rapid marches through the plains of
 Thrace, and they were soon delivered from the fear of
 pursuit by the vanity of Fravitta, who, instead of
 extinguishing the war, hastened to enjoy the popular
 applause, and to assume the peaceful honours of the
 consulship.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Fravitta', 'PERSON')"
"The
 execution of Paulinus, master of the offices, and the
 disgrace of Cyrus, Praetorian praefect of the East,
 convinced the public that the favour of Eudocia was
 insufficient to protect her most faithful friends, and the
 uncommon beauty of Paulinus encouraged the secret rumour
 that his guilt was that of a successful lover. (77)","('Paulinus', 'PERSON'), ('Cyrus', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Eudocia', 'PERSON'), ('Paulinus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 secret resentment of the court encouraged the discontent of
 the clergy and monks of Constantinople, who were too hastily
 reformed by the fervent zeal of their archbishop.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The Bosphorus was covered with innumerable
 vessels; the shores of Europe and Asia were profusely
 illuminated; and the acclamations of a victorious people
 accompanied, from the port to the cathedral, the triumph of
 the archbishop, who too easily consented to resume the
 exercise of his functions, before his sentence had been
 legally reversed by the authority of an ecclesiastical
 synod.","('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The Catholics retreated to the baths of Constantine, and afterwards to the fields, where they were still pursued and insulted by the guards, the bishops, and the magistrates.","('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The Empire of the East, A.D. 395-1453
Reign of Arcadius , A.D. 395-408
 THE division of the Roman world between the sons of
 Theodosius marks the final establishment of the empire of
 the East, which, from the reign of Arcadius to the taking of
 Constantinople by the Turks, subsisted one thousand and
 fifty-eight years in a state of premature and perpetual
 decay.","('395-1453', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arcadius', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 395-408', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Arcadius', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('one thousand and\r\n fifty-eight years', 'DATE')"
"The Goths, according to the terms of the agreement,
 were immediately transported from Asia into Europe; and the
 victorious chief, who accepted the title of master-general
 of the Roman armies, soon filled Constantinople with his
 troops, and distributed among his dependents the honours and
 rewards of the empire.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The Persian War, and Division of Armenia.","('The Persian War', 'EVENT'), ('Division of Armenia', 'ORG')"
"The Persian war, A.D. 422.","('The Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('422', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Roman world was deeply interested in the education of
 its master.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The agonies of the pale and affrighted
 wretch, who lay grovelling under the table of the altar,
 exhibited a solemn and instructive spectacle; and the
 orator, who was afterwards accused of insulting the
 misfortunes of Eutropius, laboured to excite the contempt,
 that he might assuage the fury, of the people. (29)","('Eutropius', 'PERSON'), ('29', 'CARDINAL')"
"The answer of the archbishop
 Isaac, whose sanction they earnestly solicited, is
 expressive of the character of a superstitious people.","('Isaac', 'PERSON')"
"The appearances of a fair and legal proceeding were maintained by the blunt honesty of Procopius; and he yielded with reluctance to the obsequious dexterity of his colleague, who pronounced a sentence of condemnation against the unfortunate Timasius.","('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Timasius', 'PERSON')"
"The approach of danger and the obstinacy of
 Tribigild, who refused all terms of accommodation, compelled
 Eutropius to summon a council of war. (25)","('Tribigild', 'PERSON'), ('Eutropius', 'PERSON'), ('25', 'CARDINAL')"
"The archbishop was rudely arrested,
 and conducted through the city, by one of the Imperial
 messengers, who landed him, after a short navigation, near
 the entrance of the Euxine; from whence, before the
 expiration of two days, he was gloriously recalled.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Euxine', 'FAC'), ('two days', 'DATE')"
"The archbishops of the East, who might blush that their predecessors had been the enemies of Chrysostom, were gradually disposed, by the firmness of the Roman pontiff, to restore the honours of that venerable name. (56)","('East', 'LOC'), ('Chrysostom', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('56', 'CARDINAL')"
"The birth of a son was accepted, however, by 
 the pious husband as an event the most fortunate and
 honourable to himself, to his family, and to the Eastern
 world: and the royal infant, by an unprecedented favour, was
 invested with the titles of Caesar and Augustus.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"The bold and vigorous mind of Rufinus seems to have been
 actuated by a more sanguinary and revengeful spirit; but the
 avarice of the eunuch was not less insatiate than that of
 the praefect.","('Rufinus', 'PERSON')"
"The bold satirist, who has indulged his discontent by the
 partial and passionate censure of the Christian emperors,
 violates the dignity rather than the truth of history by
 comparing the son of Theodosius to one of those harmless and
 simple animals who scarcely feel that they are the property
 of their shepherd.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The brothers of Eudocia obeyed,
 with some anxiety, her Imperial summons; but as she could
 easily forgive their fortunate unkindness, she indulged the
 tenderness, or perhaps the vanity, of a sister, by promoting
 them to the rank of consuls and praefects.","('Eudocia', 'PERSON')"
"The catholics applauded the justice of Heaven,
 which avenged the persecution of St. Chrysostom; and perhaps
 the emperor was the only person who sincerely bewailed the
 loss of the haughty and rapacious Eudoxia.","('St. Chrysostom', 'PERSON'), ('Eudoxia', 'PERSON')"
"The celebrated Athenais (74) 
 was educated by her father Leontius in the religion and
 sciences of the Greeks; and so advantageous was the opinion
 which the Athenian philosopher entertained of his
 contemporaries, that he divided his patrimony between his
 two sons, bequeathing to his daughter a small legacy of one
 hundred pieces of gold, in the lively confidence that her
 beauty and merit would be a sufficient portion.","('Athenais', 'PERSON'), ('74', 'DATE'), ('Leontius', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Athenian', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('one\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The church of the
 holy martyr Euphemia, situate on a lofty eminence near
 Chalcedon, (34) was chosen for the place of the interview.","('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('34', 'CARDINAL')"
"The colony of that warlike nation, which had been
 planted by Theodosius in one of the most fertile districts
 of Phrygia, (22) impatiently compared the slow returns of 
 laborious husbandry with the successful rapine and liberal
 rewards of Alaric and their leader resented, as a personal
 affront, his own ungracious reception in the palace of
 Constantinople.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Phrygia', 'GPE'), ('22', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The conditions
 of peace were dictated by the haughty rebel, and the
 peremptory demand of the head of Eutropius revealed the
 author and the design of this hostile conspiracy.","('Eutropius', 'ORG')"
"The confederate armies advanced without
 resistance to the straits of the Hellespont and the
 Bosphorus, and Arcadius was instructed to prevent the loss
 of his Asiatic dominions by resigning his authority and his
 person to the faith of the barbarians.","('Hellespont', 'NORP'), ('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP')"
"The consul Aurelian pronounced
 the sentence; and the motives of that sentence expose the
 jurisprudence of a despotic government.","('Aurelian', 'PERSON')"
"The crimes which
 Eutropius had committed against the people might have
 justified his death; but he was found guilty of harnessing
 to his chariot the sacred animals, who, from their breed
 or colour, were reserved for the use of the emperor alone.
  (32)","('Eutropius', 'PERSON')"
"The death of Arcadius, A.D. 408, May 1.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 408', 'DATE'), ('May 1', 'DATE')"
"The descendants of Arsaces were degraded from the royal dignity, (86) which they had possessed above five hundred and sixty years; (87) and the dominions of the unfortunate Artasires, under the new and significant appellation of Persarmenia, were reduced into the form of a province.","('Arsaces', 'PERSON'), ('five hundred and sixty years', 'DATE'), ('87', 'CARDINAL'), ('Artasires', 'NORP'), ('Persarmenia', 'GPE')"
The destruction of Timasius (13) required a more serious and regular mode of attack.,"('Timasius', 'GPE'), ('13', 'CARDINAL')"
"The discontent of Gainas, who had so boldly
 contrived and executed the death of Rufinus, was irritated
 by the fortune of his unworthy successor; he accused his own
 dishonourable patience under the servile reign of an eunuch;
 and the ambitious Goth was convicted, at least in the public
 opinion, of secretly fomenting the revolt of Tribigild, with
 whom he was connected by a domestic as well as by a national
 alliance. (27)","('Gainas', 'PERSON'), ('Rufinus', 'PERSON'), ('Goth', 'PERSON'), ('Tribigild', 'PERSON'), ('27', 'CARDINAL')"
The disregard of custom and decency always betrays a weak and ill-regulated mind; nor does Eutropius seem to have compensated for the folly of the design by any superior merit or ability in the execution.,"('Eutropius', 'PERSON')"
"The edict of Arcadius most positively and most absurdly declares that in such cases of treason, thoughts and actions ought to be punished with equal severity; that the knowledge of a mischievous intention, unless it be instantly revealed, becomes equally criminal with the intention itself; (19) and that those rash men who shall presume to solicit the pardon of traitors shall themselves be branded with public and perpetual infamy.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('19', 'CARDINAL')"
"The effeminate consul was rejected by the West as an indelible stain to the annals of the republic; and without invoking the shades of Brutus and Camillus, the colleague of Eutropius, a learned and respectable magistrate, (9) sufficiently represented the  different maxims of the two administrations.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Brutus', 'PERSON'), ('Camillus', 'PERSON'), ('Eutropius', 'PERSON'), ('9', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The elegant and familiar
 use which she had acquired both of the Greek and Latin
 languages was readily applied to the various occasions of
 speaking or writing on public business: her deliberations
 were maturely weighed; her actions were prompt and decisive;
 and while she moved without noise or ostentation the wheel
 of government, she discreetly attributed to the genius of
 the emperor the long tranquillity of his reign.","('Greek', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE')"
"The emperor Theodosius advanced to receive them as  far as Chalcedon; and, falling prostrate on the coffin, implored, in the name of his guilty parents, Arcadius and Eudoxia, the forgiveness of the injured saint. (58)","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Chalcedon', 'LOC'), ('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('Eudoxia', 'PERSON')"
"The emperor's hand was directed to sign the 
 condemnation of Eutropius; the magic spell, which during
 four years had bound the prince and the people, was
 instantly dissolved; and the acclamations that so lately
 hailed the merit and fortune of the favourite were converted
 into the clamours of the soldiers and people, who reproached
 his crimes and pressed his immediate execution.","('Eutropius', 'PERSON'), ('four years', 'DATE')"
"The empress Eudoxia was restrained, by her own prejudices or
 by those of her subjects, from violating the sanctuary of
 the church; and Eutropius was tempted to capitulate, by the
 milder arts of persuasion, and by an oath that his life
 should be spared. (30)","('Eudoxia', 'PERSON'), ('Eutropius', 'PERSON'), ('30', 'CARDINAL')"
"The enterprises of the rebel
 against the cities of Thrace were encountered by a firm and
 well-ordered defence: his hungry soldiers were soon reduced
 to the grass that grew on the margin of the fortifications;
 and Gainas, who vainly regretted the wealth and luxury of
 Asia, embraced a desperate resolution of forcing the passage
 of the Hellespont.","('Thrace', 'GPE'), ('Gainas', 'PERSON'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Hellespont', 'PERSON')"
"The fatal day of the second and final exile of Chrysostom was marked by the conflagration of the cathedral, of the senate-house, and of the adjacent buildings; and this calamity was imputed, without proof, but not without probability, to the despair of a persecuted faction. (52)
Exile of Chrysostom, A.D. 404, June 20.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Chrysostom', 'PERSON'), ('Exile of Chrysostom', 'LAW'), ('404', 'CARDINAL'), ('June 20', 'DATE')"
"The first astonishment of his faithful people had been mute
 and passive: they suddenly rose with unanimous and
 irresistible fury.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The first events of the reign of Arcadius and Honorius are
 so intimately connected, that the rebellion of the Goths and
 the fall of Rufinus have already claimed a place in the
 history of the West.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Arcadius', 'GPE'), ('Honorius', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Rufinus', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"The fondness of the emperor was not 
 abated by time and possession; and Eudocia, after the
 marriage of her daughter, was permitted to discharge her
 grateful vows by a solemn pilgrimage to Jerusalem.","('Eudocia', 'PERSON'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
"The form of government was a
 pure and simple monarchy; the name of the ROMAN REPUBLIC,
 which so long preserved a faint tradition of freedom, was
 confined to the Latin provinces; and the princes of
 Constantinople measured their greatness by the servile
 obedience of their people.","('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
The general was arraigned before the tribunal of Arcadius himself; and the principal eunuch stood by the side of the throne to suggest the questions and answers of his sovereign.,"('Arcadius', 'PERSON')"
"The gentle mind of Theodosius was never inflamed by the
 ambition of conquest or military renown; and the slight
 alarm of a Persian war scarcely interrupted the tranquillity
 of the East.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('a Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The great officers of the state and army, who had
 been appointed before the death of Arcadius, formed an
 aristocracy which might have inspired them with the idea of
 a free republic; and the government of the Eastern empire
 was fortunately assumed by the praefect Anthemius, (65) who 
 obtained, by his superior abilities, a lasting ascendant
 over the minds of his equals.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('65', 'DATE')"
"The historian Procopius (63) has indeed illuminated the mind 
 of the dying emperor with a ray of human prudence, or
 celestial wisdom.","('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('63', 'DATE')"
"The jealousy
 and avarice of her brothers soon compelled Athenais to seek
 a refuge at Constantinople, and with some hopes, either of
 justice or favour, to throw herself at the feet of
 Pulcheria.","('Athenais', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Pulcheria', 'PERSON')"
"The less fortunate nobles, who
 lamented the loss of their king, and envied the honours of
 their equals, were provoked to negotiate their peace and
 pardon at the Persian court; and, returning with their
 followers to the palace of Artaxata, acknowledged Chosroes
 for their lawful sovereign.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Artaxata', 'GPE'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON')"
"The maxims of Roman jurisprudence, if they could fairly be
 transferred from private property to public dominion, would
 have adjudged to the emperor Honorius the guardianship of
 his nephew, till he had attained, at least, the fourteenth
 year of his age.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('the fourteenth\r\n year of his age', 'DATE')"
"The military command was delegated to
 the count of the Armenian frontier; the city of
 Theodosiopolis (84) was built and fortified in a strong situation, on a fertile and lofty ground, near the sources of the Euphrates; and the dependent territories were ruled
 by five satraps, whose dignity was marked by a peculiar
 habit of gold and purple.","('Armenian', 'NORP'), ('Theodosiopolis', 'GPE'), ('84', 'CARDINAL'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('five', 'CARDINAL')"
"The mind of the illustrious exile was still
 independent; but his captive body was exposed to the revenge
 of the oppressors, who continued to abuse the name and
 authority of Arcadius. (55)","('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('55', 'CARDINAL')"
"The monuments of that eloquence,
 which was admired near twenty years at Antioch and
 Constantinople, have been carefully preserved; and the
 possession of near one thousand sermons or homilies has
 authorised the critics (42) of succeeding times to appreciate 
 the genuine merit of Chrysostom.","('twenty years', 'DATE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('near one thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('42', 'CARDINAL'), ('Chrysostom', 'PERSON')"
"The mountains of Armenia,
 and the plains of Mesopotamia, were filled with hostile
 armies; but the operations of two successive campaigns were
 not productive of any decisive or memorable events.","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Mesopotamia', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The palace of Constantinople rivalled, and perhaps excelled, the magnificence of Persia;
 and the eloquent sermons of St Chrysostom (1) celebrate, while they condemn, the pompous luxury of the reign of Arcadius","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'LOC'), ('St Chrysostom', 'PERSON'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arcadius', 'PERSON')"
"The pastoral labours of the archbishop of Constantinople
 provoked and gradually united against him two sorts of
 enemies; the aspiring clergy, who envied his success, and
 the obstinate sinners, who were offended by his reproofs.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
The piety of a Christian virgin was adorned by the zeal and liberality of an empress.,"('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The populous countries of
 that empire were the seat of art and learning, of luxury and
 wealth; and the inhabitants, who had assumed the language
 and manners of Greeks, styled themselves, with some
 appearance of truth, the most enlightened and civilised
 portion of the human species.","('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"The practice of benevolence in the midst of
 war must always tend to assuage the animosity of contending
 nations; and I wish to persuade myself that Acacius
 contributed to the restoration of peace.","('Acacius', 'PERSON')"
"The public hatred and the despair of individuals continually threatened, or seemed to threaten, the personal safety of Eutropius, as well as of the numerous adherents who were attached to his fortune and had been promoted by his venal favour.","('Eutropius', 'ORG')"
"The rashness of the Ostrogoths had drawn them
 into a disadvantageous position between the rivers Melas and
 Eurymedon, where they were almost besieged by the peasants
 of Pamphylia; but the arrival of an Imperial army, instead
 of completing their destruction, afforded the means of
 safety and victory.","('Ostrogoths', 'NORP'), ('Melas', 'LOC'), ('Eurymedon', 'LOC'), ('Pamphylia', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"The remainder of the life of Eudocia,
 about sixteen years, was spent in exile and devotion; and
 the approach of age, the death of Theodosius, the
 misfortunes of her only daughter, who was led a captive from
 Rome to Carthage, and the society of the Holy Monks of
 Palestine, insensibly confirmed the religious temper of her
 mind.","('Eudocia', 'PERSON'), ('about sixteen years', 'DATE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('the Holy Monks of\r\n Palestine', 'ORG')"
"The royal guardian accepted and
 discharged this honourable trust with unexampled fidelity;
 and the infancy of Theodosius was protected by the arms and
 councils of Persia.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"The rumours of the success of Tribigild
 might for some time be suppressed by fear, or disguised by
 flattery; yet they gradually alarmed both the court and the
 capital.","('Tribigild', 'ORG')"
"The safety of the young
 emperor proved the merit and integrity of Anthemius; and his
 prudent firmness sustained the force and reputation of an
 infant reign.","('Anthemius', 'PERSON')"
"The silent and solitary ascetics, who had secluded
 themselves from the world, were entitled to the warmest
 approbation of Chrysostom; but he despised and stigmatised,
 as the disgrace of their holy profession, the crowd of
 degenerate monks, who, from some unworthy motives of
 pleasure or profit, so frequently infested the streets of
 the capital.","('Chrysostom', 'PERSON')"
"The sovereign of that empire assumed and obstinately
 retained the vain, and at length fictitious, title of
 Emperor of the ROMANS; and the hereditary appellations of
 CAESAR and AUGUSTUS continued to declare that he was the legitimate successor of the first of men, who had reigned over the first of nations.","('Emperor of the ROMANS', 'PERSON'), ('CAESAR', 'ORG'), ('AUGUSTUS', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The story of a fair and virtuous maiden, exalted from a
 private condition to the Imperial throne, might be deemed an
 incredible romance, if such a romance had not been verified
 in the marriage of Theodosius.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The subjects of Arcadius were exasperated by the recollection that this deformed and decrepit eunuch, (6) who so perversely mimicked  the actions of a man, was born in the most abject conditions of servitude; that before he entered the Imperial palace he had been successively sold and purchased by an hundred masters, who had exhausted his youthful strength in every mean and infamous office, and at length dismissed him in his old age to freedom and poverty.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The successors of Constantine established their perpetual residence in the
 royal city which he had erected on the verge of Europe and
 Asia.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The superior forces of Uldin, 
 king of the Huns, opposed the progress of Gainas; an hostile
 and ruined country prohibited his retreat; he disdained to
 capitulate; and after repeatedly attempting to cut his way
 through the ranks of the enemy, A.D. 401, January 3. he was slain, with his desperate followers, in the field of battle.","('Uldin', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Gainas', 'PERSON'), ('401', 'CARDINAL'), ('January 3', 'DATE')"
"The synod (49) 
 was convened in the suburb of Chalcedon, surnamed the oak,
 where Rufinus had erected a stately church and monastery;
 and their proceedings were continued during fourteen days or
 sessions.","('49', 'DATE'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('Rufinus', 'GPE'), ('fourteen days', 'DATE')"
"The synod of
 the oak immediately addressed the emperor to ratify and
 execute their judgment, and charitably insinuated that the
 penalties of treason might be inflicted on the audacious
 preacher, who had reviled, under the name of Jezebel, the
 empress Eudoxia herself.","('Jezebel', 'PERSON'), ('Eudoxia', 'PERSON')"
"The triumphs of Arcadius became
 the subject of epic poems; (40) and the monarch, no longer 
 oppressed by any hostile terrors, resigned himself to the
 mild and absolute dominion of his wife, the fair and artful
 Eudoxia, who has sullied her fame by the persecution of St.
 John Chrysostom.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('40', 'CARDINAL'), ('Eudoxia', 'PERSON'), ('St.\r\n John Chrysostom', 'PERSON')"
"The usual methods of
 extortion were practised and improved; and Claudian has
 sketched a lively and original picture of the public auction
 of the state.","('Claudian', 'PERSON')"
"The vain hope of eluding, by a change of place, the
 obligation of an oath, engaged the empress to transfer the
 scene of his trial and execution from Constantinople to the
 adjacent suburb of Chalcedon.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE')"
"The vineyards and fruitful fields between
 the rapid Marsyas and the winding Maeander (23) were consumed 
 with fire; the decayed walls of the cities crumbled into
 dust at the first stroke of an enemy; the trembling
 inhabitants escaped from a bloody massacre to the shores of
 the Hellespont; and a considerable part of Asia Minor was
 desolated by the rebellion of Tribigild.","('Marsyas', 'PRODUCT'), ('Maeander', 'PRODUCT'), ('23', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Hellespont', 'GPE'), ('Asia Minor', 'LOC'), ('Tribigild', 'GPE')"
"Their dominions were bounded by the Hadriatic and the
 Tigris; and the whole interval of twenty-five days'
 navigation, which separated the extreme cold of Scythia from
 the torrid zone of Aethiopia, (2) was comprehended within the 
 limits of the empire of the East.","('Hadriatic', 'NORP'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), (""twenty-five days'"", 'DATE'), ('Scythia', 'GPE'), ('Aethiopia', 'GPE'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC')"
Theodosius II.,"('Theodosius II', 'PERSON')"
"Theodosius devoutly
 worshipped the dead and living saints of the catholic
 church; and he once refused to eat till an insolent monk,
 who had cast an excommunication on his sovereign,
 condescended to heal the spiritual wound which he had
 inflicted.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Theodosius the younger was never reduced to the disgraceful
 necessity of encountering and punishing a rebellious
 subject: and since we cannot applaud the vigour, some praise
 may be due to the mildness and prosperity, of the
 administration of Pulcheria.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Pulcheria', 'ORG')"
"Theodosius, concealed behind a curtain in the apartment of
 his sister, was permitted to behold the Athenian virgin: the
 modest youth immediately declared his pure and honourable
 love, and the royal nuptials were celebrated amidst the
 acclamations of the capital and the provinces.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Athenian', 'NORP')"
"Theophilus escaped, but the promiscuous
 crowd of monks and Egyptian mariners was slaughtered without
 pity in the streets of Constantinople. (50)","('Theophilus', 'PERSON'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('50', 'CARDINAL')"
"They insinuated themselves into
 the confidence of the prince but their ostensible functions
 were confined to the menial service of the wardrobe and
 Imperial bedchamber.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"They might direct in a whisper the
 public counsels, and blast by their malicious suggestions
 the fame and fortunes of the most illustrious citizens; but
 they never presumed to stand forward in the front of empire,  (4) or to profane the public honours of the state.","('4', 'CARDINAL')"
"They resented the injurious precaution; and
 some alarming attempts were made during the night July 20 to attack
 and destroy with fire the Imperial palace. (36)","('the night July 20', 'DATE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"They unanimously attribute
 to the Christian orator the free command of an elegant and
 copious language; the judgment to conceal the advantages
 which he derived from the knowledge of rhetoric and
 philosophy; an inexhaustible fund of metaphors and
 similitudes, of ideas and images, to vary and illustrate the
 most familiar topics; the happy art of engaging the passions
 in the service of virtue, and of exposing the folly as well
 as the turpitude of vice almost with the truth and spirit of
 a dramatic representation.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"This ecclesiastical conspiracy was managed by Theophilus, (47) 
 archbishop of Alexandria, an active and ambitious prelate,
 who displayed the fruits of rapine in monuments of
 ostentation.","('Theophilus', 'PERSON'), ('47', 'DATE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"This species of fictitious and metaphorical treason is extended to protect not only the illustrious officers of the state and army who are admitted into the sacred consistory, but likewise the principal domestics of the palace, the senators of Constantinople, the military commanders, and the civil magistrates of the provinces: a vague and indefinite list, which, under the successors of Constantine, included an obscure and numerous train of subordinate ministers.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"This strange and inexpiable prodigy (8) awakened, however, the prejudices of the Romans.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"This usurpation excited the jealousy of the Roman government; but the rising disputes were soon terminated by an amicable, though unequal, partition of the ancient kingdom of Armenia; and a territorial acquisition, which Augustus might have despised, reflected some lustre on the declining empire of the younger Theodosius.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
This venal prostitution of public honours secured the impunity of future crimes; but the riches which Eutropius derived from confiscation were already stained with injustice; since it was decent to accuse and to condemn the proprietors of the wealth which he was impatient to confiscate.,"('Eutropius', 'PERSON')"
"Timasius had despised the public clamour by promoting an infamous dependent to the command of a cohort; and he deserved to feel the ingratitude of Bargus, who was secretly instigated by the favourite to accuse his patron of a treasonable conspiracy.","('Timasius', 'PERSON'), ('Bargus', 'PERSON')"
"To the Imperial
 court he repeatedly magnified the valour, the genius, the
 inexhaustible resources of Tribigild, confessed his own
 inability to prosecute the war, and extorted the permission
 of negotiating with his invincible adversary.","('the Imperial\r\n court', 'ORG'), ('Tribigild', 'PERSON')"
"Tribigild surprised the unguarded camp
 of the Romans in the darkness of the night, seduced the
 faith of the greater part of the barbarian auxiliaries, and
 dissipated without much effort the troops which had been
 corrupted by the relaxation of discipline and the luxury of
 the capital.","('Tribigild', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Two passions, however—fear and conjugal
 affection—awakened the languid soul of Arcadius: he was
 terrified by the threats of a victorious barbarian, and he
 yielded to the tender eloquence of his wife Eudoxia, who,
 with a flood of artificial tears, presenting her infant
 children to their father, implored his justice for some real
 or imaginary insult which she imputed to the audacious
 eunuch. (28)","('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('Eudoxia', 'PERSON')"
"Uldin, with a formidable host of barbarians,
 was encamped in the heart of Thrace; he proudly rejected all
 terms of accommodation; and, pointing to the rising sun,
 declared to the Roman ambassadors that the course of that
 planet should alone terminate the conquests of the Huns.","('Uldin', 'PERSON'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"Under the weakest of the
 predecessors of Arcadius the reign of the eunuchs had been
 secret and almost invisible.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON')"
"When Chrysostom thundered from the pulpit of St. Sophia
 against the degeneracy of the Christians, his shafts were
 spent among the crowd, without wounding or even marking the
 character of any individual.","('Chrysostom', 'PERSON'), ('St. Sophia', 'GPE'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"When Gainas passed the Hellespont, to unite 
 under his standard the remains of the Asiatic troops, he
 skilfully adapted his motions to the wishes of the
 Ostrogoths, abandoning by his retreat the country which they
 desired to invade, or facilitating by his approach the
 desertion of the barbarian auxiliaries.","('Gainas', 'PERSON'), ('Hellespont', 'PERSON'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP')"
"Whenever Tribigild
 advanced into the inland country, the Romans were inclined
 to suppose that he meditated the passage of Mount Taurus and
 the invasion of Syria.","('Tribigild', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Mount Taurus', 'LOC'), ('Syria', 'GPE')"
"While this domestic revolution was transacted, Gainas (33) 
 openly revolted from his allegiance, united his forces at
 Thyatira in Lydia with those of Tribigild, and still
 maintained his superior ascendant over the rebellious leader
 of the Ostrogoths.","('Gainas', 'PERSON'), ('33', 'DATE'), ('Thyatira', 'GPE'), ('Lydia', 'PERSON'), ('Tribigild', 'PERSON'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP')"
"Yet
 Chrysostom arrived in safety at the place of his
 confinement; and the three years which he spent at Cucusus,
 and the neighbouring town of Arabissus, were the last and
 most glorious of his life.","('Chrysostom', 'PERSON'), ('the three years', 'DATE'), ('Cucusus', 'GPE'), ('Arabissus', 'GPE')"
"Yet a reasonable doubt may be entertained whether any stain
 of hereditary guilt could be derived from Arcadius to his
 successor.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON')"
"Yet the devotion of  Pulcheria never diverted her indefatigable attention from temporal affairs; and she alone, among all the descendants of the great Theodosius, appears to have inherited any share of his manly spirit and abilities.","('Pulcheria', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Yet the splendid victories which the incredible
 speed of the messenger Palladius repeatedly announced to the
 palace of Constantinople were celebrated with festivals and
 panegyrics.","('Palladius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Yet these sanguinary laws, which spread terror among a
 disarmed and dispirited people, were of too weak a texture
 to restrain the bold enterprise of Tribigild  (21) the 
 Ostrogoth.","('Tribigild', 'ORG'), ('21', 'CARDINAL')"
"he expired at Comana, in Pontus, in the sixtieth year of his age.","('Comana', 'ORG'), ('Pontus', 'GPE'), ('the sixtieth year', 'DATE')"
