Sentence,Entities
"""With this view (continues Tacitus)  he inflicted the most exquisite tortures on those men who, under the
 vulgar appellation of Christians, were already branded with deserved infamy.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
(145),"('145', 'CARDINAL')"
(15),"('15', 'CARDINAL')"
(151),"('151', 'CARDINAL')"
"(2) The enthusiasm of the Jews 
 was supported by the opinion that it was unlawful for them
 to pay taxes to an idolatrous master, and by the flattering
 promise which they derived from their ancient oracles, that
 a conquering Messiah would soon arise, destined to break
 their fetters, and to invest the favourites of heaven with
 the empire of the earth.","('Jews', 'NORP')"
"(3)
Toleration of the Jewish religion 
 Notwithstanding these repeated provocations, the resentment
 of the Roman princes expired after the victory, nor were
 their apprehensions continued beyond the period of war and
 danger.","('Jewish', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
(32),"('32', 'CARDINAL')"
"(35) The latter may be proved by the consent of the most ancient manuscripts; by the inimitable character of the style of
 Tacitus; by his reputation, which guarded his text from the interpolations of pious fraud; and by the purport of his narration, which accused the first Christians of the most atrocious crimes, without insinuating that they possessed any miraculous or even magical powers above the rest of mankind.(36) 2. Notwithstanding it is probable that Tacitus was born some years before the fire of Rome,(37) he could  derive only from reading and conversation the knowledge of an event which happened during his infancy.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('36', 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('some years', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('37', 'DATE')"
(45),"('45', 'CARDINAL')"
(5),"('5', 'CARDINAL')"
(90),"('90', 'CARDINAL')"
"1. The confessors who were condemned to work in the mines were permitted by the humanity or the negligence of their keepers to build chapels, and freely to profess their religion in the midst
 of those dreary habitations. (180) 2. The bishops were obliged to check and to censure the forward zeal of the Christians, who voluntarily threw themselves into the hands of the magistrates.","('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('180', 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
24th Feb.,"('24th Feb', 'DATE')"
"3. Tacitus very frequently trusts to the curiosity or reflection of his readers to supply those intermediate circumstances and ideas which, in his extreme conciseness, he has thought proper to suppress.","('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"4.Whatever opinion may be entertained of this conjecture (for it is no more than a conjecture), it is evident that the effect, as well as the cause, of Nero's persecution, were confined to
 the walls of Rome ; (43) that the religious tenets of the Galilaeans, or Christians, were never made a subject of punishment, or even of inquiry; and that, as the idea of their sufferings was, for a long time, connected with the idea of cruelty and injustice, the moderation of succeeding princes inclined them to spare a sect oppressed by a tyrant whose rage had been usually directed against virtue and innocence.","('4', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('43', 'CARDINAL'), ('Galilaeans', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"A Pagan
 magistrate, who possessed neither leisure nor abilities to
 discern the almost imperceptible line which divides the
 orthodox faith from heretical depravity, might easily have
 imagined that their mutual animosity had extorted the
 discovery of their common guilt.","('Pagan', 'NORP')"
"A few days
 afterwards Galerius hastily withdrew himself from Nicomedia,
 declaring that, if he delayed his departure from that
 devoted palace, he should fall a sacrifice to the rage of
 the Christians.","('A few days', 'DATE'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Nicomedia', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"A few months after the
 death of Clemens and the banishment of Domitilla, Stephen, a
 freedman belonging to the latter, who had enjoyed the
 favour, but who had not surely embraced the faith, of his
 mistress, assassinated the emperor in his palace.(55)","('A few months', 'DATE'), ('Clemens', 'PERSON'), ('Domitilla', 'PERSON'), ('Stephen', 'PERSON')"
"A great number even of bishops and presbyters acquired, by
 this criminal compliance, the opprobrious epithet of
 Traitors; and their offence was productive of much present
 scandal and of much future discord in the African church.
 (159)
 Demolition of the churches.","('African', 'NORP'), ('159', 'CARDINAL')"
"A great number even of bishops and presbyters acquired, by
 this criminal compliance, the opprobrious epithet of
 Traitors; and their offence was productive of much present
 scandal and of much future discord in the African church.
 (159)
Demolition of the churches.","('African', 'NORP'), ('159', 'CARDINAL')"
"A measure so consonant to reason was
 soon authorised by the advice and example of the most holy
 prelates; and seems to have been censured by few, except by
 the Montanists, who deviated into heresy by their strict and
 obstinate adherence to the rigour of ancient discipline.(100)
 II.","('Montanists', 'NORP'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"A reason has been assigned for the conduct of
 the emperors towards the primitive Christians, which may
 appear the more specious and probable as it is drawn from
 the acknowledged genius of Polytheism.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"A sentence of banishment was
 pronounced as the penalty of Cyprian's disobedience; and he
 was conducted without delay to Curubis, a free and maritime
 city of Zeugitana, in a pleasant situation, a fertile
 territory, and at the distance of about forty miles from
 Carthage.(82)","('Cyprian', 'PERSON'), ('Curubis', 'GPE'), ('Zeugitana', 'GPE'), ('about forty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"A sentence of death was executed upon
 Maximilianus, an African youth, who had been produced by his
 own father before the magistrate as a sufficient and legal
 recruit, but who obstinately persisted in declaring that his
 conscience would not permit him to embrace the profession of
 a soldier.","('Maximilianus', 'PERSON'), ('African', 'NORP')"
"A short
 abstract therefore of its most important circumstances will
 convey the clearest information of the spirit and of the
 forms of the Roman persecutions.(80)
 A.D. 257.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('257', 'CARDINAL')"
"A short
 abstract therefore of its most important circumstances will
 convey the clearest information of the spirit and of the
 forms of the Roman persecutions.(80)
A.D. 257.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('257', 'CARDINAL')"
"A slight penance atoned for this profane dissimulation.(101)
III.","('101', 'CARDINAL')"
"A story is related of Aglae,
 a Roman lady, descended from a consular family, and
 possessed of so ample an estate that it required the
 management of seventy-three stewards.","('Aglae', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('seventy-three', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 180..,"('A.D. 180', 'DATE')"
A.D. 211-249,"('A.D. 211-249', 'DATE')"
A.D. 253-260..,"('A.D. 253-260', 'DATE')"
A.D. 260.,"('260', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 270.,"('270', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 274.,"('A.D. 274', 'DATE')"
A.D. 284-303,"('A.D. 284-303', 'DATE')"
A.D. 303. 23rd Feb.,"('A.D. 303', 'DATE'), ('23rd Feb', 'DATE')"
"About four-score years after the
 death of Christ, his innocent disciples were punished with
 death by the sentence of a proconsul of the most amiable and
 philosophic character, and according to the laws of an
 emperor distinguished by the wisdom and justice of his
 general administration.","('four-score years', 'DATE'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"About ten years afterwards, under the reign of Trajan,
 the younger Pliny was intrusted by his friend and master
 with the government of Bithynia and Pontus.","('About ten years afterwards', 'DATE'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Pliny', 'PERSON'), ('Bithynia', 'PERSON'), ('Pontus', 'PERSON')"
"According to the distribution of Roman
 provinces, Palestine may be considered as the sixteenth part
 of the Eastern empire: (183) and since there were some 
 governors who, from a real or affected clemency, had
 preserved theirs hands unstained with the blood of the
 faithful,(184) it is reasonable to believe that the Country 
 which had given birth to Christianity produced at least the
 sixteenth part of the martyrs who suffered death within the
 dominions of Galerius and Maximin; the whole might
 consequently amount to about fifteen hundred, a number
 which, if it is equally divided between the ten years of the
 persecution, will allow an annual consumption of one hundred
 and fifty martyrs.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('sixteenth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('183', 'CARDINAL'), ('184', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('sixteenth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Galerius', 'LOC'), ('Maximin', 'NORP'), ('about fifteen hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('the ten years', 'DATE'), ('one hundred\r\n and fifty', 'CARDINAL')"
"Adauctus is the more remarkable for being the only person of
 rank and distinction who appears to have suffered death
 during the whole course of this general persecution.(167)
 under Maxentius;","('Adauctus', 'PERSON'), ('167', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON')"
"Adauctus is the more remarkable for being the only person of
 rank and distinction who appears to have suffered death
 during the whole course of this general persecution.(167)
under Maxentius;","('Adauctus', 'PERSON'), ('167', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON')"
"After
 taking such effectual measures to abolish the worship and to
 dissolve the government of the Christians, it was thought
 necessary to subject to the most intolerable hardships the
 condition of those perverse individuals who should still
 reject the religion of nature, of Rome, and of their
 ancestors.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"After Diocletian had divested himself of the
 purple, Italy and Africa were administered under the name of
 Severus, and were exposed, without defence, to the
 implacable resentment of his master Galerius.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"After making a trial of his strength in the life of Agricola, and the description of Germany, he conceived, and at length executed, a more arduous work, the history of Rome, in thirty books, from the fall of Nero to the accession of Nerva.","('Agricola', 'EVENT'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('thirty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Nerva', 'PERSON')"
"After the success of the Persian war had raised the hopes
 and the reputation of Galerius, he passed a winter with
 Diocletian in the palace of Nicomedia; and the fate of
 Christianity became the object of their secret
 consultations. (147)","('the Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Nicomedia', 'LOC'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('147', 'CARDINAL')"
"Against
 those who resisted his power, or refused to flatter his
 vanity, the prelate of Antioch was arrogant, rigid, and
 inexorable; but he relaxed the discipline, and lavished the
 treasures of the church on his dependent clergy, who were
 permitted to imitate their master in the gratification of
 every sensual appetite.","('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"Allotting the same proportion to the
 provinces of Italy, Africa, and perhaps Spain, where, at the
 end of two or three years, the rigour of the penal laws was
 either suspended or abolished, the multitude of Christians
 in the Roman empire, on whom a capital punishment was
 inflicted by a judicial sentence, will be reduced to
 somewhat less than two thousand persons.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('the\r\n end of two or three years', 'DATE'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('less than two thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Although the policy of Diocletian and humanity of
 Constantius inclined them to preserve inviolate the maxims
 of toleration, it was soon discovered that their two
 associates, Maximian and Galerius, entertained the most
 implacable aversion for the name and religion of the
 Christians.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Amidst the frequent revolutions of the empire the Christians still flourished in peace and prosperity; and notwithstanding a celebrated era of martyrs has been deduced from the accession of Diocletian, (131) the new system of policy, introduced and maintained by the wisdom of that prince, continued, during more than eighteen years, to breathe the mildest and most liberal spirit of religious toleration.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('131', 'CARDINAL'), ('more than eighteen years', 'DATE')"
"Among the
 martyrs of Rome, Adauctus deserves the notice of posterity.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Adauctus', 'PERSON')"
"Among the Christians who
 had publicly confessed their religious principles, those who
 (as it very frequently happened) had been dismissed from the
 tribunal or the prisons of the Pagan magistrates obtained
 such honours as were justly due to their imperfect martyrdom
 and their generous resolution.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Pagan', 'NORP')"
"Among the Christians who were
 brought before the tribunal of the emperor, or, as it seems
 more probable, before that of the procurator of Judaea, two
 persons are said to have appeared, distinguished by their
 extraction, which was more truly noble than that of the
 greatest monarchs.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Judaea', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Among these Boniface
 was the favourite of his mistress and, as Aglae mixed love
 with devotion, it is reported that he was admitted to share
 her bed.","('Boniface', 'PERSON'), ('Aglae', 'PERSON')"
"An elegant supper
 was provided for the entertainment of the bishop, and his
 Christian friends were permitted for the last time to enjoy
 his society, whilst the streets were filled with a multitude
 of the faithful, anxious and alarmed at the approaching fate
 of their spiritual father. (86)","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"And as the reformers were
 animated by the love of civil as well as of religious
 freedom, the Catholic princes connected their own interest
 with that of the clergy, and enforced by fire and the sword
 the terrors of spiritual censures.","('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"Anonymous charges the emperor rejects, as too
 repugnant to the equity of his government; and he strictly
 requires, for the conviction of those to whom the guilt of
 Christianity is imputed, the positive evidence of a fair and
 open accuser.","('Christianity', 'NORP')"
"Anxious as
 they were to avoid the slightest infection of idolatry,
 their conscience forbade them to contribute to the honour of
 that daemon who had assumed the character of the Capitoline
 Jupiter.","('the Capitoline\r\n Jupiter', 'LOC')"
Ardour of the first Christians.,"('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Arguments like these may seem to have determined
 the reluctant mind of Diocletian to embrace a new system of
 persecution: but though we may suspect, it is not in our
 power to relate, the secret intrigues of the palace, the
 private views and resentments, the jealousy of women or
 eunuchs, and all those trifling but decisive causes which so
 often influence the fate of empires and the councils of the
 wisest monarchs.(148)
 Demolition of the church of Nicomedia.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('148', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nicomedia', 'GPE')"
"Arguments like these may seem to have determined
 the reluctant mind of Diocletian to embrace a new system of
 persecution: but though we may suspect, it is not in our
 power to relate, the secret intrigues of the palace, the
 private views and resentments, the jealousy of women or
 eunuchs, and all those trifling but decisive causes which so
 often influence the fate of empires and the councils of the
 wisest monarchs.(148)
Demolition of the church of Nicomedia.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('148', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nicomedia', 'GPE')"
"As a Pagan and as a soldier, it could scarcely be expected that Aurelian should enter into the discussion, whether the sentiments of Paul or those of his adversaries were most agreeable to the true standard of the orthodox faith.","('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('Aurelian', 'NORP'), ('Paul', 'PERSON')"
"As a very numerous though declining party among the
 Christians still adhered to the law of Moses, their efforts
 to dissemble their Jewish origin were detected by the
 decisive test of circumcision; (47) nor were the Roman 
 magistrates at leisure to inquire into the difference of
 their religious tenets.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Moses', 'PERSON'), ('Jewish', 'NORP'), ('47', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"As long as he commanded only the
 armies and provinces of Illyricum, he could with difficulty
 either find or make a considerable number of martyrs in a
 warlike country which had entertained the missionaries of
 the Gospel with more coldness and reluctance than any other
 part of the empire. (172)","('Illyricum', 'GPE'), ('Gospel', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('172', 'CARDINAL')"
"As often as any
 occasional severities were exercised in the different parts
 of the empire, the primitive Christians lamented and perhaps
 magnified their own sufferings;","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"As soon as the
 severity of the persecution was abated, the doors of the
 churches were assailed by the returning multitude of
 penitents, who detested their idolatrous submission, and who
 solicited with equal ardour, but with various success, their
 re-admission into the society of Christians.(103)
 Alternatives of severity and toleration.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('103', 'CARDINAL')"
"As soon as the
 severity of the persecution was abated, the doors of the
 churches were assailed by the returning multitude of
 penitents, who detested their idolatrous submission, and who
 solicited with equal ardour, but with various success, their
 re-admission into the society of Christians.(103)
Alternatives of severity and toleration.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('103', 'CARDINAL')"
"As soon as the sentence was proclaimed, a general cry of ""We
 will die with him""  arose at once among the listening multitude of Christians who waited before the palace gates.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"As the
 payment of this tribute was inflexibly refused by the Jews,
 and by them alone, the consideration of the treatment which
 they experienced from the Roman magistrates will serve to
 explain how far these speculations are justified by facts,
 and will lead us to discover the true causes of the
 persecution of Christianity.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Christianity', 'NORP')"
"As the edict against the Christians was designed for a
 general law of the whole empire, and as Diocletian and
 Galerius, though they might not wait for the consent, were
 assured of the concurrence, of the Western princes, it would
 appear more consonant to our ideas of policy that the
 governors of all the provinces should have received secret
 instructions to publish, on one and the same day, this
 declaration of war within their respective departments.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('the same day', 'DATE')"
"As the lives of the 
 faithful became less mortified and austere, they were every
 day less ambitious of the honours of martyrdom; and the
 soldiers of Christ, instead of distinguishing themselves by
 voluntary deeds of heroism, frequently deserted their post,
 and fled in confusion before the enemy whom it was their
 duty to resist.","('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"As they were
 actuated, not by the furious zeal of bigots, but by the
 temperate policy of legislators, contempt must often have
 relaxed, and humanity must frequently have suspended, the
 execution of those laws which they enacted against the
 humble and obscure followers of Christ.","('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"As they were for the greater part of the race of
 Abraham, they were distinguished by the peculiar mark of
 circumcision, offered up their devotions in the Temple of
 Jerusalem till its final destruction, and received both the
 Law and the Prophets as the genuine inspirations of the
 Deity.","('Abraham', 'PERSON'), ('the Temple of\r\n Jerusalem', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Law', 'PERSON')"
"At first, indeed, the
 magistrates were restrained from the effusion of blood; but
 the use of every other severity was permitted, and even
 recommended to their zeal; nor could the Christians, though
 they cheerfully resigned the ornaments of their churches,
 resolve to interrupt their religious assemblies, or to
 deliver their sacred books to the flames.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"At length, exactly one year (85) after Cyprian was first 
 apprehended, Galerius Maximus, proconsul of Africa, received
 the imperial warrant for the execution of the Christian
 teachers.","('one year (85', 'DATE'), ('Cyprian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Galerius Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"At present it may be sufficient to
 observe that every victory of Constantine was productive of
 some relief or benefit to the church.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"At the distance of sixty years it was the duty of the annalist to adopt the narratives of contemporaries; but it was natural for the philosopher to indulge himself in the description of the origin, the progress, and the character of the new sect, not so much according to the knowledge or prejudices of the age of Nero, as according to those of the time of Hadrian.","('sixty years', 'DATE'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Hadrian', 'PERSON')"
"At the earliest dawn of day
 the Praetorian praefect, (150) accompanied by several generals, tribunes, and officers of the revenue, repaired to the principal church of Nicomedia, which was situated on an
 eminence in the most populous and beautiful part of the
 city.","('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('150', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nicomedia', 'GPE')"
"At the same
 time they urge, with equal truth and propriety, that the
 charge is not less devoid of probability than it is
 destitute of evidence; they ask whether any one can
 seriously believe that the pure and holy precepts of the
 Gospel, which so frequently restrain the use of the most
 lawful enjoyments, should inculcate the practice of the most
 abominable crimes; that a large society should resolve to
 dishonour itself in the eyes of its own members; and that a
 great number of persons, of either sex, and every age and
 character, insensible to the fear of death or infamy, should
 consent to violate those principles which nature and
 education had imprinted most deeply in their minds. (20)","('Gospel', 'LAW'), ('20', 'CARDINAL')"
"Before he gave himself to the public he calmly waited till his genius had attained its full maturity, and he was more than forty years of age when a grateful regard for the memory of the virtuous Agricola extorted from him the most early of those historical compositions which will delight and instruct the most distant posterity.","('more than forty years of age', 'DATE'), ('Agricola', 'EVENT')"
"Bishops, perhaps for the
 first time, were seen at court; and, after the death of
 Alexander, when the inhuman Maximin discharged his fury on
 the favourites and servants of his unfortunate benefactor, a
 great number of Christians, of every rank, and of both
 sexes, were involved in the promiscuous massacre, which, on
 their account, has improperly received the name of
 Persecution.(117)
 Of Maximin, Philip and Decius.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Persecution', 'ORG'), ('117', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Philip', 'PERSON'), ('Decius', 'PERSON')"
"Bishops, perhaps for the
 first time, were seen at court; and, after the death of
 Alexander, when the inhuman Maximin discharged his fury on
 the favourites and servants of his unfortunate benefactor, a
 great number of Christians, of every rank, and of both
 sexes, were involved in the promiscuous massacre, which, on
 their account, has improperly received the name of
 Persecution.(117)
Of Maximin, Philip and Decius.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Persecution', 'ORG'), ('117', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Philip', 'PERSON'), ('Decius', 'PERSON')"
"Both parties seemed to acknowledge the truth of those miracles which were claimed by their adversaries; and while they were contented with ascribing them to the arts of magic, and to the power of daemons, they mutually concurred in restoring
 and establishing the reign of superstition.(139)","('139', 'CARDINAL')"
"But Datianus, the 
 president or governor of Spain, actuated either by zeal or
 policy, chose rather to execute the public edicts of the
 emperors than to understand the secret intentions of
 Constantius; and it can scarcely be doubted that his
 provincial administration was stained with the blood of a
 few martyrs.(166)","('Datianus', 'PERSON'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('166', 'CARDINAL')"
"But Paul considered the service
 of the church as a very lucrative profession. (126)","('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('126', 'CARDINAL')"
"But a few months had
 scarcely elapsed before the edicts published by the two
 Western emperors obliged Maximim to suspend the prosecution
 of his designs: the civil war which he so rashly undertook
 against Licinius employed all his attention; and the defeat
 and death of Maximin soon delivered the church from the last
 and most implacable of her enemies.(177)","('a few months', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('Maximim', 'PERSON'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('177', 'CARDINAL')"
"But all the
 prudence and humanity affected by Nero on this occasion were
 insufficient to preserve him from the popular suspicion.","('Nero', 'PERSON')"
"But as long as
 Constantius remained in the subordinate station of Caesar,
 it was not in his power openly to reject the edicts of
 Diocletian, or to disobey the commands of Maximian.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'ORG')"
"But he had scarcely finished the
 term of his annual magistracy, when on a slight pretence he
 was condemned and executed; Domitilla was banished to a
 desolate island on the coast of Campania ;(53) and sentences 
 either of death or of confiscation were pronounced against a
 great number of persons who were involved in the same
 accusation.","('Domitilla', 'PERSON'), ('Campania', 'GPE'), ('53', 'CARDINAL')"
"But his best 
 apology may be found in the cheerful resolution with which
 about eight years afterwards, he suffered death in the cause
 of religion.","('about eight years afterwards', 'DATE')"
"But if the improbability of the fact itself should prevail over the weight of evidence; if Grotius should be convicted of exaggerating the merit and sufferings of the reformers; (186) we shall be naturally led to inquire what confidence can be placed in the doubtful and imperfect monuments of ancient credulity; what degree of credit can be assigned to a courtly bishop and a passionate declaimer, who, under the protection of Constantine, enjoyed the exclusive privilege of recording the persecutions inflicted on the Christians by the vanquished rivals or disregarded predecessors of their gracious sovereign.","('Grotius', 'PERSON'), ('186', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"But if the zeal of Cyprian was supported by the sincere
 conviction of the truth of those doctrines which he
 preached, the crown of martyrdom must have appeared to him
 as an object of desire rather than of terror.","('Cyprian', 'PERSON')"
"But it is certain, and we may appeal to the 
 grateful confessions of the first Christians, that the
 greatest part of those magistrates who exercised in the
 provinces the authority of the emperor or of the senate, and
 to whose hands alone the jurisdiction of life and death was
 intrusted, behaved like men of polished manners and liberal
 education, who respected the rules of justice, and who were
 conversant with the precepts of philosophy.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"But it would be improper to dismiss this account of Nero's
 persecution till we have made some observations that may
 serve to remove the difficulties with which it is perplexed,
 and to throw some light on the subsequent history of the
 church.","('Nero', 'PERSON')"
"But the
 Christians were not permitted to complain of any injury
 which they themselves had suffered; and thus those
 unfortunate sectaries were exposed to the severity, while
 they were excluded from the benefits, of public justice.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"But the
 policy of a well-ordered government must sometimes have
 interposed in behalf of the oppressed Christians; nor was it
 possible for the Roman princes entirely to remove the
 apprehension of punishment, or to connive at every act of
 fraud and violence, without exposing their own authority and
 the rest of their subjects to the most alarming dangers.(153)
 Zeal and punishment of a Christian.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('153', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"But the
 policy of a well-ordered government must sometimes have
 interposed in behalf of the oppressed Christians; nor was it
 possible for the Roman princes entirely to remove the
 apprehension of punishment, or to connive at every act of
 fraud and violence, without exposing their own authority and
 the rest of their subjects to the most alarming dangers.(153)
Zeal and punishment of a Christian.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('153', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"But the
 princes and magistrates of ancient Rome were strangers to
 those principles which inspired and authorised the
 inflexible obstinacy of the Christians in the cause of
 truth, nor could they themselves discover in their own
 breasts any motives which would have prompted them to refuse
 a legal, and as it were a natural, submission to the sacred
 institutions of their country.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"But the Jews possessed very powerful advocates in the palace, and even in the heart of the tyrant; his wife and mistress, the beautiful Poppaea, and a favourite player of the race of Abraham, who had already employed their intercession on behalf of the obnoxious people.(40)","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Poppaea', 'PERSON'), ('Abraham', 'PERSON'), ('40', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the decrees of Heaven had
 already disarmed their malice; and though they might
 sometimes exert the licentious privilege of sedition, they
 no longer possessed the administration of criminal justice;
 nor did they find it easy to infuse into the calm breast of
 a Roman magistrate the rancour of their own zeal and
 prejudice.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But the emperor would not
 venture to insert in the preamble the name of Maximin, whose
 consent was of the greatest importance, and who succeeded a
 few days afterwards to the provinces of Asia.","('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('a\r\n few days', 'DATE'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"But the general assertion of Origen may be explained and confirmed by the particular testimony of his friend Dionysius, who, in the immense city of Alexandria,
 and under the rigorous persecution of Decius, reckons only ten men and seven women who suffered for the profession of the Christian name.(75)
 Example of Cyprian bishop of Carthage 
 During the same period of persecution, the zealous, the
 eloquent, the ambitious Cyprian governed the church, not
 only of Carthage, but even of Africa.","('Origen', 'PERSON'), ('Dionysius', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Decius', 'PERSON'), ('only ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Cyprian', 'NORP'), ('Cyprian', 'NORP'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"But the general assertion of Origen may be explained and confirmed by the particular testimony of his friend Dionysius, who, in the immense city of Alexandria,
 and under the rigorous persecution of Decius, reckons only ten men and seven women who suffered for the profession of the Christian name.(75)
Example of Cyprian bishop of Carthage 
 During the same period of persecution, the zealous, the
 eloquent, the ambitious Cyprian governed the church, not
 only of Carthage, but even of Africa.","('Origen', 'PERSON'), ('Dionysius', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Decius', 'PERSON'), ('only ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Cyprian', 'NORP'), ('Cyprian', 'NORP'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"But the laws which Severus had enacted soon expired with the
 authority of that emperor; and the Christians, after this
 accidental tempest, enjoyed a calm of thirty-eight years.
 (112)","('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('thirty-eight years', 'DATE'), ('112', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the leisure of the two empresses, of his wife Prisca, and of Valeria his daughter, permitted them to listen with more attention and respect to the truths of Christianity, which in every age has acknowledged its important obligations to female devotion.(132)","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Prisca', 'PERSON'), ('Valeria', 'PERSON'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('132', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the ruin of the churches was easily effected
 by the authority of the government and by the labour of the
 Pagans.","('Pagans', 'NORP')"
"But this principle, which protected the Jewish
 synagogue, afforded not any favour or security to the
 primitive church.","('Jewish', 'NORP')"
"But this treacherous calm was of short duration; nor could
 the Christians of the East place any confidence in the
 character of their sovereign.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"But we are still assured by monuments of
 brass and marble, by the Imperial medals, and by the
 Antonine column, that neither the prince nor the people
 entertained any sense of this signal obligation, since they
 unanimously attribute their deliverance to the providence of
 Jupiter, and to the interposition of Mercury.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Antonine', 'PERSON'), ('Jupiter', 'LOC'), ('Mercury', 'ORG')"
"But when Galerius had obtained the 
 supreme power and the government of the East, he indulged in
 their fullest extent his zeal and cruelty, not only in the
 provinces of Thrace and Asia, which acknowledged his
 immediate jurisdiction, but in those of Syria, Palestine,
 and Egypt, where Maximin gratified his own inclination by
 yielding a rigorous obedience to the stern commands of his
 benefactor.(173)","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('173', 'CARDINAL')"
"But while we applaud the justice, we should not overlook the policy of Aurelian, who was desirous of restoring and cementing the dependence of the provinces of the capital, by every means which could bind the interest or prejudices of any part of his subjects.(130)
 Peace and prosperity of the church under Diocletian.","('Aurelian', 'PERSON'), ('130', 'CARDINAL'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"But while we applaud the justice, we should not overlook the policy of Aurelian, who was desirous of restoring and cementing the dependence of the provinces of the capital, by every means which could bind the interest or prejudices of any part of his subjects.(130)
Peace and prosperity of the church under Diocletian.","('Aurelian', 'PERSON'), ('130', 'CARDINAL'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"By
 the same edict, the property of the church was at once
 confiscated; and the several parts of which it might consist
 were either sold to the highest bidder, united to the
 Imperial domain, bestowed on the cities and corporations, or
 granted to the solicitations of rapacious courtiers.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"By
 their lofty claim of superior sanctity the Jews might
 provoke the Polytheists to consider them as an odious and
 impure race.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Polytheists', 'NORP')"
"By a
 second edict the magistrates were commanded to employ every
 method of severity which might reclaim them from their
 odious superstition, and oblige them to return to the
 established worship of the gods.","('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"By a singular fatality, the hardships which they had endured
 under the government of a virtuous prince immediately ceased
 on the accession of a tyrant; and as none except themselves
 had experienced the injustice of Marcus, so they alone were
 protected by the lenity of Commodus.","('Marcus', 'PERSON'), ('Commodus', 'PRODUCT')"
"By another rescript we shall signify our intentions to the judges and magistrates, and we hope that our indulgence will engage the Christians to offer up their prayers to the Deity whom they adore for our safety and prosperity, for their own, and for that of the republic."" (174)","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('174', 'CARDINAL')"
"By embracing the faith of the Gospel the
 Christians incurred the supposed guilt of an unnatural and
 unpardonable offence.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"By his pride and luxury the Christian
 religion was rendered odious in the eyes of the Gentiles.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Gentiles', 'NORP')"
"By imitating
 the awful secrecy which reigned in the Eleusinian mysteries,
 the Christians had flattered themselves that they should
 render their sacred institutions more respectable in the
 eyes of the Pagan World. (18)","('Eleusinian', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('the Pagan World', 'ORG'), ('18', 'CARDINAL')"
"By producing
 these false declarations, the opulent and timid Christians
 were enabled to silence the malice of an informer, and to
 reconcile in some measure their safety with their religion.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"By the first of these edicts the governors
 of the provinces were directed to apprehend all persons of
 the ecclesiastical order; and the prisons destined for the
 vilest criminals were soon filled with a multitude of
 bishops, presbyters, deacons, readers and exorcists.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"By the general indulgence of Polytheism, and by the
 mild temper of Antoninus Pius, the Jews were restored to
 their ancient privileges, and once more obtained the
 permission of circumcising their children, with the easy
 restraint that they should never confer on any foreign
 proselyte that distinguishing mark of the Hebrew race.(4)","('Antoninus Pius', 'PERSON'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Hebrew', 'NORP'), ('4', 'CARDINAL')"
"By the influence of the
 magistrates, and of the sacerdotal order, a great number of
 dutiful addresses were obtained, particularly from the
 cities of Nicomedia, Antioch, and Tyre, which artfully
 represented the well-known intentions of the court as the
 general sense of the people; solicited the emperor to
 consult the laws of justice rather than the dictates of his
 clemency; expressed their abhorrence of the Christians, and
 humbly prayed that those impious sectaries might at least be
 excluded from the limits of their respective territories.","('Nicomedia', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Tyre', 'GPE'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"By the wise dispensation of Providence a mysterious veil
 was cast over the infancy of the church, which, till the
 faith of the Christians was matured, and their numbers were
 multiplied, served to protect them not only from the malice
 but even from the knowledge of the Pagan world.","('Providence', 'GPE'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Pagan', 'NORP')"
"By their incessant labour,
 a sacred edifice, which towered above the Imperial palace,
 and had long excited the indignation and envy of the
 Gentiles, was in a few hours levelled with the ground.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Gentiles', 'NORP'), ('a few hours', 'TIME')"
"Christianity persecuted by the Roman emperors
 IF we seriously consider the purity of the Christian
 religion, the sanctity of its moral precepts, and the
 innocent as well as austere lives of the greater number of
 those who during the first ages embraced the faith of the
 Gospel, we should naturally suppose that so benevolent a
 doctrine would have been received with due reverence even
 by the unbelieving world; that the learned and the polite,
 however they might deride the miracles, would have esteemed
 the virtues of the new sect; and that the magistrates,
 instead of persecuting, would have protected an order of men
 who yielded the most passive obedience to the laws, though
 they declined the active cares of war and government.","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gospel', 'ORG')"
"Conduct of the Roman government towards the Christians, from the reign of Nero to that of Constantine","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Contenting themselves, for the most part, with the milder chastisements of imprisonment, exile, or slavery in the mines,(69) they left the unhappy victims of their justice some reason to hope that a prosperous event, the accession, the marriage, or the triumph of an emperor, might speedily restore them by a general pardon to their former state.","('69', 'DATE')"
"Could we suppose that the
 bishop of Carthage had employed the profession of the
 Christian faith only as the instrument of his avarice or
 ambition, it was still incumbent on him to support the
 character which he had assumed,(89) and, if he possessed the 
 smallest degree of manly fortitude, rather to expose himself
 to the most cruel tortures than by a single act to exchange
 the reputation of a whole life for the abhorrence of his
 Christian brethren and the contempt of the Gentile world.","('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('89', 'DATE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Gentile', 'NORP')"
"Cruel punishment of the Christians, as the incendiaries of the city.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Cruelty and superstition were
 the ruling passions of the soul of Maximin.","('Maximin', 'PERSON')"
"Cyprian replied without hesitation that
 he was a Christian and a bishop, devoted to the worship of
 the true and only Deity, to whom he offered up his daily
 supplications for the safety and prosperity of the two
 emperors, his lawful sovereigns.","('Cyprian', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Deity', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Desirous of repairing the mischief that he had
 occasioned, he published in his own name, and in those of
 Licinius and Constantine, a general edict, which, after a
 pompous recital of the Imperial titles, proceeded in the
 following manner:","('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"Diocletian and his colleagues
 frequently conferred the most important offices on those
 persons who avowed their abhorrence for the worship of the
 gods, but who had displayed abilities proper for the service
 of the state.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Diocletian had no sooner published his edicts against the
 Christians than, as if he had been desirous of committing to
 other hands the work of persecution, he divested himself of
 the Imperial purple.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"Distinctions like these, whilst they display the exalted 
 merit, betray the inconsiderable number, of those who
 suffered and of those who died for the profession of
 Christianity.","('Christianity', 'NORP')"
"During a long
 period, from the death of Christ to that memorable
 rebellion, we cannot discover any traces of Roman
 intolerance, unless they are to be found in the sudden, the
 transient, but the cruel persecution, which was exercised by
 Nero against the Christians of the capital, thirty-five
 years after the former, and only two years before the
 latter, of those great events.","('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('thirty-five\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('only two years', 'DATE')"
"During the
 ages of ignorance which followed the subversion of the Roman
 empire in the West, the bishops of the Imperial city
 extended their dominion over the laity as well as clergy of
 the Latin church.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"During the
 whole course of his reign Marcus despised the Christians as
 a philosopher, and punished them as a sovereign.(106)
 State of the Christians in the reigns of Commodus and Severus.","('Marcus', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('106', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Commodus', 'NORP'), ('Severus', 'PERSON')"
"During the
 whole course of his reign Marcus despised the Christians as
 a philosopher, and punished them as a sovereign.(106)
State of the Christians in the reigns of Commodus and Severus.","('Marcus', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('106', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Commodus', 'NORP'), ('Severus', 'PERSON')"
"Even the conduct of Maxentius towards the bishops of 
 Rome and Carthage may be considered as the proof of his
 toleration, since it is probable that the most orthodox
 princes would adopt the same measures with regard to their
 established clergy.","('Maxentius', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"Every Christian rejected with contempt the
 superstitions of his family, his city, and his province.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"Every mode of torture was put in
 practice, and the court, as well as city, was polluted with
 many bloody executions. (155)","('155', 'CARDINAL')"
"Examples of such a 
 nature savour much less of religious persecution than of
 martial or even civil law: but they served to alienate the
 mind of the emperors, to justify the severity of Galerius,
 who dismissed a great number of Christian officers from
 their employments and to authorise the opinion that a sect
 of enthusiasts, which avowed principles so repugnant to the
 public safety, must either remain useless, or would soon
 become dangerous subjects of the empire.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
Fire of the palace of Nicomedia imputed to the Christians..,"('Nicomedia', 'GPE'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"For
 this treasonable resistance Mensurius was summoned to court,
 and, instead of receiving a legal sentence of death or
 banishment, he was permitted, after a short examination, to
 return to his diocese. (170)","('Mensurius', 'PERSON'), ('170', 'CARDINAL')"
"For Paul indulged himself very
 freely in the pleasures of the table, and he had received
 into the episcopal palace two young and beautiful women, as
 the constant companions of his leisure moments.(128)","('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('128', 'CARDINAL')"
"For a while this dire superstition was checked, but it again burst forth; and not only spread itself over Judaea, the first seat of this mischievous sect, but was even introduced into Rome, the common asylum which receives and protects whatever is impure, whatever is atrocious.","('Judaea', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Four Roman
 emperors, with their families, their favourites, and their
 adherents, perished by the sword in the space of ten years,
 during which the bishop of Carthage guided by his authority
 and eloquence the councils of the African church.","('Four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('ten years', 'DATE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('African', 'NORP')"
"From the
 history of Eusebius it may however be collected that only
 nine bishops were punished with death; and we are assured,
 by his particular enumeration of the martyrs of Palestine,
 that no more than ninety-two Christians were entitled to
 that honourable appellation.(182)","('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('only\r\n nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('no more than ninety-two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('182', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the 
 ordinary term of human life, it may very naturally be
 presumed that most of them were deceased before the
 discontent of the Jews broke out into that furious war which
 was terminated only by the ruin of Jerusalem.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
"From the reign of Nero to that of Antoninus Pius,
 the Jews discovered a fierce impatience of the dominion of
 Rome, which repeatedly broke out in the most furious
 massacres and insurrections.","('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Antoninus Pius', 'PERSON'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"From their reflections, or even from their own
 feelings, a Charles V. or a Louis XIV.","('a Charles V.', 'PERSON'), ('Louis XIV', 'PERSON')"
"Galerius at length
 extorted from him the permission of summoning a council,
 composed of a few persons the most distinguished in the
 civil and military departments of the state.","('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
Galerius prevails on Diocletian to begin a general persecution.,"('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
Galerius publishes an edict of toleration,"('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"Galerius publishes an edict of toleration
""Among the important cares which have occupied our mind for the utility and preservation of the empire, it was our
 intention to correct and re-establish all things according to the ancient laws and public discipline of the Romans.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"He acknowledges the
 difficulty of fixing any general plan; but he lays down two
 salutary rules, which often afforded relief and support to
 the distressed Christians.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"He addressed several edifying letters to the emperor 
 Philip, to his wife, and to his mother, and as soon as that
 prince, who was born in the neighbourhood of Palestine, had
 usurped the Imperial sceptre, the Christians acquired a
 friend and a protector.","('Philip', 'PERSON'), ('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"He consented with reluctance
 to the ruin of the churches, but he ventured to protect the
 Christians themselves from the fury of the populace and from
 the rigour of the laws.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"He considered the bishops of Italy as the most impartial and respectable judges among the Christians, and, as soon as he was informed that they had unanimously approved the sentence of the council, he acquiesced in their opinion, and immediately gave orders that Paul should be compelled to relinquish the temporal possessions belonging to an office, of which, in the judgment of his brethren, he had been regularly deprived.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Paul', 'PERSON')"
"He depended on their gratitude and affection,
 and very naturally presumed that the injuries which they had
 suffered, and the dangers which they still apprehended, from
 his most inveterate enemy, would secure the fidelity of a
 party already considerable by their numbers and opulence.
 (168)","('168', 'CARDINAL')"
"He earnestly beseeches the Romans
 that, when he should be exposed in the amphitheatre, they
 would not, by their kind but unseasonable intercession,
 deprive him of the crown of glory; and he declares his
 resolution to provoke and irritate the wild beasts which
 might be employed as the instruments of his death.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
He is degraded from the see of Antioch.,"('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"He possessed every
 quality which could engage the reverence of the faithful, or
 provoke the suspicions and resentment of the Pagan
 magistrates.","('Pagan', 'NORP')"
"He praises their zeal
 and devotion in terms of the highest satisfaction, descants
 on the obstinate impiety of the Christians, and betrays, by
 the readiness with which he consents to their banishment,
 that he considered himself as receiving, rather than as
 conferring, an obligation.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"He there
 acquainted him with the imperial mandate which he had just
 received,(81) that those who had abandoned the Roman religion 
 should immediately return to the practice of the ceremonies
 of their ancestors.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"He was examined in the city of Tingi by
 the president of that part of Mauritania; and as he was
 convicted by his own confession, he was condemned and
 beheaded for the crime of desertion.(146)","('Tingi', 'GPE'), ('Mauritania', 'GPE'), ('146', 'CARDINAL')"
"He was of a noble family in Italy, and had raised himself,
 through the successive honours of the palace, to the
 important office of treasurer of the private demesnes.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"He was recalled from banishment, and,
 though not yet permitted to return to Carthage, his own
 gardens in the neighbourhood of the capital were assigned
 for the place of his residence.(84)
 His condemnation.","('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"He was recalled from banishment, and,
 though not yet permitted to return to Carthage, his own
 gardens in the neighbourhood of the capital were assigned
 for the place of his residence.(84)
His condemnation.","('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"He withdrew himself into
 an obscure solitude, from whence he could maintain a
 constant correspondence with the clergy and people of
 Carthage; and, concealing himself till the tempest was past,
 he preserved his life, without relinquishing either his
 power or his reputation.","('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"Her fortune enabled her to gratify the pious desire
 of obtaining some sacred relics from the East.","('East', 'LOC')"
"His authority would alone be sufficient 
 to annihilate that formidable army of martyrs, whose relics, drawn for the most part from the catacombs of Rome, have replenished so many churches, (73) and whose marvellous 
 achievements have been the subject of so many volumes of holy romance.(74)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('74', 'CARDINAL')"
"His corpse remained during some hours exposed to the curiosity of the Gentiles, but in the night it was removed, and transported, in a triumphal procession and with a splendid illumination, to the burial place of the Christians.","('some hours', 'TIME'), ('Gentiles', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"His extreme caution did not however
 escape the censure of the more rigid Christians, who
 lamented, or the reproaches of his personal enemies, who
 insulted, a conduct which they considered as a pusillanimous
 and criminal desertion of the most sacred duty.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"His fortunate son, from the first moment of his
 accession declaring himself the protector of the church, at
 length deserved the appellation of the first emperor who
 publicly professed and established the Christian religion.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"His mild constancy in the midst of cruel and
 voluntary sufferings, his universal benevolence, and the
 sublime simplicity of his actions and character, were
 insufficient in the opinion of those carnal men, to
 compensate for the want of fame, of empire, and of success;
 and whilst they refused to acknowledge his stupendous
 triumph over the powers of darkness and of the grave, they
 misrepresented, or they insulted, the equivocal birth,
 wandering life, and ignominious death, of the divine Author
 of Christianity.(13)
The union and assemblies of the Christians considered as a dangerous conspiracy.","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('13', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"His reputation was
 diffused over Africa and Italy; an account of his behaviour
 was published for the edification of the Christian world;(83) 
 and his solitude was frequently interrupted by the letters,
 the visits, and the congratulations of the faithful.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('83', 'CARDINAL')"
"How natural was it for Tacitus, in the time of Hadrian, to appropriate to the Christians the guilt and the sufferings which he might, with far greater truth and justice, have attributed to a sect whose odious memory was almost extinguished!","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Humanity is shocked at the
 recital of the horrid cruelties which they committed in the
 cities of Egypt, of Cyprus, and of Cyrene, where they dwelt
 in treacherous friendship with the unsuspecting natives;(1) 
 and we are tempted to applaud the severe retaliation which
 was exercised by the arms of the legions against a race of
 fanatics whose dire and credulous superstition seemed to
 render them the implacable enemies not only of the Roman
 government, but of human kind.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Cyprus', 'GPE'), ('Cyrene', 'GPE'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"I. A modern Inquisitor would hear with surprise, that,
 whenever an information was given to a Roman magistrate of
 any person within his jurisdiction who had embraced the sect
 of the Christians, the charge was communicated to the party
 accused, and that a convenient time was allowed him to
 settle his domestic concerns, and to prepare an answer to
 the crime which was imputed to him.(99)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"If 
 threats and persuasions proved ineffectual, he had often
 recourse to violence; the scourge and the rack were called
 in to supply the deficiency of argument, and every art of
 cruelty was employed to subdue such inflexible, and, as it
 appeared to the Pagans, such criminal obstinacy.","('Pagans', 'NORP')"
"If the empire had been afflicted by any recent
 calamity, by a plague, a famine, or an unsuccessful war; if
 the Tiber had, or if the Nile had not, risen beyond its
 banks; if the earth had shaken, or if the temperate order of
 the seasons had been interrupted, the superstitious Pagans
 were convinced that the crimes and the impiety of the
 Christians, who were spared by the excessive lenity of the
 government, had at length provoked the Divine justice.","('Tiber', 'LOC'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Pagans', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"If there were any
 Christians in that army, it was natural that they should
 ascribe some merit to the fervent prayers which, in the
 moment of danger, they had offered up for their own and the
 public safety.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"If we
 are obliged to submit our belief to the authority of
 Grotius, it must be allowed that the number of Protestants
 who were executed in a single province and a single reign, far exceeded that of the primitive martyrs in the space of three centuries, and of the Roman empire.","('Grotius', 'PERSON'), ('Protestants', 'NORP'), ('the space of three centuries', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"If, indeed, we were disposed to adopt the 
 traditions of a too credulous antiquity, we might relate the
 distant peregrinations, the wonderful achievements, and the
 various deaths of the twelve apostles: but a more accurate
 inquiry will induce us to doubt whether any of those persons
 who had been witnesses to the miracles of Christ were
 permitted, beyond the limits of Palestine, to seal with
 their blood the truth of their testimony. (27)","('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('27', 'CARDINAL')"
"If, on
 the other hand, we recollect the universal toleration of
 Polytheism, as it was invariably maintained by the faith of
 the people, the incredulity of philosophers, and the policy
 of the Roman senate and emperors, we are at a loss to
 discover what new offence the Christians had committed, what
 new provocation could exasperate the mild indifference of
 antiquity, and what new motives could urge the Roman
 princes, who beheld without concern a thousand forms of
 religion subsisting in peace under their gentle sway, to
 inflict a severe punishment on any part of their subjects
 who had chosen for themselves a singular but an inoffensive
 mode of faith and worship.","('Polytheism', 'ORG'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('a thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"If, on the contrary, they failed in their proofs,
 they incurred the severe and perhaps capital penalty, which,
 according to a law published by the emperor Hadrian, was
 inflicted on those who falsely attributed to their
 fellow-citizens the crime of Christianity.","('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('Christianity', 'NORP')"
"In a small town in Phrygia,
 of whose name as well as situation we are left ignorant, it
 should seem that the magistrates and the body of the people
 had embraced the Christian faith; and as some resistance
 might be apprehended to the execution of the edict, the
 governor of the province was supported by a numerous
 detachment of legionaries.","('Phrygia', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"In all the great cities of the empire,
 the temples were repaired and beautified by the order of
 Maximin, and the officiating priests of the various deities
 were subjected to the authority of a superior pontiff
 destined to oppose the bishop, and to promote the cause of
 paganism.","('Maximin', 'PERSON')"
"In consequence of these
 orders, great numbers of Christians were released from
 prison, or delivered from the mines.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"In every persecution there were great numbers of
 unworthy Christians who publicly disowned or renounced the
 faith which they had professed; and who confirmed the
 sincerity of their abjuration by the legal acts of burning
 incense or of offering sacrifices.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"In his domestic chapel he placed the
 statues of Abraham, of Orpheus, of Apollonius, and of
 Christ, as an honour justly due to those respectable sages
 who had instructed mankind in the various modes of
 addressing their homage to the supreme and universal Deity.
 (116)","('Abraham', 'PERSON'), ('Orpheus', 'PERSON'), ('Apollonius', 'LOC'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('116', 'CARDINAL')"
"In others they more literally complied
 with the terms of the edict; and, after taking away the
 doors, the benches, and the pulpit, which they burnt as it
 were in a funeral pile, they completely demolished the
 remainder of the edifice. (160)","('160', 'CARDINAL')"
"In particular, it has pleased
 them to suppose that the zeal of the Roman magistrates,
 disdaining every consideration of moral virtue or public
 decency, endeavoured to seduce those whom they were unable
 to vanquish, and that by their orders the most brutal
 violence was offered to those whom they found it impossible
 to seduce.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the
 general administration of the provinces they obeyed the laws
 which their benefactor had established; but they frequently
 found occasions of exercising within their camp and palaces
 a secret persecution, (144) for which the imprudent zeal of 
 the Christians sometimes offered the most specious
 pretences.","('144', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"In the Netherlands alone
 more than one hundred thousand of the subjects of Charles V.
 are said to have suffered by the hand of the executioner;
 and this extraordinary number is attested by Grotius,(185) a 
 man of genius and learning, who preserved his moderation
 amidst the fury of contending sects, and who composed the
 annals of his own age and country at a time when the
 invention of printing had facilitated the means of
 intelligence and increased the danger of detection.","('Netherlands', 'GPE'), ('more than one hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Charles V.', 'PERSON'), ('Grotius', 'PERSON'), ('185', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the autumn of the first year of
 the persecution the two emperors met at Rome to celebrate
 their triumph; several oppressive laws appear to have issued
 from their secret consultations, and the diligence of the
 magistrates was animated by the presence of their
 sovereigns.","('the autumn of the first year', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In the first
 six months, however, of his new reign, Maximin affected to
 adopt the prudent counsels of his predecessor; and though he
 never condescended to secure the tranquillity of the church
 by a public edict, Sabinus, his Praetorian praefect,
 addressed a circular letter to all the governors and
 magistrates of the provinces, expatiating on the Imperial
 clemency, acknowledging the invincible obstinacy of the
 Christians, and directing the officers of justice to cease
 their ineffectual prosecutions, and to connive at the secret
 assemblies of those enthusiasts.","('the first\r\n six months', 'DATE'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Sabinus', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"In the first part of his reign he surpassed in
 clemency those princes who had been suspected of an
 attachment to the Christian faith.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"In the last three years
 and a half, listening to the insinuations of a minister
 addicted to the superstitions of Egypt, he adopted the
 maxims, and imitated the severity, of his predecessor
 Decius.(123)","('the last three years\r\n and a half', 'DATE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Decius', 'PERSON'), ('123', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the last years of the reign of Trajan,
 whilst the victorious monarch extended the power of Rome
 beyond its ancient limits, the historian was describing, in
 the second and fourth books of his Annals, the tyranny of
 Tiberius;(39) and the emperor Hadrian must have succeeded to the throne before Tacitus, in the regular prosecution of his work, could relate the fire of the capital and the cruelty
 of Nero towards the unfortunate Christians.","('the last years', 'DATE'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Annals', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('39', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"In the morning he appeared 
 before the tribunal of the proconsul, who, after informing himself of the name and situation of Cyprian, commanded him to offer sacrifice, and pressed him to reflect on the consequences of his disobedience.","('the morning', 'TIME'), ('Cyprian', 'PERSON')"
"In the tenth year of the reign of Nero the capital of the
 empire was afflicted by a fire which raged beyond the memory
 or example of former ages.(28)","('the tenth year', 'DATE'), ('Nero', 'PERSON')"
"In their room it was 
 necessary to offer some other victims, and it might easily be suggested that, although the genuine followers of Moses were innocent of the fire of Rome, there had arisen among them a new and pernicious sect of GALILEANS, which was capable of the most horrid crimes Under the appellation of GALILEANS two distinctions of men were confounded, the most opposite to each other in their manners and principles; the disciples who had embraced the faith of Jesus of Nazareth, (41) and the zealots who had followed the standard of Judas the Gaulonite.(42)","('Moses', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jesus of Nazareth', 'PERSON'), ('41', 'CARDINAL'), ('Judas', 'PERSON'), ('42', 'CARDINAL')"
"In this
 mitigated persecution we may still discover the indulgent
 spirit of Rome and of the Polytheism, which so readily
 admitted every excuse in favour of those who practised the
 religious ceremonies of their fathers.(111)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('111', 'CARDINAL')"
"In this general view of the persecution which was first
 authorised by the edicts of Diocletian, I have purposely
 refrained from describing the particular sufferings and
 deaths of the Christian martyrs.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"In this perplexity he had recourse to his usual
 expedient, of submitting to the wisdom of Trajan an
 impartial, and, in some respects, a favourable account of
 the new superstition, requesting the emperor that he would
 condescend to resolve his doubts and to instruct his
 ignorance.(57)","('Trajan', 'PERSON')"
"It
 was at least to be expected that the convenience of the
 public highways and established posts would have enabled the
 emperors to transmit their orders with the utmost despatch
 from the palace of Nicomedia to the extremities of the Roman
 world; and that they would not have suffered fifty days to
 elapse before the edict was published in Syria, and near
 four months before it was signified to the cities of Africa.
 (157)","('Nicomedia', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('fifty days', 'DATE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('four months', 'DATE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('157', 'CARDINAL')"
"It could scarcely be expected that any 
 government should suffer the action of Marcellus the
 centurion to pass with impunity.","('Marcellus', 'PERSON')"
"It is likewise probable that the persons who
 assumed so invidious an office were obliged to declare the
 grounds of their suspicions, to specify (both in respect to
 time and place) the secret assemblies which their Christian
 adversary had frequented, and to disclose a great number of
 circumstances which were concealed with the most vigilant
 jealousy from the eye of the profane.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"It is remarkable that, of so great a multitude of bishops in the province of Africa, Cyprian was the first who was esteemed worthy to obtain the crown of martyrdom.(88)
 Various incitements to martyrdom.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Cyprian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('88', 'CARDINAL')"
"It is remarkable that, of so great a multitude of bishops in the province of Africa, Cyprian was the first who was esteemed worthy to obtain the crown of martyrdom.(88)
Various incitements to martyrdom.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Cyprian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('88', 'CARDINAL')"
"It is somewhat remarkable that the flames of war consumed
 almost at the same time the Temple of Jerusalem and the
 Capitol of Rome ; (44) and it appears no less singular that 
 the tribute which devotion had destined to the former should
 have been converted by the power of an assaulting victor to
 restore and adorn the splendour of the latter.","('the Temple of Jerusalem', 'FAC'), ('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('44', 'CARDINAL')"
"It is well known, and has been
 already observed, that Roman policy viewed with the utmost
 jealousy and distrust any association among its subjects;
 and that the privileges of private corporations, though
 formed for the most harmless or beneficial purposes, were
 bestowed with a very sparing hand.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It may be presumed that they insisted on every
 topic which might interest the pride, the piety, or the
 fears, of their sovereign in the destruction of
 Christianity.","('Christianity', 'NORP')"
"It was
 only in the third year of his administration that he had
 reason, during a few months, to apprehend the severe edicts
 of Decius, the vigilance of the magistrate, and the clamours
 of the multitude, His danger and flight.","('the third year', 'DATE'), ('a few months', 'DATE'), ('Decius', 'PERSON')"
"It was
 sometimes faintly insinuated, and sometimes boldly asserted,
 that the same bloody sacrifices, and the same incestuous
 festivals, which were so falsely ascribed to the orthodox
 believers, were in reality celebrated by the Marcionites, by
 the Carpocratians, and by several other sects of the
 Gnostics, who, notwithstanding they might deviate into the
 paths of heresy, were still actuated by the sentiments of
 men, and still governed by the precepts of Christianity.(21) 
 Accusations of a similar kind were retorted upon the church
 by the schismatics who had departed from its communion,(22) 
 and it was confessed on all sides that the most scandalous
 licentiousness of manners prevailed among great numbers of
 those who affected the name of Christians.","('Marcionites', 'NORP'), ('Carpocratians', 'NORP'), ('Gnostics', 'NORP'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('21', 'CARDINAL'), ('22', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"It was by announcing himself as
 their long-expected deliverer, and by calling on all the
 descendants of Abraham to assert the hope of Israel, that
 the famous Barchochebas collected a formidable army, with
 which he resisted during two years the power of the emperor
 Hadrian.","('Abraham', 'PERSON'), ('Israel', 'GPE'), ('Barchochebas', 'PERSON'), ('two years', 'DATE'), ('Hadrian', 'PERSON')"
"It was conceived in the following terms: 
 ""That Thascius Cyprianus should be immediately beheaded, as the enemy of the gods of Rome, and as the chief and ringleader of a criminal association, which he had seduced into an impious resistance against the laws of the most holy emperors Valerian and Gallienus."" (87)","('Thascius Cyprianus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Valerian', 'PERSON'), ('Gallienus', 'PERSON'), ('87', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was fortunate for the
 reposes or at least for the reputation, of the first
 Christians, that the magistrates sometimes proceeded with
 more temper and moderation than is usually consistent with
 religious zeal, and that they reported, as the impartial
 result of their judicial inquiry, that the sectaries who had
 deserted the established worship appeared to them sincere in
 their professions and blameless in their manners, however
 they might incur, by their absurd and excessive
 superstition, the censure of the laws.(23)
Idea of the conduct of the emperors towards the Christians
 History, which undertakes to record the transactions of the
 past, for the instruction of future ages, would ill deserve
 that honourable office if she condescended to plead the
 cause of tyrants, or to justify the maxims of persecution.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('the Christians\r\n History', 'ORG')"
"It was in the choice of Cyprian either to die a martyr or to
 live an apostate, but on that choice depended the
 alternative of honour or infamy.","('Cyprian', 'PERSON')"
"It was not long, perhaps, before
 the Jews themselves, animated with a fiercer zeal and a more
 jealous faith, perceived the gradual separation of their
 Nazarene brethren from the doctrine of the synagogue: and
 they would gladly have extinguished the dangerous heresy in
 the blood of its adherents.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Nazarene', 'NORP')"
"It would have been an easy
 task, from the history of Eusebius, from the declamations of
 Lactantius, and from the most ancient acts, to collect a
 long series of horrid and disgusting pictures, and to fill
 many pages with racks and scourges, with iron hooks and
 red-hot beds, and with all the variety of tortures which
 fire and steel, savage beasts, and more savage executioners,
 could inflict on the human body.","('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('Lactantius', 'NORP')"
"Jealousy and resentment prevailed in every
 breast, but especially in that of Diocletian.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Malice and prejudice
 concurred in representing the Christians as a society of
 atheists, who, by the most daring attack on the religious
 constitution of the empire, had merited the severest
 animadversion of the civil magistrate.","('Malice', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Marcellus, the former of those prelates,
 had thrown their capital into confusion by the severe
 penance which he imposed on a great number of Christians
 who, during the late persecution, had renounced or
 dissembled their religion.","('Marcellus', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"New synagogues were 
 frequently erected in the principal cities of the empire;
 and the sabbaths, the fasts, and the festivals, which were
 either commanded by the Mosaic law or enjoined by the
 traditions of the Rabbis, were celebrated in the most solemn
 and public manner. (6)","('Mosaic', 'NORP'), ('Rabbis', 'ORG')"
"Nor was the 
 peace of the church interrupted till the increasing numbers
 of proselytes seem at length to have attracted the
 attention, and to have alienated the mind, of Severus.","('Severus', 'PERSON')"
"Nor was this apostasy (if we may use the expression) merely
 of a partial or local kind; since the pious deserter who
 withdrew himself from the temples of Egypt or Syria would
 equally disdain to seek an asylum in those of Athens or
 Carthage.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"Notwithstanding the careless indifference
 which the most copious and the most minute of the Pagan
 writers have shown to the affairs of the Christians,(24) it 
 may still be in our power to confirm each of these probable
 suppositions by the evidence of authentic facts.","('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('24', 'CARDINAL')"
"Notwithstanding the cruel disposition of Maximin, the
 effects of his resentment against the Christians were of a
 very local and temporary nature, and the pious Origen, who
 had been proscribed as a devoted victim, was still reserved
 to convey the truths of the Gospel to the ear of monarchs.","('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Origen', 'PERSON')"
"Notwithstanding the general rules established for the
 conviction and punishment of the Christians, the fate of
 those sectaries, in an extensive and arbitrary government,
 must still, in a great measure, have depended on their own
 behaviour, the circumstances of the times, and the temper of
 their supreme as well as subordinate rulers.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Notwithstanding these scandalous vices, if Paul of Samosata
 had preserved the purity of the orthodox faith, his reign
 over the capital of Syria would have ended only with his
 life; and had a reasonable persecution intervened, an effort
 of court might perhaps have placed him in the rank of saints
 and martyrs.","('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Samosata', 'PERSON'), ('Syria', 'GPE')"
"Of Valerian, Gallienus, and his successors.","('Valerian', 'PERSON'), ('Gallienus', 'PERSON')"
"Of some particular occasions, when the
 magistrates were exasperated by some personal motives of
 interest or resentment, when the zeal of the martyrs urged
 them to forget the rules of prudence, and perhaps of
 decency, to overturn the altars, to pour out imprecations
 against the emperors, or to strike the judge as he sat on
 his tribunal, it may be presumed that every mode of torture
 which cruelty could invent, or constancy could endure, was
 exhausted on those devoted victims.(179)","('179', 'CARDINAL')"
"Of the fourteen
 regions or quarters into which Rome was divided, four only
 subsisted entire, three were levelled with the ground, and
 the remaining seven, which had experienced the fury of the
 flames, displayed a melancholy prospect of ruin and
 desolation.","('fourteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
Of the succession of Severus.,"('Severus', 'PERSON')"
"Of the two sons of his uncle Flavius Sabinus,(51) the elder 
 was soon convicted of treasonable intentions, and the
 younger, who bore the name of Flavius Clemens, was indebted
 for his safety to his want of courage and ability.(52)","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Flavius Sabinus', 'PERSON'), ('51', 'DATE'), ('Flavius Clemens', 'PERSON')"
"On the
 arrival of a new proconsul in the province the fortune of
 Cyprian appeared for some time to wear a still more
 favourable aspect.","('Cyprian', 'NORP')"
"On the day of a public
 festival, that officer threw away his belt, his arms, and
 the ensigns of his office, and exclaimed with a loud voice
 that he would obey none but Jesus Christ the eternal King,
 and that he renounced for ever the use of carnal weapons,
 and the service of an idolatrous master.","('the day', 'DATE'), ('Jesus Christ', 'PERSON'), ('King', 'PERSON')"
"On the same spot (34) a temple, which far surpasses the ancient glories of the Capitol, has been since erected by the Christian Pontiffs, who, deriving their claim of universal dominion from an humble fisherman of Galilee, have succeeded to the throne of the Caesars, given laws to the barbarian conquerors of Rome, and extended their spiritual jurisdiction from the coast of the Baltic to the shores of the Pacific Ocean.","('34', 'CARDINAL'), ('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('the Christian Pontiffs', 'NORP'), ('Galilee', 'GPE'), ('Caesars', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Baltic', 'LOC'), ('the Pacific Ocean', 'LOC')"
"On the strength of so probable an interpretation, and too
 eagerly admitting the suspicions of a tyrant as an evidence
 of their honourable crime, the church has placed both
 Clemens and Domitilla among its first martyrs, and has
 branded the cruelty of Domitian with the name of the second
 persecution.","('Clemens', 'PERSON'), ('Domitilla', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"On these melancholy occasions there were many among the Gentiles who pitied, who admired, and who were converted.","('Gentiles', 'NORP')"
Oppression of the Jews and Christians by Domitian,"('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON')"
"Origen
 obeyed so flattering an invitation, and, though he could not
 expect to succeed in the conversion of an artful and
 ambitious woman, she listened with pleasure to his eloquent
 exhortations, and honourably dismissed him to his retirement
 in Palestine.(115)","('Origen', 'PERSON'), ('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('115', 'CARDINAL')"
"Others were allured by the hope that a short confinement would expiate the sins of a whole life; and others again were actuated by the less honourable motive of deriving a plentiful subsistence, and perhaps a considerable profit, from the alms which the charity of the faithful bestowed on the prisoners.(181)","('181', 'CARDINAL')"
"Paul of Samosata, his manners.","('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Samosata', 'PERSON')"
"Pliny had never
 assisted at any judicial proceedings against the Christians,
 with whose name alone he seems to be acquainted; and he was
 totally uninformed with regard to the nature of their guilt,
 the method of their conviction, and the degree of their
 punishment.","('Pliny', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
Progress of zeal and superstition among the Pagans.,"('Pagans', 'NORP')"
"Prudence suggested the necessity of a temporary retreat, and
 the voice of prudence was obeyed.","('Prudence', 'PERSON')"
"Punishment was not the inevitable consequence of
 conviction, and the Christians whose guilt was the most
 clearly proved by the testimony of witnesses, or even by
 their voluntary confession, still retained in their own
 power the alternative of life or death.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Rebellious spirit of the jews
 Without repeating what has been already mentioned of the
 reverence of the Roman princes and governors for the temple
 of Jerusalem, we shall only observe that the destruction of
 the temple and city was accompanied and followed by every
 circumstance that could exasperate the minds of the
 conquerors, and authorise religious persecutions by the most
 specious arguments of political justice and the public
 safety.","('jews', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
"Remarks on the passage of Tacitus relative to the persecution of the Christians by Nero
1.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Nero\r\n1', 'PERSON')"
"Several
 councils were held, confutations were published,
 ex-communications were pronounced, ambiguous explanations
 were by turns accepted and refused, treaties were concluded
 and violated, and at length Paul of Samosata was degraded
 from his episcopal character by the sentence of seventy or
 eighty bishops who assembled for that purpose at Antioch,
 and who, without consulting the rights of the clergy or
 people, appointed a successor by their own authority.","('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Samosata', 'PERSON'), ('seventy or\r\n eighty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"She intrusted
 Boniface with a considerable sum of gold and a large
 quantity of aromatics, and her lover, attended by twelve
 horsemen and three covered chariots, undertook a remote
 pilgrimage as far as Tarsus in Cilicia.(171)
 in Illyricum and the East under Galerius and Maximin.","('Boniface', 'PERSON'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tarsus', 'GPE'), ('Cilicia', 'GPE'), ('171', 'CARDINAL'), ('Illyricum', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON')"
"She intrusted
 Boniface with a considerable sum of gold and a large
 quantity of aromatics, and her lover, attended by twelve
 horsemen and three covered chariots, undertook a remote
 pilgrimage as far as Tarsus in Cilicia.(171)
in Illyricum and the East under Galerius and Maximin.","('Boniface', 'PERSON'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tarsus', 'GPE'), ('Cilicia', 'GPE'), ('171', 'CARDINAL'), ('Illyricum', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON')"
"Since it cannot be
 doubted that the Christians were more numerous, and their
 enemies more exasperated, in the time of Diocletian than
 they had ever been in any former persecution, this probable
 and moderate computation may teach us to estimate the number
 of primitive saints and martyrs who sacrificed their lives
 for the important purpose of introducing Christianity into
 the world.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Christianity', 'NORP')"
"Since the 
 officers of the revenue extended their unjust claim to many
 persons who were strangers to the blood or religion of the
 Jews, it was impossible that the Christians, who had so
 often sheltered themselves under the shade of the synagogue,
 should now escape this rapacious persecution.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Since the Jews, who rejected with abhorrence the deities
 adored by their sovereign and by their fellow-subjects,
 enjoyed, however, the free exercise of their unsocial
 religion, there must have existed some other cause which
 exposed the disciples of Christ to those severities from
 which the posterity of Abraham was exempt.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Abraham', 'PERSON')"
"Since the age
 of nineteen he had pleaded with distinction in the tribunals
 of Rome,(58) filled a place in the senate, had been invested 
 with the honours of the consulship, and had formed very
 numerous connections with every order of men, both in Italy
 and in the provinces.","('the age\r\n of nineteen', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('58', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Some 
 stories are related of the courage of martyrs who actually
 performed what Ignatius had intended, who exasperated the
 fury of the lions, pressed the executioner to hasten his
 office, cheerfully leaped into the fires which were kindled
 to consume them, and discovered a sensation of joy and
 pleasure in the midst of the most exquisite tortures.","('Ignatius', 'PERSON')"
"Some nice and subtle errors, which he
 imprudently adopted and obstinately maintained, concerning
 the doctrine of the Trinity, excited the zeal and
 indignation of the Eastern churches.(129) From Egypt to the 
 Euxine Sea, the bishops were in arms and in motion.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('129', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('the \r\n Euxine Sea', 'LOC')"
"Some of these apostates
 had yielded on the first menace or exhortation of the
 magistrate; whilst the patience of others had been subdued
 by the length and repetition of tortures.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Some slight disturbances, though they were suppressed almost
 as soon as excited in Syria and the frontiers of Armenia,
 afforded the enemies of the church a very plausible occasion
 to insinuate that those troubles had been secretly fomented
 by the intrigues of the bishops, who had already forgotten
 their ostentatious professions of passive and unlimited
 obedience.(162)","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('162', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such gentle treatment insensibly 
 assuaged the stern temper of the Jews.","('Jews', 'NORP')"
"Such was the happy condition of 
 the Christian subjects of Maxentius, that, whenever they
 were desirous of procuring for their own use any bodies of
 martyrs, they were obliged to purchase them from the most
 distant provinces of the East.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Maxentius', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
Supposed edicts of Tiberius and Marcus Antoninus.,"('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('Marcus Antoninus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 Pagan multitude, reserving their gratitude for temporal
 benefits alone, rejected the inestimable present of life and
 immortality which was offered to mankind by Jesus of
 Nazareth.","('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('Jesus', 'PERSON'), ('Nazareth', 'GPE')"
"The
 deaths of a few eminent martyrs have been recorded with
 care; and from the time that Christianity was invested with
 the supreme power, the governors of the church have been no
 less diligently employed in displaying the cruelty, than in
 imitating the conduct, of their Pagan adversaries.","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Pagan', 'NORP')"
"The
 emperor was persuaded that, in a dangerous sickness, he had
 derived some benefit, either spiritual or physical, from the
 holy oil with which one of his slaves had anointed him.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 impatient clamours of the multitude denounced the Christians
 as the enemies of gods and men, doomed them to the severest
 tortures, and, venturing to accuse by names some of the most
 distinguished of the new sectaries, required with
 irresistible vehemence that they should be instantly
 apprehended and cast to the lions. (61)","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('61', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 innocence of the first Christians was protected by ignorance
 and contempt; and the tribunal of the Pagan magistrate often
 proved their most assured refuge against the fury of the
 synagogue.(26)","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('26', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 manifest irregularity of this proceeding increased the
 numbers of the discontented faction; and as Paul, who was no
 stranger to the arts of courts, had insinuated himself into
 the favour of Zenobia, he maintained above four years the
 possession of the episcopal house and office.","('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Zenobia', 'PERSON'), ('four years', 'DATE')"
"The
 one ascribes it to lightning and the divine wrath, the other
 affirms that it was kindled by the malice of Galerius
 himself.(156)
 Execution of the first edict.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('156', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The
 one ascribes it to lightning and the divine wrath, the other
 affirms that it was kindled by the malice of Galerius
 himself.(156)
Execution of the first edict.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('156', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The
 presbyters aspired to the episcopal office, which every day
 became an object more worthy of their ambition.","('every day', 'DATE')"
"The
 proconsul transmitted him to the Praetorian praefect of
 Italy; and Felix, who disdained even to give an evasive
 answer, was at length beheaded at Venusia, in Lucania, a
 place on which the birth of Horace has conferred fame.(158)","('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Felix', 'PERSON'), ('Venusia', 'PERSON'), ('Lucania', 'GPE'), ('Horace', 'PERSON'), ('158', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 whole body of Christians unanimously refused to hold any
 communion with the gods of Rome, of the empire, and of
 mankind.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The 
 controversy concerning the precise time of the celebration
 of Easter armed the bishops of Asia and Italy against each
 other, and was considered as the most important business of
 this period of leisure and tranquillity.","('Easter', 'DATE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The 
 emperor for a long time distinguished so harmless a kinsman
 by his favour and protection, bestowed on him his own niece
 Domitilla, adopted the children of that marriage to the hope
 of the succession, and invested their father with the
 honours of the consulship.","('Domitilla', 'PERSON')"
"The 
 emperors levied a general capitation tax on the Jewish
 people; and although the sum assessed on the head of each
 individual was inconsiderable, the use for which it was
 designed, and the severity with which it was exacted, were
 considered as an intolerable grievance. (46)","('Jewish', 'NORP')"
"The 
 memory of Domitian was condemned by the senate; his acts
 were rescinded; his exiles recalled; and under the gentle
 administration of Nerva, while the innocent were restored to
 their rank and fortunes, even the most guilty either
 obtained pardon or escaped punishment.(56)
 Ignorance of Pliny concerning the Christians
 II.","('Domitian', 'PERSON'), ('Nerva', 'ORG'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"The 
 memory of Domitian was condemned by the senate; his acts
 were rescinded; his exiles recalled; and under the gentle
 administration of Nerva, while the innocent were restored to
 their rank and fortunes, even the most guilty either
 obtained pardon or escaped punishment.(56)
Ignorance of Pliny concerning the Christians
 II.","('Domitian', 'PERSON'), ('Nerva', 'ORG'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"The 
 numerous remains of that people, though they were still
 excluded from the precincts of Jerusalem, were permitted to
 form and to maintain considerable establishments both in
 Italy and in the provinces, to acquire the freedom of Rome,
 to enjoy municipal honours, and to obtain at the same time
 an exemption from the burdensome and expensive offices of
 society.","('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The 
 propriety of reserving himself for the future exigencies of
 the church, the example of several holy bishops,(78) and the 
 divine admonitions which, as he declares himself, he
 frequently received in visions and ecstacies, were the
 reasons alleged in his justification. (79)","('78', 'DATE')"
"The Apology of Tertullian contains two very ancient, very
 singular, but at the same time very suspicious instances of
 Imperial clemency; the edicts published by Tiberius and by
 Marcus Antoninus, and designed not only to protect the
 innocence of the Christians, but even to proclaim those
 stupendous miracles which had attested the truth of their
 doctrine.","('The Apology of Tertullian', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('Marcus Antoninus', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"The Asiatic Christians had everything to dread from the
 severity of a bigoted monarch who prepared his measures of
 violence with such deliberate policy.","('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"The Christians (it
 might speciously be alleged), renouncing the gods and the
 institutions of Rome, had constituted a distinct republic,
 which might yet be suppressed before it had acquired any
 military force; but which was already governed by its own
 laws and magistrates, was possessed of a public treasure,
 and was intimately connected in all its parts by the
 frequent assemblies of the bishops, to whose decrees their
 numerous and opulent congregations yielded an implicit
 obedience.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The Christians sometimes supplied by
 their voluntary declaration the want of an accuser, rudely
 disturbed the public service of paganism,(94) and, rushing in 
 crowds round the tribunal of the magistrates, called upon
 them to pronounce and to inflict the sentence of the law.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('94', 'DATE')"
"The Christians, though they confessed that his
 conduct had not been strictly conformable to the laws of
 prudence, admired the divine fervour of his zeal; and the
 excessive commendations which they lavished on the memory of
 their hero and martyr contributed to fix a deep impression
 of terror and hatred in the mind of Diocletian.(154)","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('154', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Christians, with the intrepid security
 of innocence, appeal from the voice of rumour to the equity
 of the magistrates.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"The Gentile converts who by a spiritual adoption had
 been associated to the hope of Israel, were likewise
 confounded under the garb and appearance of Jews;(25) and as 
 the Polytheists paid less regard to articles of faith than
 to the external worship, the new sect, which carefully
 concealed, or faintly announced, its future greatness and
 ambition, was permitted to shelter itself under the general
 toleration which was granted to an ancient and celebrated
 people in the Roman empire.","('Gentile', 'NORP'), ('Israel', 'GPE'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('25', 'CARDINAL'), ('Polytheists', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Imperial gardens were
 thrown open to the distressed multitude, temporary buildings
 were erected for their accommodation, and a plentiful supply
 of corn and provisions was distributed at a very moderate
 price.(29)","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The Jews were a nation, the Christians were a sect: and if
 it was natural for every community to respect the sacred
 institutions of their neighbours, it was incumbent on them
 to persevere in those of their ancestors.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"The Jews were a people which folowed, the Christians, a sect which deserted, the religion of their fathers.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"The Jews, who were numerous in the capital and oppressed in their own country, were a much fitter object for the suspicions of the emperor and of the people: nor did it seem unlikely that a vanquished nation, who already discovered their abhorrence of the Roman yoke, might have recourse to the most atrocious means of gratifying their implacable revenge.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Pagans were incensed at the rashness of a recent and obscure sect, which presumed to accuse their countrymen of error, and to devote their ancestors to eternal misery.","('Pagans', 'NORP')"
"The Polytheists were disposed to adopt every article of
 faith which seemed to offer any resemblance, however distant
 or imperfect, with the popular mythology; and the legends of
 Bacchus, of Hercules, and of Aesculapius had, in some
 measure prepared their imagination for the appearance of the
 Son of God under a human form.(12) But they were astonished 
 that the Christians should abandon the temples of those
 ancient heroes who, in the infancy of the world, had
 invented arts, instituted laws, and vanquished the tyrants
 or monsters who infested the earth; in order to choose for
 the exclusive object of their religious worship an obscure
 teacher, who, in a recent age, and among a barbarous people,
 had fallen a sacrifice either to the malice of his own
 countrymen, or to the jealousy of the Roman government.","('Polytheists', 'NORP'), ('Bacchus', 'PERSON'), ('Hercules', 'LOC'), ('Aesculapius', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n Son of God', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The accession of Gallienus, which increased the 
 calamities of the empire, restored peace to the church; and
