Sentence,Entities
(5),"('5', 'CARDINAL')"
(51),"('51', 'CARDINAL')"
(54),"('54', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 public employment was converted into the patrimony of a
 private family: the elder Pepin left a king of mature years
 under the guardianship of his own widow and her child; and
 these feeble regents were forcibly dispossessed by the most
 active of his bastards.","('Pepin', 'PERSON'), ('years', 'DATE')"
"A change was scarcely visible
 as long as the lieutenants of the caliph were content with
 their vicarious title; while they solicited for themselves
 or their sons a renewal of the Imperial grant, and still
 maintained on the coin and in the public prayers the name
 and prerogative of the commander of the faithful.","('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"A country palace, in the neighbourhood of Compiegne
 (27) was allotted for their residence or prison: but each
 year, in the month of March or May, they were conducted in a
 wagon drawn by oxen to the assembly of the Franks, to give
 audience to foreign ambassadors, and to ratify the acts of
 the mayor of the palace.","('Compiegne', 'GPE'), ('27', 'CARDINAL'), ('the month of March or May', 'DATE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"A detachment of cavalry intercepted his
 march and arrested his person; and the unhappy Ibrahim,
 snatched away from the promise of untasted royalty, expired
 in iron fetters in the dungeons of Haran.","('Ibrahim', 'PERSON'), ('Haran', 'PERSON')"
"A fleet of
 Saracens from the African coast presumed to enter the mouth
 of the Tyber, and to approach a city which even yet, in her
 fallen state, was revered as the metropolis of the Christian
 world.","('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('African', 'NORP'), ('Tyber', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"A government, half savage and half
 corrupt, was almost dissolved; and the tributary dukes, and
 provincial counts, and the territorial lords, were tempted
 to despise the weakness of the monarch, and to imitate the
 ambition of the mayor.","('half', 'CARDINAL'), ('half', 'CARDINAL')"
"A knight, who despised the swords
 and lances of the Saracens, relates, with heartfelt
 sincerity, his own fears, and those of his companions, at
 the sight and sound of the mischievous engine that
 discharged a torrent of the Greek fire, the feu Gregeois, as
 it is styled by the more early of the French writers.","('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Gregeois', 'PERSON'), ('French', 'NORP')"
"A mean, perhaps a foreign, extraction
 could not repress the aspiring energy of Abu Moslem.","('Abu Moslem', 'PERSON')"
"A people continually exposed to the dangers of the field must esteem
 the healing powers of medicine, or rather of surgery; but the starving physicians of Arabia murmured a complaint that
 exercise and temperance deprived them of the greatest part
 of their practice.","('Arabia', 'GPE')"
"A pious and charitable motive may sanctify the
 foundation of cisterns and caravanseras, which he
 distributed along a measured road of seven hundred miles;
 but his train of camels, laden with snow, could serve only
 to astonish the natives of Arabia, and to refresh the fruits
 and liquors of the royal banquet. (45)","('seven hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Arabia', 'LOC'), ('45', 'CARDINAL')"
"A private doctor refused the invitation of the sultan of Bochara, because the carriage of his books would have required four hundred camels.","('Bochara', 'PERSON'), ('four hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"A rebellious faction introduced them into
 Alexandria; (81) they cut in pieces both friends and foes, pillaged the churches and the moschs, sold above six thousand Christian captives, and maintained their station in
 the capital of Egypt, till they were oppressed by the forces
 and the presence of Almamon himself.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('81', 'CARDINAL'), ('six thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Almamon', 'PERSON')"
"A report was dexterously scattered, that the Franks, the unknown nations of the Latin world, were arming by sea and land in the defence of the Christian cause, and their formidable aid was expected with far different sensations in the camp and city.","('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"A seasonable vision (for such are the manufacture of every
 religion) revealed the holy spot at the foot of the walls
 and the bottom of the harbour; and the mosch of Ayub has been
 deservedly chosen for the simple and martial inauguration of
 the Turkish sultans.","('Ayub', 'GPE'), ('Turkish', 'NORP')"
"A series of bloody and undecisive combats
 is nothing more than an anticipation of what would have been
 effected in a few years by the course of nature; but I shall
 briefly prosecute the conquests of the two emperors from the
 hills of Cappadocia to the desert of Bagdad.","('a few years', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE')"
"A standing army was unknown under the first and second race; more than half the kingdom was now in the hands of the Saracens: according to their respective situation, the Franks of Neustria and Austrasia were too conscious or too careless of the impending danger; and the voluntary aids of the Gepidae and Germans were separated by a long interval from the standard of the Christian general.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('more than half', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Neustria', 'GPE'), ('Austrasia', 'ORG'), ('Gepidae', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"A still more fatal
 and irreparable loss was that of the caliph Soliman, who died of an indigestion, (12) in his camp near Kinnisrin or Chalcis in Syria, as he was preparing to lead against Constantinople the remaining forces of the East.","('Soliman', 'PERSON'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('Kinnisrin', 'GPE'), ('Chalcis', 'PERSON'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"A superstitious reverence for the dead
 confined both the Greeks and the Arabians to the dissection
 of apes and quadrupeds; the more solid and visible parts
 were known in the time of Galen, and the finer scrutiny of
 the human frame was reserved for the microscope and the
 injections of modern artists.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Arabians', 'NORP'), ('Galen', 'PERSON')"
"A victorious line of march had
 been prolonged above a thousand miles from the rock of
 Gibraltar to the banks of the Loire; the repetition of an
 equal space would have carried the Saracens to the confines
 of Poland and the Highlands of Scotland; the Rhine is not
 more impassable than the Nile or Euphrates, and the Arabian
 fleet might have sailed without a naval combat into the
 mouth of the Thames.","('a thousand miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Gibraltar', 'GPE'), ('Loire', 'LOC'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Poland', 'GPE'), ('Highlands', 'LOC'), ('Scotland', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('Thames', 'LOC')"
"After
 the death of Mohammed, the oath of allegiance was
 administered in the name of his son Ibrahim to a numerous
 band of votaries, who expected only a signal and a leader;
 and the governor of Chorasan continued to deplore his
 fruitless admonitions and the deadly slumber of the caliphs
 of Damascus, till he himself, with all his adherents, was
 driven from the city and palace of Meru, by the rebellious
 arms of Abu Moslem. (35)","('Mohammed', 'PERSON'), ('Ibrahim', 'PERSON'), ('Chorasan', 'GPE'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Meru', 'LOC'), ('Abu Moslem', 'PERSON'), ('35', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a bloody
 conflict, they prevailed in the province of Bahrein, along the Persian Gulf: far and wide, the tribes of the desert were subject to the sceptre, or rather to the sword of Abu Said and his son Abu Taher; and these rebellious imams could muster in the field a hundred and seven thousand fanatics.","('Bahrein', 'GPE'), ('the Persian Gulf', 'LOC'), ('Abu Said', 'PERSON'), ('Abu Taher', 'PERSON'), ('a hundred and seven thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a bloody field, in which Abderame was slain, the Saracens, in the close of the evening, retired to their camp.","('Abderame', 'PERSON'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('the close of the evening', 'TIME')"
"After a similar prayer, and
 with equal resolution, the Moslems advanced to the attack of
 the Christian galleys, which preserved their advantageous
 station along the coast.","('Moslems', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"After an irretrievable
 defeat, the caliph escaped to Mosul; but the colours of the
 Abbassides were displayed from the rampart; he suddenly
 repassed the Tigris, cast a melancholy look on his palace of
 Haran, crossed the Euphrates, abandoned the fortifications
 of Damascus, and, without halting in Palestine, pitched his
 last and fatal camp at Busir, on the banks of the Nile. (37)","('Mosul', 'GPE'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP'), ('Tigris', 'NORP'), ('Haran', 'PERSON'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('Busir', 'FAC'), ('Nile', 'LOC')"
"After him, the lords of the Eastern world were reduced to the most abject misery, and exposed to the blows and insults of a servile condition.","('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"After his wars and buildings, Almansor left behind
 him in gold and silver about thirty millions sterling: (44)
 and this treasure was exhausted in a few years by the vices
 or virtues of his children.","('Almansor', 'PERSON'), ('about thirty millions', 'CARDINAL'), ('44', 'CARDINAL'), ('a few years', 'DATE')"
"After the
 fall of that religion, the Peripatetics, emerging from their
 obscurity, prevailed in the controversies of the Oriental
 sects, and their founder was long afterwards restored by the
 Mahometans of Spain to the Latin schools. (58)","('Peripatetics', 'NORP'), ('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('Mahometans', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('58', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the death of the younger Romanus, the fourth in lineal
 descent of the Basilian race, his widow Theophania
 successively married Nicephorus Phocas and his assassin John
 Zimisces, the two heroes of the age.","('Romanus', 'PERSON'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Basilian', 'NORP'), ('Theophania', 'PERSON'), ('Nicephorus Phocas', 'PERSON'), ('John\r\n Zimisces', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the death of their father, the heirs of the caliph were involved in civil discord, and the conqueror, the liberal Almamon, was sufficiently engaged in the restoration of domestic peace and the introduction of foreign science.","('Almamon', 'PERSON')"
"After the departure of the Greeks, the fugitive princes returned to their capitals; the subjects disclaimed their involuntary oaths of allegiance; the Moslems again purified their temples, and overturned the idols of the saints and martyrs; the Nestorians and Jacobites preferred a Saracen to an orthodox master; and the numbers and spirit of the Melchites were inadequate to the support of the church and state.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Moslems', 'NORP'), ('Nestorians', 'NORP'), ('Jacobites', 'NORP'), ('Saracen', 'NORP'), ('Melchites', 'PERSON')"
"After the revolt of Arabia and Persia, the house of Ommiyah. (7) was reduced to the kingdoms of Syria and Egypt: their
 distress and fear enforced their compliance with the
 pressing demands of the Christians; and the tribute was
 increased to a slave, a horse, and a thousand pieces of
 gold, for each of the three hundred and sixty-five days of
 the solar year.","('Arabia', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'LOC'), ('Ommiyah', 'GPE'), ('7', 'CARDINAL'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('a thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('three hundred and sixty-five days', 'DATE'), ('the solar year', 'DATE')"
"After the revolt of Spain from the temporal and spiritual
 supremacy of the Abbassides, the first symptoms of
 disobedience broke forth in the province of Africa.","('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"After their civil and domestic wars, the subjects of the Abbassides, awakening from this mental lethargy, found leisure and felt curiosity for the acquisition of profane science.","('Abbassides', 'NORP')"
"After they had forced and secured the narrow
 passes of Mount Amanus, Invasion of Syria.","('Mount Amanus', 'LOC'), ('Syria', 'GPE')"
"After this act of
 treason, the ensigns of royalty, the garment and
 walking-staff of Mahomet, were given and torn away by the
 foreign mercenaries, who in four years created, deposed, and
 murdered, three commanders of the faithful.","('Mahomet', 'ORG'), ('four years', 'DATE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"After this deed of
 sacrilege and cruelty, they continued to infest the confines of Irak, Syria, and Egypt: but the vital principle of enthusiasm had withered at the root.","('Irak', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"After this discovery of his weakness, he vainly
 hoped to deprecate the fate of Amorium: the inexorable
 caliph rejected with contempt his prayers and promises; and
 detained the Roman ambassadors to be the witnesses of his
 great revenge.","('Amorium', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Among the ideal systems which have varied with the fashion of the times, the Arabians
 adopted the philosophy of the Stagirite, alike intelligible
 or alike obscure for the readers of every age.","('Arabians', 'NORP'), ('Stagirite', 'NORP')"
"Among these a matron of the house of Abbas invoked, in an
 agony of despair, the name of Motassem; and the insults of
 the Greeks engaged the honour of her kinsman to avenge his
 indignity, and to answer her appeal.","('Abbas', 'PERSON'), ('Motassem', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"Among these independent chiefs, one
 of the boldest and most successful was Eudes, duke of
 Aquitain, who in the southern provinces of Gaul usurped the
 authority, and even the title of king.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Eudes', 'PERSON'), ('Aquitain', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"An army of Bulgarians was attracted from the Danube by the gifts and promises of Leo; and these savage auxiliaries made some atonement for the evils which they had inflicted on the empire, by the defeat and slaughter of twenty-two thousand Asiatics.","('Bulgarians', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('twenty-two thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Asiatics', 'NORP')"
"An army of Christians attempted the
 relief of the city: the tombs of their leaders were yet
 visible in the thirteenth century; and many thousands of
 their dead bodies were carried down the rapid stream into
 the Mediterranean Sea.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('the thirteenth century', 'DATE'), ('many thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Mediterranean Sea', 'LOC')"
"An army of ninety-five thousand Persians
 and Arabs was sent from the Tigris to the Thracian
 Bosphorus, under the command of Harun, (75) or Aaron, the second son of the commander of the faithful.","('ninety-five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('the Thracian\r\n Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Harun', 'PERSON'), ('75', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aaron', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"And the
 sword of the Saracens became less formidable when their
 youth was drawn away from the camp to the college, when the
 armies of the faithful presumed to read and to reflect.","('Saracens', 'NORP')"
Another year they suffered the pilgrims to proceed without interruption;,"('Another year', 'DATE')"
"As far as the
 scantiness of his means and the shortness of his leisure
 would allow, the ancient walls were repaired by the command
 of Leo; fifteen towers, in the most accessible stations,
 were built or renewed; two of these commanded on either side
 of the Tyber; and an iron chain was drawn across the stream
 to impede the ascent of a hostile navy.","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('fifteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tyber', 'PRODUCT')"
"As often as the
 Turks were inflamed by fear, or rage, or avarice, these
 caliphs were dragged by the feet, exposed naked to the
 scorching sun, beaten with iron clubs, and compelled to
 purchase, by the abdication of their dignity, a short
 reprieve of inevitable fate. (99)","('Turks', 'NORP')"
"At length, after a siege of thirteen months, (14) the hopeless Moslemah received from the caliph the welcome permission of retreat.","('thirteen months', 'DATE'), ('14', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moslemah', 'PERSON')"
"At length, however, the
 fury of the tempest was spent or diverted: the Abbassides
 returned to the less turbulent residence of Bagdad; the
 insolence of the Turks was curbed with a firmer and more
 skilful hand, and their numbers were divided and destroyed
 in foreign warfare.","('Abbassides', 'NORP'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE'), ('Turks', 'NORP')"
"At the dawn of the day, the stillness of a hostile camp was suspected by the victorious Christians:
 on the report of their spies, they ventured to explore the riches of the vacant tents; but if we except some celebrated relics, a small portion of the spoil was restored to the innocent and lawful owners.","('the dawn of the day', 'TIME'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"At the instigation, or at
 least in the cause of his son, they burst into his apartment
 at the hour of supper, and the caliph was cut into seven
 pieces by the same swords which he had recently distributed
 among the guards of his life and throne.","('the hour', 'TIME'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the nuptials of the same
 prince, a thousand pearls of the largest size were showered
 on the head of the bride, (46) and a lottery of lands and
 houses displayed the capricious bounty of fortune.","('a thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('46', 'DATE')"
"At the same fatal period, the Persian kingdom was again usurped by the dynasty of  A.D. 933-1055.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('the dynasty of  A.D. 933-1055', 'DATE')"
"At the well-known passage
 of Abydus, on the Hellespont, the Mahometan arms were transported, for the first time,  from Asia to Europe.","('Abydus', 'GPE'), ('Hellespont', 'PRODUCT'), ('Mahometan', 'PRODUCT'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"Before his
 accession to the throne, he had deserved, by his Georgian
 warfare, the honourable epithet of the ass of Mesopotamia;
 (36) and he might have been ranked amongst the greatest
 princes, had not, says Abulfeda, the eternal order decreed
 that moment for the ruin of his family; a decree against
 which all human fortitude and prudence must struggle in
 vain.","('Georgian', 'NORP'), ('Mesopotamia', 'LOC'), ('36', 'CARDINAL'), ('Abulfeda', 'PERSON')"
"Before the evening, the camp was surprised, and the menace was executed.","('the evening', 'TIME')"
"Botany is an active science,
 and the discoveries of the torrid zone might enrich the
 herbal of Dioscorides with two thousand plants.","('Dioscorides', 'PRODUCT'), ('two thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"But
 the ancient geometry, if I am not misinformed, was resumed
 in the same state by the Italians of the fifteenth century;
 and whatever may be the origin of the name, the science of
 algebra is ascribed to the Grecian Diophantus by the modest
 testimony of the Arabs themselves. (60)","('Italians', 'NORP'), ('the fifteenth century', 'DATE'), ('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('60', 'CARDINAL')"
"But
 the mosch was converted into a stable; the pulpit was
 delivered to the flames; many rich crosses of gold and gems,
 the spoils of Asiatic churches, were made a grateful
 offering to the piety or avarice of the emperor; and he
 transported the gates of Mopsuestia and Tarsus, which were
 fixed in the walls of Constantinople, an eternal monument of
 his victory.","('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Mopsuestia', 'NORP'), ('Tarsus', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"But
 this venerable spot was still open to sacrilegious insult:
 the design of enclosing it with walls and towers exhausted
 all that authority could command, or charity would supply:
 and the pious labor of four years was animated in every
 season, and at every hour, by the presence of the
 indefatigable pontiff.","('four years', 'DATE'), ('every hour', 'TIME')"
"But a severe retribution was
 exacted by Mohadi, the third caliph of the new dynasty, who
 seized, in his turn, the favourable opportunity, while a
 woman and a child, Irene and Constantine, were seated on the
 Byzantine throne.","('Mohadi', 'PERSON'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Irene', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"But as soon as the empire was again united
 by the arms and policy of Abdalmalek, he disclaimed a badge
 of servitude not less injurious to his conscience than to
 his pride; he discontinued the payment of the tribute; and
 the resentment of the Greeks was disabled from action by the
 mad tyranny of the second Justinian, the just rebellion of
 his subjects, and the frequent change of his antagonists and
 successors.","('Abdalmalek', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"But in the depth of winter, in a dark and rainy night, an adventurous subaltern, with three hundred soldiers, approached the rampart, applied his scaling-ladders, occupied two adjacent towers, stood firm against the pressure of multitudes, and bravely maintained his post till he was relieved by the tardy, though effectual, support of his reluctant chief.","('the depth of winter', 'DATE'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"But in the science of
 medicine, the Arabians have been deservedly applauded.","('Arabians', 'NORP')"
"But it was
 on the banks of the Zab, and not in the mosch of Cufa, that
 this important controversy was determined.","('Zab', 'PERSON'), ('Cufa', 'PERSON')"
"But on the fortieth day, at the audience of
 the ambassadors of Chorasan, and in the presence of a trembling multitude, the caliph was dragged from his throne to a dungeon, by the command of the stranger, and the rude hands of his Dilamites.","('the fortieth day', 'DATE'), ('Chorasan', 'GPE'), ('Dilamites', 'NORP')"
"But the
 vigilance of Leo had formed an alliance with the vassals of
 the Greek empire, the free and maritime states of Gayeta,
 Naples, and Amalfi; and in the hour of danger, their galleys
 appeared in the port of Ostia under the command of
 Caesarius, the son of the Neapolitan duke, a noble and
 valiant youth, who had already vanquished the fleets of the
 Saracens.","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Gayeta', 'GPE'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Amalfi', 'GPE'), ('Ostia', 'GPE'), ('Caesarius', 'PERSON'), ('Neapolitan', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'PRODUCT')"
"But the Greek fires were again kindled; and if the destruction was less complete, it was owing to the experience which had taught the Moslems to remain at a safe distance, or to the perfidy of the Egyptian mariners, who deserted with their ships to the emperor of the Christians.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Moslems', 'NORP'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"But the Moslems deprived themselves of the principal
 benefits of a familiar intercourse with Greece and Rome, the
 knowledge of antiquity, the purity of taste, and the freedom
 of thought.","('Moslems', 'NORP'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But the apprehensions of Bagdad were relieved by the retreat of the Greeks: thirst and hunger guarded the desert of Mesopotamia; and the emperor, satiated with glory, and laden with Oriental spoils, returned to Constantinople, and displayed, in his triumph, the silk, the aromatics, and three hundred myriads of gold and silver.","('Bagdad', 'GPE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Mesopotamia', 'LOC'), ('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the attempt and disgrace of the second siege
 was reserved for his brother Soliman, whose ambition appears
 to have been quickened by a more active and martial spirit.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Soliman', 'PERSON')"
"But the besiegers had formed an
 insufficient estimate of the strength and resources of
 Constantinople.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"But the calamities of famine and disease were soon felt by the troops of Moslemah, and as the former was miserably assuaged, so the latter was
 dreadfully propagated, by the pernicious nutriment which hunger compelled them to extract from the most unclean or unnatural food.","('Moslemah', 'GPE')"
"But the caliphs of
 Bagdad had lost their authority in the West; the Aglabites
 and Fatimites usurped the provinces of Africa, their emirs
 of Sicily aspired to independence; and the design of
 conquest and dominion was degraded to a repetition of
 predatory inroads. (85)
Invasion of Rome by the Saracens, A.D. 846.","('Bagdad', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Aglabites', 'NORP'), ('Fatimites', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('85', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('846', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the human faculties are fortified by the
 art and practice of dialectics; the ten predicaments of
 Aristotle collect and methodize our ideas, (59) and his
 syllogism is the keenest weapon of dispute.","('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aristotle', 'PERSON')"
"But the most eager search of Arabian chemistry
 was the transmutation of metals, and the elixir of immortal
 health: the reason and the fortunes of thousands were
 evaporated in the crucibles of alchemy, and the consummation
 of the great work was promoted by the worthy aid of mystery,
 fable, and superstition.","('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the nations of the East had been
 taught to trample on the successors of the prophet; and the
 blessings of domestic peace were obtained by the relaxation
 of strength and discipline.","('East', 'LOC')"
"But the strongest fortresses of Cerdagne were
 invested by a superior force; the rebel was overtaken and
 slain in the mountains; and his widow was sent a captive to
 Damascus, to gratify the desires, or more probably the
 vanity, of the commander of the faithful.","('Cerdagne', 'GPE'), ('Damascus', 'GPE')"
But the walls of the city withstood the strokes of their battering-rams: and the besiegers pitched their tents on the neighbouring mountain of Jaushan.,"('Jaushan', 'GPE')"
"But their misfortunes had been embittered by the triumph of the Fatimites, the real or spurious progeny of Ali. Arising from the extremity of Africa, these successful rivals extinguished, in Egypt and Syria, both the spiritual and temporal authority of the Abbassides; and the monarch of the Nile insulted the humble pontiff on the banks of the Tigris.","('Fatimites', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"But these narrow limits were scorned by the spirit of
 Abdalraman, or Abderame, who had been restored by the caliph
 Hashem to the wishes of the soldiers and people of Spain.","('Abdalraman', 'NORP'), ('Abderame', 'PERSON'), ('Hashem', 'PERSON'), ('Spain', 'GPE')"
"But this incredible tale is sufficiently disproved by the caution of the French general, who apprehended the snares and accidents of a pursuit, and dismissed his German
 allies to their native forests.","('French', 'NORP'), ('German', 'NORP')"
"But when the Eastern world was convulsed and broken, the Greeks were roused from their lethargy by the hopes of conquest and revenge.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"But when the sceptre devolved to Almamon, the seventh of the Abbassides, he completed the designs of his grandfather, and invited the
 muses from their ancient seats.","('Almamon', 'GPE'), ('seventh', 'ORDINAL'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP')"
"But when the unnatural mother of
 Constantine was deposed and banished, her successor,
 Nicephorus, resolved to obliterate this badge of servitude
 and disgrace.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Nicephorus', 'PERSON')"
"But when they advanced in the career of victory to
 the banks of the Indus and the summit of the Pyrenees; when
 they had repeatedly tried the edge of their scymetars and the
 energy of their faith, they might be equally astonished that
 any nation could resist their invincible arms; that any
 boundary should confine the dominion of the successor of the
 prophet.","('Indus', 'LOC'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC')"
"By
 the command of that caliph, a national mint was established,
 both for silver and gold, and the inscription of the Dinar,
 though it might be censured by some timorous casuists,
 proclaimed the unity of the God of Mahomet. (8)","('8', 'CARDINAL')"
"By his liberality, a colony of Corsicans, with
 their wives and children, was planted in the station of
 Porto, at the mouth of the Tyber: the falling city was
 restored for their use, the fields and vineyards were
 divided among the new settlers: their first efforts were
 assisted by a gift of horses and cattle; and the hardy
 exiles, who breathed revenge against the Saracens, swore to
 live and die under the standard of St. Peter.","('Corsicans', 'NORP'), ('Porto', 'GPE'), ('Tyber', 'FAC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE')"
"By the event of the civil war,
 the dynasty of the Abbassides was firmly established; but
 the Christians only could triumph in the mutual hatred and
 common loss of the disciples of Mahomet. (38)
Revolt of Spain, A.D. 755.","('the civil war', 'EVENT'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('38', 'CARDINAL'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('755', 'CARDINAL')"
"By the special order of Moctader, the bridges had been broken down, and the person or head of the rebel was expected every hour by the commander of the faithful.","('Moctader', 'GPE'), ('every hour', 'TIME')"
"By these precautions, the secret was confined,
 above four hundred years, to the Romans of the East; and at
 the end of the eleventh century, the Pisans, to whom every
 sea and every art were familiar, suffered the effects,
 without understanding the composition, of the Greek fire.","('four hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('the end of the eleventh century', 'DATE'), ('Pisans', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"Charles, the illegitimate son of
 the elder Pepin, was content with the titles of mayor or
 duke of the Franks; but he deserved to become the father of
 a line of kings.","('Charles', 'PERSON'), ('Pepin', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"Confident in the riches of their native tongue,
 the Arabians disdained the study of any foreign idiom.","('Arabians', 'NORP')"
"Constantinople applauded the long-forgotten pomp of a triumph; but the Imperial diadem was the sole reward that could repay the services, or satisfy the ambition, of Nicephorus.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Nicephorus', 'ORG')"
"Damascus was
 disgraced by the choice, and polluted with the blood, of the
 Ommiades; and, after some hesitation, Almansor, the brother
 and successor of Saffah, laid the foundations of Bagdad, (41)
 the Imperial seat of his posterity during a reign of five
 hundred years. (42)","('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Ommiades', 'NORP'), ('Almansor', 'PERSON'), ('Saffah', 'PERSON'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE'), ('41', 'CARDINAL'), ('five\r\n hundred years', 'DATE'), ('42', 'DATE')"
Danger of Bagdad.,"('Bagdad', 'GPE')"
"Despoiled of their armour and silken robes, they fasted, they prayed, they studied the Koran and the tradition of the Sonnites: they performed, with zeal and knowledge, the functions of their ecclesiastical character.","('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Sonnites', 'NORP')"
"Disorders of the Turkish guards, A.D. 841-870, etc.
 With Motassem, the eighth of the Abbassides, the glory of
 his family and nation expired.","('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('841-870', 'CARDINAL'), ('Motassem', 'PERSON'), ('eighth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP')"
"During a hostile period of one hundred and thirty-eight years, the princes of Constantinople attacked these licentious corsairs with fruitless curses and ineffectual arms.","('one hundred and thirty-eight years', 'DATE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Enterprises of the Greeks, A.D. 960.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('960', 'CARDINAL')"
"Euphemius appealed to the reason
 and policy of the Saracens of Africa; and soon returned with
 the Imperial purple, a fleet of one hundred ships, and an
 army of seven hundred horse and ten thousand foot.","('Euphemius', 'PERSON'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('one hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten thousand foot', 'QUANTITY')"
"Every advantage
 appeared to be on the side of the white faction: the
 authority of established government; an army of a hundred
 and twenty thousand soldiers, against a sixth part of that
 number; and the presence and merit of the caliph Mervan, the
 fourteenth and last of the house of Ommiyah.","('a hundred\r\n and twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('sixth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Mervan', 'PERSON'), ('fourteenth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Ommiyah', 'GPE')"
"Except among the
 Syrians, the caliphs of the house of Ommiyah had never been
 the objects of the public favour.","('Syrians', 'NORP'), ('Ommiyah', 'GPE')"
"Expedition and victories of Abderame, A.D. 731.","('Abderame', 'PERSON'), ('731', 'CARDINAL')"
Failure and retreat of the Saracens,"('Saracens', 'NORP')"
"Fall of the Ommiades, A.D. 750, February 10  the remains of the white faction were finally
 vanquished in Egypt; and the lance, which terminated the
 life and anxiety of Mervan, was not less welcome perhaps to
 the unfortunate than to the victorious chief.","('A.D. 750', 'DATE'), ('February 10', 'DATE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Mervan', 'PERSON')"
"Fallen state of the caliphs of Bagdad, A.D. 936, etc.
Rahadi, the twentieth of the Abbassides, and the thirty-ninth of the successors of Mahomet, was the last who deserved the title of commander of the faithful; (108) the last (says Abulfeda) who spoke to the people, or conversed with the learned; the last who, in the expense of his household, represented the wealth and magnificence of the ancient caliphs.","('Bagdad', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 936', 'DATE'), ('Rahadi', 'PERSON'), ('twentieth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP'), ('thirty-ninth', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('108', 'CARDINAL'), ('Abulfeda', 'PERSON')"
"First siege of Constantinople by the Arabs, A.D. 668-675
 Forty-six years after the flight of Mahomet from Mecca, his
 disciples appeared in arms under the walls of
 Constantinople.","('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 668-675', 'DATE'), ('Forty-six years', 'DATE'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Five years
 after this expedition, Harun ascended the throne of his
 father and his elder brother; the most powerful and vigorous
 monarch of his race, illustrious in the West, as the ally of
 Charlemagne, and familiar to the most childish readers, as
 the perpetual hero of the Arabian tales.","('Five years', 'DATE'), ('Harun', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Arabian', 'NORP')"
"Fourscore of the Ommiades, who had yielded to the faith or
 clemency of their foes, were invited to a banquet at
 Damascus.","('Ommiades', 'PERSON'), ('Damascus', 'GPE')"
"From Tarsus, the place of assembly, the Saracens
 advanced in three divisions along the high road of
 Constantinople: Motassem himself commanded the centre, and
 the vanguard was given to his son Abbas, who, in the trial
 of the first adventures, might succeed with the more glory,
 or fail with the least reproach.","('Tarsus', 'GPE'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Motassem', 'PERSON'), ('Abbas', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"From an obscure residence in Syria, they
 secretly despatched their agents and missionaries, who
 preached in the Eastern provinces their hereditary
 indefeasible right; and Mohammed, the son of Ali, the son of
 Abdallah, the son of Abbas, the uncle of the prophet, gave
 audience to the deputies of Chorasan, and accepted their
 free gift of four hundred thousand pieces of gold.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Mohammed', 'PERSON'), ('Ali', 'PERSON'), ('Abdallah', 'PERSON'), ('Abbas', 'PERSON'), ('Chorasan', 'GPE'), ('four hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"From such calamities was Christendom delivered by the genius
 and fortune of one man.","('Christendom', 'ORG'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the Indus to the Euphrates, the
 East was convulsed by the quarrel of the white and the black
 factions: the Abbassides were most frequently victorious;
 but their public success was clouded by the personal
 misfortune of their chief.","('Indus', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP')"
"From the Pyrenees,
 Abderame proceeded without delay to the passage of the Rhone
 and the siege of Arles.","('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('Abderame', 'PERSON'), ('Rhone', 'LOC'), ('Arles', 'GPE')"
"From the Roman conquest to this final calamity, Syracuse,
 now dwindled to the primitive Isle of Ortygea, had
 insensibly declined.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Syracuse', 'GPE'), ('Isle of Ortygea', 'FAC')"
"From the height where he stood, the descent would not have been so soft or harmless: a timely death secured his own repose and that of the caliph, who paid with the most lavish concessions the retreat of his brother Amrou to the palaces of Shiraz and Ispahan.","('Amrou', 'PERSON'), ('Shiraz', 'GPE'), ('Ispahan', 'PERSON')"
"From the mouth of the
 Nile to the Hellespont, the islands and sea-coasts both of
 the Greeks and Moslems were exposed to their depredations;
 they saw, they envied, they tasted the fertility of Crete,
 and soon returned with forty galleys to a more serious
 attack.","('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Hellespont', 'GPE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Moslems', 'NORP'), ('Crete', 'GPE'), ('forty', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the reign of the
 Abbassides to that of the grandchildren of Tamerlane, the
 stars, without the aid of glasses, were diligently observed;
 and the astronomical tables of Bagdad, Spain, and Samarcand,
 (62) correct some minute errors, without daring to renounce
 the hypothesis of Ptolemy, without advancing a step towards
 the discovery of the solar system.","('Abbassides', 'NORP'), ('Tamerlane', 'GPE'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Samarcand', 'NORP'), ('62', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ptolemy', 'PERSON')"
"From their obscure,
 and perhaps fallacious, hints it should seem that the
 principal ingredient of the Greek fire was the naphtha, (18) or liquid bitumen, a light, tenacious, and inflammable oil,
 (19) which springs from the earth, and catches fire as soon
 as it comes in contact with the air.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('18', 'CARDINAL'), ('19', 'CARDINAL')"
"From thence, wheeling round the Thracian cities of the Propontis, Moslemah invested Constantinople on the land side, surrounded his camp with a ditch and rampart, prepared and planted his engines of assault, and declared, by words and actions, a patient resolution of expecting the return of seed-time and harvest, should the obstinacy of the besieged prove equal to his own.","('Thracian', 'NORP'), ('Propontis', 'LOC'), ('Moslemah', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"From this mixture, which produced a
 thick smoke and a loud explosion, proceeded a fierce and
 obstinate flame, which not only rose in perpendicular
 ascent, but likewise burnt with equal vehemence in descent
 or lateral progress; instead of being extinguished, it was
 nourished and quickened by the element of water; and sand,
 urine, or vinegar, were the only remedies that could damp
 the fury of this powerful agent, which was justly
 denominated by the Greeks the liquid, or the maritime, fire.","('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"Had the Mahometans been
 united, Italy must have fallen an easy and glorious
 accession to the empire of the prophet.","('Mahometans', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
Hamadan.,"('Hamadan', 'PERSON')"
"He issued a peremptory
 mandate, that all persons who were not provided with the
 means of subsistence for a three years' siege should
 evacuate the city: the public granaries and arsenals were
 abundantly replenished; the walls were restored and
 strengthened; and the engines for casting stones, or darts,
 or fire, were stationed along the ramparts, or in the
 brigantines of war, of which an additional number was
 hastily constructed.","(""a three years'"", 'DATE')"
"He passed without
 opposition the Garonne and Dordogne, which unite their
 waters in the Gulf of Bourdeaux; but he found, beyond those
 rivers, the camp of the intrepid Eudes, who had formed a
 second army and sustained a second defeat, so fatal to the
 Christians, that, according to their sad confession, God
 alone could reckon the number of the slain.","('Garonne', 'NORP'), ('Dordogne', 'GPE'), ('the Gulf of Bourdeaux', 'LOC'), ('Eudes', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"He slew in
 battle a lieutenant of the Abbassides, who had invaded his
 dominions with a fleet and army: the head of Ala, in salt
 and camphire, was suspended by a daring messenger before the
 palace of Mecca; and the caliph Almansor rejoiced in his
 safety, that he was removed by seas and lands from such a
 formidable adversary.","('Abbassides', 'PERSON'), ('Ala', 'GPE'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Almansor', 'PERSON')"
"He was alarmed by the sound of
 war; and his ambassador returned from Damascus with the
 tremendous news, that the Saracens were preparing an
 armament by sea and land, such as would transcend the
 experience of the past, or the belief of the present age.","('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Saracens', 'NORP')"
"He was sent into honourable exile, to command on
 the banks of the Oxus; and the independence of his
 successors, who reigned in Chorasan till the fourth
 generation, was palliated by their modest and respectful
 demeanour, the happiness of their subjects and the security
 of their frontier.","('Oxus', 'PERSON'), ('Chorasan', 'GPE'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL')"
"His
 presence in the neighbourhood of Spain revived the zeal of
 the white faction.","('Spain', 'GPE')"
"His ambassadors at Constantinople, his agents in Armenia, Syria, and Egypt, collected the volumes of Grecian science at his command they were translated by the most skilful interpreters into the
 Arabic language: his subjects were exhorted assiduously to peruse these instructive writings; and the successor of Mahomet assisted with pleasure and modesty at the assemblies and disputations of the learned.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('Arabic', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"His ardour was quickened by the desire of grasping the virgin treasures of Ecbatana, (117) a well-known name, under which the Byzantine writer has concealed the capital of the Abbassides.","('Ecbatana', 'GPE'), ('117', 'CARDINAL'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP')"
"His court was adorned with luxury and
 science; but, in a reign of three-and-twenty years, Harun
 repeatedly visited his provinces from Chorasan to Egypt;
 nine times he performed the pilgrimage of Mecca; eight times
 he invaded the territories of the Romans; and as often as
 they declined the payment of the tribute, they were taught
 to feel that a month of depredation was more costly than a
 year of submission.","('three-and-twenty years', 'DATE'), ('Harun', 'PERSON'), ('Chorasan', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('a month', 'DATE'), ('a\r\n year', 'DATE')"
"His encampment
 on the opposite heights of Chrysopolis, or Scutari, informed
 Irene, in her palace of Constantinople, of the loss of her
 troops and provinces.","('Chrysopolis', 'GPE'), ('Scutari', 'GPE'), ('Irene', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"His first care was
 to suppress a domestic rebel, who commanded the most
 important passes of the Pyrenees: Manuza, a Moorish chief,
 had accepted the alliance of the duke of Aquitain; and
 Eudes, from a motive of private or public interest, devoted
 his beauteous daughter to the embraces of the African
 misbeliever.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('Manuza', 'PERSON'), ('Moorish', 'NORP'), ('Aquitain', 'PERSON'), ('Eudes', 'PERSON'), ('African', 'NORP')"
"His lieutenant, from a motive of fear or pity, apprised Abu Taher of his danger, and recommended a speedy escape.","('Abu Taher', 'PERSON')"
"His memory
 was revered; but the place of his burial was neglected and
 unknown, during a period of seven hundred and eighty years,
 till the conquest of Constantinople by Mahomet the Second.","('seven hundred and eighty years', 'DATE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL')"
"His merits were forgotten, his sacrilege alone was remembered, and, in an
 epistle to a Carlovingian prince, a Gallic synod presumes to declare that his ancestor was damned; that on the opening of his tomb, the spectators were affrighted by a smell of fire and the aspect of a horrid dragon; and that a saint of the times was indulged with a pleasant vision of the soul and body of Charles Martel, burning, to all eternity, in the abyss of hell. (34)
Elevation of the Abbassides, A.D. 746-750.","('Carlovingian', 'NORP'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Charles Martel', 'PERSON'), ('Elevation of the Abbassides', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('746-750', 'CARDINAL')"
"His palace was pillaged, his eyes
 were put out, and the mean ambition of the Abbassides aspired to the vacant station of danger and disgrace.","('Abbassides', 'NORP')"
"His son Mahadi, in a single
 pilgrimage to Mecca, expended six millions of dinars of
 gold.","('Mahadi', 'PERSON'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('six millions', 'CARDINAL')"
"His son Motawakkel was a jealous and cruel tyrant: odious to his subjects, he cast
 himself on the fidelity of the strangers, and these
 strangers, ambitious and apprehensive, were tempted by the
 rich promise of a revolution.","('Motawakkel', 'PERSON')"
"His speed was urged by the incessant diligence of Abdallah,
 who in every step of the pursuit acquired strength and
 reputation:","('Abdallah', 'PERSON')"
"His title to the
 name of Al Rashid (the Just) is sullied by the extirpation
 of the generous, perhaps the innocent, Barmecides; yet he
 could listen to the complaint of a poor widow who had been
 pillaged by his troops, and who dared, in a passage of the
 Koran, to threaten the inattentive despot with the judgment
 of God and posterity.","('Al Rashid', 'PERSON'), ('Barmecides', 'PERSON'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"His twelve apostles
 dispersed themselves among the Bedoweens,  and the success of their preaching seemed to threaten Arabia
 with a new revolution.","('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bedoweens', 'NORP'), ('Arabia', 'GPE')"
"His two younger
 brothers, Saffah  and Almansor, eluded the search of the
 tyrant, and lay concealed at Cufa, till the zeal of the
 people and the approach of his Eastern friends allowed them
 to expose their persons to the impatient public.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saffah', 'PERSON'), ('Almansor', 'PERSON'), ('Cufa', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"His well-conducted march was covered with a range of hills, and Abderame appears to have been surprised by his unexpected presence.","('Abderame', 'PERSON')"
"How carefully soever the book of
 prophecy had been sealed by the apostle of Mecca, the
 wishes, and (if we may profane the word) even the reason, of
 fanaticism might believe that, after the successive missions
 of Adam, Noah, Abraham, Moses, Jesus, and Mahomet, the same
 God, in the fullness of time, would reveal a still more
 perfect and permanent law.","('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Adam', 'PERSON'), ('Noah', 'PERSON'), ('Abraham', 'PERSON'), ('Moses', 'PERSON'), ('Jesus', 'PERSON'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"Ibrahim, the son of Aglab, the lieutenant of the vigilant
 and rigid Harun, bequeathed to the dynasty of  A.D. 800-941.","('Ibrahim', 'PERSON'), ('Aglab', 'PERSON'), ('Harun', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 800-941', 'DATE')"
"If
 this change was productive of the invention or familiar use
 of our present numerals, the Arabic or Indian ciphers, as
 they are commonly styled, a regulation of office has
 promoted the most important discoveries of arithmetic,
 algebra, and the mathematical sciences. (10)
Second siege of Constantinople, A.D. 716-718.","('Arabic', 'NORP'), ('Indian', 'NORP'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('716-718', 'CARDINAL')"
"If he wept at the
 sight of an old tapestry which represented the crime and
 punishment of the son of Chosroes, if his days were abridged
 by grief and remorse, we may allow some pity to a parricide,
 who exclaimed, in the bitterness of death, that he had lost
 both this world and the world to come.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON')"
"If the
 caliphs escaped to the camp or court of any neighbouring prince, their deliverance was a change of servitude, till they were prompted by despair to invite the Bowides, the sultans of Persia, who silenced the factions of Bagdad by their irresistible arms.","('Bowides', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE')"
"In
 the decline of society and art, the deserted cities could
 supply a slender booty to the Saracens; their richest spoil
 was found in the churches and monasteries, which they
 stripped of their ornaments and delivered to the flames: and
 the tutelar saints, both Hilary of Poitiers and Martin of
 Tours, forgot their miraculous powers in the defence of
 their own sepulchres. (29)","('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Hilary', 'PERSON'), ('Poitiers', 'GPE'), ('Martin of\r\n Tours', 'ORG'), ('29', 'CARDINAL')"
"In
 the six first days of desultory combat, the horsemen and archers of the East maintained their advantage: but in the closer onset of the seventh day, the Orientals were oppressed by the strength and stature of the Germans, who,
 with stout hearts and iron hands, (31) asserted the civil and religious freedom of their posterity.","('the six first days', 'DATE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('the seventh day', 'DATE'), ('Orientals', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('31', 'DATE')"
"In Sicily, the religion
 and language of the Greeks were eradicated; and such was the
 docility of the rising generation, that fifteen thousand
 boys were circumcised and clothed on the same day with the
 son of the Fatimite caliph.","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('fifteen thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('the same day', 'DATE'), ('Fatimite', 'NORP')"
"In a daring inroad beyond the Tigris, Abu Taher advanced to the gates of the capital with no more than five hundred horse.","('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Abu Taher', 'PERSON'), ('more than five hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"In a laborious administration of
 twenty-four years, he restored and supported the dignity of
 the throne, and the rebels of Germany and Gaul were
 successively crushed by the activity of a warrior, who, in
 the same campaign, could display his banner on the Elbe, the
 Rhone, and the shores of the ocean.","('twenty-four years', 'DATE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Elbe', 'LOC'), ('Rhone', 'LOC')"
"In a lofty pavilion of the gardens, one of these basins and fountains,
 so delightful in a sultry climate, was replenished not with
 water, but with the purest quicksilver.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"In a nocturnal visit to the treasure of the prince of Sistan, Jacob, the son of Leith, stumbled over a lump of salt, which he unwarily tasted with
 his tongue.","('Sistan', 'GPE'), ('Jacob', 'PERSON'), ('Leith', 'PERSON')"
"In a private condition, our desires are perpetually
 repressed by poverty and subordination; but the lives and
 labours of millions are devoted to the service of a despotic
 prince, whose laws are blindly obeyed, and whose wishes are
 instantly gratified.","('millions', 'CARDINAL')"
"In each profession, which allowed room for two persons, the one was a votary, the other an antagonist, of Ali; and the Abbassides were awakened by the clamorous grief of the sectaries, who denied their title,
 and cursed their progenitors.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ali', 'PERSON'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP')"
In every city the productions of Arabic literature were copied and collected by the curiosity of the studious and the vanity of the rich.,"('Arabic', 'LANGUAGE')"
"In his mystic volume, the precepts of the Koran
 were refined to a more spiritual sense: he relaxed the
 duties of ablution, fasting, and pilgrimage; allowed the
 indiscriminate use of wine and forbidden food; and nourished
 the fervour of his disciples by the daily repetition of fifty
 prayers.","('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('fifty', 'CARDINAL')"
"In his stately palace, that stood without the walls of Aleppo, they joyfully seized a well-furnished magazine of arms, a stable of fourteen hundred mules, and three hundred bags of silver and gold.","('Aleppo', 'GPE'), ('fourteen hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"In his youth he fought, at
 Beder and Ohud, under the holy standard: in his mature age
 he was the friend and follower of Ali; and the last remnant
 of his strength and life was consumed in a distant and
 dangerous war against the enemies of the Koran.","('Beder', 'PERSON'), ('Ohud', 'PERSON'), ('Ali', 'PERSON'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"In offensive or
 defensive war, he marched in person five times against the
 Saracens, formidable in his attack, esteemed by the enemy in
 his losses and defeats.","('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saracens', 'NORP')"
"In the
 double city of Mopsuestia, which is divided by the River
 Sarus, two hundred thousand Moslems were predestined to
 death or slavery, (115) a surprising degree of population, which must at least include the inhabitants of the dependent districts.","('Mopsuestia', 'GPE'), ('the River\r\n Sarus', 'LOC'), ('two hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moslems', 'NORP'), ('115', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the
 treaties of the administration of the empire, the royal
 author (21) suggests the answers and excuses that might best
 elude the indiscreet curiosity and importunate demands of
 the Barbarians.","('21', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"In the East, the first dynasty was that
 of A.D. 813-872.","('East', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('872', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the Eastern courts,
 the truths of science could be recommended only by ignorance
 and folly, and the astronomer would have been disregarded,
 had he not debased his wisdom or honesty by the vain
 predictions of astrology. (63)","('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"In the West, the Ommiades of Spain supported, with equal pomp, the title of commander of the faithful.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Ommiades', 'PERSON'), ('Spain', 'GPE')"
"In the bloody conflict of the Ommiades and Abbassides, the
 Greeks had stolen the opportunity of avenging their wrongs
 and enlarging their limits.","('Ommiades', 'NORP'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"In the decline of their empire, Mesopotamia, with the important cities of Mosul and Aleppo, was occupied by the Arabian princes of the tribe of The Hamadanites, A.D. 892-1001.","('Mesopotamia', 'GPE'), ('Mosul', 'GPE'), ('Aleppo', 'GPE'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('The Hamadanites', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 892-1001', 'DATE')"
"In the declining age of the caliphs, in the century which elapsed after the war of Theophilus and Motassem, the hostile transactions of the two nations were confined to some inroads by sea and land, the fruits of their close vicinity and indelible hatred.","('the century', 'DATE'), ('Theophilus', 'PERSON'), ('Motassem', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the disorder and despair of the night, the various tribes of Yemen and Damascus, of Africa and Spain, were provoked to turn their arms against each other: the remains of their host were suddenly dissolved, and each emir consulted his safety by a hasty and separate retreat.","('the night', 'TIME'), ('Yemen', 'GPE'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Spain', 'GPE')"
"In the last
 and fatal siege, her citizens displayed some remnant of the
 spirit which had formerly resisted the powers of Athens and
 Carthage.","('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"In the last of these expeditions he
 penetrated into Syria, and besieged the obscure town of
 Sozopetra; the casual birthplace of the caliph Motassem,
 whose father Harun was attended in peace or war by the most
 favoured of his wives and concubines.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Sozopetra', 'GPE'), ('Motassem', 'PERSON'), ('Harun', 'PERSON')"
"In the libraries of the Arabians, as in those of Europe, the
 far greater part of the innumerable volumes were possessed
 only of local value or imaginary merit. (55)","('Arabians', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"In the new treaty, the ruins of Heraclea were left forever as a lesson and a trophy; and the coin of
 the tribute was marked with the image and superscription of Harun and his three sons. (78)","('Heraclea', 'PERSON'), ('Harun', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the plains of Sinaar,
 and a second time in those of Cufa, his mathematicians
 accurately measured a degree of the great circle of the
 earth, and determined at twenty-four thousand miles the
 entire circumference of our globe. (61)","('Sinaar', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Cufa', 'GPE'), ('twenty-four thousand miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('61', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the proscription of the Ommiades, a royal
 youth of the name of Abdalrahman alone escaped the rage of
 his enemies, who hunted the wandering exile from the banks
 of the Euphrates to the valleys of Mount Atlas.","('Ommiades', 'PERSON'), ('Abdalrahman', 'PERSON'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Mount Atlas', 'LOC')"
"In the public danger he
 was summoned by the voice of his country; and his rival, the
 duke of Aquitain, was reduced to appear among the fugitives
 and suppliants.","('Aquitain', 'PERSON')"
"In the revolutions of the Greek empire, after the tyrant
 Justinian had been punished and avenged, an humble
 secretary, Anastasius or Artemius, was promoted by chance or
 merit to the vacant purple.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Anastasius', 'PERSON'), ('Artemius', 'PERSON')"
"In the subordinate station of great domestic, or general of the East, Reduction of Crete.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Crete', 'GPE')"
"In the sufferings of prostrate Italy, the name of Rome
 awakens a solemn and mournful recollection.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In the tenth century, the chair of Mahomet was
 disputed by three caliphs or commanders of the faithful, who
 reigned at Bagdad, Cairoan, and Cordova, excommunicating
 each other, and agreed only in a principle of discord, that
 a sectary is more odious and criminal than an unbeliever.
 (40)","('the tenth century', 'DATE'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE'), ('Cairoan', 'GPE'), ('Cordova', 'GPE')"
"In the two hundred and
 seventy-seventh year of the Hegira, and in the neighbourhood
 of Cufa, an Arabian preacher, of the name of Carmath,
 assumed the lofty and incomprehensible style of the Guide,
 the Director, the Demonstration, the Word, the Holy Ghost,
 the Camel, the Herald of the Messiah, who had conversed with
 him in a human shape, and the representative of Mohammed the
 son of Ali, of St. John the Baptist, and of the angel
 Gabriel.","('the two hundred and\r\n seventy-seventh year', 'DATE'), ('Hegira', 'NORP'), ('Cufa', 'GPE'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('Carmath', 'PERSON'), ('Guide', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Word', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('the Holy Ghost,\r\n the Camel, the Herald of the Messiah', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Mohammed the\r\n son of', 'PERSON'), ('Ali', 'PERSON'), ('St. John the Baptist', 'PERSON'), ('Gabriel', 'PERSON')"
"In the two sieges, the deliverance of Constantinople may be chiefly ascribed to the novelty, the terrors, and the real efficacy of the Greek fire.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"In the visible separation of
 parties, the green was consecrated to the Fatimites; the
 Ommiades were distinguished by the white; and the black, as
 the most adverse, was naturally adopted by the Abbassides.","('Fatimites', 'NORP'), ('Ommiades', 'NORP'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP')"
"In their Syrian inroads they commanded the husbandmen to cultivate their lands, that they themselves, in the ensuing season, might reap the benefit; more than a hundred cities were reduced to obedience; and
 eighteen pulpits of the principal moschs were committed to the flames to expiate the sacrilege of the disciples of Mahomet.","('Syrian', 'NORP'), ('the ensuing season', 'DATE'), ('more than a hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('eighteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"In their course
 along the Appian way, they pillaged Fundi and besieged
 Gayeta; but they had turned aside from the walls of Rome,
 and by their divisions, the Capitol was saved from the yoke
 of the prophet of Mecca.","('Appian', 'NORP'), ('Fundi', 'PERSON'), ('Gayeta', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('Mecca', 'GPE')"
"In their turn they were
 relieved by a powerful reinforcement of their brethren of
 Andalusia; the largest and western part of the island was
 gradually reduced, and the commodious harbour of Palermo was
 chosen for the seat of the naval and military power of the
 Saracens.","('Andalusia', 'GPE'), ('Palermo', 'GPE'), ('Saracens', 'PRODUCT')"
"In this city of peace,
 (43) amidst the riches of the East, the Abbassides soon
 disdained the abstinence and frugality of the first caliphs,
 and aspired to emulate the magnificence of the Persian
 kings.","('43', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"In this inquiry I shall unfold the events that
 rescued our ancestors of Britain, and our neighbours of Gaul,
 from the civil and religious yoke of the Koran; that
 protected the majesty of Rome, and delayed the servitude of
 Constantinople; that invigorated the defence of the
 Christians, and scattered among their enemies the seeds of
 division and decay.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"In this personal
 quarrel, the troops of Irak, Syria, and Egypt, were
 recruited from the tribes of Arabia and the Turkish hordes;
 his cavalry might be numerous, though we should deduct some
 myriads from the hundred and thirty thousand horses of the
 royal stables; and the expense of the armament was computed
 at four millions sterling, or one hundred thousand pounds of
 gold.","('Irak', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Arabia', 'LOC'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('the hundred and thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('four millions sterling', 'MONEY'), ('one hundred thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"Instead of a regular
 supply of men and money, the successors of the prophet were
 flattered with the ostentatious gift of an elephant, or a
 cast of hawks, a suit of silk hangings, or some pounds of
 musk and amber. (103)","('103', 'CARDINAL')"
"Instead of the legal tithes, he claimed the fifth
 of their substance and spoil; the most flagitious sins were
 no more than the type of disobedience; and the brethren were
 united and concealed by an oath of secrecy.","('fifth', 'ORDINAL')"
"Introduction of learning among the Arabians, A.D. 754, etc, 813, etc.","('Arabians', 'NORP'), ('754', 'CARDINAL'), ('813', 'CARDINAL')"
"It
 came flying through the air, says Joinville, (22) like a
 winged long-tailed dragon, about the thickness of a
 hogshead, with the report of thunder and the velocity of
 lightning; and the darkness of the night was dispelled by
 this deadly illumination.","('Joinville', 'PERSON'), ('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"It had been proposed by the
 wisest counsellors, to evacuate Amorium, to remove the
 inhabitants, and to abandon the empty structures to the vain
 resentment of the Barbarians.","('Amorium', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"It is yet more probable, that the delays of Charles were inevitable and reluctant.","('Charles', 'PERSON')"
"It may
 therefore be of some use to borrow the experience of the
 same Abdalrahman, whose magnificence has perhaps excited our
 admiration and envy, and to transcribe an authentic memorial
 which was found in the closet of the deceased caliph.","('Abdalrahman', 'NORP')"
"It might have been expected that the saviour of Christendom would have been canonized, or at least applauded, by the gratitude of the clergy, who are indebted to his sword for their present existence.","('Christendom', 'GPE')"
"It was
 dexterously wielded in the schools of the Saracens, but as
 it is more effectual for the detection of error than for the
 investigation of truth, it is not surprising that new
 generations of masters and disciples should still revolve in
 the same circle of logical argument.","('Saracens', 'LOC')"
"It was at length either discovered or stolen by the
 Mahometans; and, in the holy wars of Syria and Egypt, they
 retorted an invention, contrived against themselves, on the
 heads of the Christians.","('Mahometans', 'NORP'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
It was written in characters of blood and fire on the plains of Phrygia; and the warlike celerity of the Arabs could only be checked by the arts of deceit and the show of repentance.,"('Phrygia', 'LOC'), ('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"Jealous
 of his wives, liberal of his wealth, prodigal of his own
 blood and of that of others, he could boast with pleasure,
 and possibly with truth, that he had destroyed six hundred
 thousand of his enemies; and such was the intrepid gravity
 of his mind and countenance, that he was never seen to smile
 except on a day of battle.","('six hundred\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
Learning of the ArabsLuxury of the Caliphs,"('Arabs', 'NORP')"
Limits of the Arabian conquests,"('Arabian', 'NORP')"
"Magnificence of the caliphs, A.D. 750-960.","('A.D. 750-960', 'DATE')"
"Mecca was the patrimony of the line of Hashem, yet the
 Abbassides were never tempted to reside either in the
 birthplace or the city of the prophet.","('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Hashem', 'PERSON'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP')"
"Motassem, the
 first author of this dangerous example, introduced into the
 capital above fifty thousand Turks: their licentious conduct
 provoked the public indignation, and the quarrels of the
 soldiers and people induced the caliph to retire from
 Bagdad, and establish his own residence and the camp of his
 Barbarian favourites at Samara on the Tigris, about twelve
 leagues above the city of Peace. (98)","('Motassem', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('Samara', 'PERSON'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('about twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('Peace', 'FAC')"
"Mutual necessity could sometimes extort the exchange or
 ransom of prisoners: (94) but in the national and religious
 conflict of the two empires, peace was without confidence,
 and war without mercy.","('94', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Naval Enterprises on Crete, Sicily, and RomeDecay and Division of the Empire of the CaliphsDefeats and Victories of the Greek Emperors.","('Naval Enterprises', 'ORG'), ('Crete', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Defeats and Victories of the Greek Emperors', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Nicephorus was astonished by the bold and rapid march of the commander of the faithful, who repassed, in the depth of winter, the snows of Mount Taurus: his stratagems of policy and war were exhausted; and the perfidious Greek escaped with three wounds from a field of battle overspread with forty thousand of his subjects.","('Nicephorus', 'PERSON'), ('Mount Taurus', 'LOC'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('forty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"No sooner had he collected his forces, than he sought and found the enemy in the centre of France, between Tours and Poitiers.","('France', 'GPE'), ('Tours', 'LOC'), ('Poitiers', 'GPE')"
"No sooner had the caliph Moawiyah
 suppressed his rivals and established his throne, than he
 aspired to expiate the guilt of civil blood, by the success
 and glory of this holy expedition; (2) his preparations by
 sea and land were adequate to the importance of the object;
 his standard was entrusted to Sophian, a veteran warrior,
 but the troops were encouraged by the example and presence
 of Yezid, the son and presumptive heir of the commander of
 the faithful.","('Moawiyah', 'PERSON'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sophian', 'PERSON'), ('Yezid', 'PERSON')"
"Of the Turks (97) who dwelt beyond the Oxus and Jaxartes, the robust youths,
 either taken in war or purchased in trade, were educated in
 the exercises of the field, and the profession of the
 Mahometan faith.","('Turks', 'NORP'), ('97', 'DATE'), ('Oxus', 'NORP'), ('Jaxartes', 'NORP'), ('Mahometan', 'NORP')"
"Of these extensive conquests, Antioch, with the cities of Cilicia and the Isle of Cyprus, was alone restored, a permanent and useful accession to the Roman empire. (118)","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Cilicia', 'GPE'), ('the Isle of Cyprus', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('118', 'CARDINAL')"
"Of these the Fatimites were
 either rash or pusillanimous; but the descendants of Abbas
 cherished, with courage and discretion, the hopes of their
 rising fortunes.","('Fatimites', 'NORP'), ('Abbas', 'PERSON')"
"On Friday,
 in the dress of a caliph, in the colours of the sect, Saffah
 proceeded with religious and military pomp to the mosch:
 ascending the pulpit, he prayed and preached as the lawful
 successor of Mahomet; and after his departure, his kinsmen
 bound a willing people by an oath of fidelity.","('Friday', 'DATE'), ('Saffah', 'PERSON'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"On his march towards Bagdad, the conqueror was
 arrested by a fever.","('Bagdad', 'GPE')"
"On which of these
 actions did he reflect with the most pleasure, when he was
 summoned by the angel of death? (96)","('96', 'CARDINAL')"
"One hundred and thirty-five thousand regular soldiers received pay, and were inscribed in the military roll; and above three hundred thousand persons of every denomination marched under the black standard of the Abbassides.","('One hundred and thirty-five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('three hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Abbassides', 'PRODUCT')"
"Our education in the Greek and Latin
 schools may have fixed in our minds a standard of exclusive
 taste; and I am not forward to condemn the literature and
 judgment of nations, of whose language I am ignorant.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
Passage of the Euphrates.,"('Passage of the Euphrates', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Peace and tribute, A.D. 677.","('A.D. 677', 'DATE')"
"Perhaps the interpretation of the Koran
 would now be taught in the schools of Oxford, and her
 pulpits might demonstrate to a circumcised people the
 sanctity and truth of the revelation of Mahomet. (30)
Defeat of the Saracens by Charles Martel, A.D. 732.","('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Oxford', 'GPE'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('30', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Charles Martel', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 732', 'DATE')"
"Plato wrote
 for the Athenians, and his allegorical genius is too closely
 blended with the language and religion of Greece.","('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('Athenians', 'NORP'), ('Greece', 'GPE')"
"Quarter was seldom given in the
 field; those who escaped the edge of the sword were
 condemned to hopeless servitude, or exquisite torture; and a
 Catholic emperor relates, with visible satisfaction, the
 execution of the Saracens of Crete, who were flayed alive,
 or plunged into cauldrons of boiling oil. (95)","('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Crete', 'GPE')"
Recovery of Antioch.,"('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"Revolt of the provinces, A.D. 800-936.","('800-936', 'CARDINAL')"
"Rise and progress of the Carmathians, A.D. 890-951.","('Carmathians', 'NORP'), ('890-951', 'CARDINAL')"
"Salt, among the Orientals, is the symbol of
 hospitality, and the pious robber immediately retired
 without spoil or damage.","('Orientals', 'NORP')"
"Seven months were consumed in the siege of Candia; the despair of the native Cretans was stimulated by the frequent aid of their brethren of Africa and Spain; and after the massy wall and double ditch had been stormed by
 the Greeks a hopeless conflict was still maintained in the streets and houses of the city.","('Seven months', 'DATE'), ('Candia', 'GPE'), ('Cretans', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"Since the days of Heraclius, the Euphrates, below the passage of Mount Taurus, had been impervious, and almost invisible, to the Greeks.","('the days of Heraclius', 'DATE'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Mount Taurus', 'LOC'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"So patient was their perseverance, or so
 languid were their operations, that they repeated in the six
 following summers the same attack and retreat, with a
 gradual abatement of hope and vigour, till the mischances of
 shipwreck and disease, of the sword and of fire, compelled
 them to relinquish the fruitless enterprise.","('the six\r\n following summers', 'DATE')"
"So uniform are the mischiefs of
 military despotism, that I seem to repeat the story of the
 praetorians of Rome. (100)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"Some
 traditionary knowledge might be secreted in the temples and
 monasteries of Egypt; much useful experience had been
 acquired in the practice of arts and manufactures; but the
 science of chemistry owes its origin and improvement to the
 industry of the Saracens.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Saracens', 'NORP')"
"Sozopetra was
 levelled with the ground, the Syrian prisoners were marked
 or mutilated with ignominious cruelty, and a thousand female
 captives were forced away from the adjacent territory.","('Sozopetra', 'PERSON'), ('Syrian', 'NORP'), ('a thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Strongly
 prompted by gratitude, indignation, and fear, they invited
 the grandson of the caliph Hashem to ascend the throne of
 his ancestors; and, in his desperate condition, the extremes
 of rashness and prudence were almost the same.","('Hashem', 'PERSON')"
"Such troops were discomfited in every action; the cities of Racca and Baalbec, of Cufa and Bassora, were taken and pillaged; Bagdad was filled with consternation; and the caliph trembled behind the veils of his palace.","('Racca', 'GPE'), ('Baalbec', 'GPE'), ('Cufa', 'GPE'), ('Bassora', 'GPE'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE')"
"Syracuse preserved about fifty years the faith
 which she had sworn to Christ and to Caesar.","('Syracuse', 'GPE'), ('about fifty years', 'DATE'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"Temporal and spiritual conquest had been the sole occupation of the first successors of Mahomet; and after supplying themselves with the necessaries of life, the whole revenue was scrupulously devoted to that salutary work.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"That maker of kings, the author, as
 he is named, of the call of the Abbassides, was at length
 rewarded for his presumption of merit with the usual
 gratitude of courts.","('Abbassides', 'PERSON')"
"That venerable Arab,
 one of the last of the companions of Mahomet, was numbered
 among the ansars, or auxiliaries, of Medina, who sheltered
 the head of the flying prophet.","('Arab', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Medina', 'PERSON')"
"That veteran and daring commander adjudged to the obedience
 of the prophet whatever yet remained of France or of Europe;
 and prepared to execute the sentence, at the head of a
 formidable host, in the full confidence of surmounting all
 opposition either of nature or of man.","('France', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"The
 Byzantine empire, since the accession of the Basilian race, had reposed in peace and dignity; and they might encounter with their entire strength the front of some petty emir, whose rear was assaulted and threatened by his national foes
 of the Mahometan faith.","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Basilian', 'NORP'), ('Mahometan', 'NORP')"
"The
 Greek interpreters were chosen among their Christian
 subjects; they formed their translations, sometimes on the
 original text, more frequently perhaps on a Syriac version;
 and in the crowd of astronomers and physicians, there is no
 example of a poet, an orator, or even an historian, being
 taught to speak the language of the Saracens. (70)","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Syriac', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('70', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 acclamations of the people saluted his landing on the coast
 of Andalusia: and, after a successful struggle, Abdalrahman
 established the throne of Cordova, and was the father of the
 Ommiades of Spain, who reigned above two hundred and fifty
 years from the Atlantic to the Pyrenees. (39)","('Andalusia', 'GPE'), ('Abdalrahman', 'PERSON'), ('Cordova', 'PERSON'), ('Ommiades', 'PERSON'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('two hundred and fifty\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Atlantic', 'LOC'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('39', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 advantageous situation which had recommended Narbonne (28) as the first Roman colony, was again chosen by the Moslems:
 they claimed the province of Septimania or Languedoc as a
 just dependence of the Spanish monarchy: the vineyards of
 Gascony and the city of Bourdeaux were possessed by the
 sovereign of Damascus and Samarcand; and the south of
 France, from the mouth of the Garonne to that of the Rhone,
 assumed the manners and religion of Arabia.","('Narbonne', 'GPE'), ('28', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Moslems', 'NORP'), ('Septimania', 'GPE'), ('Languedoc', 'LOC'), ('Spanish', 'NORP'), ('Gascony', 'GPE'), ('Bourdeaux', 'GPE'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Samarcand', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Garonne', 'GPE'), ('Rhone', 'LOC'), ('Arabia', 'GPE')"
"The
 deacon Theodosius, with the bishop and clergy, was dragged
 in chains from the altar to Palermo, cast into a
 subterraneous dungeon, and exposed to the hourly peril of
 death or apostasy.","('The\r\n deacon Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Palermo', 'GPE')"
"The
 glories of the court were brightened, rather than impaired,
 in the decline of the empire, and a Greek ambassador might
 admire, or pity, the magnificence of the feeble Moctader.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Moctader', 'PERSON')"
"The
 instinct of superstition was alarmed by the introduction
 even of the abstract sciences; and the more rigid doctors of
 the law condemned the rash and pernicious curiosity of
 Almamon. (73)","('Almamon', 'PERSON')"
"The
 mythology of Homer would have provoked the abhorrence of
 those stern fanatics: they possessed in lazy ignorance the
 colonies of the Macedonians, and the provinces of Carthage
 and Rome: the heroes of Plutarch and Livy were buried in
 oblivion; and the history of the world before Mahomet was
 reduced to a short legend of the patriarchs, the prophets,
 and the Persian kings.","('Homer', 'PERSON'), ('Macedonians', 'NORP'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Plutarch', 'PERSON'), ('Livy', 'PERSON'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The
 names of Mesua and Geber, of Razis and Avicenna, are ranked
 with the Grecian masters; in the city of Bagdad, eight
 hundred and sixty physicians were licensed to exercise their
 lucrative profession: (64) in Spain, the life of the Catholic
 princes was entrusted to the skill of the Saracens, (65) and
 the school of Salerno, their legitimate offspring, revived
 in Italy and Europe the precepts of the healing art. (66)","('Mesua', 'PERSON'), ('Geber', 'PERSON'), ('Razis', 'GPE'), ('Avicenna', 'GPE'), ('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE'), ('eight\r\n hundred and sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('64', 'CARDINAL'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('65', 'CARDINAL'), ('Salerno', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('66', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 reign of Leo the Fourth was employed in the defence and
 ornament of the Roman state.","('Leo the Fourth', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The
 sages of Greece were translated and illustrated in the
 Arabic language, and some treatises, now lost in the
 original, have been recovered in the versions of the East,
 (56) which possessed and studied the writings of Aristotle and Plato, of Euclid and Apollonius, of Ptolemy,
 Hippocrates, and Galen. (57)","('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Arabic', 'LANGUAGE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Aristotle', 'PERSON'), ('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('Euclid and Apollonius', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Ptolemy,\r\n Hippocrates', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Galen', 'PERSON'), ('57', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 success of each professor must have been influenced by
 personal and accidental causes; but we may form a less
 fanciful estimate of their general knowledge of anatomy, (67)
 botany, (68) and chemistry, (69) the threefold basis of their
 theory and practice.","('67', 'CARDINAL'), ('68', 'CARDINAL'), ('69', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Abbassides were impoverished by the multitude of their wants, and their contempt of economy.","('Abbassides', 'PERSON')"
"The Abbassides were too feeble to contend, too proud to forgive: they invited the powerful dynasty of  A.D. 874-999.","('Abbassides', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 874-999', 'DATE')"
"The African and the Turkish guards drew their
 swords against each other, and the chief commanders, the emirs al Omra, (110) imprisoned or deposed their sovereigns, and violated the sanctuary of the mosch and harem.","('African', 'NORP'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('al Omra', 'PERSON'), ('110', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Aglabite, (88) who reigned in
 Africa, had inherited from his father a treasure and an
 army: a fleet of Arabs and Moors, after a short refreshment
 in the harbours of Sardinia, cast anchor before the mouth of
 the Tyber, sixteen miles from the city: and their discipline
 and numbers appeared to threaten, not a transient inroad,
 but a serious design of conquest and dominion.","('Aglabite', 'PERSON'), ('88', 'DATE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Moors', 'NORP'), ('Sardinia', 'GPE'), ('Tyber', 'NORP'), ('sixteen miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"The Amorian war between Theophilus and Motassem, A.D. 838.","('The Amorian war', 'EVENT'), ('Theophilus', 'PERSON'), ('Motassem', 'PERSON'), ('838', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Andalusians wandered over the land fearless and
 unmolested; but when they descended with their plunder to
 the sea-shore, their vessels were in flames, and their
 chief, Abu Caab, confessed himself the author of the
 mischief.","('Andalusians', 'NORP'), ('Abu Caab', 'PERSON')"
"The Arabian fleet cast
 anchor, and the troops were disembarked near the palace of
 Hebdomon, seven miles from the city.","('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('Hebdomon', 'GPE'), ('seven miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"The Arabian squadrons issued
 from the harbours of Palermo, Biserta, and Tunis; a hundred
 and fifty towns of Calabria and Campania were attacked and
 pillaged; nor could the suburbs of Rome be defended by the
 name of the Caesars and apostles.","('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('Palermo', 'GPE'), ('Biserta', 'GPE'), ('Tunis', 'GPE'), ('a hundred\r\n and fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Calabria', 'GPE'), ('Campania', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Caesars', 'ORG')"
"The Arabs subdue the isle of Crete, A.D. 823.","('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Crete', 'GPE'), ('823', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Arabs were broken, but it was by the swords of
 thirty thousand Persians, who had obtained service and
 settlement in the Byzantine empire.","('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"The Carmathians were ripe for
 rebellion, since they disclaimed the title of the house of
 Abbas, and abhorred the worldly pomp of the caliphs of
 Bagdad.","('Carmathians', 'NORP'), ('Abbas', 'PERSON'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE')"
"The Christian idols were stripped of their
 costly offerings; a silver altar was torn away from the
 shrine of St. Peter; and if the bodies or the buildings were
 left entire, their deliverance must be imputed to the haste,
 rather than the scruples, of the Saracens.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('St. Peter', 'FAC'), ('Saracens', 'NORP')"
"The Christians were
 sheltered in a friendly harbour, while the Africans were
 scattered and dashed in pieces among the rocks and islands
 of a hostile shore.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Africans', 'NORP')"
"The Eastern conquests of Nicephorus Phocas and John Zimisces, A.D. 963-975.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Nicephorus Phocas', 'ORG'), ('John Zimisces', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 963-975', 'DATE')"
"The Goths, the
 Gascons, and the Franks, assembled under the standard of
 this Christian hero: he repelled the first invasion of the
 Saracens; and Zama, lieutenant of the caliph, lost his army
 and his life under the walls of Thoulouse.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Gascons', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Zama', 'PERSON'), ('Thoulouse', 'PRODUCT')"
"The Greek ambassador was
 favourably received at Damascus, a general council of the
 emirs or Koreish: a peace, or truce, of thirty years was
 ratified between the two empires; and the stipulation of an
 annual tribute, fifty horses of a noble breed, fifty slaves,
 and three thousand pieces of gold, degraded the majesty of
 the commander of the faithful.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Koreish', 'NORP'), ('thirty years', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('three thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Greeks had little to hope, nor had their
 enemies any reason of fear, from the courage and vigilance
 of the reigning emperor, who disgraced the name of
 Constantine, and imitated only the inglorious years of his
 grandfather Heraclius.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON')"
"The Greeks were
 repulsed and vanquished, but it was by the arrows of the
 Turkish cavalry; and had not their bowstrings been damped
 and relaxed by the evening rain, very few of the Christians
 could have escaped with the emperor from the field of
 battle.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"The Greeks would gladly have ransomed their religion and empire, by a fine or assessment of a piece of gold on the head of each inhabitant of the
 city; but the liberal offer was rejected with disdain, and the presumption of Moslemah was exalted by the speedy approach and invincible force of the natives of Egypt and Syria.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Moslemah', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE')"
"The Ikshidites, A.D. 934-968. (107)","('Ikshidites', 'ORG'), ('934-968', 'CARDINAL'), ('107', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Romans were
 assured of a short respite by the welcome news, that the
 siege of Gayeta had been raised, and that a part of the
 enemy, with their sacrilegious plunder, had perished in the
 waves.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Gayeta', 'GPE')"
"The Saracens
 had too rashly advanced into the midst of a distant and
 hostile land: their retreat was solicited by the promise of
 faithful guides and plentiful markets; and not a Greek had
 courage to whisper, that their weary forces might be
 surrounded and destroyed in their necessary passage between
 a slippery mountain and the River Sangarius.","('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('the River Sangarius', 'LOC')"
The Saracens of Crete soon repaired the loss of their navy; and the timbers of Mount Ida were launched into the main.,"('Saracens', 'PRODUCT'), ('Crete', 'GPE'), ('Mount Ida', 'LOC')"
"The Saracens were confounded by the landing of his troops on safe and level bridges, which he cast from the vessels to
 the shore.","('Saracens', 'NORP')"
"The Turkish guards stood in arms round the
 throne of their benefactor, and their chiefs usurped the
 dominion of the palace and the provinces.","('Turkish', 'NORP')"
"The Two Sieges of Constantinople by the ArabsTheir Invasion of France, and Defeat by Charles Martel Civil War of the Ommiades and Abbassides","('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Charles Martel', 'PERSON'), ('Civil War of the Ommiades and Abbassides', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"The age of Arabian learning continued about five hundred years, till
 the great eruption of the Moguls, and was coeval with the darkest and most slothful period of European annals; but since the sun of science has arisen in the West, it should seem that the Oriental studies have languished and declined.","('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('about five hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Moguls', 'NORP'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Oriental', 'NORP')"
"The aged caliph was
 desirous of possessing his dominions, and ending his days in
 tranquillity and repose: while the Moors and Indians
 trembled at his name, his palace and city of Damascus was
 insulted by the Mardaites, or Maronites, of Mount Libanus,
 the firmest barrier of the empire, till they were disarmed
 and transplanted by the suspicious policy of the Greeks. (6)","('Moors', 'NORP'), ('Indians', 'NORP'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Mardaites', 'NORP'), ('Maronites', 'NORP'), ('Mount Libanus', 'LOC'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('6', 'CARDINAL')"
"The ambition of
 his successors was stimulated by revenge; they repassed the
 Pyrenees with the means and the resolution of conquest.","('Pyrenees', 'LOC')"
"The arms of Abderame were not less
 successful on the side of the ocean.","('Abderame', 'GPE')"
"The best of their race, the
 pious Omar, was dissatisfied with his own title: their
 personal virtues were insufficient to justify a departure
 from the order of succession; and the eyes and wishes of the
 faithful were turned towards the line of Hashem, and the
 kindred of the apostle of God.","('Omar', 'PERSON'), ('Hashem', 'PERSON')"
"The boundary was trod by the bishop and his clergy,
 barefoot, in sackcloth and ashes; the songs of triumph were
 modulated to psalms and litanies; the walls were besprinkled
 with holy water; and the ceremony was concluded with a
 prayer, that, under the guardian care of the apostles and
 the angelic host, both the old and the new Rome might ever
 be preserved pure, prosperous, and impregnable. (90)","('Rome', 'GPE')"
The brother of Moslemah was succeeded by a kinsman and an enemy; and the throne of an active and able prince was degraded by the useless and pernicious virtues of a bigot. !,"('Moslemah', 'PERSON')"
"The caliph Almamon might
 proudly assert, that it was easier for him to rule the East
 and the West, than to manage a chess-board of two feet
 square: (102) yet I suspect that in both those games he was
 guilty of many fatal mistakes; and I perceive, that in the
 distant provinces the authority of the first and most
 powerful of the Abbassides was already impaired.","('Almamon', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('two feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('102', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Abbassides', 'PRODUCT')"
"The caliph smiled at the menace, and drawing his scymetar, samsamah, a weapon of historic or fabulous renown, he cut asunder the feeble arms of the Greeks, without turning the edge, or endangering the temper, of his blade.","('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"The captive Amrou was sent in chains, a grateful offering to the court of Bagdad; and as the victor was content with the
 inheritance of Transoxiana and Chorasan, the realms of Persia returned for a while to the allegiance of the caliphs.","('Amrou', 'PERSON'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE'), ('Transoxiana', 'NORP'), ('Chorasan', 'NORP'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"The chosen spot is on the eastern bank of
 the Tigris, about fifteen miles above the ruins of Modain:
 the double wall was of a circular form; and such was the
 rapid increase of a capital, now dwindled to a provincial
 town, that the funeral of a popular saint might be attended
 by eight hundred thousand men and sixty thousand women of
 Bagdad and the adjacent villages.","('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('about fifteen miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Modain', 'GPE'), ('eight hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE')"
"The churches were renewed and
 embellished: near four thousand pounds of silver were
 consecrated to repair the losses of St. Peter; and his
 sanctuary was decorated with a plate of gold of the weight
 of two hundred and sixteen pounds, embossed with the
 portraits of the pope and emperor, and encircled with a
 string of pearls.","('four thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('two hundred and sixteen pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"The city bands, in
 arms, attended their father to Ostia, where he reviewed and
 blessed his generous deliverers.","('Ostia', 'PERSON')"
"The civil and military powers were assumed by Moezaldowlat, the second of the three brothers, and a stipend of sixty thousand pounds sterling was assigned by his generosity for the private expense of the commander of the faithful.","('Moezaldowlat', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('sixty thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"The classic names of Hierapolis, Apamea, and Emesa, revive for a moment in the list of conquest: the emperor Zimisces encamped in the paradise of Damascus, and accepted the ransom of a submissive people; and the torrent was only stopped by the impregnable fortress of Tripoli, on the sea-coast of Phoenicia.","('Hierapolis', 'PERSON'), ('Apamea', 'PERSON'), ('Emesa', 'PERSON'), ('Zimisces', 'NORP'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Tripoli', 'GPE'), ('Phoenicia', 'GPE')"
"The confidence of soldiers and fanatics may indeed
 be excused, since the calm historian of the present hour,
 who strives to follow the rapid course of the Saracens, must
 study to explain by what means the church and state were
 saved from this impending, and, as it should seem, from this
 inevitable, danger.","('the present hour', 'TIME'), ('Saracens', 'NORP')"
The consternation of the fugitives had already diffused the terror of his name; but the fancied riches of Bagdad had already been dissipated by the avarice and prodigality of domestic tyrants.,"('Bagdad', 'GPE')"
"The costly instruments of
 observation were supplied by the caliph Almamon, and the
 land of the Chaldaeans still afforded the same spacious
 level, the same unclouded horizon.","('Almamon', 'GPE'), ('Chaldaeans', 'NORP')"
"The courage of the South is the artificial fruit of
 discipline and prejudice; the active power of enthusiasm had
 decayed, and the mercenary forces of the caliphs were
 recruited in those climates of the North, of which valour is
 the hardy and spontaneous production.","('South', 'LOC'), ('North', 'LOC')"
"The court of Damascus, awakening
 from a long slumber, resolved to prevent the pilgrimage of
 Mecca, which Ibrahim had undertaken with a splendid retinue,
 to recommend himself at once to the favour of the prophet and
 of the people.","('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Ibrahim', 'PERSON')"
"The courtiers would
 surely praise the liberality of his grandson Almamon, who
 gave away four fifths of the income of a province, a sum of
 two millions four hundred thousand gold dinars, before he
 drew his foot from the stirrup.","('Almamon', 'PERSON'), ('four fifths', 'CARDINAL'), ('two millions four hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The decline of
 the French monarchy invited the attack of these insatiate
 fanatics.","('French', 'NORP')"
"The descendants of Clovis had lost the
 inheritance of his martial and ferocious spirit; and their
 misfortune or demerit has affixed the epithet of lazy to the
 last kings of the Merovingian race. (26)","('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('26', 'CARDINAL')"
"The deserts of Scythia and Sarmatia
 might be guarded by their extent, their climate, their
 poverty, and the courage of the northern shepherds; China
 was remote and inaccessible; but the greatest part of the
 temperate zone was subject to the Mahometan conquerors, the
 Greeks were exhausted by the calamities of war and the loss
 of their fairest provinces, and the Barbarians of Europe
 might justly tremble at the precipitate fall of the Gothic
 monarchy.","('Scythia', 'LOC'), ('Sarmatia', 'LOC'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('Mahometan', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"The discovery of this honourable
 behaviour recommended Jacob to pardon and trust; he led an
 army at first for his benefactor, at last for himself,
 subdued Persia, and threatened the residence of the
 Abbassides.","('Jacob', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Persia', 'PERSON'), ('Abbassides', 'NORP')"
The emir was inexorable; the furniture of the palace was sold; and the paltry price of forty thousand pieces of gold was instantly consumed in private luxury.,"('forty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The emperor Theophilus, son of Michael the Stammerer, was
 one of the most active and high-spirited princes who reigned
 at Constantinople during the middle age.","('Theophilus', 'PERSON'), ('Michael the Stammerer', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('the middle age', 'DATE')"
"The epistle of the emperor to the caliph was
 pointed with an allusion to the game of chess, which had
 already spread from Persia to Greece.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE')"
"The epithet of Martel, the Hammer, which has been added to the name of Charles, is expressive of his weighty and irresistible strokes: the valour of Eudes was excited by resentment and emulation; and their companions, in the eye of history, are the true Peers
 and Paladins of French chivalry.","('Martel, the Hammer', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Charles', 'PERSON'), ('Eudes', 'PERSON'), ('Paladins', 'NORP'), ('French', 'NORP')"
"The event of the siege revived, both in the East and West,
 the reputation of the Roman arms, and cast a momentary shade
 over the glories of the Saracens.","('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP')"
"The example of the Ommiades was imitated by the
 real or fictitious progeny of Ali, the Edrissites of
 Mauritania, and the more powerful fatimites of Africa and
 Egypt.","('Ommiades', 'PERSON'), ('Ali', 'PERSON'), ('Edrissites', 'NORP'), ('Mauritania', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"The father of Theophilus was a native of Amorium (92) in
 Phrygia: the original seat of the Imperial house had been
 adorned with privileges and monuments; and, whatever might
 be the indifference of the people, Constantinople itself was
 scarcely of more value in the eyes of the sovereign and his
 court.","('Theophilus', 'PERSON'), ('Amorium', 'GPE'), ('92', 'CARDINAL'), ('Phrygia', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The fire-ships of the Greeks were launched against them; the Arabs, their arms, and vessels,
 were involved in the same flames; the disorderly fugitives were dashed against each other or overwhelmed in the waves; and I no longer find a vestige of the fleet, that had threatened to extirpate the Roman name.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The first days of his reign were
 consecrated to the purification and removal of relics, to
 prayers and processions, and to all the solemn offices of
 religion, which served at least to heal the imagination, and
