Sentence,Entities
(45),"('45', 'CARDINAL')"
(54),"('54', 'CARDINAL')"
(55),"('55', 'CARDINAL')"
"A cool
 head, an unfeeling heart, and a cowardly disposition,
 prompted him, at the age of nineteen, to assume the mask of
 hypocrisy, which he never afterwards laid aside.","('nineteen', 'DATE')"
"A feeble senate and
 enervated people cheerfully acquiesced in the pleasing
 illusion, as long as it was supported by the virtue, or even
 by the prudence, of the successors of Augustus.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"A law was passed that wherever the
 emperor was present, his extraordinary commission should
 supersede the ordinary jurisdiction of the governor; a
 custom was introduced, that the new conquest belonged to the
 Imperial portion; and it was soon discovered that the
 authority of the Prince, the favourite epithet of Augustus,
 was the same in every part of the empire.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"Above two hundred and fifty years
 after the death of Trajan, the senate, in pouring out the
 customary acclamations on the accession of a new emperor,
 wished that he might surpass the felicity of Augustus, and
 the virtue of Trajan.  (37)","('two hundred and fifty years', 'DATE'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('37', 'CARDINAL')"
Adoption and character of Trajan.,"('Trajan', 'PERSON')"
Adoption of the elder and younger Verus.,"('Verus', 'PERSON')"
Adoption of the two Antonines.,"('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antonines', 'PRODUCT')"
"After a decent resistance,
 the crafty tyrant submitted to the orders of the senate; and
 consented to receive the government of the provinces, and
 the general command of the Roman armies, under the
 well-known names of PROCONSUL and IMPERATOR.  (5)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('PROCONSUL', 'ORG'), ('5', 'CARDINAL')"
"After revolving in his mind several men of distinguished
 merit, whom he esteemed and hated, he adopted Aelius Verus,
 a gay and voluptuous nobleman, recommended by uncommon
 beauty to the lover of Antinous.  (40)","('Aelius Verus', 'PERSON'), ('Antinous', 'PERSON'), ('40', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the
 victory of Actium, the fate of the Roman world depended on
 the will of Octavianus, surnamed Caesar, by his uncle's
 adoption, and afterwards Augustus, by the flattery of the
 senate.","('Actium', 'EVENT'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Octavianus', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"Although
 Pius had two sons,  (42) he preferred the welfare of Rome to 
 the interest of his family, gave his daughter Faustina in
 marriage to young Marcus, obtained from the senate the
 tribunitian and proconsular powers, and with a noble
 disdain, or rather ignorance of jealousy, associated him to
 all the labours of government.","('Pius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('42', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Faustina', 'PERSON'), ('Marcus', 'PERSON')"
"Although Augustus considered a military force as the firmest
 foundation, he wisely rejected it, as a very odious
 instrument of government.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"Among the
 many vices of this younger Verus he possessed one virtue; a
 dutiful reverence for his wiser colleague, to whom he
 willingly abandoned the ruder cares of empire.","('Verus', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"As soon as Hadrian's passion was either gratified or
 disappointed, he resolved to deserve the thanks of
 posterity, by placing the most exalted merit on the Roman
 throne.","('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"As they prevailed, and as they were attracted by different
 objects, Hadrian was, by turns, an excellent prince, a
 ridiculous sophist, and a jealous tyrant.","('Hadrian', 'PERSON')"
"At the age of twelve years he
 embraced the rigid system of the Stoics, which taught him to
 submit his body to his mind, his passions to his reason; to
 consider virtue as the only good, vice as the only evil, all
 things external as things indifferent.  (46)","('the age of twelve years', 'DATE'), ('Stoics', 'PRODUCT'), ('46', 'CARDINAL')"
Attempt of the senate after the death of Caligula.,"('Caligula', 'PERSON')"
"Augustus or Trajan would have blushed at 
 employing the meanest of the Romans in those menial offices,
 which, in the household and bedchamber of a limited monarch,
 are so eagerly solicited by the proudest nobles of Britain.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"Augustus permitted indeed
 some of the provincial cities to erect temples to his
 honour, on condition that they should associate the worship
 of Rome with that of the sovereign; he tolerated private
 superstition, of which he might be the object;  (23) but he 
 contented himself with being revered by the senate and
 people in his human character, and wisely left to his
 successor the care of his public deification.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('23', 'CARDINAL')"
"Augustus summoned to his aid whatever remained in those
 fierce minds of Roman prejudices; enforced the rigour of
 discipline by the sanction of law; and interposing the
 majesty of the senate between the emperor and the army,
 boldly claimed their allegiance, as the first magistrate of
 the republic.  (29)","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('29', 'CARDINAL')"
"Augustus was sensible that mankind
 is governed by names; nor was he deceived in his
 expectation, that the senate and people would submit to
 slavery, provided they were respectfully assured that they
 still enjoyed their ancient freedom.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"Augustus was therefore a personal, Caesar a 
 family distinction.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"Before an assembly thus modelled and prepared, Augustus
 pronounced a studied oration, which displayed his
 patriotism, and disguised his ambition.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"But
 as it was impossible that he could personally command the
 legions of so many distant frontiers, he was indulged by the
 senate, as Pompey had already been, in the permission of
 devolving the execution of his great office on a sufficient
 number of lieutenants.","('Pompey', 'PERSON')"
"But
 the empire of the Romans filled the world, and when that
 empire fell into the hands of a single person, the world
 became a safe and dreary prison for his enemies.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
But Nero involved the whole empire in his ruin.,"('Nero', 'PERSON')"
"But as soon as the senate had been humbled and disarmed,
 such an assembly, consisting of five or six hundred persons,
 was found a much more tractable and useful instrument of
 dominion.","('five or six hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"But he would 
 receive them only for ten years.","('ten years', 'DATE')"
"But his life was 
 the noblest commentary on the precepts of Zeno.","('Zeno', 'PERSON')"
"But the conquerors soon imitated the vanquished
 nations in the arts of flattery; and the imperious spirit of
 the first Caesar too easily consented to assume, during his
 lifetime, a place among the tutelar deities of Rome.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But we may venture to ascribe to his councils, 
 the first measure of the succeeding reign, by which the
 elections were transferred to the senate.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But when the arms of the legions were carried
 to a great distance from Italy, the generals assumed the
 liberty of directing them against whatever people, and in
 whatever manner, they judged most advantageous for the
 public service.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"But when the consular and tribunitian powers
 were united, when they were vested for life in a single
 person, when the general of the army was, at the same time,
 the minister of the senate, and the representative of the
 Roman people, it was impossible to resist the exercise, nor
 was it easy to define the limits, of his Imperial
 prerogative.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"But while Hadrian was 
 delighting himself with his own applause, and the
 acclamations of the soldiers, whose consent had been secured
 by an immense donative, the new Caesar  (41) was ravished from 
 his embraces by an untimely death.","('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"But while they deliberated, the
 Praetorian Guards had resolved.","('the\r\n Praetorian Guards', 'ORG')"
"But, at the time of his
 death, the practice of a century had inseparably connected
 those appellations with the Imperial dignity, and they have
 been preserved by a long succession of emperors, Romans,
 Greeks, Franks, and Germans, from the fall of the republic
 to the present time.","('a century', 'DATE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"By declaring themselves the protectors of the people, Marius
 and Caesar had subverted the constitution of their country.","('Marius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"By the former he acquired the
 management of the religion, and by the latter a legal
 inspection over the manners and fortunes, of the Roman
 people.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"By this assembly the last of the Romans were
 condemned for imaginary crimes and real virtues.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Caesar 
 had provoked his fate, as much by the ostentation of his
 power as by his power itself.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"Caligula and Domitian were assassinated in their palace by
 their own domestics; the convulsions which agitated Rome on
 the death of the former, were confined to the walls of the
 city.","('Caligula', 'PERSON'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
Character and policy of Augustus.,"('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
Character and reign of Pius.,"('Pius', 'PERSON')"
"Deserted
 by the people, and threatened by a military force, that
 feeble assembly was compelled to ratify the choice of the
 Praetorians, and to embrace the benefit of an amnesty, which
 Claudius had the prudence to offer, and the generosity to
 observe  (28).","('Praetorians', 'NORP'), ('Claudius', 'PERSON'), ('28', 'CARDINAL')"
"During
 four-score years (excepting only the short and doubtful
 respite of Vespasian's reign  (51))","('four-score years', 'DATE'), ('Vespasian', 'ORG'), ('51', 'DATE')"
"During a long period of two hundred and twenty years, from
 the establishment of this artful system to the death of
 Commodus, the dangers inherent to a military government
 were, in a great measure, suspended.","('two hundred and twenty years', 'DATE'), ('Commodus', 'EVENT')"
"Even the character of Caesar or
 Augustus were far superior to those of the popular deities.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"Every barrier of the Roman constitution had been levelled by
 the vast ambition of the dictator; every fence had been
 extirpated by the cruel hand of the Triumvir.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Triumvir', 'PERSON')"
"Excepting only this short, though
 violent, eruption of military licence, the two centuries
 from Augustus to Commodus passed away unstained with civil
 blood, and undisturbed by revolutions.","('the two centuries', 'DATE'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Commodus', 'NORP')"
"From Grecian philosophy they had imbibed the justest
 and most liberal notions of the dignity of human nature, and
 the origin of civil society.","('Grecian', 'NORP')"
"From these causes were derived,
 1 The exquisite sensibility of the sufferers; and, 2, the
 impossibility of escaping from the hand of the oppressor.","('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 'CARDINAL')"
"From what has been already observed in the first chapter of
 this work, some notion may be formed of the armies and
 provinces thus intrusted to the ruling hand of Augustus.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
General idea of the Imperial system.,"('Imperial', 'ORG')"
Hadrian commended the boy to the gratitude of the Antonines.,"('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('Antonines', 'PERSON')"
Happiness of the Romans.,"('Romans', 'NORP')"
"He
 adopted Trajan, then about forty years of age, and who
 commanded a powerful army in the Lower Germany; and
 immediately, by a decree of the senate, declared him his
 colleague and successor in the empire.  (36)","('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('about forty years of age', 'DATE'), ('the Lower Germany', 'GPE')"
"He
 enjoyed with moderation the conveniences of his fortune, and
 the innocent pleasures of society:  (44) and the benevolence of 
 his soul displayed itself in a cheerful serenity of temper.","('44', 'CARDINAL')"
He left only one son.,"('only one', 'CARDINAL')"
"He regretted that
 Avidius Cassius, who excited a rebellion in Syria, had
 disappointed him, by a voluntary death, of the pleasure of
 converting an enemy into a friend; and he justified the
 sincerity of that sentiment, by moderating the zeal of the
 senate against the adherents of the traitor.  (48)","('Avidius Cassius', 'PERSON'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('48', 'CARDINAL')"
"He was adopted by Pius; and, on the accession of Marcus, was
 invested with an equal share of sovereign power.","('Pius', 'PERSON'), ('Marcus', 'PERSON')"
"He was elected censor; and, in
 concert with his faithful Agrippa, he examined the list of
 the senators, expelled a few members, whose vices or whose
 obstinacy required a public example, persuaded near two
 hundred to prevent the shame of an expulsion by a voluntary
 retreat, raised the qualification of a senator to about ten
 thousand pounds, created a sufficient number of Patrician
 families, and accepted for himself the honourable title of
 Prince of the Senate, which had always been bestowed, by the
 censors, on the citizen the most eminent for his honours and
 services.","('Agrippa', 'PERSON'), ('near two\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('about ten\r\n thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('Patrician', 'NORP'), ('Senate', 'ORG')"
"His
 mild disposition was respected by the good; but the
 degenerate Romans required a more vigorous character, whose
 justice should strike terror into the guilty.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"His
 virtues, and even his vices, were artificial; and according
 to the various dictates of his interest, he was at first the
 enemy, and at last the father, of the Roman world.  (26)","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('26', 'CARDINAL')"
"His command, indeed,
 was confined to those citizens who were engaged in the
 service by the military oath; but such was the propensity of
 the Romans to servitude, that the oath was voluntarily taken
 by the magistrates, the senators, and the equestrian order,
 till the homage of flattery was insensibly converted into an
 annual and solemn protestation of fidelity.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"His discerning eye easily discovered a senator about
 fifty years of age, blameless in all the offices of life,
 and a youth of about seventeen, whose riper years opened the
 fair prospect of every virtue: the elder of these was
 declared the son and successor of Hadrian, on condition,
 however, that he himself should immediately adopt the
 younger.","('about\r\n fifty years of age', 'DATE'), ('about seventeen', 'CARDINAL'), ('years', 'DATE'), ('Hadrian', 'PERSON')"
"His memory was revered by a grateful posterity, and above a
 century after his death, many persons preserved the image of
 Marcus Antoninus, among those of their household gods.  (49)","('a\r\n century', 'DATE'), ('Marcus Antoninus', 'PERSON')"
I. The death of Caesar was ever before his eyes.,"('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"I. When Persia was governed by the descendants of Sefi, a
 race of princes whose wanton cruelty often stained their
 divan, their table, and their bed, with the blood of their
 favourites, there is a saying recorded of a young nobleman,
 that he never departed from the sultan's presence without
 satisfying himself whether his head was still on his
 shoulders.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Sefi', 'PERSON')"
"If a man were called to fix the period in the history of the
 world, during which the condition of the human race was most
 happy and prosperous, he would, without hesitation, name
 that which elapsed from the death of Domitian to the
 accession of Commodus.","('Domitian', 'PERSON'), ('Commodus', 'NORP')"
"In his last moments, the arts of the empress Plotina
 either fixed the irresolution of Trajan, or boldly supposed
 a fictitious adoption;  (38) the truth of which could not be 
 safely disputed, and Hadrian was peaceably acknowledged as
 his lawful successor.","('Plotina', 'PERSON'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('38', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hadrian', 'PERSON')"
"In return for this imaginary concession, Augustus obtained
 an important privilege, which rendered him master of Rome
 and Italy.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"In the
 space of eighteen months, four princes perished by the
 sword; and the Roman world was shaken by the fury of the
 contending armies.","('the\r\n space of eighteen months', 'DATE'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the 
 election of these magistrates, the people, during the reign
 of Augustus, were permitted to expose all the inconveniences
 of a wild democracy.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"In the consideration of the Imperial government, we have
 frequently mentioned the artful founder, under his
 well-known title of Augustus, which was not however
 conferred upon him till the edifice was almost completed.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"In the division of the provinces, Augustus
 provided for his own power, and for the dignity of the
 republic.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"Instead
 of listening to such unworthy suspicions, the prudent
 monarch associated Titus to the full powers of the Imperial
 dignity and the grateful son ever approved himself the
 humble and faithful minister of so indulgent a father.  (33)","('Titus', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"It is almost superfluous to enumerate the
 unworthy successors of Augustus.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"It is sincerely to 
 be lamented, that whilst we are fatigued with the disgustful
 relation of Nero's crimes and follies, we are reduced to
 collect the actions of Trajan from the glimmerings of an
 abridgment, or the doubtful light of a panegyric.","('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON')"
"It was a
 motive of self-preservation, not a principle of liberty,
 that animated the conspirators against Caligula, Nero, and
 Domitian.","('Caligula', 'PERSON'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON')"
"It was dangerous to trust the sincerity of
 Augustus; to seem to distrust it was still more dangerous.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"It was easily transferred
 from the kings to the governors of Asia; and the Roman
 magistrates very frequently were adored as provincial
 deities, with the pomp of altars and temples, of festivals
 and sacrifices.  (22)","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was natural that the emperors should 
 not refuse what the proconsuls had accepted; and the divine
 honours which both the one and the other received from the
 provinces, attested rather the despotism than the servitude
 of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"It was not without reluctance and remorse that
 the Praetorian Guards had been persuaded to abandon the
 cause of the tyrant. (34)","('the Praetorian Guards', 'ORG')"
"It was on the dignity of the senate, that Augustus
 and his successors founded their new empire; and they
 affected, on every occasion, to adopt the language and
 principles of Patricians.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Patricians', 'NORP')"
"It was proposed in the senate, to
 dignify their minister with a new appellation: and after a
 very serious discussion, that of Augustus was chosen, among
 several others, as being the most expressive of the
 character of peace and sanctity, which he uniformly
 affected.  (25)","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('25', 'CARDINAL')"
"It would require the pen of Tacitus (if Tacitus had assisted
 at this assembly) to describe the various emotions of the
 senate; those that were suppressed, and those that were
 affected.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
Knowledge and free spirit of the Romans.,"('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Marcus, on the other hand,
 revered the character of his benefactor, loved him as a
 parent, obeyed him as his sovereign,  (43) and, after he was no 
 more, regulated his own administration by the example and
 maxims of his predecessor.","('Marcus', 'PERSON'), ('43', 'DATE')"
"Memory of Tiberius, Caligula, Nero, and Domitian.","('Memory of Tiberius', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Caligula', 'PERSON'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON')"
"Nerva had scarcely accepted the purple from the assassins of
 Domitian before he discovered that his feeble age was unable
 to stem the torrent of public disorders, which had
 multiplied under the long tyranny of his predecessor.","('Nerva', 'PERSON'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON')"
Of Hadrian.,"('Hadrian', 'PERSON')"
Of Marcus.,"('Marcus', 'PERSON')"
Of the Constitution of the Roman Empire in the Age of the Antonines Idea of a monarchy.,"('Constitution', 'LAW'), ('the Roman Empire', 'ORG')"
"On
 his return to Rome, he obtained, by a single act of the
 senate and people, the universal ratification of all his
 proceedings.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"One revolution
 had been purchased by immense rewards; but a second
 revolution might double those rewards.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
Peculiar misery of the Romans under their tyrants.,"('Romans', 'NORP')"
Power of the Roman generals.,"('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Rome groaned beneath an 
 unremitting tyranny, which exterminated the ancient families
 of the republic, and was fatal to almost every virtue, and
 every talent, that arose in that unhappy period.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Rome, Italy, and the internal
 provinces, were subject to the immediate jurisdiction of the
 senate.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Rustan's knowledge,
 if he possessed any, could only serve to confirm his habits
 by prejudices.","('Rustan', 'PERSON')"
Situation of Augustus.,"('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"Such
 princes deserved the honour of restoring the republic had
 the Romans of their days been capable of enjoying a rational
 freedom.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Such
 was their ordinary jurisdiction; but whenever the senate
 empowered the first magistrate to consult the safety of the
 commonwealth, he was raised by that decree above the laws,
 and exercised, in the defence of liberty, a temporary
 despotism  (13).","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('13', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such a prince consulted his true interest
 by the association of a son, whose more splendid and amiable
 character might turn the public attention from the obscure
 origin to the future glories of the Flavian house.","('Flavian', 'NORP')"
"Such was the power over the soldiers, and 
 over the enemies of Rome, which was either granted to, or
 assumed by, the generals of the republic.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"That artful prince, instead of
 discovering the least symptom of impatience, humbly
 solicited their suffrages for himself or his friends, and
 scrupulously practised all the duties of an ordinary
 candidate  (17).","('17', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 door of the assembly had been designedly left open, for a
 mixed multitude of more than a thousand persons, who
 reflected disgrace upon their rank, instead of deriving
 honour from it.  (2)","('more than a thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 illustrious surname of Caesar he had assumed as the adopted
 son of the dictator; but he had too much good sense, either
 to hope to be confounded, or to wish to be compared, with
 that extraordinary man.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"The
 milder temper of his successor declined so dangerous an
 ambition, which was never afterwards revived, except by the
 madness of Caligula and Domitian.","('Caligula', 'PERSON'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON')"
"The 
 most sacred rights of freedom, confirmed by the Porcian and
 Sempronian laws, were suspended by the military engagement.","('Porcian', 'NORP'), ('Sempronian', 'NORP')"
"The Asiatic Greeks were the first inventors, the
 successors of Alexander the first objects, of this servile
 and impious mode of adulation.","('The Asiatic Greeks', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The Imperial lieutenants were of
 consular or praetorian dignity; the legions were commanded
 by senators, and the praefecture of Egypt was the only
 important trust committed to a Roman knight.","('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Koran, and the interpreters of that divine 
 book, inculcated to him, that the sultan was the descendant
 of the prophet, and the vice-regent of heaven; that patience
 was the first virtue of a Mussulman, and unlimited obedience
 the great duty of a subject.","('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Mussulman', 'NORP')"
"The Roman emperors,
 desirous to spare the legions that interval of suspense, and
 the temptation of an irregular choice, invested their
 designed successor with so large a share of present power,
 as should enable him, after their decease, to assume the
 remainder, without suffering the empire to perceive the
Of Tiberius change of masters.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON')"
"The armies were restrained by the firm but
 gentle hand of four successive emperors, whose characters
 and authority commanded involuntary respect.","('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"The birth of Vespasian was mean; his grand-father
 had been a private soldier, his father a petty officer of
 the revenue;  (35) his own merit had raised him, in an advanced 
 age, to the empire; but his merit was rather useful, than
 shining, and his virtues were disgraced by a strict and even
 sordid parsimony.","('Vespasian', 'PERSON'), ('35', 'CARDINAL')"
The caprice of Hadrian influenced his choice of a successor.,"('Hadrian', 'PERSON')"
"The choice of 
 the enemies of Rome was regularly decided by the legislative
 authority.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The conqueror was at the head of forty-four veteran
 legions,  (1) conscious of their own strength, and of the 
 weakness of the constitution, habituated, during twenty
 years civil war, to every act of blood and violence, and
 passionately devoted to the house of Caesar, from whence
 alone they had received, and expected, the most lavish
 rewards.","('forty-four', 'CARDINAL'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"The consuls had succeeded
 to the kings of Rome, and represented the dignity of the
 state.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The dark unrelenting Tiberius, the
 furious Caligula, the feeble Claudius, the profligate and
 cruel Nero, the beastly Vitellius,  (50) and the timid inhuman 
 Domitian, are condemned to everlasting infamy.","('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('Caligula', 'PERSON'), ('Claudius', 'PERSON'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Vitellius', 'PERSON'), ('50', 'DATE'), ('Domitian', 'NORP')"
"The deification of the emperor  (21) is the only instance in 
 which they departed from their accustomed prudence and
 modesty.","('21', 'CARDINAL')"
"The dictator, or
 consul, had a right to command the service of the Roman
 youth; and to punish an obstinate or cowardly disobedience
 by the most severe and ignominious penalties, by striking
 the offender out of the list of citizens, by confiscating
 his property, and by selling his person into slavery.  (7)","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The division of Europe into a number of independent
 states, connected, however, with each other, by the general
 resemblance of religion, language, and manners, is
 productive of the most beneficial consequences to the
 liberty of mankind.","('Europe', 'LOC')"
"The education of Helvidius and Thrasea,
 of Tacitus and Pliny, was the same as that of Cato and
 Cicero.","('Helvidius', 'PERSON'), ('Thrasea', 'PERSON'), ('Tacitus', 'NORP'), ('Pliny', 'PERSON'), ('Cato', 'PERSON'), ('Cicero', 'PERSON')"
"The emperor alone was the general of the republic, and his
 jurisdiction, civil as well as military, extended over all
 the conquests of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The emperor was
 elected by the authority of the senate, and the consent of
 the soldiers.  (30)","('30', 'CARDINAL')"
"The emperors, as the
 first ministers of the republic, were exempted from the
 obligation and penalty of many inconvenient laws: they were
 authorised to convoke the senate, to make several motions in
 the same day, to recommend candidates for the honours of the
 state, to enlarge the bounds of the city, to employ the
 revenue at their discretion, to declare peace and war, to
 ratify treaties; and by a most comprehensive clause, they
 were empowered to execute whatsoever they should judge
 advantageous to the empire, and agreeable to the majesty of
 things private or public, human or divine.  (14)","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the same day', 'DATE')"
"The experience of every day might almost justify
 the scepticism of Rustan.  (52)","('every day', 'DATE'), ('Rustan', 'PERSON'), ('52', 'CARDINAL')"
"The fidelity of the legions might defend his
 authority against open rebellion; but their vigilance could
 not secure his person from the dagger of a determined
 republican; and the Romans, who revered the memory of
 Brutus,  (27) would applaud the imitation of his virtue.","('republican', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Brutus', 'PERSON'), ('27', 'DATE')"
"The former preserves his military command, and guards Rome itself .","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The former should naturally have expired
 with the prince on whom it was bestowed; and however the
 latter was diffused by adoption and female alliance, Nero
 was the last prince who could allege any hereditary claim to
 the honours of the Julian line.","('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The forms of
 the civil administration were carefully preserved by Nerva,
 Trajan, Hadrian, and the Antonines, who delighted in the
 image of liberty, and were pleased with considering
 themselves as the accountable ministers of the laws.","('Nerva', 'PERSON'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('Antonines', 'PERSON')"
"The golden age of Trajan and the Antonines had been preceded
 by an age of iron.","('Trajan', 'PERSON')"
"The good sense of Vespasian engaged him indeed to embrace
 every measure that might confirm his recent and precarious
 elevation.","('Vespasian', 'PERSON')"
"The history of the
 East informed him, that such had ever been the condition of
 mankind.","('East', 'LOC')"
"The history of their own
 country had taught them to revere a free, a virtuous, and a
 victorious commonwealth; to abhor the successful crimes of
 Caesar and Augustus; and inwardly to despise those tyrants
 whom they adored with the most abject flattery.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"The insolence of the armies inspired Augustus with fears
 of a still more alarming nature.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"The legions respected their oath of 
 fidelity; and it requires a minute inspection of the Roman
 annals to discover three inconsiderable rebellions, which
 were all suppressed in a few months, and without even the
 hazard of a battle.  (31)","('a minute', 'TIME'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('a few months', 'DATE'), ('31', 'CARDINAL')"
"The masters of the
 Roman world surrounded their throne with darkness, concealed
 their irresistible strength, and humbly professed themselves
 the accountable ministers of the senate, whose supreme
 decrees they dictated and obeyed.  (19)","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The memory of this comedy, repeated several
 times during the life of Augustus, was preserved to the last
 ages of the empire, by the peculiar pomp with which the
 perpetual monarchs of Rome always solemnised the tenth years
 of their reign.  (6)","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('the tenth years', 'DATE'), ('6', 'CARDINAL')"
"The military force was a
 blind and irresistible instrument of oppression; and the
 corruption of Roman manners would always supply flatterers
 eager to applaud, and ministers prepared to serve the fear
 or the avarice, the lust or the cruelty, of their masters.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The military oath, and the fidelity of the
 troops, had been consecrated by the habits of an hundred
 years, to the name and family of the Caesars; and although
 that family had been continued only by the fictitious rite
 of adoption, the Romans still revered, in the person of
 Nero, the grandson of Germanicus, and the lineal successor
 of Augustus.","('an hundred\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Germanicus', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"The minds of the Romans were very differently prepared for
 slavery.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The monarch's frown, he well knew, could level him
 with the dust; but the stroke of lightning or apoplexy might
 be equally fatal; and it was the part of a wise man to
 forget the inevitable calamities of human life in the
 enjoyment of the fleeting hour.","('the fleeting hour', 'TIME')"
"The names and
 forms of the ancient administration were preserved by
 Augustus with the most anxious care.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"The obscure name of Octavianus he derived from a mean family
 in the little town of Aricia.","('Octavianus', 'PERSON'), ('Aricia', 'GPE')"
"The people of Rome, viewing, with a secret
 pleasure, the humiliation of the aristocracy, demanded only
 bread and public shows; and were supplied with both by the
 liberal hand of Augustus.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"The proconsuls of the senate, particularly those
 of Asia, Greece, and Africa, enjoyed a more honourable
 character than the lieutenants of the emperor, who commanded
 in Gaul or Syria.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Syria', 'GPE')"
The race of Caesars and the Flavian family.,"('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Flavian', 'NORP')"
"The rapid downfall of Galba, Otho, 
 and Vitellius, taught the armies to consider the emperors as
 the creatures of their will, and the instruments of their
 licence.","('Galba', 'GPE'), ('Otho', 'GPE'), ('Vitellius', 'GPE')"
"The reformation of the senate was one of the first steps in
 which Augustus laid aside the tyrant, and professed himself
 the father of his country.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"The republicans of spirit and ability had
 perished in the field of battle, or in the proscription.","('republicans', 'NORP')"
"The respective advantages of monarchy and a republic have
 often divided speculative inquirers; the present greatness
 of the Roman state, the corruption of manners, and the
 licence of the soldiers, supplied new arguments to the
 advocates of monarchy; and these general views of government
 were again warped by the hopes and fears of each individual.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The rich and polite Italians, who
 had almost universally embraced the philosophy of Epicurus,
 enjoyed the present blessings of ease and tranquillity, and
 suffered not the pleasing dream to be interrupted by the
 memory of their old tumultuous freedom.","('Italians', 'NORP'), ('Epicurus', 'PERSON')"
"The sacred title of Augustus was always reserved
 for the monarch, whilst the name of Caesar was more freely
 communicated to his relations; and, from the reign of
 Hadrian, at least, was appropriated to the second person in
 the state, who was considered as the presumptive heir of the
 empire.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"The senate doubted whether they should pronounce him a god
 or a tyrant; and the honours decreed to his memory were
 granted to the prayers of the pious Antoninus.  (39)","('Antoninus', 'PERSON'), ('39', 'CARDINAL')"
"The servile judges professed to 
 assert the majesty of the commonwealth, violated in the
 person of its first magistrate;  (56) whose clemency they most 
 applauded when they trembled the most at his inexorable and
 impending cruelty  (57)","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('56', 'CARDINAL')"
"The slave
 of Imperial despotism, whether he was condemned to drag his
 gilded chain in Rome and the senate, or to wear out a life
 of exile on the barren rock of Seriphus, or the frozen banks
 of the Danube, expected his fate in silent despair.  (58)","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Seriphus', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('58', 'CARDINAL')"
"The stupid Claudius, brother
 of Germanicus, was already in their camp, invested with the
 Imperial purple, and prepared to support his election by
 arms.","('Claudius', 'PERSON'), ('Germanicus', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The tender respect of Augustus for a free constitution which
 he had destroyed, can only be explained by an attentive
 consideration of the character of that subtle tyrant.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"The title of king had armed the
 Romans against his life.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The troops professed
 the fondest attachment to the house of Caesar; but the
 attachments of the multitude are capricious and inconstant.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"The two Antonines (for it is of them that we are
 now speaking) governed the Roman world forty-two years, with
 the same invariable spirit of wisdom and virtue.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antonines', 'PRODUCT'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('forty-two years', 'DATE')"
"The usual number of
 consuls, praetors, tribunes,  (15) were annually invested with 
 their respective ensigns of office, and continued to
 discharge some of their least important functions.","('15', 'CARDINAL')"
"The vast extent of the Roman empire
 was governed by absolute power, under the guidance of virtue
 and wisdom.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The virtue of Marcus Aurelius Antoninus was of a severer and
 more laborious kind.","('Marcus Aurelius Antoninus', 'PERSON')"
"Their authority expired with the year in which
 they were elected; the former office was divided between
 two, the latter among ten persons; and, as both in their
 private and public interest they were averse to each other,
 their mutual conflicts contributed, for the most part, to
 strengthen rather than to destroy the balance of the
 constitution.","('the year', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL')"
"Their family, however numerous or
 splendid, was composed entirely of their domestic slaves and
 freedmen.  (20)","('20', 'CARDINAL')"
"Their regular meetings were held
 on three stated days in every month, the Calends, the Nones,
 and the Ides.","('three stated days', 'DATE'), ('every month', 'DATE'), ('Calends', 'ORG'), ('Nones', 'ORG'), ('Ides', 'PERSON')"
"There
 remains, however, one panegyric far removed beyond the
 suspicion of flattery.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"There appears, indeed, one memorable occasion, in which the
 senate, after seventy years of patience, made an ineffectual
 attempt to reassume its long-forgotten rights.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('seventy years', 'DATE')"
"These gloomy apprehensions had been already justified by the
 experience of the Romans.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"They refused to accept
 the resignation of Augustus; they conjured him not to desert
 the republic, which he had saved.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"Those
 honours still attracted the vain ambition of the Romans; and
 the emperors themselves, though invested for life with the
 powers of the consulship, frequently aspired to the title of
 that annual dignity, which they condescended to share with
 the most illustrious of their fellow-citizens.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Thus 
Of Titus Vespasian subdued the generous mind of his eldest son.","('Titus Vespasian', 'PERSON')"
"Thus Augustus, after all his fairer  prospects had been snatched from him by untimely deaths rested his last hopes on Tiberius, obtained for his adopted
 son the censorial and tribunitian powers, and dictated a law
 by which the future prince was invested with an authority
 equal to his own, over the provinces and the armies.  (32)","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON')"
"Tiberius, and those emperors who
 adopted his maxims, attempted to disguise their murders by
 the formalities of justice, and perhaps enjoyed a secret
 pleasure in rendering the senate their accomplice as well as
 their victim.","('Tiberius', 'PERSON')"
Titles of Augustus and Caesar.,"('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"Titus  was adored by the eastern legions, which, under his command, had recently achieved the conquest of Judaea.","('Titus', 'PERSON'), ('Judaea', 'PERSON')"
"Titus Antoninus Pius has been justly denominated a second
 Numa.","('Titus Antoninus Pius', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"To resume, in a few words, the system of the Imperial
 government, as it was instituted by Augustus, and maintained
 by those princes who understood their own interest and that
 of the people, it may be defined an absolute monarchy
 disguised by the forms of a commonwealth.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"To these accumulated honours, the policy of Augustus soon
 added the splendid as well as important dignities of supreme
 pontiff, and of censor.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"Under the
 mild administration of Titus, the Roman world enjoyed a
 transient felicity, and his beloved memory served to
 protect, above fifteen years, the vices of his brother
 Domitian.","('Titus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('fifteen years', 'DATE'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON')"
"Under the reign of these monsters the slavery of the Romans
 was accompanied with two peculiar circumstances, the one
 occasioned by their former liberty, the other by their
 extensive conquests, which rendered their condition more
 completely wretched than that of the victims of tyranny in
 any other age or country.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"War he 
 detested, as the disgrace and calamity of human nature; but
 when the necessity of a just defence called upon him to take
 up arms, he readily exposed his person to eight winter
 campaigns on the frozen banks of the Danube, the severity of
 which was at last fatal to the weakness of his constitution.","('eight winter', 'DATE'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"We may readily believe, that the father of his country
 hesitated whether he ought to intrust the various and
 doubtful character of his kinsman Hadrian with sovereign
 power.","('Hadrian', 'PERSON')"
"We should disgrace the
 virtues of the Antonines, by comparing them with the vices
 of Hercules or Jupiter.","('Antonines', 'PERSON'), ('Hercules', 'PRODUCT'), ('Jupiter', 'LOC')"
"When 
 he framed the artful system of the Imperial authority his
 moderation was inspired by his fears.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"When Pompey commanded in the East, he rewarded his soldiers
 and allies, dethroned princes, divided kingdoms, founded
 colonies, and distributed the treasures of Mithridates.","('Pompey', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Mithridates', 'NORP')"
"When all the various powers of executive government were
 committed to the Imperial magistrate, the ordinary
 magistrates of the commonwealth languished in obscurity,
 without vigour, and almost without business.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"When the
 throne was vacant by the murder of Caligula, the consuls
 convoked that assembly in the Capitol, condemned the memory
 of the Caesars, gave the watchword liberty to the few
 cohorts who faintly adhered to their standard, and during
 eight and forty hours acted as the independent chiefs of a
 free commonwealth.","('Caligula', 'PERSON'), ('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('Caesars', 'PERSON'), ('eight and forty hours', 'TIME')"
"With regard to civil objects, it was the supreme
 court of appeal; with regard to criminal matters, a tribunal
 constituted for the trial of all offences that were
 committed by men in any public station, or that affected the
 peace and majesty of the Roman people.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"With regard to the
 soldiers, the jealousy of freedom had, even from the
 earliest ages of Rome, given way to the hopes of conquest,
 and a just sense of military discipline.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"With the
 same hand, and probably with the same temper, he signed the
 proscription of Cicero, and the pardon of Cinna.","('Cicero', 'PERSON'), ('Cinna', 'PERSON')"
"With this view, he permitted the senate to
 confer upon him, for his life, the powers of the consular  (11) 
 and tribunitian offices,  (12) which were, in the same manner, 
 continued to all his successors.","('11', 'CARDINAL'), ('12', 'CARDINAL')"
"Within six days after Augustus had been compelled to accept
 so very liberal a grant, he resolved to gratify the pride of
 the senate by an easy sacrifice.","('six days', 'DATE'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"Without any violation of the principles of the constitution,
 the general of the Roman armies might receive and exercise
 an authority almost despotic over the soldiers, the enemies,
 and the subjects of the republic.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Yet in the first days of his reign, he put to
 death four consular senators, his personal enemies and men
 who had been judged worthy of empire; and the tediousness of
 a painful illness rendered him, at last, peevish and cruel.","('the first days', 'DATE'), ('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"Yet the fatal sword, suspended 
 above him by a single thread, seems not to have disturbed
 the slumbers, or interrupted the tranquillity, of the
 Persian.","('Persian', 'NORP')"
