Sentence,Entities
"""It is your own,""  replied a Greek attendant, who watched the motions of his soul; and Bohemond, after some hesitation,
 condescended to accept this magnificent present.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON')"
"(11) Philip the First was the great-grandson of Hugh Capet, the founder of the present race, who, in the decline of Charlemagne's posterity, added the regal title to his patrimonial estates of Paris and Orleans.","('Philip', 'PERSON'), ('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Hugh Capet', 'PERSON'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Orleans', 'GPE')"
(33),"('33', 'CARDINAL')"
(41),"('41', 'CARDINAL')"
(6),"('6', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 mercantile, rather than a martial, spirit prevailed among
 his provincials, (51) a common name, which included the natives of Auvergne and Languedoc, (52) the vassals of the kingdom of Burgundy or Arles.","('51', 'CARDINAL'), ('Auvergne', 'LOC'), ('Languedoc', 'GPE'), ('52', 'CARDINAL'), ('Burgundy', 'GPE'), ('Arles', 'GPE')"
"A
 remnant was saved by the firmness of their bishops, who
 accepted a feigned and transient conversion; but the more
 obstinate Jews opposed their fanaticism to the fanaticism of
 the Christians, barricaded their houses, and precipitating
 themselves, their families, and their wealth, into the
 rivers or the flames, disappointed the malice, or at least
 the avarice, of their implacable foes.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"A Norman clerk presumed to sift, with a philosophic spirit, the truth of the legend, the circumstances of the discovery, and the character of the prophet; and the pious Bohemond ascribed their deliverance to the merits and intercession of Christ alone.","('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON')"
"A bloody
 sacrifice was offered by his mistaken votaries to the God of
 the Christians: resistance might provoke but neither age nor
 sex could mollify, their implacable rage: they indulged
 themselves three days in a promiscuous massacre; (110) and
 the infection of the dead bodies produced an epidemical
 disease.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('three days', 'DATE'), ('110', 'CARDINAL')"
"A debt of
 three hundred years, or twelve hundred pounds, was enough to
 impoverish a plentiful fortune; the scarcity of gold and
 silver was supplied by the alienation of land; and the
 princely donations of Pepin and Charlemagne are expressly
 given for the remedy of their soul.","('three hundred years', 'DATE'), ('twelve hundred pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('Pepin', 'PERSON'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON')"
"A latent motive of affection or vanity might influence the choice of Urban: he was himself a native of France, a monk of Clugny, and the first of his countrymen who ascended the throne of St. Peter.","('Urban', 'PERSON'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Clugny', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE')"
"A literal accomplishment of
 penance was indeed impracticable: the guilt of adultery was
 multiplied by daily repetition; that of homicide might
 involve the massacre of a whole people; each act was
 separately numbered; and, in those times of anarchy and
 vice, a modest sinner might easily incur a debt of three
 hundred years.","('three\r\n hundred years', 'DATE')"
"A part of the infantry might be enrolled for the service of scouts, pioneers, and archers; but the promiscuous crowd were lost in their own disorder; and we depend not on the eyes and knowledge, but
 on the belief and fancy, of a chaplain of Count Baldwin, (74)
 in the estimate of six hundred thousand pilgrims able to
 bear arms, besides the priests and monks, the women and
 children of the Latin camp.","('Count Baldwin', 'PERSON'), ('74', 'CARDINAL'), ('six hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"A pernicious tenet has been imputed to the Mahometans, the
 duty of extirpating all other religions by the sword.","('Mahometans', 'NORP')"
"A pile of dry faggots, four feet high and fourteen long, was erected in the midst of the camp; the flames burnt fiercely to the elevation of thirty cubits; and a narrow path of twelve inches was left for the perilous trial.","('four feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('fourteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirty cubits', 'QUANTITY'), ('twelve inches', 'QUANTITY')"
"A private letter of Stephen of Chartres attests his admiration of the emperor, the most excellent and liberal of men, who taught him to believe that he was a favourite, and promised to educate and
 establish his youngest son.","('Stephen of Chartres', 'PERSON')"
"A repetition of the old complaint of
 famine may be imputed in some degree to the voracious or
 disorderly appetite of the Franks; but the stony soil of
 Jerusalem is almost destitute of water; the scanty springs
 and hasty torrents were dry in the summer season; nor was
 the thirst of the besiegers relieved, as in the city, by the
 artificial supply of cisterns and aqueducts.","('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
"A scanty
 supply of provisions was rudely demanded, forcibly seized,
 and greedily consumed; and on the first quarrel, the
 crusaders gave a loose to indignation and revenge.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"A secret correspondence, for their
 mutual interest, was soon established between Phirouz and
 the prince of Tarento; and Bohemond declared in the council
 of the chiefs, that he could deliver the city into their
 hands.","('Phirouz', 'PERSON'), ('Tarento', 'PERSON'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON')"
"A session of eight days produced some useful or edifying canons for the reformation of manners; a severe censure was pronounced against the license of private war; the Truce of God (16) was confirmed, a suspension of hostilities during four days of the week; women and priests were placed under the safeguard of the church; and a protection of three years was extended to husbandmen and merchants, the defenceless victims of military rapine.","('eight days', 'DATE'), ('16', 'CARDINAL'), ('four days of the week', 'DATE'), ('three years', 'DATE')"
"A single knight could impart, according to his
 judgment, the character which he received; and the warlike
 sovereigns of Europe derived more glory from this personal
 distinction than from the lustre of their diadem.","('Europe', 'LOC')"
"A small remnant of the pilgrims, who passed the Bosphorus,
 was permitted to visit the holy sepulchre.","('Bosphorus', 'LOC')"
"A third court was
 instituted for their use, of limited and domestic
 jurisdiction: the sworn members were Syrians, in blood,
 language, and religion; but the office of the president (in
 Arabic, of the rais) was sometimes exercised by the viscount
 of the city.","('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Syrians', 'NORP'), ('Arabic', 'LANGUAGE')"
"About a third of the
 naked fugitives (and the hermit Peter was of the number)
 escaped to the Thracian mountains; and the emperor, who
 respected the pilgrimage and succour of the Latins, conducted
 them by secure and easy journeys to Constantinople, and
 advised them to await the arrival of their brethren.","('About a third', 'CARDINAL'), ('Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Thracian', 'NORP'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"About twenty years after the conquest of Jerusalem by the Turks, the holy sepulchre was visited by Peter the Hermit.","('About twenty years', 'DATE'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Peter the Hermit', 'PERSON')"
"Above four
 hundred years before the first crusade, the eastern and
 western provinces of the Roman empire had been acquired
 about the same time, and in the same manner, by the
 Barbarians of Germany and Arabia.","('four\r\n hundred years', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Arabia', 'GPE')"
"Abroad in enterprise and pilgrimage, at home
 in martial exercise, the warriors of every country were
 perpetually associated; and impartial taste must prefer a
 Gothic tournament to the Olympic games of classic antiquity.
 (57)","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Olympic', 'EVENT'), ('57', 'CARDINAL')"
"According to the
 feudal jurisprudence, the principal states and subordinate
 baronies descended in the line of male and female
 succession: (123) but the children of the first conquerors,
 (124) a motley and degenerate race, were dissolved by the
 luxury of the climate; the arrival of new crusaders from
 Europe was a doubtful hope and a casual event.","('123', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('124', 'CARDINAL'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"Adhemar, bishop of Puy,
 who excelled both in council and action, had been swept away
 in the last plague at Antioch: the remaining ecclesiastics
 preserved only the pride and avarice of their character; and
 their seditious clamours had required that the choice of a
 bishop should precede that of a king.","('Adhemar', 'PERSON'), ('Puy', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"After a long march and painful abstinence,
 the troops of Godfrey encamped in the plains of Thrace; they
 heard with indignation, that their brother, the count of
 Vermandois, was imprisoned by the Greeks; and their
 reluctant duke was compelled to indulge them in some freedom
 of retaliation and rapine.","('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Vermandois', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"After an easy and pleasant journey
 through Lombardy, from Turin to Aquileia, Raymond and his
 provincials marched forty days through the savage country of
 Dalmatia (59) and Sclavonia.","('Lombardy', 'GPE'), ('Turin', 'GPE'), ('Aquileia', 'GPE'), ('Raymond', 'PERSON'), ('forty days', 'DATE'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('59', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sclavonia', 'PERSON')"
"After seventy thousand Moslems had been put to the
 sword, and the harmless Jews had been burnt in their
 synagogue, they could still reserve a multitude of captives,
 whom interest or lassitude persuaded them to spare.","('seventy thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moslems', 'NORP'), ('Jews', 'NORP')"
"After suspending before the holy sepulchre the sword
 and standard of the sultan, the new king (he deserves the
 title) embraced his departing companions, and could retain
 only with the gallant Tancred three hundred knights, and two
 thousand foot-soldiers for the defence of Palestine.","('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('two\r\n thousand foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('Palestine', 'GPE')"
"After the confession and absolution of their sins, the champions of the cross were dismissed with a superfluous admonition to invite their countrymen and friends; and their departure for the Holy Land was fixed to the festival of the Assumption, the fifteenth of August, of the ensuing year. (19)
Justice of the crusades?","('the Holy Land', 'GPE'), ('the Assumption', 'EVENT'), ('the fifteenth of August', 'DATE'), ('the ensuing year', 'DATE'), ('19', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the reduction of the maritime cities of Laodicea,
 Tripoli, Tyre, and Ascalon, (120) which were powerfully
 assisted by the fleets of Venice, Genoa, and Pisa, and even
 of Flanders and Norway, (121) the range of sea-coast from
 Scanderoon to the borders of Egypt was possessed by the
 Christian pilgrims.","('Laodicea', 'GPE'), ('Tripoli', 'GPE'), ('Tyre', 'GPE'), ('Ascalon', 'GPE'), ('120', 'CARDINAL'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('Genoa', 'GPE'), ('Pisa', 'GPE'), ('Flanders', 'GPE'), ('Norway', 'GPE'), ('121', 'CARDINAL'), ('Scanderoon', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"Against the private wars of the Barbarians, their bloody
 tournaments, licentious love, and judicial duels, the popes
 and synods might ineffectually thunder.","('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"Aladin, or Iftikhar, the
 caliph's lieutenant, was entrusted with the defence: his
 policy strove to restrain the native Christians by the dread
 of their own ruin and that of the holy sepulchre; to animate
 the Moslems by the assurance of temporal and eternal
 rewards.","('Aladin', 'PERSON'), ('Iftikhar', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Moslems', 'NORP')"
Alexius dismissed the challenger with some prudent advice for his conduct in the Turkish warfare; and history repeats with pleasure this lively example of the manners of his age and country.,"('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('Turkish', 'NORP')"
"Alexius esteemed his virtues, deservedly
 named him the champion of the empire, and dignified his
 homage with the filial name and the rights of adoption. (67)","('Alexius', 'PERSON')"
"Amidst the slaves of Asia,
 unconscious of the lesson or example, a model of political
 liberty was introduced; and the laws of the French kingdom
 are derived from the purest source of equality and justice.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('French', 'NORP')"
"Among the Turks and Saracens, the idolaters of
 Europe were rendered more odious by the name and reputation
 of Cannibals; the spies, who introduced themselves into the
 kitchen of Bohemond, were shown several human bodies turning
 on the spit: and the artful Norman encouraged a report,
 which increased at the same time the abhorrence and the
 terror of the infidels. (79)
Siege of Nice, A.D. 1097,May 14-June 20.","('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Cannibals', 'NORP'), ('Bohemond', 'GPE'), ('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 1097', 'DATE'), ('May 14-June 20', 'DATE')"
"Among the causes which enfranchised the plebeians from the
 yoke of feudal tyranny, the institution of cities and
 corporations is one of the most powerful; and if those of
 Palestine are coeval with the first crusade, they may be
 ranked with the most ancient of the Latin world.","('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"Among the chiefs, three
 heroes may be found without fear or reproach: Godfrey of
 Bouillon was supported by his magnanimous piety; Bohemond by
 ambition and interest; and Tancred declared, in the true
 spirit of chivalry, that as long as he was at the head of
 forty knights, he would never relinquish the enterprise of
 Palestine.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Bouillon', 'PERSON'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON'), ('Tancred', 'PERSON'), ('forty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Palestine', 'GPE')"
"An intercourse of epistles
 and embassies, which rose and fell with the events of war,
 was maintained between the throne of Cairo and the camp of
 the Latins; and their adverse pride was the result of
 ignorance and enthusiasm.","('Cairo', 'GPE'), ('Latins', 'NORP')"
"Another Robert was
 count of Flanders, a royal province, which, in this century,
 gave three queens to the thrones of France, England, and
 Denmark: he was surnamed the Sword and Lance of the
 Christians; but in the exploits of a soldier he sometimes
 forgot the duties of a general.","('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Flanders', 'GPE'), ('this century', 'DATE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('Denmark', 'GPE'), ('Lance', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Another class of subjects, the Syrians, (142)
 or Oriental Christians, were oppressed by the zeal of the
 clergy, and protected by the toleration of the state.","('Syrians', 'NORP'), ('142', 'CARDINAL'), ('Oriental Christians', 'NORP')"
"As Robert of
 Normandy rode against his antagonist,  and that head was instantly cloven to the breast by the resistless stroke of his descending falchion.","('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Normandy', 'GPE')"
"As long as the horses were
 fresh, and the quivers full, Soliman maintained the
 advantage of the day; and four thousand Christians were
 pierced by the Turkish arrows.","('Soliman', 'PERSON'), ('four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Turkish', 'NORP')"
"As the manners of the Christians were relaxed, their
 discipline of penance (22) was enforced; and with the
 multiplication of sins, the remedies were multiplied.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"As the pilgrims
 passed over a desert, where a draught of water is exchanged
 for silver, they were tormented by intolerable thirst; and
 on the banks of the first rivulet, their haste and
 intemperance were still more pernicious to the disorderly
 throng.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Ascanius, which stretches several
 miles to the westward of the city.","('Ascanius', 'GPE'), ('several\r\n miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"At
 the voice of their pastor, the robber, the incendiary, the
 homicide, arose by thousands to redeem their souls, by
 repeating on the infidels the same deeds which they had
 exercised against their Christian brethren; and the terms of
 atonement were eagerly embraced by offenders of every rank
 and denomination.","('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"At Clermont, in the territories of the count of Auvergne, (13) the pope might brave with impunity the resentment of Philip; and the council which he convened in that city was not less numerous or respectable than the synod of Placentia. (14)","('Clermont', 'GPE'), ('Auvergne', 'LOC'), ('13', 'CARDINAL'), ('Philip', 'PERSON'), ('Placentia', 'PERSON'), ('14', 'CARDINAL')"
"At Verdun,
 Treves, Mentz, Spires, Worms, many thousands of that unhappy
 people were pillaged and massacred: (37) nor had they felt a
 more bloody stroke since the persecution of Hadrian.","('Verdun', 'FAC'), ('Treves', 'FAC'), ('Mentz', 'GPE'), ('Spires', 'FAC'), ('many thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('37', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hadrian', 'PERSON')"
"At an immeasurable distance below the nobles, the burgesses, and the strangers, the Assise of Jerusalem condescends to mention the villains and slaves, the peasants of the land and the captives of war, who were almost equally considered as the objects of property.","('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
"At the end of seven
 months, after the ruin of their cavalry, and an enormous
 loss by famine, desertion and fatigue, the progress of the
 crusaders was imperceptible, and their success remote, if
 the Latin Ulysses, the artful and ambitious Bohemond, had
 not employed the arms of cunning and deceit.","('the end of seven\r\n months', 'DATE'), ('the Latin Ulysses', 'LOC'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON')"
"At the head of a hundred thousand men, he declared that he was the soldier and servant of Christ alone, and that the Greek might be satisfied with an equal treaty of alliance and friendship.","('a hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"At the head of the Turkish emirs,
 Baghisian, a veteran chief, commanded in the place: his
 garrison was composed of six or seven thousand horse, and
 fifteen or twenty thousand foot: one hundred thousand
 Moslems are said to have fallen by the sword; and their
 numbers were probably inferior to the Greeks, Armenians, and
 Syrians, who had been no more than fourteen years the slaves
 of the house of Seljuk.","('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Baghisian', 'PERSON'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty thousand foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('one hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moslems', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Armenians', 'NORP'), ('Syrians', 'NORP'), ('no more than fourteen years', 'DATE'), ('Seljuk', 'PERSON')"
"At the sad tale of the misery and perils of their Eastern brethren, the assembly burst into tears; the most eager champions declared their readiness to march; and the Greek ambassadors were dismissed with the assurance of a speedy and powerful succour.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"Baldwin accepted the character of his son and champion: but
 no sooner was he introduced into the city, than he inflamed
 the people to the massacre of his father, occupied the
 throne and treasure, extended his conquests over the hills
 of Armenia and the plain of Mesopotamia, and founded the
 first principality of the Franks or Latins, which subsisted
 fifty-four years beyond the Euphrates. (89)
Seige of Antioch, A.D. 1097, October 21- A.D. 1098, June 3..","('Baldwin', 'PERSON'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Mesopotamia', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('fifty-four years', 'DATE'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Seige', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('1097', 'CARDINAL'), ('October 21- A.D. 1098', 'DATE'), ('June 3', 'DATE')"
"Baldwin founds the principality of Edessa, A.D. 1097-1151.","('Baldwin', 'PERSON'), ('Edessa', 'GPE'), ('1097-1151', 'DATE')"
"Baldwin was
 established at Edessa, and Bohemond at Antioch; and two
 Roberts, the duke of Normandy (114) and the count of
 Flanders, preferred their fair inheritance in the West to a
 doubtful competition or a barren sceptre.","('Baldwin', 'PERSON'), ('Edessa', 'ORG'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roberts', 'PERSON'), ('Normandy', 'GPE'), ('114', 'CARDINAL'), ('Flanders', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"Bareheaded and barefoot, with
 contrite hearts, and in an humble posture, they ascended the
 hill of Calvary, amidst the loud anthems of the clergy;
 kissed the stone which had covered the Saviour of the world;
 and bedewed with tears of joy and penitence the monument of
 their redemption.","('Calvary', 'GPE')"
"Battle of Ascalon, A.D. 1099, August 12.","('Ascalon', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1099', 'DATE'), ('August 12', 'DATE')"
"Battle of Dorylaeum, A.D. 1097, July 4.
 Soliman was rather provoked than dismayed by the loss of his
 capital: he admonished his subjects and allies of this
 strange invasion of the Western Barbarians; the Turkish
 emirs obeyed the call of loyalty or religion; the Turkman
 hordes encamped round his standard; and his whole force is
 loosely stated by the Christians at two hundred, or even
 three hundred and sixty thousand horse.","('Dorylaeum', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1097', 'DATE'), ('July 4', 'DATE'), ('Soliman', 'PERSON'), ('the Western Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Turkman', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('two hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('three hundred and sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Before the Franks could enter Syria, the summer, and even
 the autumn, were completely wasted: the siege of Antioch, or
 the separation and repose of the army during the winter
 season, was strongly debated in their council: the love of
 arms and the holy sepulchre urged them to advance; and
 reason perhaps was on the side of resolution, since every
 hour of delay abates the fame and force of the invader, and
 multiplies the resources of defensive war.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('the winter\r\n season', 'DATE'), ('every\r\n hour', 'TIME')"
"Before this city, the French princes
 occupied their stations, and prosecuted their attacks
 without correspondence or subordination: emulation prompted
 their valour; but their valour was sullied by cruelty, and
 their emulation degenerated into envy and civil discord.","('French', 'NORP')"
"Besides a nameless and
 unaccounted multitude, three thousand Pagan knights were
 slain in the battle and pursuit; the camp of Soliman was
 pillaged; and in the variety of precious spoil, the
 curiosity of the Latins was amused with foreign arms and
 apparel, and the new aspect of dromedaries and camels.","('three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('Soliman', 'GPE'), ('Latins', 'NORP')"
"Besides an
 honest sympathy for their brethren, the Latins had a right
 and interest in the support of Constantinople, the most
 important barrier of the West; and the privilege of defence
 must reach to prevent, as well as to repel, an impending
 assault.","('Latins', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"Besides his court and council of Roman cardinals, he was supported by thirteen archbishops and two hundred and
 twenty-five bishops: the number of mitred prelates was computed at four hundred; and the fathers of the church were blessed by the saints and enlightened by the doctors of the age.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('thirteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('two hundred and\r\n twenty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('four hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"Between the age of Charlemagne and that of the crusades, a
 revolution had taken place among the Spaniards, the Normans,
 and the French, which was gradually extended to the rest of
 Europe.","('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Spaniards', 'NORP'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"Between the frontiers of Austria and the seat of the Byzantine monarchy, the crusaders were compelled to traverse an interval of six hundred miles; the wild and desolate
 countries of Hungary (38) and Bulgaria.","('Austria', 'GPE'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('six hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('38', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bulgaria', 'GPE')"
Bohemond and Tancred.,"('Bohemond', 'PERSON'), ('Tancred', 'PERSON')"
"Bohemond had arms and vessels, and foresight and
 discipline; and his name was not forgotten in the provinces
 of Epirus and Thessaly.","('Bohemond', 'PERSON'), ('Epirus', 'GPE'), ('Thessaly', 'GPE')"
"Both nations had imbibed the rudiments of
 Christianity; the Hungarians were ruled by their native
 princes; the Bulgarians by a lieutenant of the Greek
 emperor; but, on the slightest provocation, their ferocious
 nature was rekindled, and ample provocation was afforded by
 the disorders of the first pilgrims Agriculture must have
 been unskilful and languid among a people, whose cities were
 built of reeds and timber, which were deserted in the summer
 season for the tents of hunters and shepherds.","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Hungarians', 'NORP'), ('Bulgarians', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the summer\r\n season', 'DATE')"
"But a law, however venerable be the sanction, cannot suddenly transform the temper of the times; and the benevolent efforts of Urban deserve the less praise, since he labored to appease some domestic quarrels that he might spread the flames of war from the Atlantic to the Euphrates.","('Urban', 'NORP'), ('Atlantic', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"But an
 incurable jealousy still rankled in the minds of the two
 nations, who despised each other as slaves and Barbarians.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"But at the time of the crusade, the inheritance
 of Malek Shaw was disputed by his four sons; their private
 ambition was insensible of the public danger; and, in the
 vicissitudes of their fortune, the royal vassals were
 ignorant, or regardless, of the true object of their
 allegiance.","('Malek Shaw', 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"But he claimed the sovereignty of Antioch as the reward of his service; and the proposal which had been rejected by the envy, was at length extorted from the distress, of his equals.","('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"But in their most dissolute
 period, the knights of their hospital and temple maintained
 their fearless and fanatic character: they neglected to
 live, but they were prepared to die, in the service of
 Christ; and the spirit of chivalry, the parent and offspring
 of the crusades, has been transplanted by this institution
 from the holy sepulchre to the Isle of Malta. (131)
Assise of Jerusalem, A.D. 1099-1369.","('the Isle of Malta', 'GPE'), ('131', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('1099-1369', 'CARDINAL')"
"But in this visit of piety and pleasure,
 they neglected to secure the season, and the means of their
 embarkation: the winter was insensibly lost: their troops
 were scattered and corrupted in the towns of Italy.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"But it
 cannot be denied, that the Oriental churches are depressed
 under their iron yoke; that, in peace and war, they assert a
 divine and indefeasible claim of universal empire; and that,
 in their orthodox creed, the unbelieving nations are
 continually threatened with the loss of religion or liberty.","('Oriental', 'NORP')"
"But it
 was easier for him to extort the praise of the Infidels,
 than to preserve the love of his subjects and associates.","('Infidels', 'NORP')"
"But the
 firmest bulwark of Jerusalem was founded on the knights of
 the Hospital of St. John, (128) and of the temple of Solomon;
 (129) on the strange association of a monastic and military
 life, which fanaticism might suggest, but which policy must
 approve.","('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('the Hospital of St. John', 'ORG'), ('128', 'CARDINAL'), ('Solomon', 'PERSON'), ('129', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the Turks could protract their
 resistance and secure their escape, as long as they were
 masters of the Lake (82)","('Turks', 'NORP'), ('82', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the appellation of the Great was
 applied, not so much to his merit or possessions, (though
 neither were contemptible,) as to the royal birth of the
 brother of the king of France. (46)","('France', 'GPE')"
"But the citadel still refused to surrender; and the victims
 themselves were speedily encompassed and besieged by the
 innumerable forces of Kerboga, prince of Mosul, who, with
 twenty-eight Turkish emirs, advanced to the deliverance of
 Antioch.","('Kerboga', 'PERSON'), ('Mosul', 'GPE'), ('twenty-eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"But the count of
 Vermandois was produced as a captive; his foremost vessels
 were scattered by a tempest; and his person, against the law
 of nations, was detained by the lieutenants of Alexius.","('Vermandois', 'PERSON'), ('Alexius', 'PERSON')"
"But the count of Tholouse and Provence was
 suspected of a voluntary indisposition; the duke of Normandy
 was recalled from the sea-shore by the censures of the
 church: Hugh the Great, though he led the vanguard of the
 battle, embraced an ambiguous opportunity of returning to
 France and Stephen, count of Chartres, basely deserted the
 standard which he bore, and the council in which he
 presided.","('Tholouse', 'PERSON'), ('Provence', 'GPE'), ('Normandy', 'GPE'), ('Hugh the Great', 'PERSON'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Stephen', 'PERSON'), ('Chartres', 'PERSON')"
"But the emperor's party was crushed in Italy by the arms of the Normans and the Countess Mathilda; and the long quarrel had been recently envenomed by the revolt of his son Conrad and the shame of his wife, (5) who, in the synods of Constance and Placentia, confessed the manifold prostitutions to which she had been exposed by a husband regardless of her honour and his own.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Mathilda', 'PERSON'), ('Conrad', 'PERSON'), ('Constance', 'PERSON'), ('Placentia', 'PERSON')"
"But the glory or reproach of executing, though not in person, this holy enterprise, was reserved for Urban the Second, (4) the most faithful of his disciples.","('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('4', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the holy wars which have been waged in every
 climate of the globe, from Egypt to Livonia, and from Peru
 to Hindostan, require the support of some more general and
 flexible tenet.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Livonia', 'GPE'), ('Peru', 'GPE'), ('Hindostan', 'GPE')"
"But the name and nature of a holy war demands a more rigorous scrutiny; nor can we hastily believe, that the servants of the Prince of Peace would unsheathe the sword of destruction, unless the motive were pure, the quarrel legitimate, and the necessity inevitable.","('the Prince of Peace', 'PERSON')"
"But the reality or the report of such gigantic prowess (92) must have taught the
 Moslems to keep within their walls: and against those walls of earth or stone, the sword and the lance were unavailing weapons.","('92', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moslems', 'NORP')"
"But the rigid
 execution of these laws would have depopulated the palace,
 the camp, and the city; the Barbarians of the West believed
 and trembled; but nature often rebelled against principle;
 and the magistrate labored without effect to enforce the
 jurisdiction of the priest.","('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"But the same Christians were the
 enemies of the prophet; and from the overthrow of Nice and
 Antioch, the motive of their enterprise, which was gradually
 understood, would urge them forwards to the banks of the
 Jordan, or perhaps of the Nile.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Nice', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Jordan', 'GPE'), ('Nile', 'LOC')"
"But this salutary purpose might have been
 accomplished by a moderate succour; and our calmer reason
 must disclaim the innumerable hosts, and remote operations,
 which overwhelmed Asia and depopulated Europe.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"But, after weighing the motives
 and the events, the virtuous duke was content to pity the
 crimes and misfortunes of his worthless brethren; and his
 twelve deputies, the messengers of peace, requested in his
 name a free passage and an equal market.","('twelve', 'CARDINAL')"
"By
 his skill and diligence, Alexius prevented the union of any
 two of the confederate armies at the same moment under the
 walls of Constantinople; and before the feast of the
 Pentecost not a Latin pilgrim was left on the coast of
 Europe.","('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Pentecost', 'EVENT'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"By a fantastic arithmetic, a year of penance was taxed at
 three thousand lashes; (25) and such was the skill and
 patience of a famous hermit, St. Dominic of the iron
 Cuirass, (26) that in six days he could discharge an entire
 century, by a whipping of three hundred thousand stripes.","('a year', 'DATE'), ('three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('25', 'CARDINAL'), ('St. Dominic', 'PERSON'), ('26', 'CARDINAL'), ('six days', 'DATE'), ('an entire\r\n century', 'DATE'), ('three hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"By a rumour that their foremost companions
 were rioting in the spoils of his capital, Soliman tempted the main body to descend into the plain of Nice: they were overwhelmed by the Turkish arrows; and a pyramid of bones (40) informed their companions of the place of their defeat.","('Soliman', 'PERSON'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('40', 'CARDINAL')"
"By the arms of
 Godfrey himself, and of the two Baldwins, his brother and
 cousin, who succeeded to the throne, the Latins breathed
 with more ease and safety; and at length they equalled, in
 the extent of their dominions, though not in the millions of
 their subjects, the ancient princes of Judah and Israel.
 (119)","('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Baldwins', 'PERSON'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('millions', 'CARDINAL'), ('Judah', 'GPE'), ('Israel', 'GPE'), ('119', 'CARDINAL')"
"By the dint of brutal
 force, they burst the first barrier; but they were driven
 back with shame and slaughter to the camp: the influence of
 vision and prophecy was deadened by the too frequent abuse
 of those pious stratagems; and time and labour were found to
 be the only means of victory.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"By the experience of a
 recent siege, and a three years' possession, the Saracens of
 Egypt had been taught to discern, and in some degree to
 remedy, the defects of a place, which religion as well as
 honour forbade them to resign.","(""three years'"", 'DATE'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"Champions were only
 allowed to women, and to men maimed or past the age of
 sixty.","('sixty', 'CARDINAL')"
"Christendom, in her rudest state, must have
 yielded to the climate and cultivation of the Mahometan
 countries; and their natural and artificial wealth had been
 magnified by the tales of pilgrims, and the gifts of an
 imperfect commerce.","('Christendom', 'GPE'), ('Mahometan', 'NORP')"
"Conquest of Nice, Antioch, and Jerusalem, by the Franks.","('Nice', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"Council of Clermont, A.D. 1095,November.","('Council of Clermont', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 1095', 'DATE'), ('November', 'DATE')"
"Daimbert, archbishop of Pisa, had long been
 trained in the secret policy of Rome: he brought a fleet at
 his countrymen to the succour of the Holy Land, and was
 installed, without a competitor, the spiritual and temporal
 head of the church.","('Daimbert', 'PERSON'), ('Pisa', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('the Holy Land', 'GPE')"
Deliverance of the Holy Sepulchre.,"('the Holy Sepulchre', 'PERSON')"
"Departure of the first crusaders, A.D. 1096, March and May etc.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('A.D. 1096', 'DATE'), ('March', 'DATE'), ('May', 'DATE')"
"Disease, the faithful companion of want, was
 envenomed by the rains of the winter, the summer heats,
 unwholesome food, and the close imprisonment of multitudes.","('the winter', 'DATE')"
"Each knight was attended to the field by his faithful
 squire, a youth of equal birth and similar hopes; he was
 followed by his archers and men at arms, and four, or five,
 or six soldiers were computed as the furniture of a complete
 lance .","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('six', 'CARDINAL')"
"Early in the
 spring, from the confines of France and Lorraine, above
 sixty thousand of the populace of both sexes flocked round
 the first missionary of the crusade, and pressed him with
 clamorous importunity to lead them to the holy sepulchre.","('the\r\n spring', 'DATE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Lorraine', 'GPE'), ('sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Eight days after this memorable event, which Pope Urban did
 not live to hear, the Latin chiefs proceeded to the election
 of a king, to guard and govern their conquests in Palestine.","('Eight days', 'DATE'), ('Pope Urban', 'PERSON'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Palestine', 'GPE')"
"Election and reign of Godfrey of Bouillon, A.D. 1099, July 23-A.D. 1100, July 18.","('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Bouillon', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1099', 'DATE'), ('July 23-A.D. 1100', 'DATE'), ('July 18', 'DATE')"
"Experience
 blows away this charitable illusion; and seldom does the
 history of profane war display such scenes of intemperance
 and prostitution as were exhibited under the walls of
 Antioch.","('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"Few were able to command, and
 none were willing to obey; the domestic feuds, which had
 been stifled by common fear, were again renewed in acts, or
 at least in sentiments, of hostility; the fortune of Baldwin
 and Bohemond excited the envy of their companions; the
 bravest knights were enlisted for the defence of their new
 principalities; and Count Raymond exhausted his troops and
 treasures in an idle expedition into the heart of Syria.","('Baldwin', 'PERSON'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON'), ('Raymond', 'PERSON'), ('Syria', 'GPE')"
"Five thousand and seventy-five  serjeants, most probably foot-soldiers, were supplied by the churches and
 cities; and the whole legal militia of the kingdom could not
 exceed eleven thousand men, a slender defence against the
 surrounding myriads of Saracens and Turks. (127)","('Five thousand and seventy-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('eleven thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('127', 'CARDINAL')"
"Five-and-twenty days the Christians spent on the
 verge of destruction; and the proud lieutenant of the caliph
 and the sultan left them only the choice of servitude or
 death.","('Five-and-twenty days', 'DATE'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"For a while, the Provincials defended their national palladium with clamours and arms and new visions condemned to death and hell the profane sceptics who presumed to scrutinize the truth and merit of the discovery.","('Provincials', 'NORP')"
"For his own safety, Alexius
 allured them to pass over to the Asiatic side of the
 Bosphorus; but their blind impetuosity soon urged them to
 desert the station which he had assigned, and to rush
 headlong against the Turks, who occupied the road to
 Jerusalem.","('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
"For the trifling sum of ten thousand marks, he
 mortgaged Normandy during his absence to the English
 usurper; (47) but his engagement and behaviour in the holy war  announced in Robert a reformation of manners, and restored him in some degree to the public esteem.","('ten thousand marks', 'MONEY'), ('Normandy', 'GPE'), ('English', 'LANGUAGE'), ('47', 'CARDINAL'), ('Robert', 'PERSON')"
"Four thousand of the clergy, and thirty thousand of the laity, attended this important meeting; and, as the most spacious cathedral would have been inadequate to the multitude, the session of seven days was held in a plain adjacent to the city.","('Four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven days', 'DATE')"
"From
 the banks of the Meuse and the Moselle, Godfrey of Bouillon
 followed the direct way of Germany, Hungary, and Bulgaria;
 and, as long as he exercised the sole command every step
 afforded some proof of his prudence and virtue.","('Meuse', 'FAC'), ('Moselle', 'FAC'), ('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Bouillon', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('Bulgaria', 'GPE')"
"From Austria to
 Belgrade, they traversed the plains of Hungary, without
 enduring or offering an injury; and the proximity of
 Carloman, who hovered on their flanks with his numerous
 cavalry, was a precaution not less useful for their safety
 than for his own.","('Austria', 'GPE'), ('Belgrade', 'GPE'), ('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('Carloman', 'PERSON')"
"From Caesarea they
 advanced into the midland country; their clerks recognized
 the sacred geography of Lydda, Ramla, Emmaus, and Bethlem,
 and as soon as they descried the holy city, the crusaders
 forgot their toils and claimed their reward. (104)","('Caesarea', 'GPE'), ('Lydda', 'LOC'), ('Ramla', 'NORP'), ('Emmaus', 'GPE'), ('Bethlem', 'PERSON')"
"From Jerusalem the pilgrim returned an accomplished fanatic; but as he excelled in the popular madness of the times, Pope Urban the Second received him as a prophet, applauded his glorious design, promised to support it in a general council, and encouraged him to proclaim the deliverance of the Holy Land.","('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Pope Urban', 'PERSON'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('the Holy Land', 'GPE')"
"From the Alps to Apulia the
 march of Hugh the Great, of the two Roberts, and of Stephen
 of Chartres, through a wealthy country, and amidst the
 applauding Catholics, was a devout or triumphant progress:
 they kissed the feet of the Roman pontiff; and the golden
 standard of St. Peter was delivered to the brother of the
 French monarch. (62)","('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Hugh the Great', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roberts', 'PERSON'), ('Stephen\r\n of Chartres', 'PERSON'), ('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('French', 'NORP')"
"From the adjacent frontier of
 Spain he drew a band of hardy adventurers; as he marched
 through Lombardy, a crowd of Italians flocked to his
 standard, and his united force consisted of one hundred
 thousand horse and foot.","('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Lombardy', 'GPE'), ('Italians', 'NORP'), ('one hundred\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the adjacent kingdoms, a martial train of lords and knights of power and renown attended the council, (15) in high expectation of its resolves; and such was the ardour of zeal and curiosity, that the city was filled, and many thousands, in the month of November, erected their tents or huts in the open field.","('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('the month of November', 'DATE')"
"From the synod of Placentia, the rumour of his great design had gone forth among the nations: the clergy on their return had preached in every diocese the merit and glory of the deliverance of the Holy Land; and when the pope ascended a lofty scaffold in the market-place of Clermont, his eloquence was addressed to a well-prepared and impatient audience.","('Placentia', 'PERSON'), ('the Holy Land', 'GPE'), ('Clermont', 'GPE')"
"From their
 first station in the neighbourhood of Nicomedia, they
 advanced in successive divisions; passed the contracted
 limit of the Greek empire; opened a road through the hills,
 and commenced, by the siege of his capital, their pious
 warfare against the Turkish sultan.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Nicomedia', 'GPE'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Turkish', 'NORP')"
"From these materials, with the counsel and approbation of
 the patriarch and barons, of the clergy and laity, Godfrey
 composed the ASSISE OF JERUSALEM, (132) a precious monument of feudal jurisprudence.","('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('132', 'CARDINAL')"
"Godfrey listened to their reasonable prayer, that they might
 be judged by their own national laws.","('Godfrey', 'PERSON')"
"Godfrey of Bouillon (45) was accompanied by his
 two brothers, by Eustace the elder, who had succeeded to the
 county of Boulogne, and by the younger, Baldwin, a character
 of more ambiguous virtue.","('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Bouillon', 'PERSON'), ('45', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Eustace', 'PERSON'), ('Boulogne', 'GPE'), ('Baldwin', 'PERSON')"
"Godfrey of Bouillon erected his standard on
 the first swell of Mount Calvary: to the left, as far as St.
 Stephen's gate, the line of attack was continued by Tancred
 and the two Roberts; and Count Raymond established his
 quarters from the citadel to the foot of Mount Sion, which
 was no longer included within the precincts of the city.","('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Bouillon', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Mount Calvary', 'FAC'), (""St.\r\n Stephen's"", 'FAC'), ('Tancred', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roberts', 'PERSON'), ('Raymond', 'PERSON'), ('Mount Sion', 'FAC')"
"Godfrey of Bouillon, First King of Jerusalem.","('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Bouillon', 'GPE'), ('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
Godfrey of Bouillon..,"('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Bouillon', 'GPE')"
"Godfrey sounded his
 trumpets, burst the net, overspread the plain, and insulted
 the suburbs; but the gates of Constantinople were strongly
 fortified; the ramparts were lined with archers; and, after
 a doubtful conflict, both parties listened to the voice of
 peace and religion.","('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Had not
 superstition condemned the sacrilegious prudence of
 depriving the poorest or weakest Christian of the merit of
 the pilgrimage, the useless crowd, with mouths but without
 hands, might have been stationed in the Greek empire, till
 their companions had opened and secured the way of the Lord.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"Had the diminished strength and numbers of the Latins
 allowed them to grasp the whole circumference of four
 thousand yards, (about two English miles and a half, (107))
 to what useful purpose should they have descended into the
 valley of Ben Hinnom and torrent of Cedron, (108) or approach the precipices of the south and east, from whence they had
 nothing either to hope or fear?","('Latins', 'NORP'), ('four\r\n thousand yards', 'QUANTITY'), ('about two English miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('107', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ben Hinnom', 'PERSON'), ('Cedron', 'GPE'), ('108', 'CARDINAL')"
"He attempted to unite the powers of the West, at a time when the princes were separated from the church, and the people from their princes, by the excommunication which himself and his predecessors had thundered against the emperor and the king of France.","('West', 'LOC'), ('France', 'GPE')"
"He disdained the gold and flattery of the Greek monarch; assaulted in his presence an insolent patrician; escaped to Asia in the habit of a private soldier; and yielded with a sigh to the authority of Bohemond, and the interest of the Christian cause.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"He had firmly resisted the temptations of Bohemond
 and Raymond, who urged the attack and conquest of
 Constantinople.","('Bohemond', 'PERSON'), ('Raymond', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"He presented
 himself at the door of the council-chamber, to disclose an
 apparition of St. Andrew, which had been thrice reiterated
 in his sleep with a dreadful menace, if he presumed to
 suppress the commands of Heaven.","('St. Andrew', 'LOC')"
"He undertook the conquest of the East, whilst the larger portion of Rome was possessed and fortified by his rival Guibert of Ravenna, who contended with Urban for the name and honours of the pontificate.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Guibert', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Urban', 'PERSON')"
"He was born of a gentleman's family, (for we must now adopt a modern idiom,) and his military service was under the neighbouring counts of Boulogne, the heroes of the first crusade.","('Boulogne', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"He was called to the assistance
 of a Greek or Armenian tyrant, who had been suffered under
 the Turkish yoke to reign over the Christians of Edessa.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Armenian', 'NORP'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Edessa', 'GPE')"
"Henry the Fourth, of Germany, asserted the right of investitures, the prerogative of confirming his bishops by the delivery of the ring and crosier.","('Henry the Fourth', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"High on his throne, the emperor sat mute and immovable: his majesty was adored by the Latin princes; and they submitted to kiss either his feet or his knees, an indignity which their own writers are ashamed to confess and unable to deny. (70)","('Latin', 'NORP')"
"His
 conduct may justify a belief that he had secretly directed
 the design of the pope, which he affected to second with
 astonishment and zeal: at the siege of Amalphi, his example
 and discourse inflamed the passions of a confederate army;
 he instantly tore his garment to supply crosses for the
 numerous candidates, and prepared to visit Constantinople
 and Asia at the head of ten thousand horse and twenty
 thousand foot.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Amalphi', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty\r\n thousand foot', 'QUANTITY')"
"His
 government of a single year, (115) too short for the public
 happiness, was interrupted in the first fortnight by a
 summons to the field, by the approach of the vizier or
 sultan of Egypt, who had been too slow to prevent, but who
 was impatient to avenge, the loss of Jerusalem.","('a single year', 'DATE'), ('115', 'CARDINAL'), ('the first fortnight', 'DATE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
"His
 prudence, or his pride, was content with extorting from the
 French princes an oath of homage and fidelity, and a solemn
 promise, that they would either restore, or hold, their Asiatic conquests as
 the humble and loyal vassals of the Roman empire.","('French', 'NORP'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"His
 sovereignty was soon attacked by a new enemy, the only one
 against whom Godfrey was a coward.","('Godfrey', 'PERSON')"
"His diet was abstemious, his prayers long and fervent, and the alms which he received with one hand, he distributed with the other: his head was bare, his feet naked, his meagre body was wrapped in a coarse garment; he bore and displayed a weighty crucifix; and the ass on which he rode was sanctified, in the public eye, by the service of the man of God.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"His disgust of the noise and insolence of the French, his suspicions of the designs of Bohemond, the emperor imparted to his faithful Raymond; and that aged statesman might clearly discern, that however false in friendship, he was sincere in his enmity. (69)","('French', 'NORP'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON'), ('Raymond', 'PERSON')"
"His eminent qualities were clouded by a temper haughty,
 envious, and obstinate; and, though he resigned an ample
 patrimony for the cause of God, his piety, in the public
 opinion, was not exempt from avarice and ambition. (50)","('50', 'CARDINAL')"
"His example was
 followed on every side by the emulation of valour; and about
 four hundred and sixty years after the conquest of Omar, the
 holy city was rescued from the Mahometan yoke.","('about\r\n four hundred and sixty years', 'DATE'), ('Omar', 'PERSON'), ('Mahometan', 'NORP')"
"His experience and riches gave him a
 strong ascendant in the Christian camp, whose distress he
 was often able, and sometimes willing, to relieve.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"His father was of the noble race of the counts of
 Boulogne: Brabant, the lower province of Lorraine, (43) was
 the inheritance of his mother; and by the emperor's bounty
 he was himself invested with that ducal title, which has
 been improperly transferred to his lordship of Bouillon in
 the Ardennes. (44)","('Boulogne: Brabant', 'GPE'), ('Lorraine', 'PERSON'), ('43', 'DATE'), ('Bouillon', 'PERSON'), ('44', 'CARDINAL')"
"His garrison is said to have consisted of forty
 thousand Turks and Arabians; and if he could muster twenty
 thousand of the inhabitants, it must be confessed that the
 besieged were more numerous than the besieging army. (106)","('forty\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Arabians', 'NORP'), ('twenty\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('106', 'CARDINAL')"
"His insolvency was relieved by a commutation,
 or indulgence: a year of penance was appreciated at
 twenty-six solidi (24) of silver, about four pounds sterling, for the rich; at three solidi, or nine shillings, for the
 indigent: and these alms were soon appropriated to the use
 of the church, which derived, from the redemption of sins,
 an inexhaustible source of opulence and dominion.","('a year', 'DATE'), ('twenty-six solidi', 'QUANTITY'), ('24', 'CARDINAL'), ('about four pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('three solidi, or nine shillings', 'QUANTITY')"
"His kingdom of Roum
 extended from the Hellespont to the confines of Syria, and
 barred the pilgrimage of Jerusalem, his name was
 Kilidge-Arslan, or Soliman, (80) of the race of Seljuk, and
 son of the first conqueror; and in the defence of a land
 which the Turks considered as their own, he deserved the
 praise of his enemies, by whom alone he is known to
 posterity.","('Roum', 'PERSON'), ('Hellespont', 'NORP'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Kilidge-Arslan', 'PERSON'), ('Soliman', 'PERSON'), ('80', 'CARDINAL'), ('Seljuk', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Turks', 'NORP')"
"His magnanimity accepted a
 trust as full of danger as of glory; but in a city where his
 Saviour had been crowned with thorns, the devout pilgrim
 rejected the name and ensigns of royalty; and the founder of
 the kingdom of Jerusalem contented himself with the modest
 title of Defender and Baron of the Holy Sepulchre.","('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Baron of the Holy Sepulchre', 'PERSON')"
"His march between
 Durazzo and Constantinople was harassed, without being
 stopped, by the peasants and soldiers of the Greek emperor;
 and the same faint and ambiguous hostility was prepared for
 the remaining chiefs, who passed the Adriatic from the coast
 of Italy.","('Durazzo', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"His mind
 was improved by literature; and, in the council of the
 chiefs, the eloquent Stephen (48) was chosen to discharge the
 office of their president.","('Stephen', 'PERSON'), ('48', 'DATE')"
"His obstinate resistance enhanced the value and the price of his submission; and he shone, says the princess Anne, among the Barbarians, as the sun amidst the stars of heaven.","('Anne', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"His resentment and sympathy were excited by his own injuries and the oppression of the Christian name; he mingled his tears with those of the patriarch, and earnestly inquired, if no hopes of relief could be entertained from the Greek emperors of the East.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"His total
 overthrow in the battle of Ascalon sealed the establishment
 of the Latins in Syria, and signalized the valour of the
 French princes who in this action bade a long farewell to
 the holy wars.","('Ascalon', 'GPE'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('French', 'NORP')"
"Honour was the motive, and fame the reward,
 of Tancred; but fortune smiled on the more selfish
 enterprise of his rival. (88)","('Tancred', 'PERSON')"
"Hugh of Vernadois, etc.  II.","('Hugh of Vernadois', 'PERSON')"
"Hugh the Great, and Stephen of Chartres, had retired with
 some loss of reputation, which they strove to regain by a
 second crusade and an honourable death.","('Hugh the Great', 'PERSON'), ('Stephen of Chartres', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"I have expiated with pleasure on the first steps of the
 crusaders, as they paint the manners and character of
 Europe: but I shall abridge the tedious and uniform
 narrative of their blind achievements, which were performed
 by strength and are described by ignorance.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"If Raymond was the first to enlist
 and the last to depart, the delay may be excused by the
 greatness of his preparation and the promise of an
 everlasting farewell.","('Raymond', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"If the prince of Antioch disclaimed his
 supremacy, the counts of Edessa and Tripoli owned themselves
 the vassals of the king of Jerusalem: the Latins reigned
 beyond the Euphrates; and the four cities of Hems, Hamah,
 Damascus, and Aleppo, were the only relics of the Mahometan
 conquests in Syria. (122)","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Edessa', 'PERSON'), ('Tripoli', 'GPE'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hems', 'GPE'), ('Hamah', 'GPE'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Aleppo', 'GPE'), ('Mahometan', 'NORP'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('122', 'CARDINAL')"
"If they fell, the spirit of the Latin clergy
 did not hesitate to adorn their tomb with the crown of
 martyrdom; (29) and should they survive, they could expect
 without impatience the delay and increase of their heavenly
 reward.","('Latin', 'NORP'), ('29', 'CARDINAL')"
"Ignorance is the ground of suspicion, and suspicion was
 inflamed into daily provocations: prejudice is blind, hunger
 is deaf; and Alexius is accused of a design to starve or
 assault the Latins in a dangerous post, on all sides
 encompassed with the waters. (66)","('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('Latins', 'NORP')"
"In
 the first days of the siege and the possession of Antioch,
 the Franks consumed with wanton and thoughtless prodigality
 the frugal subsistence of weeks and months: the desolate
 country no longer yielded a supply; and from that country
 they were at length excluded by the arms of the besieging
 Turks.","('the first days', 'DATE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'NORP'), ('weeks and months', 'DATE'), ('Turks', 'NORP')"
"In
 the siege of Nice, the arts and engines of antiquity were
 employed by the Latins; the mine and the battering-ram, the
 tortoise, and the belfrey or movable turret, artificial
 fire, and the catapult and balist, the sling, and the
 crossbow for the casting of stones and darts. (81)","('Nice', 'GPE'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('81', 'CARDINAL')"
"In a march of five hundred miles, the
 crusaders traversed the Lesser Asia, through a wasted land
 and deserted towns, without finding either a friend or an
 enemy.","('five hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('the Lesser Asia', 'LOC')"
"In either fortune, the answer of the
 crusaders was firm and uniform: they disdained to inquire
 into the private claims or possessions of the followers of
 Mahomet; whatsoever was his name or nation, the usurper of
 Jerusalem was their enemy; and instead of prescribing the
 mode and terms of their pilgrimage, it was only by a timely
 surrender of the city and province, their sacred right, that
 he could deserve their alliance, or deprecate their
 impending and irresistible attack. (103)
Delay of the Franks, A.D. 1098, July- A.D. 1099, May.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('103', 'CARDINAL'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 1098', 'DATE'), ('July- A.D. 1099', 'DATE'), ('May', 'DATE')"
"In his enthusiasm, Alexius indulged, or
 affected, the ambitious hope of leading his new allies to
 subvert the thrones of the East; but the calmer dictates of
 reason and temper dissuaded him from exposing his royal
 person to the faith of unknown and lawless Barbarians.","('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"In his southern province, the count of St. Giles and Thoulouse faintly recognized the supremacy of the king of France, a prince of a foreign nation and language.","('St. Giles', 'FAC'), ('Thoulouse', 'PERSON'), ('France', 'GPE')"
"In many
 cases it was in the option of the judge to award or to
 refuse the combat: but two are specified, in which it was
 the inevitable result of the challenge; if a faithful vassal
 gave the lie to his compeer, who unjustly claimed any
 portion of their lord's demesnes; or if an unsuccessful
 suitor presumed to impeach the judgment and veracity of the
 court.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In some oriental tale I have read the fable of a shepherd,
 who was ruined by the accomplishment of his own wishes: he
 had prayed for water; the Ganges was turned into his
 grounds, and his flock and cottage were swept away by the
 inundation.","('Ganges', 'LOC')"
"In the
 accomplished character of Tancred we discover all the
 virtues of a perfect knight, (54) the true spirit of
 chivalry, which inspired the generous sentiments and social
 offices of man far better than the base philosophy, or the
 baser religion, of the times.","('Tancred', 'PERSON'), ('54', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the
 mind of Godfrey of Bouillon every human consideration was
 subordinate to the glory of God and the success of the
 crusade.","('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Bouillon', 'GPE')"
"In the
 pillage of public and private wealth, the adventurers had
 agreed to respect the exclusive property of the first
 occupant; and the spoils of the great mosque, seventy lamps
 and massy vases of gold and silver, rewarded the diligence,
 and displayed the generosity, of Tancred.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('seventy', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the
 space of seven weeks much labour and blood were expended, and
 some progress, especially by Count Raymond, was made on the
 side of the besiegers.","('the\r\n space of seven weeks', 'DATE'), ('Raymond', 'PERSON')"
"In the Assise of Jerusalem, the
 legal subtlety of the count of Jaffa is more laudably
 employed to elude, than to facilitate, the judicial combat,
 which he derives from a principle of honour rather than of
 superstition. (140)
Court of Burgesses.","('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Jaffa', 'PERSON'), ('140', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the age of the crusades, the Christians, both of the East and West, were persuaded of
 their lawfulness and merit; their arguments are clouded by the perpetual abuse of Scripture and rhetoric; but they seem to insist on the right of natural and religious defence, their peculiar title to the Holy Land, and the impiety of their Pagan and Mahometan foes. (20)
I.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Scripture', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('the Holy Land', 'PERSON'), ('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('Mahometan', 'NORP'), ('20', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the belief of their lost
 condition, the caliph Mostali despised their arms and
 imprisoned their deputies: the conquest and victory of
 Antioch prompted him to solicit those formidable champions
 with gifts of horses and silk robes, of vases, and purses of
 gold and silver; and in his estimate of their merit or
 power, the first place was assigned to Bohemond, and the
 second to Godfrey.","('Mostali', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Godfrey', 'PERSON')"
"In the conquest and
 settlement of new cities, the example of Jerusalem was
 imitated by the kings and their great vassals; and above
 thirty similar corporations were founded before the loss of
 the Holy Land.","('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('thirty', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Holy Land', 'GPE')"
"In the conquest of Nice, they had been powerfully assisted by the wealth and knowledge of the Greek emperor: his absence was poorly supplied by some Genoese and Pisan vessels, that were
 attracted by religion or trade to the coast of Syria: the stores were scanty, the return precarious, and the communication difficult and dangerous.","('Nice', 'GPE'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Genoese', 'NORP'), ('Pisan', 'NORP'), ('Syria', 'GPE')"
"In the council of
 Clermont, that pope proclaimed a plenary indulgence to those
 who should enlist under the banner of the cross; the
 absolution of all their sins, and a full receipt for all
 that might be due of canonical penance. (28)","('Clermont', 'GPE')"
"In the council of Placentia, A.D. 1095,March.","('Placentia', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1095', 'DATE'), ('March', 'DATE')"
"In the council of Placentia, his
 ambassadors had solicited a moderate succour, perhaps of ten
 thousand soldiers, but he was astonished by the approach of
 so many potent chiefs and fanatic nations.","('Placentia', 'GPE'), ('ten\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the description of Antioch, (90) it is
 not easy to define a middle term between her ancient
 magnificence, under the successors of Alexander and
 Augustus, and the modern aspect of Turkish desolation.","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('90', 'DATE'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Turkish', 'NORP')"
"In the distress of
 Antioch, they were repeated with unusual energy and success:
 St. Ambrose had assured a pious ecclesiastic, that two years
 of trial must precede the season of deliverance and grace;
 the deserters were stopped by the presence and reproaches of
 Christ himself; the dead had promised to arise and combat
 with their brethren; the Virgin had obtained the pardon of
 their sins; and their confidence was revived by a visible
 sign, the seasonable and splendid discovery of the HOLY
 LANCE.","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('St. Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('two years', 'DATE'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Virgin', 'PERSON')"
"In the eleventh century, the victorious arms of the Turks
 presented a real and urgent apprehension of these losses.","('the eleventh century', 'DATE'), ('Turks', 'NORP')"
"In the evening, swiftness
 yielded to strength: on either side, the numbers were equal
 or at least as great as any ground could hold, or any
 generals could manage; but in turning the hills, the last
 division of Raymond and his provincials was led, perhaps
 without design on the rear of an exhausted enemy; and the
 long contest was determined.","('the evening', 'TIME'), ('Raymond', 'PERSON')"
"In the evening, when Count Raymond had withdrawn to his post, and the weary assistants began to murmur, Bartholemy, in his shirt, and without his
 shoes, boldly descended into the pit; the darkness of the
 hour and of the place enabled him to secrete and deposit the
 head of a Saracen lance; and the first sound, the first
 gleam, of the steel was saluted with a devout rapture.","('the evening', 'TIME'), ('Raymond', 'PERSON'), ('Bartholemy', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n hour', 'TIME'), ('Saracen', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"In the eventful period of the siege and defence of Antioch,
 the crusaders were alternately exalted by victory or sunk in
 despair; either swelled with plenty or emaciated with
 hunger.","('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"In the expeditions to the neighbouring kingdoms or
 the Holy Land, the duties of the feudal tenure no longer
 subsisted; the voluntary service of the knights and their
 followers were either prompted by zeal or attachment, or
 purchased with rewards and promises; and the numbers of each
 squadron were measured by the power, the wealth, and the
 fame, of each independent chieftain.","('the Holy Land', 'GPE')"
"In the moment of victory, or at
 least of hope, the crusaders, thirsting for blood and
 plunder, were awed by the Imperial banner that streamed from
 the citadel; and Alexius guarded with jealous vigilance this important conquest.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Alexius', 'PERSON')"
"In the month of May, the relics of this mighty host
 proceeded from Antioch to Laodicea: about forty thousand
 Latins, of whom no more than fifteen hundred horse, and
 twenty thousand foot, were capable of immediate service.","('the month of May', 'DATE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Laodicea', 'GPE'), ('about forty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('more than fifteen hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty thousand foot', 'QUANTITY')"
"In the painful and various service of
 Antioch, the cavalry was annihilated; many thousands of
 every rank had been lost by famine, sickness, and desertion:
 the same abuse of plenty had been productive of a third
 famine; and the alternative of intemperance and distress had
 generated a pestilence, which swept away above fifty
 thousand of the pilgrims.","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('fifty\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the parliament that was held at Paris, in the king's presence, about two months after the council of Clermont, Hugh, count  of Vermandois, was the most conspicuous of the princes who assumed the cross.","('Paris', 'GPE'), ('about two months', 'DATE'), ('Clermont', 'GPE'), ('Hugh', 'PERSON'), ('Vermandois', 'PERSON')"
"In the petty quarrels of Europe, they shed the blood
 of their friends and countrymen, for the acquisition perhaps
 of a castle or a village.","('Europe', 'LOC')"
"In the season of danger and triumph, the revelation of Bartholemy of Marseilles was unanimously asserted; but as soon as the temporary service was accomplished, the personal dignity and liberal arms which the count of Tholouse derived from the custody of the holy lance, provoked the envy, and awakened the reason, of his rivals.","('the season', 'DATE'), ('Bartholemy', 'PERSON'), ('Marseilles', 'GPE'), ('Tholouse', 'PERSON')"
"In the service of Henry the Fourth, he
 bore the great standard of the empire, and pierced with his
 lance the breast of Rodolph, the rebel king: Godfrey was the
 first who ascended the walls of Rome; and his sickness, his
 vow, perhaps his remorse for bearing arms against the pope,
 confirmed an early resolution of visiting the holy
 sepulchre, not as a pilgrim, but a deliverer.","('Henry', 'PERSON'), ('Fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rodolph', 'PERSON'), ('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In the south of
 France, the command was assumed by Adhemar bishop of Puy,
 the pope's legate, and by Raymond count of St. Giles and
 Thoulouse who added the prouder titles of duke of Narbonne
 and marquis of Provence.","('France', 'GPE'), ('Adhemar bishop of Puy', 'PERSON'), ('Raymond', 'PERSON'), ('St. Giles', 'PERSON'), ('Thoulouse', 'PERSON'), ('Narbonne', 'GPE'), ('Provence', 'GPE')"
"In the trading cities of the Moselle and the
 Rhine, their colonies were numerous and rich; and they
 enjoyed, under the protection of the emperor and the
 bishops, the free exercise of their religion. (36)","('Moselle', 'LOC'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('36', 'CARDINAL')"
"In their pleadings,
 replies, and rejoinders, the advocates of the court were
 subtle and copious; but the use of argument and evidence was
 often superseded by judicial combat; and the Assise of
 Jerusalem admits in many cases this barbarous institution,
 which has been slowly abolished by the laws and manners of
 Europe.","('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"In their suppliant address they flattered the pride of the Latin princes; and, appealing at once to their policy and religion, exhorted them to repel the Barbarians on the confines of Asia, rather than to expect them in the heart of Europe.","('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"In this dangerous estimate of
 crimes and punishments, each case was supposed, each
 difference was remarked, by the experience or penetration of
 the monks; some sins are enumerated which innocence could
 not have suspected, and others which reason cannot believe;
 and the more ordinary offences of fornication and adultery,
 of perjury and sacrilege, of rapine and murder, were
 expiated by a penance, which, according to the various
 circumstances, was prolonged from forty days to seven years.","('forty days to seven years', 'DATE')"
"In this extremity they collected the relics of
 their strength, sallied from the town, and in a single
 memorable day, annihilated or dispersed the host of Turks
 and Arabians, which they might safely report to have
 consisted of six hundred thousand men. (94)","('a single\r\n memorable day', 'DATE'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Arabians', 'NORP'), ('six hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('94', 'CARDINAL')"
"In this narrow compass, he was possessed of wealth and jurisdiction; but in the rest of France, Hugh and his first descendants were no more than the feudal lords of about sixty dukes and counts, of independent and hereditary power, (12) who disdained the control of laws and legal assemblies, and whose disregard of their sovereign was revenged by the disobedience of their inferior vassals.","('France', 'GPE'), ('Hugh', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('about sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('12', 'CARDINAL')"
"In this rapid portrait of chivalry I have been urged to
 anticipate on the story of the crusades, at once an effect
 and a cause, of this memorable institution. (58)
March of the princes to Constantinople, A.D. 1096, August 15-A.D. 1097, May.","('58)\r\nMarch', 'DATE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1096', 'DATE'), ('August 15-A.D. 1097', 'DATE'), ('May', 'DATE')"
"Indolence or weakness had prevented the Franks from investing the entire circuit; and the perpetual freedom of two gates relieved the wants
 and recruited the garrison of the city.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
Insolence of the Franks.,"('Insolence of the Franks', 'PERSON')"
"Instead of the naked spectacles which corrupted the
 manners of the Greeks, and banished from the stadium the
 virgins and matrons, the pompous decoration of the lists was
 crowned with the presence of chaste and high-born beauty,
 from whose hands the conqueror received the prize of his
 dexterity and courage.","('Greeks', 'NORP')"
Institutions of the French or Latin Kingdom.,"('French', 'NORP'), ('Latin Kingdom', 'LOC')"
"It is a more easy
 task to provoke the metaphysical disputes of the Greeks, to
 drive into the cloister the victims of anarchy or despotism,
 to sanctify the patience of slaves and cowards, or to assume
 the merit of the humanity and benevolence of modern
 Christians.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"It is expressly declared in the
 Assise of Jerusalem, that after instituting, for his knights
 and barons, the court of peers, in which he presided
 himself, Godfrey of Bouillon established a second tribunal,
 in which his person was represented by his viscount.","('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Bouillon', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"It is in the person of this
 Norman chief that we may seek for the coolest policy and
 ambition, with a small allay of religious fanaticism.","('Norman', 'PERSON')"
"It may occasion some surprise that the Roman pontiff should erect, in the heart of France, the tribunal from whence he hurled his anathemas against the king; but our surprise will vanish so soon as we form a just estimate of a king of France of the eleventh century.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('the eleventh century', 'DATE')"
"It was not then as a mode of proof that the
 combat was received, nor as making negative evidence,
 (according to the supposition of Montesquieu; (139)) but in
 every case the right to offer battle was founded on the
 right to pursue by arms the redress of an injury; and the
 judicial combat was fought on the same principle, and with
 the same spirit, as a private duel.","('Montesquieu', 'PERSON'), ('139', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was not till after a
 long and obstinate contest that Babylon and Rome could
 prevail against the obstinacy of the people, the craggy
 ground that might supersede the necessity of fortifications,
 and the walls and towers that would have fortified the most
 accessible plain. (105)","('Babylon', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('105', 'CARDINAL')"
"Jerusalem has derived some reputation from the number and
 importance of her memorable sieges.","('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
Law of judicial combats.,"('Law', 'PERSON')"
Legend of the Holy Lance.,"('Legend of the Holy Lance', 'PERSON')"
"Like hounds, or hawks, who had strayed from the lawful owner, they might be lost and claimed: the slave and falcon were of the same value; but three slaves, or twelve
 oxen, were accumulated to equal the price of the war- horse; and a sum of three hundred pieces of gold was fixed, in the age of chivalry, as the equivalent of the more noble animal. (143)","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('143', 'CARDINAL')"
"Many of
 the pilgrims had escaped from their lords under the banner
 of the cross; and it was the policy of the French princes to
 tempt their stay by the assurance of the rights and
 privileges of freemen.","('French', 'NORP')"
"March through the lesser Asia, July-September.","('March', 'DATE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('July-September', 'DATE')"
"Might not the Christians more reasonably hope that the
 rivers would open for their passage; that the walls of their
 strongest cities would fall at the sound of their trumpets;
 and that the sun would be arrested in his mid career, to
 allow them time for the destruction of the infidels?","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Nice
 was invested by land and water; and a Greek emissary
 persuaded the inhabitants to accept his master's protection,
 and to save themselves, by a timely surrender, from the rage
 of the savages of Europe.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"No sooner had Godfrey of Bouillon
 accepted the office of supreme magistrate, than he solicited
 the public and private advice of the Latin pilgrims, who
 were the best skilled in the statutes and customs of Europe.","('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Bouillon', 'PERSON'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"None of the great sovereigns of Europe embarked their
 persons in the first crusade.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Nor was this sufficient;
 Daimbert claimed the immediate property of Jerusalem and
 Jaffa; instead of a firm and generous refusal, the hero
 negotiated with the priest; a quarter of either city was
 ceded to the church; and the modest bishop was satisfied
 with an eventual reversion of the rest, on the death of
 Godfrey without children, or on the future acquisition of a
 new seat at Cairo or Damascus.","('Daimbert', 'PERSON'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Jaffa', 'GPE'), ('quarter', 'CARDINAL'), ('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Cairo', 'GPE'), ('Damascus', 'GPE')"
"Notwithstanding these fortifications, the city had been
 repeatedly taken by the Persians, the Arabs, the Greeks, and
 the Turks; so large a circuit must have yielded many
 pervious points of attack; and in a siege that was formed
 about the middle of October, the vigour of the execution
 could alone justify the boldness of the attempt.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('about the middle of October', 'DATE')"
"Of
 these savage heroes of the cross, Tancred alone betrayed
 some sentiments of compassion; yet we may praise the more
 selfish lenity of Raymond, who granted a capitulation and
 safe-conduct to the garrison of the citadel.","('Tancred', 'PERSON'), ('Raymond', 'PERSON')"
"Of such laws, the first and indispensable condition is the
 assent of those whose obedience they require, and for whose
 benefit they are designed.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Of the diocese of
 Marseilles, there was a priest of low cunning and loose
 manners, and his name was Peter Bartholemy.","('Marseilles', 'GPE'), ('Peter Bartholemy', 'PERSON')"
"Of the first crusaders, three hundred thousand had already perished, before a single city was rescued from the infidels, before their graver and more noble brethren had completed the preparations of their enterprise.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('three hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Of the multitude of recreant warriors, the
 names (says an historian) are blotted from the book of life;
 and the opprobrious epithet of the rope-dancers was applied
 to the deserters who dropped in the night from the walls of
 Antioch.","('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"Of their troops the most numerous portion were
 natives of France: the Low Countries, the banks of the
 Rhine, and Apulia, sent a powerful reinforcement: some bands
 of adventurers were drawn from Spain, Lombardy, and England;
 (77) and from the distant bogs and mountains of Ireland or
 Scotland (78) issued some naked and savage fanatics,
 ferocious at home but unwarlike abroad.","('France', 'GPE'), ('the Low Countries', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Lombardy', 'GPE'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('77', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ireland', 'GPE'), ('Scotland', 'GPE'), ('78', 'CARDINAL')"
"Of these the four most conspicuous were the
 prince of Galilee, the lord of Sidon and Caesarea, and the
 counts of Jaffa and Tripoli, who, perhaps with the constable
 and marshal, (137) were in a special manner the compeers and
 judges of each other.","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Galilee', 'GPE'), ('Sidon', 'GPE'), ('Caesarea', 'GPE'), ('Jaffa', 'GPE'), ('Tripoli', 'GPE'), ('137', 'CARDINAL')"
"Of these, and of other bands of enthusiasts, the first
 and most easy warfare was against the Jews, the murderers of
 the Son of God.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('the Son of God', 'PERSON')"
"On
 the fifth day, the crusaders made a general assault, in the
 fanatic hope of battering down the walls without engines,
 and of scaling them without ladders.","('the fifth day', 'DATE')"
"On the
 confines of Hungary he was stopped three weeks by a
 Christian people, to whom the name, or at least the abuse,
 of the cross was justly odious.","('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('three weeks', 'DATE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"On the
 return of spring, Godfrey was persuaded to occupy a pleasant
 and plentiful camp in Asia; and no sooner had he passed the
 Bosphorus, than the Greek vessels were suddenly recalled to
 the opposite shore.","('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"On the festival of St. Peter and St. Paul, the gates of Antioch were thrown open: a martial psalm, ""Let the Lord arise, and let his enemies be scattered!""  was chanted by a procession of priests and monks; the battle array was marshalled in twelve divisions, in honour of the twelve apostles; and the holy lance, in the absence of Raymond, was entrusted to the hands of his chaplain.","('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('St. Paul', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('Raymond', 'PERSON')"
Palestine could add nothing to the strength or safety of the Latins; and fanaticism alone could pretend to justify the conquest of that distant and narrow province.,"('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('Latins', 'NORP')"
"Perhaps it is too rigorously applied
 to the same persons and the same hour; the example of the
 virtuous Godfrey awakened the piety of his companions; while
 they cleansed their bodies, they purified their minds; nor
 shall I believe that the most ardent in slaughter and rapine
 were the foremost in the procession to the holy sepulchre.","('the same hour', 'TIME'), ('Godfrey', 'PERSON')"
"Philip the First, of France, supported with patience the censures which he had provoked by his scandalous life and adulterous marriage.","('Philip', 'PERSON'), ('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('France', 'GPE')"
Policy of the Greek Emperor Alexius.,"('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Alexius', 'PERSON')"
"Policy of the emperor Alexius Comnenus, A.D. 1096, December - A.D. 1097, May.","('Alexius Comnenus', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 1096', 'DATE'), ('December - A.D. 1097', 'DATE'), ('May', 'DATE')"
"Private or public interest suppressed the murmurs of the dukes and counts; but a French baron (he is supposed to be Robert of Paris (71)) presumed to ascend the throne, and to place himself by the side of Alexius.","('French', 'NORP'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('71', 'DATE'), ('Alexius', 'PERSON')"
"Raymond's Tower was
 reduced to ashes by the fire of the besieged, but his
 colleague was more vigilant and successful; the enemies
 were driven by his archers from the rampart; the draw-bridge
 was let down; and on a Friday, at three in the afternoon,
 the day and hour of the passion, Godfrey of Bouillon stood
 victorious on the walls of Jerusalem.","(""Raymond's Tower"", 'FAC'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('three in the afternoon', 'TIME'), ('the day and hour', 'TIME'), ('Godfrey', 'PERSON'), ('Bouillon', 'PERSON'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
"Robert, duke of Normandy,
 was the eldest son of William the Conqueror; but on his
 father's death he was deprived of the kingdom of England, by
 his own indolence and the activity of his brother Rufus.","('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Normandy', 'GPE'), ('William the Conqueror', 'PERSON'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('Rufus', 'PERSON')"
"Seige and conquest of Jerusalem, A.D. 1099, June 7 - July 15.","('Seige', 'PERSON'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1099', 'DATE'), ('June 7 - July 15', 'DATE')"
"Several princes of the Norman race
 accompanied this veteran general; and his cousin Tancred (53)
 was the partner, rather than the servant, of the war.","('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('Tancred', 'PERSON'), ('53', 'DATE')"
"Since the
 Turkish conquest, the paths of pilgrimage were obliterated;
 the chiefs themselves had an imperfect notion of the length
 of the way and the state of their enemies; and such was the
 stupidity of the people, that, at the sight of the first
 city or castle beyond the limits of their knowledge, they
 were ready to ask whether that was not the Jerusalem, the
 term and object of their labours.","('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
"Sixty thousand horse had been
 reviewed in the camp: before the end of the siege they were
 diminished to two thousand, and scarcely two hundred fit for
 service could be mustered on the day of battle.","('Sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('two thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('two hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('the day', 'DATE')"
"So popular was the cause of Urban, so weighty was his influence, that the council which he summoned at Placentia (7) was composed of two hundred bishops of Italy, France, Burgandy, Swabia, and Bavaria.","('Urban', 'NORP'), ('Placentia', 'ORG'), ('two hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Burgandy', 'GPE'), ('Swabia', 'GPE'), ('Bavaria', 'GPE')"
"Some counts and
 gentlemen, at the head of three thousand horse, attended the
 motions of the multitude to partake in the spoil; but their
 genuine leaders (may we credit such folly?) were a goose and
 a goat, who were carried in the front, and to whom these
 worthy Christians ascribed an infusion of the divine spirit.
 (35)","('three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('35', 'CARDINAL')"
"Some efforts were made by the Provincials to substitute a cross, a ring, or a tabernacle, in the place of the holy lance, which soon vanished in contempt and oblivion. (100)","('Provincials', 'NORP'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"Some glory might be derived from the
 prodigious inequality of numbers, though I shall not count
 the myriads of horse and foot on the side of the
 Fatimites; but, except three thousand Ethiopians or Blacks,
 who were armed with flails or scourges of iron, the
 Barbarians of the South fled on the first onset, and
 afforded a pleasing comparison between the active valour of
 the Turks and the sloth and effeminacy of the natives of
 Egypt.","('Fatimites', 'NORP'), ('three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ethiopians', 'NORP'), ('Blacks', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('South', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"Some miles before they could reach
 Dorylaeum in Phrygia, the left, and least numerous, division
 was surprised, and attacked, and almost oppressed, by the
 Turkish cavalry. (84)","('Some miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Dorylaeum', 'PRODUCT'), ('Phrygia', 'GPE'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('84', 'CARDINAL')"
"Stephen, count of Chartres,
 of Blois, and of Troyes, was one of the richest princes of
 the age; and the number of his castles has been compared to
 the three hundred and sixty-five days of the year.","('Stephen', 'PERSON'), ('Chartres', 'PERSON'), ('Blois', 'GPE'), ('Troyes', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('three hundred and sixty-five days', 'DATE'), ('the year', 'DATE')"
"Such was the fortune, or at least the
 apprehension of the Greek emperor Alexius Comnenus, whose
 name has already appeared in this history, and whose conduct
 is so differently represented by his daughter Anne, (64) and
 by the Latin writers. (65)","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Alexius Comnenus', 'PERSON'), ('Anne', 'PERSON'), ('64', 'DATE'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('65', 'CARDINAL')"
"Superior to the
 private factions of the chiefs, he reserved his enmity for
 the enemies of Christ; and though he gained a kingdom by the
 attempt, his pure and disinterested zeal was acknowledged by
 his rivals.","('Christ', 'PERSON')"
Syrians.,"('Syrians', 'NORP')"
"The
 Tetrapolis, or four cities, if they retained their name and
 position, must have left a large vacuity in a circumference
 of twelve miles; and that measure, as well as the number of
 four hundred towers, are not perfectly consistent with the
 five gates, so often mentioned in the history of the siege.","('Tetrapolis', 'NORP'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('twelve miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('four hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 ancient hosts of Darius and Xerxes labour under the same
 doubt of a vague and indefinite magnitude; but I am inclined
 to believe, that a larger number has never been contained
 within the lines of a single camp, than at the siege of
 Nice, the first operation of the Latin princes.","('Darius', 'PERSON'), ('Xerxes', 'PERSON'), ('Nice', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"The
 circumjacent country is equally destitute of trees for the
 uses of shade or building, but some large beams were
 discovered in a cave by the crusaders: a wood near Sichem,
 the enchanted grove of Tasso, (109) was cut down: the
 necessary timber was transported to the camp by the vigour
 and dexterity of Tancred; and the engines were framed by
 some Genoese artists, who had fortunately landed in the
 harbour of Jaffa.","('Sichem', 'GPE'), ('Tasso', 'GPE'), ('109', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tancred', 'GPE'), ('Genoese', 'NORP'), ('Jaffa', 'LOC')"
"The
 difficulty of procuring subsistence for so many myriads of
 men and horses engaged them to separate their forces: their
 choice or situation determined the road; and it was agreed
 to meet in the neighbourhood of Constantinople, and from
 thence to begin their operations against the Turks.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Turks', 'NORP')"
"The
 example and footsteps of Peter were closely pursued by
 another fanatic, the monk Godescal, whose sermons had swept
 away fifteen or twenty thousand peasants from the villages
 of Germany.","('Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Godescal', 'PERSON'), ('fifteen or twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"The
 importance of the victory was proved by the hasty retreat of
 the sultan: reserving ten thousand guards of the relics of
 his army, Soliman evacuated the kingdom of Roum, and
 hastened to implore the aid, and kindle the resentment, of
 his Eastern brethren.","('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Soliman', 'PERSON'), ('Roum', 'GPE'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"The
 latter was a veteran warrior, who had fought against the
 Saracens of Spain, and who consecrated his declining age,
 not only to the deliverance, but to the perpetual service,
 of the holy sepulchre.","('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE')"
"The
 lofty and solid walls of Nice were covered by a deep ditch,
 and flanked by three hundred and seventy towers; and on the
 verge of Christendom, the Moslems were trained in arms, and
 inflamed by religion.","('Nice', 'GPE'), ('three hundred and seventy', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christendom', 'NORP'), ('Moslems', 'NORP')"
"The
 pride of Hugh of Vermandois was soothed by the honours of his
 captivity; and in the brother of the French king, the
 example of submission was prevalent and weighty.","('Hugh of Vermandois', 'PERSON'), ('French', 'NORP')"
"The
 savage countries of Hungary and Bulgaria were whitened with
 their bones: their vanguard was cut in pieces by the Turkish
 sultan; and the loss of the first adventure, by the sword,
 or climate, or fatigue, has already been stated at three
 hundred thousand men.","('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('Bulgaria', 'GPE'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('three\r\n hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 soldiers were dismissed to their quarters with an injunction to fortify their minds and bodies for the approaching conflict, freely to bestow their last pittance on themselves and their horses, and to expect with the dawn of day the signal of victory.","('the dawn of day', 'DATE')"
"The Christians
 of Antioch were numerous and discontented: Phirouz, a Syrian
 renegade, had acquired the favour of the emir and the command
 of three towers; and the merit of his repentance disguised
 to the Latins, and perhaps to himself, the foul design of
 perfidy and treason.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Phirouz', 'PERSON'), ('Syrian', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Latins', 'NORP')"
"The Christians affirmed that their inalienable title to the
 promised land had been sealed by the blood of their divine
 Saviour; it was their right and duty to rescue their
 inheritance from the unjust possessors, who profaned his
 sepulchre, and oppressed the pilgrimage of his disciples.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"The Greek praefect of Bulgaria
 commanded a regular force; at the trumpet of the Hungarian king, the eighth or the tenth of his martial subjects bent their bows and mounted on horseback; their policy was insidious, and their retaliation on these pious
 robbers was unrelenting and bloody. (39)","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Bulgaria', 'GPE'), ('Hungarian', 'NORP'), ('the eighth', 'DATE'), ('tenth', 'ORDINAL')"
"The Hungarians still
 smarted with the wounds which they had received from the
 first pilgrims: in their turn they had abused the right of
 defence and retaliation; and they had reason to apprehend a
 severe revenge from a hero of the same nation, and who was
 engaged in the same cause.","('Hungarians', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The Norman was flattered by the assurance of an independent principality; and Alexius eluded, rather than denied, his daring demand of the office of great domestic, or general of the East.","('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The ambassadors of the Greek emperor, Alexius Comnenus, were introduced to plead the distress of their sovereign, and the danger of Constantinople, which was divided only by a narrow sea from the victorious Turks, the common enemies of the Christian name.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Alexius Comnenus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The asperity of national prejudice was
 softened; and the community of religion and arms spread a
 similar colour and generous emulation over the face of
 Christendom.","('Christendom', 'NORP')"
"The astonished patriarch dismissed him with epistles of credit and complaint; and no sooner did he land at Bari, than Peter hastened to kiss the feet of the Roman pontiff.","('Bari', 'PERSON'), ('Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The austerity of the convent soon evaporated in the exercise
 of arms; the world was scandalized by the pride, avarice,
 and corruption of these Christian soldiers; their claims of
 immunity and jurisdiction disturbed the harmony of the
 church and state; and the public peace was endangered by
 their jealous emulation.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The bath and white garment of the novice were an indecent
 copy of the regeneration of baptism: his sword, which he
 offered on the altar, was blessed by the ministers of
 religion: his solemn reception was preceded by fasts and
 vigils; and he was created a knight in the name of God, of
 St. George, and of St. Michael the archangel.","('St. George', 'GPE'), ('St. Michael', 'GPE')"
"The battle is described with as much disorder as it was
 fought; but we may observe the tent of Kerboga, a movable
 and spacious palace, enriched with the luxury of Asia, and
 capable of holding above two thousand persons; we may
 distinguish his three thousand guards, who were cased, the
 horse as well as the men, in complete steel.","('Kerboga', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('two thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('three thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The best
 and most ostensible reason was the impossibility of passing the sea and accomplishing their vow, without the license and the vessels of Alexius; but they cherished a secret hope, that as soon as they trod the continent of Asia, their swords would obliterate their shame, and dissolve the engagement, which on his side might not be very faithfully performed.","('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The bulwarks had been completely
 destroyed and imperfectly restored: the Jews, their nation,
 and worship, were forever banished; but nature is less
 changeable than man, and the site of Jerusalem, though
 somewhat softened and somewhat removed, was still strong
 against the assaults of an enemy.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
"The caliph of
 Egypt embraced this opportunity of weakness and discord to
 recover his ancient possessions; and his sultan Aphdal
 besieged Jerusalem and Tyre, expelled the children of Ortok,
 and restored in Palestine the civil and ecclesiastical
 authority of the Fatimites. (102)","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Aphdal', 'PERSON'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Tyre', 'PERSON'), ('Ortok', 'NORP'), ('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('Fatimites', 'NORP'), ('102', 'CARDINAL')"
"The capital of
 Syria was protected by the River Orontes; and the iron
 bridge, of nine arches, derives its name from the massy gates of the two towers which are constructed at either end.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('the River Orontes', 'LOC'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
The chiefs of the first crusade.,"('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The cloud and pillar of Jehovah
 had marched before the Israelites into the promised land.","('Jehovah', 'GPE'), ('Israelites', 'NORP')"
"The conquest of Asia was undertaken and achieved by Alexander, with thirty-five thousand Macedonians and Greeks; (73) and his best hope was in the strength and discipline of his phalanx of infantry.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('thirty-five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Macedonians', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('73', 'CARDINAL')"
"The consort and the principal
 servants of Soliman had been honourably restored without
 ransom; and the emperor's generosity to the miscreants (83) was interpreted as treason to the Christian cause.","('Soliman', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The coolest scepticism will remember, that of
 these religious volunteers great numbers never beheld
 Constantinople and Nice.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Nice', 'GPE')"
"The copious energy of her language sinks under the efforts
 of the princess Anne: (76) the images of locusts, of leaves
 and flowers, of the sands of the sea, or the stars of
 heaven, imperfectly represent what she had seen and heard;
 and the daughter of Alexius exclaims, that Europe was
