Sentence,Entities
"""How often,"" was he accustomed to say, ""is it the interest of four or five ministers to combine together to deceive their
 sovereign!","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL')"
"""It well becomes the Persians,""  replied Galerius, with a transport of fury which seemed to convulse his whole frame, ""it well becomes the Persians to expatiate on the vicissitudes of fortune, and calmly to read us lectures on the virtues of moderation.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"""The soil was dry and fertile, the air is pure and wholesome, and, though extremely hot during the summer months, this country seldom feels those sultry and noxious winds to which the coasts of Istria and some parts of Italy are exposed.","('the summer months', 'DATE'), ('Istria', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
(1),"('1', 'CARDINAL')"
(111),"('111', 'CARDINAL')"
(112),"('112', 'CARDINAL')"
"(114)
 Description of Salona and the adjacent country.","('114', 'CARDINAL'), ('Salona', 'GPE')"
"(114)
Description of Salona and the adjacent country.","('114', 'CARDINAL'), ('Salona', 'GPE')"
(115),"('115', 'CARDINAL')"
(119),"('119', 'CARDINAL')"
"(15)
(3),"('3', 'CARDINAL')"
(31),"('31', 'CARDINAL')"
(33),"('33', 'CARDINAL')"
"(5)
Association and character of Maximian.","('5', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
(51),"('51', 'CARDINAL')"
"(73)
Negotiation for peace.","('73', 'CARDINAL')"
"(9)
Association of two caesars.","('9)\r\nAssociation', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 surprise, especially in the night-time, was for the most
 part fatal to a Persian army.","('Persian', 'NORP')"
"A circus, a theatre, a mint,
 a palace, baths, which bore the name of their founder
 Maximian; porticoes adorned with statues, and a double
 circumference of walls, contributed to the beauty of the new
 capital.","('Maximian', 'NORP')"
"A confederacy of five
 Moorish nations issued from their deserts to invade the
 peaceful provinces. (40) Julian had assumed the purple at 
 Carthage. (41)","('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moorish', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"A just estimate of greatness, and the assurance of immortal fame, improve
 our relish for the pleasures of retirement; but the Roman emperor had filled too important a character in the world to enjoy without alloy the comforts and security of a private condition.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"A languid and affected eloquence
 was still retained in the pay and service of the emperors,
 who encouraged not any arts except those which contributed
 to the gratification of their pride or the defence of their
 power. (123)","('123', 'CARDINAL')"
"A miserable village still preserves the name of Salona; but so late as the sixteenth century the remains of a theatre, and a confused prospect of broken arches and marble columns,  continued to attest its ancient splendour. (116)","('Salona', 'GPE'), ('the sixteenth century', 'DATE'), ('116', 'CARDINAL')"
"A slight resistance was followed by a dreadful carnage, and
 in the general confusion the wounded monarch (for Narses
 commanded his armies in person) fled towards the deserts of
 Media.","('Narses', 'PERSON')"
A.D. 285.,"('285', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 286.,"('A.D. 286', 'DATE')"
A.D. 287.,"('A.D. 287', 'DATE')"
A.D. 294.,"('294', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 296,"('A.D. 296', 'DATE')"
A.D. 296.,"('A.D. 296', 'DATE')"
A.D. 297.,"('A.D. 297', 'DATE')"
A.D. 303.,"('303', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 313.,"('313', 'CARDINAL')"
Abdication of Diocletian and Maximian.,"('Abdication of Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'NORP')"
"About six or seven miles from the city Diocletian constructed a magnificent palace, and we may infer, from the greatness of the work, how long he had meditated his design of abdicating
 the empire.","('About six or seven miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Above all, they regretted the large amount of the revenue of
 Britain, whilst they confessed that such a province well
 deserved to become the seat of an independent monarchy. (27) Power of Carausius.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('27', 'CARDINAL')"
"According to his religion and situation, each writer chooses either Diocletian, or Constantine, or Valens, or Theodosius, for the object of his invectives; but they unanimously agree in representing the burden of the public impositions, and particularly the land-tax and capitation, as the intolerable and increasing grievance of their own times.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Achilleus at Alexandria, and even the Blemmyes, 
 renewed, or rather continued, their incursions into the
 Upper Egypt.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Blemmyes', 'NORP'), ('the\r\n Upper Egypt', 'LOC')"
"Adversity had confirmed the Roman discipline, while the 
 barbarians, elated by success, were become so negligent and
 remiss that, in the moment when they least expected it, they
 were surprised by the active conduct of Galerius, who,
 attended only by two horsemen, had with his own eyes
 secretly examined the state and position of their camp.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Africa and Britain, the
 Rhine, the Danube, and the Nile, furnished their respective
 trophies; but the most distinguished ornament was of a more
 singular nature, a Persian victory followed by an important
 conquest.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"After a siege of eight months,
 Alexandria, wasted by the sword and by fire, implored the
 clemency of the conqueror, but it experienced the full
 extent of his severity.","('eight months', 'DATE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"After the example
 of Marcus, he gave himself a colleague in the person of
 Maximian, on whom he bestowed at first the title of Caesar,
 and afterwards that of Augustus. (6)","('Marcus', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('6', 'CARDINAL')"
"Although the youth of 
 Constantius had been spent in arms, he was endowed with a
 mild and amiable disposition, and the popular voice had long
 since acknowledged him worthy of the rank which he at last
 attained.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"Among the Armenian nobles appeared an ally whose
 fortunes are too remarkable to pass unnoticed.","('Armenian', 'NORP')"
"And when, after
 a vast expense of time and labour, a new armament was
 launched into the water, (29) the Imperial troops, 
 unaccustomed to that element, were easily baffled and
 defeated by the veteran sailors of the usurper.","('29', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
Answer of Gallerius.,"('Gallerius', 'PERSON')"
"Apharban
 opened the conference by expressing his master's gratitude
 for the generous treatment of his family, and by soliciting
 the liberty of those illustrious captives.","('Apharban', 'PERSON')"
"Apharban concluded his discourse in
 the style of Eastern allegory, by observing that the Roman
 and Persian monarchies were the two eyes of the world, which
 would remain imperfect and mutilated if either of them
 should be put out.","('Apharban', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
April 1.,"('April 1', 'DATE')"
"Armenia was chosen for the place of exile, and a
 large district was assigned to the Scythian horde, on which
 they might feed their flocks and herds, and remove their
 encampment from one place to another, according to the
 different seasons of the year.","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('the\r\n different seasons of the year', 'DATE')"
Armenia.,"('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"As
 the minister of peace, he was received with every mark of
 politeness and friendship; but, under the pretence of
 allowing him the necessary repose after so long a journey,
 the audience of Probus was deferred from day to day, and he
 attended the slow motions of the king, till at length he was
 admitted to his presence, near the river Asprudus, in Media.","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"As he wished to
 secure the obedience of Maximian, he exacted from him either
 a general assurance that he would submit his actions to the
 authority of his benefactor, or a particular promise that he
 would descend from the throne whenever he should receive the
 advice and the example.","('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"As long as that enthusiasm prevailed, many of the
 nobles imprudently displayed their zeal in the cause of
 freedom; and after the successors of Probus had withdrawn
 their countenance from the republican party, the senators
 were unable to disguise their impotent resentment.","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('the republican party', 'ORG')"
"As long as the
 emperors resided at Rome, that assembly might be oppressed,
 but it could scarcely be neglected.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"As soon as Diocletian
 entered into the twentieth year of his reign, he celebrated
 that memorable era, as well as the success of his arms by
 the pomp of a Roman triumph. (85) Maximian, the equal partner 
 of his power, was his only companion in the glory of that
 day.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('the twentieth year', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('that\r\n day', 'DATE')"
"As soon as Diocletian had indulged his private resentment,
 and asserted the majesty of supreme power, he yielded to the
 submissive entreaties of the Caesar, and permitted him to
 retrieve his own honour, as well as that of the Roman arms.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"As soon as a bloody
 sacrifice had been offered to prudence or to revenge,
 Diocletian, by his seasonable intercession, saved the
 remaining few whom he had never designed to punish, gently
 censured the severity of his stern colleague, and enjoyed
 the comparison of a golden and an iron age, which was
 universally applied to their opposite maxims of government.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as he had divested himself of the purple,
 he withdrew from the gazing multitude, and, traversing the
 city in a covered chariot, proceeded without delay to the
 favourite retirement which he had chosen in his native
 country of Dalmatia.","('Dalmatia', 'GPE')"
"As soon as this difficulty was removed, a solemn peace was
 concluded and ratified between the two nations.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"As the
 sovereign of Italy, Maximian was intrusted with the care of
 extinguishing this troublesome rather than dangerous spirit,
 and the task was perfectly suited to his cruel temper.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"As the reign of Diocletian was more illustrious than that of
 any of his predecessors, so was his birth more abject and
 obscure.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"As they agreed with the Christians
 in a few mysterious points of faith, they attacked the
 remainder of their theological system with all the fury of
 civil war.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Asclepiodotus
 had no sooner disembarked the imperial troops than he set
 fire to his ships; and, as the expedition proved fortunate,
 his heroic conduct was universally admired.","('Asclepiodotus', 'PERSON')"
"At
 length, however, on the first of March, Diocletian once more
 appeared in public, but so pale and emaciated that he could
 scarcely have been recognised by those to whom his person
 was the most familiar.","('the first of March', 'DATE'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"At the head of a chosen army 
 of twenty-five thousand men Galerius again passed the
 Euphrates; but, instead of exposing his legions in the open
 plains of Mesopotamia, he advanced through the mountains of
 Armenia, where he found the inhabitants devoted to his
 cause, and the country as favourable to the operations of
 infantry as it was inconvenient for the motions of cavalry.
 (70)","('twenty-five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Mesopotamia', 'LOC'), ('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"At the same time that Diocletian chastised the past crimes
 of the Egyptians, he provided for their future safety and
 happiness by many wise regulations, which were confirmed and
 enforced under the succeeding reigns. (49)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Egyptians', 'NORP')"
"Before the preparations were finished, Constantius received
 the intelligence of the tyrant's death, and it was
 considered as a sure presage of the approaching victory.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"Before we dismiss the consideration of the life and
 character of Diocletian, we may for a moment direct our view
 to the place of his retirement.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Born on
 the confines of the Franks, he courted the friendship of
 that formidable people by the flattering imitation of their
 dress and manners.","('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"Britain had none but domestic enemies to dread; and as long
 as the governors preserved their fidelity, and the troops
 their discipline, the incursions of the naked savages of
 Scotland or Ireland could never materially affect the safety
 of the province.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Scotland', 'GPE'), ('Ireland', 'GPE')"
"But after the
 adoption of the two Caesars, the emperors, themselves
 retiring to a less laborious scene of action, devolved on
 their adopted sons the defence of the Danube and of the
 Rhine.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"But even the omnipotence of Jovius and Herculius was
 insufficient to sustain the weight of the public
 administration.","('Jovius', 'PRODUCT'), ('Herculius', 'PERSON')"
"But he yielded, however
 reluctantly, to the ascendant which his wiser colleague had
 acquired over him, and retired immediately after his
 abdication to a villa in Lucania, where it was almost
 impossible that such an impatient spirit could find any
 lasting tranquillity.","('Lucania', 'GPE')"
"But if 
 Diocletian had been convinced of the reality of that
 valuable art, far from extinguishing the memory, he would
 have converted the operation of it to the benefit of the
 public revenue.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"But the
 sentiments of the East were very different from those of the
 West.","('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"But the adoption of the two Caesars restored new 
 vigour to the Roman arms; and while the Rhine was guarded by
 the presence of Maximian, his brave associate Constantius
 assumed the conduct of the British war.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('British', 'NORP')"
"But the crafty Menapian
 foresaw and prevented the severity of the emperor.","('Menapian', 'NORP')"
"But the most 
 fatal though secret wound which the senate received from the
 hands of Diocletian and Maximian was inflicted by the
 inevitable operation of their absence.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"But the reign of Diocletian had flowed with a;
 tide of uninterrupted success; nor was it till after he had
 vanquished all his enemies, and accomplished all his
 designs, that he seems to have entertained any serious
 thoughts of resigning the empire.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"But the sovereignty of the capital was 
 gradually annihilated in the extent of conquest; the
 provinces rose to the same level, and the vanquished nations
 acquired the name and privileges, without imbibing the
 partial affections, of Romans.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"But though the character
 of Galerius had in general very little affinity with that of
 Alexander, he imitated, after his victory, the amiable
 behaviour of the Macedonian towards the family of Darius.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Macedonian', 'NORP'), ('Darius', 'PERSON')"
"But we have preferred for the sake of
 perspicuity, first to describe the more perfect form of
 Diocletian's government, and afterwards to relate the
 actions of his reign, following rather the natural order of
 the events than the dates of a very doubtful chronology.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"But, on the news of his distress, the Roman
 troops hastened from all sides to his relief, and before the
 evening he had satisfied his honour and revenge by the
 slaughter of six thousand Alemanni. (36)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('six thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON')"
"By
 associating a friend and a fellow-soldier to the favours of
 government, Diocletian, in a time of public danger, provided
 for the defence both of the East and of the West.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"By
 investing a luxurious youth with the honours of the purple,
 Marcus had discharged a debt of private gratitude, at the
 expense, indeed, of the happiness of the state.","('Marcus', 'PERSON')"
"By comparing the present remains with the
 precepts of Vitruvius, the several parts of the building,
 the baths, bedchamber, the atrium, the basilica, and the
 Cyzicene, Corinthian, and Egyptian halls have been described
 with some degree of precision, or at least of probability.","('Vitruvius', 'GPE'), ('Cyzicene', 'NORP'), ('Corinthian', 'NORP'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP')"
"By seizing the fleet of Boulogne, Carausius had deprived his
 master of the means of pursuit and revenge.","('Boulogne', 'PRODUCT'), ('Carausius', 'PERSON')"
"By such infamous arts,""  added
 Diocletian, ""the best and wisest princes are sold to the
 venal corruption of their courtiers."" (113)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('113', 'CARDINAL')"
"By the prudent measures of
 Diocletian, the numbers of the Praetorians were insensibly
 reduced, their privileges abolished, (94) and their place 
 supplied by two faithful legions of Illyricum, New bodies of guards, Jovians and Herculians.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorians', 'NORP'), ('94', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Illyricum', 'ORG'), ('Jovians', 'NORP'), ('Herculians', 'NORP')"
"By the taste
 of the monarch, and at the expense of the people, Nicomedia
 acquired, in he space of a few years, a degree of
 magnificence which might appear to have required the labour
 of ages, and became inferior only to Rome, Alexandria, and
 Antioch in extent or populousness. (91)","('Nicomedia', 'PERSON'), ('a few years', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"Carausius
 still preserved the possession of Boulogne and the adjacent
 country.","('Carausius', 'PERSON'), ('Boulogne', 'PERSON')"
Cession of five provinces beyond the Tigris.,"('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
Conduct of Diocletian in Egypt.,"('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"Congenial
 to the avarice of the human heart, it was studied in China
 as in Europe, with equal eagerness and with equal success.","('China', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
Debasement of Rome and of the senate.,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
Defeat of Galerius.,"('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
Departments and harmony of the four princes.,"('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"Diocletian
 acquired the glory of giving to the world the first example
 of a resignation (106) which has not been very frequently 
 imitated by succeeding monarchs.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('106', 'CARDINAL')"
"Diocletian
 was successively promoted to the government of Maesia, the
 honours of the consulship, and the important command of the
 guards of the palace.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Maesia', 'GPE')"
"Diocletian and his colleague, who justly dreaded the
 enterprising spirit of Carausius, resigned to him the
 sovereignty of Britain, and reluctantly admitted their
 perfidious servant to a participation of the Imperial
 honours. (30)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Carausius', 'PERSON'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('30', 'CARDINAL')"
"Diocletian assumes the diadem, and introduces the Persian ceremonial.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"Diocletian received into his confidence Aristobulus,
 the principal minister of the house of Carus, respected the
 lives, the fortunes, and the dignity of his adversaries, and
 even continued in their respective stations the greater
 number of the servants of Carinus. (4)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Aristobulus', 'PERSON'), ('Carus', 'PERSON'), ('Carinus', 'PERSON'), ('4', 'CARDINAL')"
"Diocletian was a man of sense, who, in the course of private as well as public life, had formed a just estimate both of himself and of mankind: nor is it easy to conceive that in substituting the manners of Persia to those of Rome he was seriously actuated by so mean a principle as that of vanity.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Diocletian, on his side, opened the campaign in Egypt by the siege of
 Alexandria, cut off the aqueducts which conveyed the waters
 of the Nile into every quarter of that immense city, (43) and, 
 rendering his camp impregnable to the sallies of the
 besieged multitude, he pushed his reiterated attacks with
 caution and vigour.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('quarter', 'CARDINAL'), ('43', 'CARDINAL')"
"Diocletian, who, from a servile origin, had raised himself
 to the throne, passed the nine last years of his life in a
 private condition.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('the nine last years', 'DATE')"
"Diocletian, with the calm dignity which he constantly
 assumed, fixed his own station in the city of Antioch, from
 whence he prepared and directed the military operations. (63)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('63', 'CARDINAL')"
"Disgusted with the licentious familiarity of the
 people, he quitted Rome with precipitation thirteen days
 before it was expected that he should have appeared in the
 senate invested with the ensigns of the consular dignity. (92)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('thirteen days', 'DATE')"
"During a long period,
 however, the remains of the ancient constitution and the
 influence of custom preserved the dignity of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"During the
 three years which Constantius employed in preparing a fleet
 adequate to the conquest of Britain, he secured the coast of
 Gaul, invaded the country of the Franks, and deprived the
 usurper of the assistance of those powerful allies.","('the\r\n three years', 'DATE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"During the long series of troubles which
 agitated Gaul, from the reign of Gallienus to that of
 Diocletian, the condition of those servile peasants was
 peculiarly miserable; and they experienced at once the
 complicated tyranny of their masters, of the barbarians, of
 the soldiers, and of the officers of the revenue.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Gallienus', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"During the space of seven years it was possessed by Carausius; and fortune continued propitious to a rebellion
 supported with courage and ability.","('the space of seven years', 'DATE'), ('Carausius', 'PERSON')"
"During twenty-six years the country had experienced the real
 and imaginary hardships of a foreign yoke.","('twenty-six years', 'DATE')"
"Eutropius, his father, was one of the
 most considerable nobles of Dardania, and his mother was the
 niece of the emperor Claudius. (12)","('Eutropius', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dardania', 'PERSON'), ('Claudius', 'PERSON'), ('12', 'CARDINAL')"
"Even in the splendour of the Roman triumph, Diocletian had meditated
 his design of abdicating the government.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Even on that memorable occasion his stay did not exceed two
 months.","('two\r\n months', 'DATE')"
"Even the attributes, or at least the titles, of the DIVINITY were usurped by Diocletian and Maximian, who transmitted them to a succession of Christian
 emperors. (100)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"Ever since the rash but successful enterprise of
 the Franks under the reign of Probus, their daring
 countrymen had constructed squadrons of light brigantines,
 in which they incessantly ravaged the provinces adjacent to
 the ocean. (24)","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('24', 'CARDINAL')"
"Fear, sorrow, and discontent sometimes pursued him into the solitude of Salona.","('Salona', 'PERSON')"
"For a while fortune appeared to favour the enterprising
 valour of Tiridates.","('Tiridates', 'ORG')"
"For this account of
 Diocletian's palace we are principally indebted to an
 ingenious artist of our own time and country, whom a very
 liberal curiosity carried into the heart of Dalmatia. (121)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('121', 'CARDINAL')"
"Four of these, to the north of the river, were
 districts of obscure fame and inconsiderable extent -
 Intiline, Zabdicene, Arzanene, and Moxoene; but on the east
 of the Tigris the empire acquired the large and mountainous
 territory of Carduene, the ancient seat of the Carduchians,
 who preserved for many ages their manly freedom in the heart
 of the despotic monarchies of Asia.","('Four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Intiline', 'NORP'), ('Zabdicene', 'LOC'), ('Arzanene', 'LOC'), ('Moxoene', 'NORP'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Carduene', 'LOC'), ('Carduchians', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"Four streets, intersecting each other at
 right angles, divided the several parts of this great
 edifice, and the approach to the principal apartment was
 from a very stately entrance, which is still denominated the
 Golden Gate.","('Four', 'CARDINAL'), ('the\r\n Golden Gate', 'FAC')"
"From a motive either of pride or 
 superstition, the two emperors assumed the titles, the one
 of Jovius, the other of Herculius.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jovius', 'PRODUCT'), ('Herculius', 'PERSON')"
"From the Nile
 to Mount Atlas Africa was in arms.","('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Mount Atlas Africa', 'LOC')"
"From the earliest period of history, the sovereigns of
 Asia had been celebrated in the Greek language by the title
 of BASILEUS, or King; and since it was considered as the
 first distinction among men, it was soon employed by the
 servile provincials of the East in their humble addresses to
 the Roman throne. (99)","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('BASILEUS', 'EVENT'), ('King', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('99', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the inclemency of
 the weather and the fatigue of the journey, he soon
 contracted a slow illness; and though he made easy marches,
 and was generally carried in a close litter, his disorder,
 before he arrived at Nicomedia, about the end of the summer,
 was become very serious and alarming.","('Nicomedia', 'GPE'), ('about the end of the summer', 'DATE')"
"From the monuments of 
 those times the obscure traces of several other victories
 over the barbarians of Sarmatia and Germany might possibly
 be collected; but the tedious search would not be rewarded
 either with amusement or with instruction","('Sarmatia', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"From the mouth of the Rhine to that of the Danube,
 the ancient camps, towns, and citadels were diligently
 re-established, and, in the most exposed places, new ones
 were skilfully constructed; the strictest vigilance was
 introduced among the garrisons of the frontier, and every
 expedient was practised that could render the long chain of
 fortifications firm and impenetrable.","('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"From the port of Boulogne he sailed over to Britain,
 persuaded the legions and the auxiliaries which guarded that
 island to embrace his party, and boldly assuming, with the
 Imperial purple, the title of Augustus, defied the justice
 and the arms of his injured sovereign. (26)
Importance of Britain.","('Boulogne', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('26', 'CARDINAL'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"From the time of Augustus to that of Diocletian, the Roman princes, conversing in a familiar manner among their fellow-citizens, were saluted only with the same respect that was usually paid to senators and magistrates.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
Galerius and Constantius.. A.D. 292.,"('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 292', 'DATE')"
"Gessoriacum, or Boulogne, in the straits of the British
 Channel, was chosen by the emperor for the station of the
 Roman fleet; and the command of it was intrusted to
 Carausius, a Menapian of the meanest origin, (25) but who had 
 long signalised his skill as a pilot and his valour as a
 soldier.","('Gessoriacum', 'ORG'), ('Boulogne', 'GPE'), ('the British\r\n Channel', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Carausius', 'PERSON'), ('Menapian', 'NORP'), ('25', 'CARDINAL')"
"Having incurred the displeasure of his master, Mamgo, with
 his followers, retired to the banks of the Oxus, and
 implored the protection of Sapor.","('Mamgo', 'PERSON'), ('Oxus', 'ORG'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON')"
"He
 retreated with difficulty towards Langres; but, in the
 general consternation, the citizens refused to open their
 gates, and the wounded prince was drawn up the wall by the
 means of a rope.","('Langres', 'PERSON')"
"He beheld with
 anxious terror the opposite shores of the continent, already
 filled with arms, with troops, and with vessels; for
 Constantius had very prudently divided his forces, that he
 might likewise divide the attention and resistance of the
 enemy.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"He caused a diligent inquiry to be made ""for all the ancient books which treated of the
 admirable art of making gold and silver, and without pity
 committed them to the flames; apprehensive, as we are
 assured, lest the opulence of the Egyptians should inspire
 them with confidence to rebel against the empire."" (50)","('Egyptians', 'NORP'), ('50', 'CARDINAL')"
"He celebrated the
 valour of Galerius, without degrading the reputation of
 Narses, and thought it no dishonour to confess the
 superiority of the victorious Caesar over a monarch who had
 surpassed in glory all the princes of his race.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"He despatched Apharban, a
 servant who possessed his favour and confidence, with a
 commission to negotiate a treaty, or rather to receive
 whatever conditions the conqueror should impose.","('Apharban', 'PERSON')"
"He dismissed Apharban with a hope that Narses would soon be informed on what conditions he night obtain, from the clemency of the emperors, a lasting peace and the restoration of his wives and children.","('Apharban', 'PERSON'), ('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"He distinguished his abilities in the
 Persian war; and after the death of Numerian, the slave, by
 the confession and judgment of his rivals, was declared the
 most worthy of the Imperial throne.","('the\r\n Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('Numerian', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"He had associated three
 colleagues in the exercise of the supreme power; and as he was convinced that the abilities of a single man were inadequate to the public defence, he considered the joint administration of four princes not as a temporary expedient, but as a fundamental law of the constitution.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"He not only expelled the enemies of his
 family and country from the whole extent of Armenia, but in
 the prosecution of his revenge he carried his arms, or at
 least his incursions, into the heart of Assyria.","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Assyria', 'GPE')"
"He rejected the temptation with a smile of pity,
 calmly observing that, if he could show Maximian the
 cabbages which he had planted with his own hands at Salona,
 he should no longer be urged to relinquish the enjoyment of
 happiness for the pursuit of power.","('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Salona', 'PERSON')"
"He resolved to pass
 the remainder of his days in honourable repose, to place his
 glory beyond the reach of fortune, and to relinquish the
 theatre of the world to his younger and more active
 associates. (108)
 A.D. 305.","('108', 'CARDINAL'), ('305', 'CARDINAL')"
"He resolved to pass
 the remainder of his days in honourable repose, to place his
 glory beyond the reach of fortune, and to relinquish the
 theatre of the world to his younger and more active
 associates. (108)
A.D. 305.","('108', 'CARDINAL'), ('305', 'CARDINAL')"
"He signalised his youth by deeds of
 valour, and displayed a matchless dexterity, as well as
 strength, in every martial exercise, and even in the less
 honourable contests of the Olympian games. (52)","('Olympian', 'NORP'), ('52', 'CARDINAL')"
"He suppressed the peasants of Gaul, who, under the
 appellation of Bagaudae, (16) had risen in a general 
 insurrection; very similar to those which in the fourteenth
 century successively afflicted both France and England. (17)","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Bagaudae', 'PERSON'), ('16', 'CARDINAL'), ('the fourteenth\r\n century', 'DATE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('17', 'CARDINAL')"
"He ventured to assume the diadem, an ornament detested by the Romans as the odious ensign of royalty, and the use of which had been considered as the most desperate act of the madness of
 Caligula.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Caligula', 'PERSON')"
"He was
 pursued as far as the Euphrates; his horse was wounded, and
 it appeared impossible for him to escape the victorious
 enemy.","('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"He was murdered by his first minister
 Allectus, and the assassin succeeded to his power and to his
 danger.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Allectus', 'PERSON')"
He was solicited by that restless old man to reassume the reins of government and the Imperial purple.,"('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"His
 tenderness, or at least his pride, was deeply wounded by the misfortunes of his wife and daughter; and the last moments of Diocletian were embittered by some affronts, which Licinius and Constantine might have spared the father of so many emperors, and the first author of their own fortune.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"His armour was heavy, the river very deep, and at
 those parts at least half a mile in breadth; (66) yet such was 
 his strength and dexterity, that he reached in safety the
 opposite bank. (67)","('those parts at least half a mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('66', 'CARDINAL')"
"His first enterprise
 was against the important place of Boulogne.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Boulogne', 'PERSON')"
"His fleets rode triumphant in the channel,
 commanded the mouths of the Seine and of the Rhine, ravaged
 the coasts of the ocean, and diffused beyond the Columns of
 Hercules the terror of his name.","('Seine', 'LOC'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('the Columns of\r\n Hercules', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"His name was
 Mamgo, his origin was Scythian, and the horde which
 acknowledged his authority had encamped a very few years
 before on the skirts of the Chinese empire, (58) which at that 
 time extended as far as the neighbourhood of Sogdiana. (59)","('Mamgo', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'PERSON'), ('a very few years\r\n before', 'DATE'), ('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('58', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sogdiana', 'GPE'), ('59', 'CARDINAL')"
"His philosophy, His answer to Maximian is deservedly celebrated.","('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
His reception by Diocletian.,"('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
His restoration to the throne of Armenia.,"('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"I. The Aboras, or, as it is called by Xenophon, the Araxes, was fixed as the boundary
 between the two monarchies.","('Aboras', 'PRODUCT'), ('Xenophon', 'PERSON'), ('Araxes', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
Iberia.,"('Iberia', 'ORG')"
"Ignorant of Letters, (7) careless of laws, the 
 rusticity of his appearance and manners still betrayed in
 the most elevated fortune the meanness of his extraction.","('7', 'CARDINAL')"
Imperial dignity and titles.,"('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"In
 describing the country, extraction, and manners of
 Herculius, we have already delineated those of Galerius, who
 was often, and not improperly, styled the younger Maximian,
 though, in many instances both of virtue and ability, he
 appears to have possessed a manifest superiority over the
 elder.","('Herculius', 'GPE'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'NORP')"
"In
 the East he fixed a line of camps from Egypt to the Persian
 dominions, and, for every camp, he instituted an adequate
 number of stationary troops, commanded by their respective
 officers, and supplied with every kind of arms, from the new
 arsenals which he had formed at Antioch, Emesa, and
 Damascus. (32)","('East', 'LOC'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Emesa', 'GPE'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('32', 'CARDINAL')"
"In pursuance of their promise, the emperors soon afterwards
 appointed Sicorius Probus, one of their secretaries, to
 acquaint the Persian court with their final resolution.","('Sicorius Probus', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"In that immense register, where Pliny has deposited the
 discoveries the arts, and the errors of mankind, there is
 not the least mention of the transmutation of metals; and
 the persecution of Diocletian is the first authentic event
 in the history of alchemy.","('Pliny', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"In the armies and in the provinces they
 displayed the dignity of monarchs; and when they fixed their
 residence at a distance from the capital, they forever laid
 aside the dissimulation which Augustus had recommended to
 his successors.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"In the room of the unwarlike troops of Asia, which had most
 probably served in the first expedition, a second army was
 drawn from the veterans and new levies of the Illyrian
 frontier, and a considerable body of Gothic auxiliaries were
 taken into the Imperial pay. (69)","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"In the third year of that emperor's reign,
 Tiridates was invested with the kingdom of Armenia.","('the third year', 'DATE'), ('Tiridates', 'PERSON'), ('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"In this conference we may discover the fierce passions of Galerius, as well as his deference to the superior wisdom and authority of Diocletian.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"In this extremity Tiridates embraced the only refuge
 which he saw before him: he dismounted and plunged into the
 stream.","('Tiridates', 'PERSON')"
"In wars of a
 more difficult nature, and more doubtful event, he employed
 the rough valour of Maximian; and that faithful soldier was
 content to ascribe his own victories to the wise counsels
 and auspicious influence of his benefactor.","('Maximian', 'NORP')"
"Instead of a modest family of slaves and freedmen,
 such as had contented the simple greatness of Augustus and
 Trajan, three or four magnificent courts were established in
 the various parts of the empire, and as many Roman kings
 contended with each other and with the Persian monarch for
 the vain superiority of pomp and luxury.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"It
 was a plain of more than sixty miles, which extended from
 the hills of Carrhae to the Euphrates; a smooth and barren
 surface of sandy desert, without a hillock, without a tree,
 and without a spring of fresh water. (65)","('more than sixty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Carrhae', 'GPE'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('65', 'CARDINAL')"
"It covered an extent 
 of ground consisting of between nine and ten English acres.","('between nine and ten English acres', 'QUANTITY')"
"It is almost needless to observe that Tiridates, the faithful ally of Rome, was restored to the throne of his fathers, and that the rights of the Imperial supremacy were fully asserted and secured.","('Tiridates', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"It is from other information
 that we discover the distracted state of the Persian
 monarchy, to which the king of Armenia was indebted for some
 part of his advantages.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"It is not improbable 
 that motives of prudence might assist the humanity of the
 artful Dalmatian: of these servants, many had purchased his
 favour by secret treachery; in others, he esteemed their
 grateful fidelity to an unfortunate master.","('Dalmatian', 'NORP')"
"It may be added, that his revenues were managed with prudent economy; and that, after all the current expenses were discharged, there still remained in the Imperial treasury an ample provision either for judicious liberality or for any emergency of the state.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"It may be remarked that these ancient books, so liberally
 ascribed to Pythagoras, to Solomon, or to Hermes, were the
 pious frauds of more recent adepts.","('Pythagoras', 'PERSON'), ('Solomon', 'PERSON'), ('Hermes', 'PERSON')"
"It should seem that very many of those institutions,
 referred by an easy solution to the feudal system, are
 derived from the Celtic barbarians.","('Celtic', 'NORP')"
"It was his intention that the two elder princes should be distinguished by the use of the diadem and the title of Augusti; that, as affection or esteem might direct their choice, they should regularly call to their assistance two subordinate
 colleagues; and that the Caesars, rising in their turn to the first rank, should supply an uninterrupted succession of emperors.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Augusti', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"It was in that city
 that they soon afterwards gave audience to the ambassador of
 the Great King. (74)","('the Great King', 'GPE'), ('74', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was in the twenty first year of his reign that Diocletian
 executed his memorable resolution of abdicating the empire;
 an action more naturally to have been expected from the
 elder or the younger Antoninus than from a prince who had
 never practised the lessons of philosophy either in the
 attainment or in the use of supreme power.","('the twenty first year', 'DATE'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Antoninus', 'PERSON')"
"It was reserved for the reign of Diocletian to
 vanquish that powerful nation, and to extort a confession
 from the successors of Artaxerxes of the superior majesty of
 the Roman empire.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Artaxerxes', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It was the aim of the one to disguise, and the object of the other to display, the unbounded power which the emperors possessed over the Roman world.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
It was the last that Rome ever beheld.,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
"It was time to put an end to the painful struggle, which he had sustained during more than a year, between the care of his health and that of his
 dignity.","('more than a year', 'DATE')"
"It was time to rescue from the usurpation of the
 Persian monarch an important territory, which, since the
 reign of Nero, had been always granted under the protection
 of the empire to a younger branch of the house of Arsaces.
 (54)
A.D. 286.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Arsaces', 'PERSON'), ('54', 'CARDINAL'), ('286', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was very natural for
 the plebeians, oppressed by debt or apprehensive of
 injuries, to implore the protection of some powerful chief,
 who acquired over their persons and property the same
 absolute rights as, among the Greeks and Romans, a master
 exercised over his slaves.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Italy and Africa were considered as the
 department of Maximian; and for his peculiar portion
 Diocletian reserved Thrace, Egypt, and the rich countries of
 Asia.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"Its principal city, in
 the same situation perhaps as the modern Tauris, was frequently honoured with the residence of Tiridates; and as it sometimes bore the name of Ecbatana, he imitated, in the buildings and fortifications, the splendid capital of the Medes. (82)","('Tauris', 'NORP'), ('Tiridates', 'PERSON'), ('Ecbatana', 'PERSON'), ('Medes', 'LOC'), ('82', 'CARDINAL')"
Let them remember their own moderation towards the unhappy Valerian.,"('Valerian', 'PERSON')"
"Licinius was
 in every station the friend and companion of Galerius, and
 the merit of Galerius, long before he was raised to the
 dignity of Caesar, had been known and esteemed by
 Diocletian.","('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Like Augustus, Diocletian may be considered as the founder
 of a new empire.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Like the adopted son of Caesar, he was
 distinguished as a statesman rather than as a warrior; nor
 did either of those princes employ force, whenever their
 purpose could be effected by policy.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"Like the modesty affected by Augustus, the state maintained by Diocletian was a theatrical representation; but it must be confessed that, of the two comedies, the former was of a much more liberal and manly character than
 the latter.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
Long absence of the emperor from Rome .,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
Long illness of Diocletian.,"('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Many thousands of the citizens
 perished in a promiscuous slaughter, and there were few
 obnoxious persons in Egypt who escaped a sentence either of
 death or at least of exile. (44)","('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
March 1.,"('March 1', 'DATE')"
"Maximian
 was born a peasant, and, like Aurelian, in the territory of
 Sirmium.","('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Aurelian', 'NORP'), ('Sirmium', 'LOC')"
"Maximian had no sooner recovered Gaul from the hands of the
 peasants, than he lost Britain by the usurpation of
 Carausius.","('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Carausius', 'PERSON')"
"Maximian, as it had been previously concerted, made his resignation of the Imperial dignity at Milan.","('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
May 1,"('May 1', 'DATE')"
"Milan
 soon assumed the splendour of an imperial city.","('Milan', 'GPE')"
Moderation of Diocletian.,"('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Narses soon re-established his authority over the revolted
 province; and, loudly complaining of the protection afforded
 by the Romans to rebels and fugitives, aspired to the
 conquest of the East. (62)","('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('62', 'CARDINAL')"
"Neither Charles nor
 Diocletian were arrived at a very advanced period of life;
 since the one was only fifty-five, and the other was no more
 than fifty-nine years of age; but the active life of those
 princes, their wars and journeys, the cares of royalty, and
 their application to business, had already impaired their
 constitution, and brought on the infirmities of a premature
 old age. (107)
 A.D. 304.","('Charles', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('fifty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifty-nine years of age', 'DATE'), ('107', 'CARDINAL'), ('304', 'CARDINAL')"
"Neither Charles nor
 Diocletian were arrived at a very advanced period of life;
 since the one was only fifty-five, and the other was no more
 than fifty-nine years of age; but the active life of those
 princes, their wars and journeys, the cares of royalty, and
 their application to business, had already impaired their
 constitution, and brought on the infirmities of a premature
 old age. (107)
A.D. 304.","('Charles', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('fifty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifty-nine years of age', 'DATE'), ('107', 'CARDINAL'), ('304', 'CARDINAL')"
"Neither prudence nor honour could permit the emperors to
 forsake the cause of the Armenian king, and it was resolved
 to exert the force of the empire in the Persian war.","('Armenian', 'NORP'), ('the Persian war', 'EVENT')"
"New form of administration, two Augusti, and two Caesars.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Augusti', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesars', 'ORG')"
"Nor did it seem oppressed even by the proximity of
 Rome. (90)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('90', 'CARDINAL')"
"Nor did the emperors refuse the property of lands,
 with a less servile tenure, to such of the barbarians as
 solicited the protection of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Nor was the precaution of the emperor less watchful against the well-known valour of the barbarians of
 Europe.","('Europe', 'LOC')"
"Nor were the vices of Maximian
 less useful to his benefactor.","('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"Notwithstanding the difference of their characters, the two
 emperors maintained, on the throne, that friendship which
 they had contracted in a private station.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Notwithstanding the justice of the Persian cause, he was
 empowered to submit the present differences to the decision
 of the emperors themselves; convinced as he was that, in the
 midst of prosperity, they would not be unmindful of the
 vicissitudes of fortune.","('Persian', 'NORP')"
"Notwithstanding the policy of Diocletian, it was impossible
 to maintain an equal and undisturbed tranquillity during a
 reign of twenty years, and along a frontier of many hundred
 miles.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('twenty years', 'DATE'), ('many hundred\r\n miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"Notwithstanding the severity of a very cold and rainy
 winter, Diocletian left Italy soon after the ceremony of his
 triumph, and began his progress towards the East round the
 circuit of the Illyrian provinces.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP')"
"Notwithstanding these precautions, the political union of the Roman world was gradually dissolved, and a principle of division was introduced, which, in the course of a few years, occasioned the perpetual separation of the eastern and western empires.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('a few years', 'DATE')"
November 20,"('November 20', 'DATE')"
Of Diocletian's palace.,"('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Of the provinces already mentioned beyond the Tigris, the four first had been dismembered by the Parthians from the crown of Armenia; (81) 
 and when the Romans acquired the possession of them, they stipulated, at the expense of the usurpers, an ample compensation, which invested their ally with the extensive and fertile country of Atropatene.","('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Parthians', 'PERSON'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('81', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Atropatene', 'ORG')"
"On the intelligence of the
 victory he condescended to advance towards the frontier,
 with a view of moderating, by his presence and counsels, the
 pride of Galerius.","('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"On the north side lies the bay, which led to the ancient city of Salona; and the country beyond it, appearing in sight, forms a proper
 contrast to that more extensive prospect of water which the Adriatic presents both to the south and to the east.","('Salona', 'GPE'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC')"
"On the same day, which was the first of
 May, (109) Compliance of Maximian.","('the same day', 'DATE'), ('the first of\r\n May', 'DATE'), ('109', 'CARDINAL')"
"On this occasion the impetuous attack of Galerius 
 spread disorder and dismay over the camp of the barbarians.","('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"One of the first military
 dignities was conferred on the satrap Otas, a man of
 singular temperance and fortitude, who presented to the king
 his sister, (57) and a considerable treasure, both of which, 
 in a sequestered fortress, Otas had preserved from
 violation.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Otas', 'PERSON'), ('57', 'DATE'), ('Otas', 'PERSON')"
"One very remarkable 
 edict which he published, instead of being condemned as the
 effect of jealous tyranny, deserves to be applauded as an
 act of prudence and humanity.","('One', 'CARDINAL')"
Ostentation was the first principle of the new system instituted by Diocletian.,"('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
Recovery of Britain by Constantius.,"('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'ORG')"
Resemblance to Charles the Fifth.,"('Charles the Fifth', 'PERSON')"
"Reserving, 
 therefore, for the reign of Constantine a more exact picture of the new empire, we shall content ourselves with describing the principal and decisive outline, as it was traced by the hand of Diocletian.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
Retirement of Diocletian at Salona.,"('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Salona', 'GPE')"
Revolt of Carausius in Britain.,"('Carausius', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"Salona, a principal city of
 his native province of Dalmatia, was near two hundred Roman
 miles (according to the measurement of the public highways)
 from Aquileia and the confines of Italy, and about two
 hundred and seventy from Sirmium, the usual residence of the
 emperors whenever they visited the Illyrian frontier.","('Salona', 'GPE'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('two hundred Roman\r\n miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Aquileia', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('about two\r\n hundred and seventy', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sirmium', 'GPE'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP')"
"Scarcely any circumstances have been preserved
 of the exploits of Maximian in the western parts of Africa;
 but it appears, by the event, that the progress of his arms
 was rapid and decisive, that he vanquished the fiercest
 barbarians of Mauritania, and that he removed them from the
 mountains, whose inaccessible strength had inspired their
 inhabitants with a lawless confidence, and habituated them
 to a life of rapine and violence. (42)
A.D. 296.","('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Mauritania', 'GPE'), ('296', 'CARDINAL')"
"Several of these masters -
 Ammonius, Plotinus, Amelius, and Porphyry (124) - were men of profound thought and intense application; but, by mistaking
 the true object of philosophy, their labours contributed
 much less to improve than to corrupt the human
 understanding.","('Plotinus', 'NORP'), ('Amelius', 'NORP'), ('Porphyry', 'PERSON'), ('124', 'CARDINAL')"
"Since the usurpation of
 Firmus, the province of Upper Egypt, incessantly relapsing
 into rebellion, had embraced the alliance of the savages of
 Ethiopia.","('Firmus', 'ORG'), ('Upper Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Ethiopia', 'GPE')"
"So imperfect in those
 times was the art of navigation, that orators have
 celebrated the daring courage of the Romans, who ventured to
 set sail with a side wind, and on a stormy day.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('a stormy day', 'DATE')"
"So strong and uniform is the current of popular
 passions, that we might almost venture, from very scanty
 materials, to relate the particulars of this war but we are
 not disposed to believe that the principal leaders, Aelianus
 and Amandus, were Christians, (23) or to insinuate that the 
 rebellion, as it happened in the time of Luther, was
 occasioned by the abuse of those benevolent principles of
 Christianity which inculcate the natural freedom of mankind.","('Aelianus', 'PERSON'), ('Amandus', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('23', 'CARDINAL'), ('Luther', 'PERSON'), ('Christianity', 'NORP')"
"Softening, however, his tone, Galerius insinuated to the ambassador that it had never been the practice of the Romans to trample on a prostrate enemy; and that, on this occasion, they should consult their own dignity rather than
 the Persian merit.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"Soon after this
 period the emperors ceased to vanquish, and Rome ceased to
 be the capital of the empire.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
Speech of the Persian ambassador.,"('Persian', 'NORP')"
"St. John the
 Baptist has usurped the honours of Esculapius; and the
 temple of Jupiter, under the protection of the Virgin, is
 converted into the cathedral church.","('St. John the\r\n Baptist', 'FAC'), ('Esculapius', 'NORP'), ('Jupiter', 'LOC'), ('Virgin', 'LOC')"
State of the peasants of Gaul.,"('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
Story of Mamgo.,"('Mamgo', 'PERSON')"
"Such a conduct, however, displayed to the Roman
 world the fairest prospect of the new reign, and he emperor
 affected to confirm this favourable prepossession by
 declaring that, among all the virtues of his predecessors,
 he was the most ambitious of imitating the humane philosophy
 of Marcus Antoninus.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Marcus Antoninus', 'PERSON')"
"Such had been the unworthy allies of the Egyptians; and
 while the attention of the state was engaged in more serious
 wars, their vexatious inroads might again harass the repose
 of the province.","('Egyptians', 'NORP')"
"Such lofty epithets were
 sufficient to elate and satisfy the most excessive vanity;
 and if the successors of Diocletian still declined the title
 of King, it seems to have been the effect not so much of
 their moderation as of their delicacy.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('King', 'PERSON')"
"That officer, in the sedition which 
 occasioned the death of Probus, was exposed to the most
 imminent danger, and the enraged soldiers were forcing their
 way into his tent when they were checked by the single arm
 of the Armenian prince.","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Armenian', 'NORP')"
"That river, which rose near 
 the Tigris, was increased, a few miles below Nisibis, by the
 little stream of the Mygdonius, passed under the walls of
 Singara, and fell into the Euphrates at Circesium, a
 frontier town which, by the care of Diocletian, was very
 strongly fortified. (78) Mesopotamia, the object of so many 
 wars, was ceded to the empire; and the Persians, by this
 treaty, renounced all pretensions to that great province II.","('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('a few miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Nisibis', 'PRODUCT'), ('Mygdonius', 'FAC'), ('Singara', 'GPE'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Circesium', 'GPE'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"The
 ancient sages had derided the popular superstition; after
 disguising its extravagance by the thin pretence of
 allegory, the disciples of Plotinus and Porphyry became its
 most zealous defenders.","('Plotinus', 'PERSON'), ('Porphyry', 'PERSON')"
"The
 conditions of a treaty so glorious to the empire, and so
 necessary to Persia, may deserve a more peculiar attention,
 as the history of Rome presents very few transactions of a
 similar nature; most of her wars having either been
 terminated by absolute conquest, or waged against barbarians
 ignorant of the use of letters.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The
 emperors, though perhaps of African or Illyrian extraction,
 respected their adopted country as the seat of their power
 and the centre of their extensive dominions.","('African', 'NORP'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP')"
"The
 historian who has preserved the name of Tiridates from
 oblivion, celebrates, with a degree of national enthusiasm,
 his personal prowess and, in the true spirit of eastern
 romance, describes the giants and the elephants that fell
 beneath his invincible arm.","('Tiridates', 'PERSON')"
"The
 most illustrious members of the senate, whom Diocletian
 always affected to esteem, were involved, by his colleague,
 in the accusation of imaginary plots; and the possession of
 an elegant villa, or a well-cultivated estate, was
 interpreted as a convincing evidence of guilt. (93)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The
 parents of Diocletian had been slaves in the house of
 Anulinus, a Roman senator; nor was he himself distinguished
 by any other name than that which he derived from a small
 town in Dalmatia, from whence his mother deduced her origin.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Anulinus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE')"
"The
 seditions of Alexandria had often affected the tranquillity
 and subsistence of Rome itself.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The
 servants of Carausius imitated the example of treason which
 he had given.","('Carausius', 'PERSON')"
"The
 suspicious jealousy of power found not any place among them;
 and the singular happiness of their union has been compared
 to a chorus of music, whose harmony was regulated and
 maintained by the skilful hand of the first artist.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
The Aboras fixed as the limits between the empires.,"('Aboras', 'PERSON')"
"The Armenian
 prince, who was well acquainted with the merit as well as
 power of Mamgo, treated him with distinguished respect; and,
 by admitting him into his confidence, acquired a brave and
 faithful servant, who contributed very effectually to his
 restoration. (60)","('Armenian', 'NORP'), ('Mamgo', 'PERSON')"
"The British emperor
 defended the frontiers of his dominions against the
 Caledonians of the North, invited from the continent a great
 number of skilful artists, and displayed, on a variety of
 coins that are still extant, his taste and opulence.","('British', 'NORP'), ('Caledonians', 'NORP'), ('North', 'LOC')"
"The Caesars, in their exalted
 rank, revered the majesty of the emperors, and the three
 younger princes invariably acknowledged, by their gratitude
 and obedience, the common parent of their fortunes.","('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"The East and Italy were the most honourable, the Danube and the Rhine the most laborious stations.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"The East enjoyed a profound tranquillity during forty years; and the treaty between the rival monarchies was strictly observed till the death of Tiridates; when a new generation, animated with
 different views and different passions, succeeded to the government of the world; and the grandson of Narses undertook a long and memorable war against the princes of the house of Constantine.","('East', 'LOC'), ('forty years', 'DATE'), ('Tiridates', 'PERSON'), ('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The Gallic
 nobles, justly dreading their revenge, either took refuge in
 the fortified cities, or fled from the wild scene of
 anarchy.","('Gallic', 'NORP')"
The Golden Gate now opens into the marketplace.,"('The Golden Gate', 'FAC')"
"The Goths, the Vandals, the Gepidae, the Burgundians, the
 Alemanni, wasted each other's strength by destructive
 hostilities: and whosoever vanquished, they vanquished the
 enemies of Rome.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Gepidae', 'NORP'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The Greeks were
 inattentive either to the use or to the abuse of chemistry.","('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"The Persian
 monarchs adorned their new conquest with magnificent
 buildings; but those monuments had been erected at the
 expense of the people, and were abhorred as badges of
 slavery.","('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The Persian monarch pleaded the laws of hospitality, and
 with some difficulty avoided a war by the promise that he
 would banish Mamgo to the uttermost parts of the West, a
 punishment, as he described it, not less dreadful than death
 itself.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Mamgo', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC')"
The Persian war.,"('The Persian war', 'EVENT')"
The Persians recover Armenia.,"('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"The Romans celebrated, and perhaps magnified, the
 extent of that noble island, provided on every side with
 convenient harbours; the temperature of the climate, and the
 fertility of the soil, alike adapted for the production of
 corn.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The abdication of Charles
 appears to have been hastened by the vicissitude of fortune;
 and the disappointment of his favourite schemes urged him to
 relinquish a power which he found inadequate to his
 ambition.","('Charles', 'PERSON')"
"The ambition of the former grasped at the conquest of the East, and had proposed to reduce
 Persia into the state of a province.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"The amusements of
 letters and of devotion, which afford so many resources in
 solitude, were incapable of fixing the attention of
 Diocletian; but he had preserved, or at least he soon
 recovered, a taste for the most innocent as well as natural
 pleasures, and his leisure hours were sufficiently employed
 in building, planting, and gardening.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The approach was terminated by a peristylium
 of granite columns, on one side of which we discover the
 square temple of Esculapius, on the other the octagon temple
 of Jupiter.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Esculapius', 'GPE'), ('Jupiter', 'LOC')"
"The arduous work of rescuing the distressed empire from
 tyrants and barbarians had now been completely achieved by a
 succession of IIlyrian peasants.","('IIlyrian', 'NORP')"
"The armies soon encountered each other in the plains of Mesopotamia, and two battles were fought with various and doubtful success; but the third engagement was
 of a more decisive nature, and the Roman army received a total overthrow, which is attributed to the rashness of Galerius, who, with an inconsiderable body of troops, attacked the innumerable host of the Persians. (64)","('Mesopotamia', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"The attack was at length made by the principal
 squadron, which, under the command of the praefect
 Asclepiodotus, an officer of distinguished merit, had been
 assembled in the mouth of the Seine.","('Asclepiodotus', 'PRODUCT'), ('Seine', 'LOC')"
"The birth of Constantius was less obscure than that
 of his colleagues.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The brave and active Constantius delivered 
 Gaul from a very furious inroad of the Alemanni; and his
 victories of Langres and Vindonissa appear to have been
 actions of considerable danger and merit.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Langres', 'PERSON'), ('Vindonissa', 'PERSON')"
"The brother of Artavasdes obtained
 the government of a province.","('Artavasdes', 'PERSON')"
"The camp 
 of the Praetorians, which had so long oppressed, began to
 protect, the majesty of Rome; and as those haughty troops
 were conscious of the decline of their power, they were
 naturally disposed to unite their strength with the
 authority of the senate.","('Praetorians', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The captive barbarians, exchanging death for slavery, were
 distributed among the provincials, and assigned to those
 districts (in Gaul, the territories of Amiens, Beauvais,
 Carnbray, Treves, Langres, and Troyes, are particularly
 specified) (37) which had been depopulated by the calamities 
 of war.","('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Amiens', 'GPE'), ('Beauvais', 'GPE'), ('Carnbray', 'GPE'), ('Treves', 'LOC'), ('Langres', 'LOC'), ('Troyes', 'LOC'), ('37', 'CARDINAL')"
"The ceremony of his abdication was performed in a spacious
 plain, about three miles from Nicomedia.","('about three miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Nicomedia', 'GPE')"
"The character of the Egyptian 
 nation, insensible to kindness, but extremely susceptible of
 fear, could alone justify this excessive rigour.","('Egyptian', 'NORP')"
"The civil offices of consul, of
 proconsul, of censor, and of tribune, by the union of which
 it had been formed, betrayed to the people its republican
 extraction.","('republican', 'NORP')"
"The civil war was, however, 
 soon terminated, either by a victory or by a reconciliation;
 and Narses, who was universally acknowledged as king of
 Persia, directed his whole force against the foreign enemy.","('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"The command of the 
 army was bestowed on Artavasdes, whose father had saved the
 infancy of Tiridates, and whose family had been massacred
 for that generous action.","('Artavasdes', 'PERSON'), ('Tiridates', 'PERSON')"
"The conduct of the legions was intrusted to the intrepid
 valour of Galerius, who, for that important purpose, was
 removed from the banks of the Danube to those of the
 Euphrates.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"The conduct which the emperor Probus had adopted in the disposal of the
 vanquished was imitated by Diocletian and his associates.","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The conquest of Egypt by the
 Arabs diffused that vain science over the globe.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"The country of Iberia was barren, its inhabitants rude and savage.","('Iberia', 'LOC')"
"The court of the emperor
 of the West was, for the most part, established at Milan,
 whose situation, at the foot of the Alps, appeared far more
 convenient than that of Rome, for the important purpose of
 watching the motions of the barbarians of Germany.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"The crafty prince had
 framed a new system of Imperial government, which was
 afterwards completed by the family of Constantine; and as
 the image of the old constitution was religiously preserved
 in the senate, he resolved to deprive that order of its
 small remains of power and consideration.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The declining age of learning and of mankind is marked,
 however, by the rise and rapid progress of the new
 Platonists.","('Platonists', 'NORP')"
"The defence of Gaul, Spain, (14) and Britain was 
 intrusted to Constantius: Galerius was stationed on the
 banks of the Danube, as the safeguard of the Illyrian
 provinces.","('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('14', 'CARDINAL'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'GPE'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP')"
"The discerning
 judgment of Aurelian, of Probus, and of Carus, had filled
 the several departments of the state and army with officers
 of approved merit, whose removal would have injured the
 public service, without promoting the interest of the
 successor.","('Aurelian', 'PERSON'), ('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Carus', 'PERSON')"
"The dislike expressed by Diocletian towards Rome and Roman
 freedom was not the effect of momentary caprice, but the
 result of the most artful policy.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The emergencies
 of war very frequently required their presence on the
 Frontiers; but Diocletian and Maximian were the first Roman
 princes who fixed, in time of peace, their ordinary
 residence in the provinces and their conduct, however it
 might be suggested by private motives, was justified by very
 specious considerations of policy.","('Frontiers', 'LOC'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The emperor Diocletian was indeed the author of that system; but during his reign the growing evil was confined within the bounds of modesty and discretion, and he deserves the reproach of establishing pernicious precedents, rather than of exercising actual oppression. (105)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('105', 'CARDINAL')"
"The emperor of China
 claimed the fugitive, and alleged the rights of sovereignty.","('China', 'GPE')"
The empire was divided into four parts.,"('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"The engagement was soon terminated by
 the total defeat and death of Allectus; a single battle, as
 it has often happened, decided the fate of this great
 island; and when Constantius landed on the shores of Kent,
 he found them covered with obedient subjects.","('Allectus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Kent', 'GPE')"
"The epithet of DOMINUS, or LORD, in its
 primitive signification, was expressive not of the authority
 of a prince over his subjects, or of a commander over his
 soldiers, but of the despotic power of a master over his
 domestic slaves. (98)","('DOMINUS', 'PERSON')"
"The fate of Busiris and of 
 Coptos was still more melancholy than that of Alexandria;
 those proud cities, the former distinguished by its
 antiquity, the latter enriched by the passage of the Indian
 trade, were utterly destroyed by the arms and by the severe
 order of Diocletian. (45)","('Busiris', 'LOC'), ('Coptos', 'LOC'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Indian', 'NORP'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('45', 'CARDINAL')"
"The first condition proposed by the ambassador 
 is not at present of a very intelligible nature; that the
 city of Nisibis might be established for the place of mutual
 exchange, or, as we should formerly have termed it, for the
 staple of trade, between the two empires.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Nisibis', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The first considerable action of his reign seemed to evince
 his sincerity as well as his moderation.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The first exploit of Maximian, though it is mentioned in a
 few words by our imperfect writers, deserves, from its
 singularity, to be recorded in a history of human manners.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Maximian', 'NORP')"
"The first governed by superstition, the second by
 arms, but the third and last was not of any weight or
 account in their public councils.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL')"
"The form was quadrangular, flanked with sixteen towers.","('sixteen', 'CARDINAL')"
"The former claimed the presence of the Augusti, the latter were intrusted to the administration of the Caesars.","('Augusti', 'PRODUCT'), ('Caesars', 'ORG')"
"The gratitude of Tiridates
 contributed soon afterwards to his restoration.","('Tiridates', 'PERSON')"
"The greatest part of the 
 nation was gradually reduced in a state of servitude;
 compelled to perpetual labour on the estates of the Gallic
 nobles, and confined to the soil, either by the real weight
 of fetters, or by the no less cruel and forcible restraints
 of the laws.","('Gallic', 'NORP')"
"The haughtiest of men,
 clothed in his purple, but humbled by the sense of his fault
 and misfortune, was obliged to follow the emperor's chariot
 above a mile on foot, and to exhibit, before the whole
 court, the spectacle of his disgrace. (68)
Second campaign of Galerius.","('a mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('68', 'CARDINAL'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"The haughty,
 turbulent spirit of Maximian, so fatal afterwards to himself
 and to the public peace, was accustomed to respect the
 genius of Diocletian, and confessed the ascendant of reason
 over brutal violence. (8)","('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The images
 of the captive wives, the sisters, and the children of the
 Great King afforded a new and grateful spectacle to the
 vanity of the people. (87)","('the\r\n Great King', 'GPE'), ('87', 'CARDINAL')"
"The interview of the Roman princes at
 Nisibis was accompanied with every expression of respect on
 one side, and of esteem on the other.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Nisibis', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The king
 of Armenia had signalised his valour in the battle, and
 acquired personal glory by the public misfortune.","('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"The knowledge that is suited to our situation
 and powers, the whole compass of moral, natural, and
 mathematical science, was neglected by the new Platonists;
 whilst they exhausted their strength in the verbal disputes
 of metaphysics, attempted to explore the secrets of the
 invisible world, and studied to reconcile Aristotle with
 Plato, on subjects of which both these philosophers were as
 ignorant as the rest of mankind.","('Platonists', 'NORP'), ('Aristotle', 'PERSON'), ('Plato', 'PERSON')"
"The latter of those deities Diocletian revered
 as the patron of his fortunes, the former as the protector
 of his health.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The life of Diocletian 
 and Maximian was a life of action, and a considerable
 portion of it was spent in camps, or in their long and
 frequent marches; but whenever the public business allowed
 them any relaxation, they seemed to have retired with
 pleasure to their favourite residences of Nicomedia and
 Milan.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Nicomedia', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"The limits of Armenia were extended as far as the forests of Sintha in Media, and this increase of dominion was not so much an act of liberality as of justice.","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Sintha', 'LOC')"
"The malice of religious
 zeal, whilst it arraigns the savage fierceness of his
 colleague Maximian, has affected to cast suspicion on the
 personal courage of the emperor Diocletian.","('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The model of ancient
 freedom was preserved in its deliberations and decrees; and
 wise princes, who respected the prejudices of the Roman
 people, were in some measure obliged to assume the language
 and behaviour suitable to the general and first magistrate
 of the republic.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The name of Emperor, which was at first
 of a military nature, was associated with another of a more
 servile kind.","('Emperor', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The name of the senate was mentioned with honour
 till the last period of the empire; the vanity of its
 members was still flattered with honorary distinctions; (96) 
 but the assembly which had so long been the source, and so
 long the instrument of power, was respectfully suffered to
 sink into oblivion.","('96', 'CARDINAL')"
"The narrow defiles of Mount Caucasus were in their hands, and it was in their choice either to admit or to exclude the wandering tribes of Sarmatia, whenever a rapacious spirit urged them
 to penetrate into the richer climates of the South. (83)","('Mount Caucasus', 'LOC'), ('Sarmatia', 'NORP'), ('South', 'LOC'), ('83', 'CARDINAL')"
"The native Romans felt and 
 confessed the power of this agreeable illusion.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The new Platonists would scarcely deserve a place
 in the history of science, but in that of the church the
 mention of them will very frequently occur.","('Platonists', 'NORP')"
The new Platonists.,"('Platonists', 'NORP')"
"The nobles of Armenia flew to the standard
 of Tiridates, all alleging their past merit, offering their
 future service, and soliciting from the new king those
 honours and rewards from which they had been excluded with
 disdain under the foreign government. (56)","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Tiridates', 'ORG')"
"The nomination of the kings of Iberia, which was resigned by the Persian monarch to the emperors, contributed to the strength and security of the Roman power in Asia. (84)","('Iberia', 'GPE'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('84', 'CARDINAL')"
"The number of
 ministers, of magistrates, of officers, and of servants, who
 filled the different departments of the state, was
 multiplied beyond the example of former times; and (if we
 may borrow the warm expression of a contemporary), 
""when the proportion of those who received exceeded the proportion of those who contributed, the provinces were oppressed by the weight of tributes."" (104)","('104', 'CARDINAL')"
"The number of the Blemmyes, scattered between the
 island of Meroe and the Red Sea, was very inconsiderable,
 their disposition was unwarlike, their weapons rude and
 inoffensive. (46)","('Blemmyes', 'PRODUCT'), ('Meroe', 'LOC'), ('the Red Sea', 'LOC')"
"The parallel of Charles the
 Fifth, however, will naturally offer itself to our mind, not
 only since the eloquence of a modern historian has rendered
 that name so familiar to an English reader, but from the
 very striking resemblance between the characters of the two
 emperors, whose political abilities were superior to their
 military genius, and whose specious virtues were much less
 the effect of nature than of art.","('Charles', 'PERSON'), ('Fifth', 'ORDINAL'), ('English', 'LANGUAGE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The peasants reigned without control, and two of
 their most daring leaders had the folly and rashness to
 assume the Imperial ornaments. (21)","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('21', 'CARDINAL')"
"The ploughman became a foot soldier,
 the shepherd mounted on horseback, the deserted villages and
 open towns were abandoned to the flames, and the ravages of
 the peasants equalled those of the fiercest barbarians. (20)","('20', 'CARDINAL')"
"The policy
 of Diocletian, which inspired the councils of his
 associates, provided for the public tranquillity, by
 encouraging a spirit of dissension among the barbarians, and
 by strengthening the fortifications of the Roman limit.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The power, or at least the spirit, of 
 Narses had been broken by his last defeat; and he considered
 an immediate peace as the only means that could stop the
 progress of the Roman arms.","('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The presence of
 some god, or the memory of some hero, seemed to animate
 every part of the city, and the empire of the world had been
 promised to the Capitol. (88)","('Capitol', 'FAC')"
"The pride, or rather the policy, of Diocletian, engaged that artful prince to introduce the
 stately magnificence of the court of Persia. (101)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('101', 'CARDINAL')"
"The principal loss of 
 Narses was of a much more affecting nature.","('Narses', 'GPE')"
"The professions of law and physic are of
 such common use and certain profit that they will always
 secure a sufficient number of practitioners endowed with a
 reasonable degree of abilities and knowledge; but it does
 not appear that the students in those two faculties appeal
 to any celebrated masters who have flourished within that
 period.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The prudence of Diocletian discovered that
 the empire, assailed on every side by the barbarians,
 required on every side the presence of a great army and of
 an emperor.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The prudence of the latter, who adhered to the moderate policy of Augustus and the Antonines, embraced the favourable opportunity of terminating a successful war by an honourable and
 advantageous peace. (75)
 Conclusion.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Antonines', 'PERSON'), ('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"The prudence of the latter, who adhered to the moderate policy of Augustus and the Antonines, embraced the favourable opportunity of terminating a successful war by an honourable and
 advantageous peace. (75)
Conclusion.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Antonines', 'PERSON'), ('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"The range
 of principal apartments was protected towards the south-west
 by a portico five hundred and seventeen feet long, which
 must have formed a very noble and delightful walk, when the
 beauties of painting and sculpture were added to those of
 the prospect.","('five hundred and seventeen feet', 'QUANTITY')"
"The reduction of Egypt was immediately followed by the
 Persian war.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('the\r\n Persian war', 'EVENT')"
"The reign of Diocletian and his three associates,
 Maximian, Galerius, and Constantius","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The representations of rivers, mountains, and
 provinces were carried before the Imperial car.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The same ground on which Galerius was vanquished had been rendered memorable
 by the death of Crassus and the slaughter of ten legions.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Crassus', 'PERSON'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL')"
"The school of Alexandria silenced those of
 Athens; and the ancient sects enrolled themselves under the
 banners of the more fashionable teachers, who recommended
 their system by the novelty of their method and the
 austerity of their manners.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Athens', 'GPE')"
The second was division.,"('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"The secret motive of Narses in this delay had been to
 collect such a military force as might enable him, though
 sincerely desirous of peace, to negotiate with the greater
 weight and dignity.","('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"The senate of Rome, losing all
 connection with the Imperial court and the actual
 constitution, was left a venerable but useless monument of
 antiquity on the Capitoline hill.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('the Capitoline hill', 'LOC')"
"The spot on which Rome was founded had been consecrated by
 ancient ceremonies and imaginary miracles.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The statues of the deified kings of
 Armenia, and the sacred images of the sun and moon, were
 broke in pieces by the zeal of the conqueror and the
 perpetual fire of Ormuzd was kindled and preserved upon as
 altar erected on the summit of Mount Bagavan. (55)","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Ormuzd', 'GPE'), ('Mount Bagavan', 'GPE'), ('55', 'CARDINAL')"
"The steady infantry 
 of the Romans, fainting with heat and thirst, could neither
 hope for victory if they preserved their ranks, nor break
 their ranks without exposing themselves to the most imminent
 danger.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The strength of the legions was in the hands of the four partners of sovereignty, and the despair of successively vanquishing four formidable rivals might intimidate the ambition of an aspiring general.","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"The strength of union and
 discipline obtained an easy victory over a licentious and
 divided multitude. (22) and chastisement.","('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"The subjects of Diocletian enjoyed the
 bloody spectacle, and congratulated each other that the
 mischiefs of civil war were now experienced only by the
 barbarians. (34)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The succession of Illyrian princes restored the
 empire without restoring the sciences.","('Illyrian', 'NORP')"
"The successors of
 Augustus exercised the power of dictating whatever laws
 their wisdom or caprice might suggest; but those laws were
 ratified by the sanction of the senate.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
The sumptuous robes of Diocletian and his successors were of silk and gold; and it is remarked with indignation that even their shoes were studded with the most precious gems.,"('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The system of Diocletian was accompanied with another very
 material disadvantage, which cannot even at present be
 totally overlooked; a more expensive establishment, and
 consequently an increase of taxes, and the oppression of the
 people.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The ten thousand Greeks
 traversed their country after a painful march, or rather
 engagement, of seven days; and it is confessed by their
 leader, in his incomparable relation of the retreat, that
 they suffered more from the arrows of the Carduchians than
 from the power of the Great King. (80)","('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('seven days', 'DATE'), ('Carduchians', 'NORP'), ('the Great King', 'GPE'), ('80', 'CARDINAL')"
"The throne was disputed by the
 ambition of contending brothers; and Hormuz, after exerting
 without success the strength of his own party, had recourse
 to the dangerous assistance of the barbarians who inhabited
 the banks of the Caspian Sea. (61)","('Hormuz', 'PERSON'), ('the Caspian Sea', 'LOC'), ('61', 'CARDINAL')"
"The torrent bore
 down every obstacle, and the Persian garrisons retreated
 before its fury.","('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The town surrendered after an obstinate
 defence; and a considerable part of the naval strength of
 Carausius fell into the hands of the besiegers.","('Carausius', 'PRODUCT')"
"The treaty long subsisted;
 and till the establishment of Christianity introduced
 stricter notions of religious worship, it was annually
 ratified by a solemn sacrifice in the isle of Elephantine,
 in which the Romans, as well as the barbarians, adored the
 same visible or invisible powers of the universe. (48)","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Elephantine', 'LOC'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The triumph of Diocletian and Maximian was 
 less magnificent, perhaps, than those of Aurelian and
 Probus, but it was dignified by several circumstances of
 superior fame and good fortune.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Aurelian', 'PERSON'), ('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"The two Caesars had fought and conquered, but the merit
 of their exploits was ascribed, according to the rigour of
 ancient maxims, to the auspicious influence of their fathers
 and emperors. (86)","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesars', 'ORG')"
"The usurper had
 posted himself near London, to expect the formidable attack
 of Constantius, who commanded in person the fleet of
 Boulogne; but the descent of a new enemy required his
 immediate presence in the West.","('London', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Boulogne', 'PRODUCT')"
"The valour of Diocletian
 was never found inadequate to his duty, or to the occasion;
 but he appears not to have possessed the daring and generous
 spirit of a hero, who courts danger and fame, disdains
 artifice, and boldly challenges the allegiance of his
 equals.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The victory of Diocletian was remarkable for its singular
 mildness.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The vigilant Galerius was never reduced to the
 necessity of vanquishing an army of barbarians on the Roman
 territory. (35)","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The village of Aspalathus, (120) and, long afterwards, the 
 provincial town of Spalatro, have grown out of its ruins.","('Aspalathus', 'GPE'), ('120', 'CARDINAL'), ('Spalatro', 'GPE')"
"The wealth of Carausius was, on this occasion, very justly
 considered as an evidence of his guilt; and Maximian had
 already given orders for his death.","('Carausius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"The whole was constructed of
 a beautiful freestone, extracted from the neighbouring
 quarries of Trau, or Tragutium, and very little inferior to
 marble itself.","('Trau', 'LOC'), ('Tragutium', 'LOC')"
"The wives and children of Narses were protected from
 violence and rapine, conveyed to a place of safety, and
 treated; with every mark of respect and tenderness that was
 due from a generous enemy to their age, their sex, and their
 royal dignity.","('Narses', 'NORP')"
"Their
 acclamations were loud and unanimous; and the virtues of the
 conqueror may induce us to believe that they sincerely
 rejoiced in a revolution which, after a separation of ten
 years, restored Britain to the body of the Roman empire.","('ten\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Their forms were various, their proportions just, but they
 were all attended with two imperfections, very repugnant to
 our modern notions of taste and convenience.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Their military
 education was not calculated to inspire them with the love
 of letters; and even the mind of Diocletian, however active
 and capacious in business, was totally uninformed by study
 or speculation.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Their posterity, the 
 Curds, with very little alteration either of name or
 manners, acknowledged the nominal sovereignty of the Turkish
 sultan.","('Curds', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Turkish', 'NORP')"
"Their principal distinction was the Imperial or military robe of purple; whilst the senatorial garment was marked by a broad, and the equestrian by a narrow, band or stripe of the same honourable colour.","('Imperial', 'NORP')"
Their residence at Milan.,"('Milan', 'GPE')"
"Their resistance insensibly became more feeble, and the name less
 odious; till at length the style of our Lord and Emperor was
 not only bestowed by flattery, but was regularly admitted
 into the laws and public monuments.","('Emperor', 'PERSON')"
"There is no
 difficulty in conceiving the intention of the Roman princes
 to improve their revenue by some restraints upon commerce;
 but as Nisibis was situated within their own dominions, and
 as they were masters both of the imports and exports, it
 should seem that such restraints were the objects of an
 internal law, rather than of a foreign treaty.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Nisibis', 'PERSON')"
"These four princes 
 distributed among themselves the wide extent of the Roman
 empire.","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"They congratulated their
 masters on the powerful accession of subjects and soldiers;
 but they forgot to observe that multitudes of secret
 enemies, insolent from favour, or desperate from oppression,
 were introduced into the heart of the empire. (39)
Wars of Africa and Egypt.","('39', 'CARDINAL'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"They granted a settlement
 to several colonies of the Carpi, the Bastarnae, and the
 Sarmatians; and, by a dangerous indulgence, permitted them
 in some measure to retain their national manners and
 independence. (38)","('Carpi', 'PERSON'), ('Bastarnae', 'NORP'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP')"
"They relinquished to the Romans five provinces beyond the
 Tigris. (79)","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('79', 'CARDINAL')"
"They were employed to repel
 the invasion of Tiridates; but their leader, after weighing
 the obligations and injuries which he had received from the
 Persian monarch, resolved to abandon his party.","('Tiridates', 'ORG'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"They were lighted
 from the top (for the building seems to have consisted of no
 more than one story), and they received their heat by the
 help of pipes that were conveyed along the walls.","('no\r\n more than one', 'CARDINAL')"
"This engagement, though it was
 confirmed by the solemnity of an oath before the altar of
 the Capitoline Jupiter, (110) would have proved a feeble restraint on the fierce temper of Maximian, whose passion was the love of power, and who neither desired present
 tranquillity nor future reputation.","('the Capitoline Jupiter', 'ORG'), ('110', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maximian', 'NORP')"
"This important measure was not carried into execution till
 about six years after the association of Maximian, and that
 interval of time had not been destitute of memorable
 incidents.","('about six years', 'DATE'), ('Maximian', 'GPE')"
"Those 
 qualities were more nobly exerted in the defence of his
 benefactor Licinius. (53)","('Licinius', 'PERSON')"
"Those modest titles were laid aside; (97) and if 
 they still distinguished their high station by the
 appellation of Emperor, or IMPERATOR, that word was
 understood in a new and more dignified sense, and no longer
 denoted the general of the Roman armies, but the sovereign
 of the Roman world.","('97', 'CARDINAL'), ('IMPERATOR', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Though Constantine, from a very obvious prejudice, affects
 to mention the palace of Diocletian with contempt, (118) yet 
 one of their successors, who could only see it in a
 neglected and mutilated state, celebrates its magnificence
 in terms of the highest admiration.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('118', 'CARDINAL')"
"Three persons only assisted at this
 important conference, the minister Apharban, the praefect of
 the guards, and an officer who had commanded on the Armenian
 frontier. (76)","('Three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Apharban', 'PERSON'), ('Armenian', 'NORP')"
"Till Diocletian, in the twentieth year of his reign,
 celebrated his Roman triumph, it is extremely doubtful
 whether he ever visited the ancient capital of the empire.","('Till Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('the twentieth year', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'PERSON')"
"Tiridates derived from his exile such
 advantages as he could never have obtained on the throne of
 Armenia; the early knowledge of adversity, of mankind, and
 of the Roman discipline.","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
Tiridates the Armenian.,"('Armenian', 'NORP')"
"Tiridates, a second time expelled from the throne of
 Armenia, once more took refuge in the court of the emperors.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"To render
 them more effectual, some stipulations were probably
 required on the side of the king of Persia, which appeared
 so very repugnant either to his interest or to his dignity
 that Narses could not be persuaded to subscribe them.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"To rival the majesty of Rome was the ambition 
 likewise of Diocletian, and Nicomedia.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Nicomedia', 'PERSON')"
"To strengthen the bonds of political, by those of
 domestic, union, each of the emperors assumed the character
 of a father to one of the Caesars, Diocletian to Galerius,
 and Maximian to Constantius; and each, obliging them to
 repudiate their former wives, bestowed his daughter in
 marriage on his adopted son. (13)","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"Towards the north the view is terminated by high and irregular mountains, situated at a proper distance, and in many places covered with villages, woods, and vineyards."" (117)","('117', 'CARDINAL')"
"Towards the west lies the fertile shore that stretches along the Adriatic, in which a number of small islands are
 scattered in such a manner as to give this part of the sea the appearance of a great lake.","('Adriatic', 'LOC')"
Treatment of the barbarians,"('Treatment of the barbarians', 'PERSON')"
Triumph of Diocletian amd Maximian.,"('Triumph of Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Two
 of the sides were near six hundred, and the other two near
 seven hundred, feet in length.","('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('six hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('the other two near\r\n seven hundred, feet', 'QUANTITY')"
"Under his command, Britain,
 destined in a future age to obtain the empire of the sea,
 already assumed its natural and respectable station of a
 maritime power. (28)
A.D. 289.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('289', 'CARDINAL')"
"Under the cover of a
 thick fog they escaped the fleet of Allectus, which had been
 stationed off the Isle of Wight to receive them, landed in
 safety on some part of the western coast, and convinced the
 Britons that a superiority of naval strength will not always
 protect their country from a foreign invasion.","('Allectus', 'PRODUCT'), ('the Isle of Wight', 'GPE'), ('Britons', 'NORP')"
Valour of the Caesars.,"('Valour', 'PERSON'), ('Caesars', 'ORG')"
"Viewing it in that odious light, it had been rejected with abhorrence by the first Caesars.","('Caesars', 'ORG')"
War between the Persians and the Romans.,"('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"We are informed by
 a more recent and very judicious traveller that the awful
 ruins of Spalatro are not less expressive of the decline of
 the arts than of the greatness of the Roman empire in the
 time of Diocletian. (122)","('Spalatro', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('122', 'CARDINAL')"
"We have already remarked the intolerant spirit
 of the Magian religion.","('Magian', 'NORP')"
"We have observed, under the reign of Valerian, that Armenia
 was subdued by the perfidy and the arms of the Persians, and
 that, after the assassination of Chosroes, his son
 Tiridates, the infant heir of the monarchy, was saved by the
 fidelity of his friends, and educated under the protection
