Sentence,Entities
(2),"('2', 'CARDINAL')"
(3),"('3', 'CARDINAL')"
(43),"('43', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 rumor was spread among the Christians, that the daughter of
 Theon was the only obstacle to the reconciliation of the
 praefect and the archbishop; and that obstacle was speedily
 removed.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Theon', 'PERSON')"
"A Jesuit, Alphonso Mendez, the
 Catholic patriarch of Aethiopia, accepted, in the name of Urban VIII., the homage and abjuration of the penitent.","('Jesuit', 'NORP'), ('Alphonso Mendez', 'PERSON'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Aethiopia', 'GPE'), ('Urban VIII', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"A bishop of Treves, secure beyond the limits of his
 power, addressed the monarch of the East in the language of
 authority and affection.","('Treves', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"A bishop was named as the inquisitor of
 the faith, and his diligence soon discovered, in the court
 and city, the magistrates, lawyers, physicians, and
 sophists, who still cherished the superstition of the
 Greeks.","('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"A charge was instantly sounded by the successor of
 the apostles; the soldiers waded to their knees in blood;
 and two hundred thousand Christians are said to have fallen
 by the sword: an incredible account, even if it be extended
 from the slaughter of a day to the eighteen years of the
 reign of Apollinaris.","('two hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('a day to the eighteen years of the\r\n reign of Apollinaris', 'DATE')"
"A generous effort might have edeemed the religion and liberty of Egypt, and her six hundred monasteries might have poured forth their myriads of holy warriors, for whom death should have no terrors, since life had no comfort or delight.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('six hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"A laudable regard for the honor of the first proselyte
 has countenanced the belief, the hope, the wish, that the
 Ebionites, or at least the Nazarenes, were distinguished
 only by their obstinate perseverance in the practice of the
 Mosaic rites.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Ebionites', 'NORP'), ('Nazarenes', 'NORP'), ('Mosaic', 'NORP')"
"A metaphysical
 religion may appear too refined for the capacity of the
 negro race: yet a black or a parrot might be taught to
 repeat the words of the Chalcedonian or Monophysite creed.","('Chalcedonian', 'NORP'), ('Monophysite', 'NORP')"
"A more
 substantial, though less simple, hypothesis, was contrived
 by Cerinthus of Asia, (14) who dared to oppose the last of
 the apostles.","('Cerinthus of Asia', 'ORG'), ('14', 'CARDINAL')"
"A more important conquest still remained, of the patriarch,
 the oracle and leader of the Egyptian church.","('Egyptian', 'NORP')"
"A mystery, which had
 long floated in the looseness of popular belief, was defined
 by his perverse diligence in a technical form; and he first
 proclaimed the memorable words, ""One incarnate nature of
 Christ,"" which are still reechoed with hostile clamors in
 the churches of Asia, Egypt, and Aethiopia.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Aethiopia', 'GPE')"
A perpetual succession of patriarchs arose from the ashes of Theodosius; and the Monophysite churches of Syria and Egypt were united by the name of Jacobites and the communion of the faith.,"('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('Monophysite', 'NORP'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Jacobites', 'PERSON')"
"A quarter of a mile from
 the Thracian Bosphorus, the church of St. Euphemia was built
 on the summit of a gentle though lofty ascent: the triple
 structure was celebrated as a prodigy of art, and the
 boundless prospect of the land and sea might have raised the
 mind of a sectary to the contemplation of the God of the
 universe.","('A quarter of a mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('the Thracian Bosphorus', 'FAC'), ('St. Euphemia', 'FAC')"
"A secret remnant of Pagans of Pagans, who still lurked in the most
 refined and most rustic conditions of mankind, excited the
 indignation of the Christians, who were perhaps unwilling
 that any strangers should be the witnesses of their
 intestine quarrels.","('Pagans', 'NORP'), ('Pagans', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"A sentiment or
 fear or indignation prompted him, while it was yet time, to
 affect the glory of a voluntary abdication: (52) his wish, or
 at least his request, was readily granted; he was conducted
 with honor from Ephesus to his old monastery of Antioch;
 and, after a short pause, his successors, Maximian and
 Proclus, were acknowledged as the lawful bishops of
 Constantinople.","('52', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ephesus', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Proclus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"A similar oath was repeated by his son, his brother, the clergy, the nobles, and even the ladies of the court: the Latin patriarch was invested with honors and wealth; and his missionaries erected their churches or citadels in the most convenient stations of the empire.","('Latin', 'NORP')"
"A similar or a less cruel mode of persecution
 soon converted the unresisting subjects of the plain, while
 the glorious title of Mardaites, (135) or rebels, was bravely
 maintained by the hardy natives of Mount Libanus.","('Mardaites', 'PERSON'), ('135', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mount Libanus', 'LOC')"
"A solemn anathema is pronounced against Nestorius
 and Eutyches; against all heretics by whom Christ is
 divided, or confounded, or reduced to a phantom.","('Nestorius', 'NORP'), ('Eutyches', 'NORP'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"A tardy
 repentance was allowed to expiate the guilt or error of the
 accomplices of Dioscorus: but their sins were accumulated on
 his head; he neither asked nor hoped for pardon, and the
 moderation of those who pleaded for a general amnesty was
 drowned in the prevailing cry of victory and revenge.","('Dioscorus', 'PERSON')"
"A thousand years were now elapsed since Egypt had ceased to be a kingdom, since the conquerors of Asia and Europe had trampled on the ready necks of a people, whose ancient wisdom and power ascend beyond the records of history.","('A thousand years', 'DATE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"A wandering
 tribe of the Blemmyes or Nubians invaded his solitary
 prison: in their retreat they dismissed a crowd of useless
 captives: but no sooner had Nestorius reached the banks of
 the Nile, than he would gladly have escaped from a Roman and
 orthodox city, to the milder servitude of the savages.","('Blemmyes', 'NORP'), ('Nubians', 'NORP'), ('Nestorius', 'PERSON'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
A.D. 1599-1663.,"('A.D. 1599-1663', 'DATE')"
"According to the legend of antiquity, the gospel was
 preached in India by St. Thomas. (122)","('India', 'GPE'), ('St. Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('122', 'CARDINAL')"
"Aethiopia was saved by
 four hundred and fifty Portuguese, who displayed in the
 field the native valor of Europeans, and the artificial
 power of the musket and cannon.","('Aethiopia', 'PERSON'), ('four hundred and fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Portuguese', 'NORP'), ('Europeans', 'NORP')"
"After a period of thirteen
 hundred and sixty years, the spark of controversy, first
 kindled by a sermon of Nestorius, still burns in the bosom
 of the East, and the hostile communions still maintain the
 faith and discipline of their founders.","('thirteen\r\n hundred and sixty years', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Nestorius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"After a residence at Antioch of four
 years, the hand of Theodosius subscribed an edict, (53) which
 ranked him with Simon the magician, proscribed his opinions
 and followers, condemned his writings to the flames, and
 banished his person first to Petra, in Arabia, and at length
 to Oasis, one of the islands  of the Libyan desert. (54)","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('four\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('53', 'DATE'), ('Simon', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Petra', 'PERSON'), ('Arabia', 'GPE'), ('Oasis', 'LOC'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Libyan', 'NORP'), ('54', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a short
 correspondence, in which the rival prelates disguised their
 hatred in the hollow language of respect and charity, the
 patriarch of Alexandria denounced to the prince and people,
 to the East and to the West, the damnable errors of the
 Byzantine pontiff.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"After comforting his brethren, he embarked for Constantinople, and sustained, in six successive interviews, the almost irresistible weight of the royal presence.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('six', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the amusement of some unequal combats between
 the Jesuits and his illiterate priests, the emperor declared
 himself a proselyte to the synod of Chalcedon, presuming
 that his clergy and people would embrace without delay the
 religion of their prince.","('Jesuits', 'NORP'), ('Chalcedon', 'PERSON')"
"After the disgrace and exile of Dioscorus, the
 Egyptians still regretted their spiritual father; and
 detested the usurpation of his successor, who was introduced
 by the fathers of Chalcedon.","('Dioscorus', 'PERSON'), ('Egyptians', 'NORP'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE')"
"After the short and troubled reign of
 Sisinnius, bishop of Constantinople, the factions of the
 clergy and people were appeased by the choice of the
 emperor, who, on this occasion, consulted the voice of fame,
 and invited the merit of a stranger.","('Sisinnius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"After three obstinate and equal campaigns, John of Antioch and Cyril of Alexandria condescended to explain and embrace: but their seeming reunion must be imputed rather to prudence than to reason, to the mutual lassitude rather than to the
 Christian charity of the patriarchs.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"Among the
 titles of Imperial greatness, the name of Pious  was most
 pleasing to his ear; to promote the temporal and spiritual
 interest of the church was the serious business of his life;
 and the duty of father of his country was often sacrificed
 to that of defender of the faith.","('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Pious', 'PERSON')"
"An
 army of Greeks invaded Syria; the monastery of St. Maron was
 destroyed with fire; the bravest chieftains were betrayed
 and murdered, and twelve thousand of their followers were
 transplanted to the distant frontiers of Armenia and Thrace.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('St. Maron', 'GPE'), ('twelve thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Thrace', 'LOC')"
"An epistle of menace and invective, (48)
 which accompanied the summons, accused him as a busy,
 insolent, and envious priest, who perplexed the simplicity
 of the faith, violated the peace of the church and state,
 and, by his artful and separate addresses to the wife and
 sister of Theodosius, presumed to suppose, or to scatter,
 the seeds of discord in the Imperial family.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"And
 they might complain with the more reason, since the
 Catholics themselves did not agree with the astronomical
 calculations of their sovereign: the people of
 Constantinople delayed the beginning of their Lent a whole
 week after it had been ordained by authority; and they had
 the pleasure of fasting seven days, while meat was exposed
 for sale by the command of the emperor. of Samaritans","('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Lent', 'EVENT'), ('seven days', 'DATE'), ('Samaritans', 'NORP')"
"And such was the event of the first  of the religious wars which have been waged in the name and by the
 disciples, of the God of peace. (79)","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('79', 'CARDINAL')"
"And the metaphorical style of the
 Hebrews might ascribe to a saint and martyr the adoptive
 title of SON OF GOD.","('Hebrews', 'NORP')"
"And the rigid unity of the
 Monophysites, who, under the reigns of Zeno and Anastasius,
 had invaded the thrones of the East, provoked their
 antagonists, in a land of freedom, to avow a moral, rather
 than a physical, union of the two persons of Christ.","('Monophysites', 'NORP'), ('Zeno', 'PERSON'), ('Anastasius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Apollinaris entered
 the hostile city in military array, alike qualified for
 prayer or for battle.","('Apollinaris', 'PERSON')"
"Ardent in the prosecution of
 heresy, Cyril auspiciously opened his reign by oppressing
 the Novatians, the most innocent and harmless of the
 sectaries.","('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('Novatians', 'NORP')"
"Armenia and Abyssinia
 were infected by the speech or learning of the Greeks; and
 their Barbaric tongues, which have been revived in the
 studies of modern Europe, were unintelligible to the
 inhabitants of the Roman empire.","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Abyssinia', 'GPE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Barbaric', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Articulate sounds
 vibrated on the ears of the disciples; but the image which
 was impressed on their optic nerve eluded the more stubborn
 evidence of the touch; and they enjoyed the spiritual, not
 the corporeal, presence of the Son of God.","('the Son of God', 'PERSON')"
"As he passed
 through the streets, his chariot was assaulted by a band of
 five hundred of the Nitrian monks his guards fled from the
 wild beasts of the desert; his protestations that he was a
 Christian and a Catholic were answered by a volley of
 stones, and the face of Orestes was covered with blood.","('five hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nitrian', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Orestes', 'PERSON')"
"As the representative of the
 Western church, Pope Martin and his Lateran synod
 anathematized the perfidious and guilty silence of the
 Greeks: one hundred and five bishops of Italy, for the most
 part the subjects of Constans, presumed to reprobate his
 wicked type, and the impious ecthesis of his grandfather;
 and to confound the authors and their adherents with the
 twenty-one notorious heretics, the apostates from the
 church, and the organs of the devil.","('Western', 'NORP'), ('Pope Martin', 'PERSON'), ('Lateran', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('one hundred and five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Constans', 'PERSON'), ('twenty-one', 'CARDINAL')"
"Astonishment held them
 mute; but no sooner had Apollinaris begun to read the tome
 of St. Leo, than a volley of curses, and invectives, and
 stones, assaulted the odious minister of the emperor and the
 synod.","('Apollinaris', 'PERSON'), ('St. Leo', 'GPE')"
"At a distance
 from the court, and at the head of an immense capital, the
 patriarch, as he was now styled, of Alexandria had gradually
 usurped the state and authority of a civil magistrate.","('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"At length they yielded to the importunities of their masters; but their infallible decree, after it had been ratified with deliberate votes and
 vehement acclamations, was overturned in the next session by the opposition of the legates and their Oriental friends.","('Oriental', 'NORP')"
"At the command of Cyril his
 body was raised from the ground, and transported, in solemn
 procession, to the cathedral; the name of Ammonius was
 changed to that of Thaumasius the wonderful ; his tomb was
 decorated with the trophies of martyrdom, and the patriarch
 ascended the pulpit to celebrate the magnanimity of an
 assassin and a rebel.","('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('Ammonius', 'PERSON'), ('Thaumasius', 'PERSON')"
"At the end of four hundred years, the Montanists
 of Phrygia (85) still breathed the wild enthusiasm of
 perfection and prophecy which they had imbibed from their
 male and female apostles, the special organs of the
 Paraclete.","('the end of four hundred years', 'DATE'), ('the Montanists\r\n of Phrygia', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('85', 'CARDINAL'), ('Paraclete', 'NORP')"
"At the end of the
 ninth century, his shrine, perhaps in the neighborhood of
 Madras, was devoutly visited by the ambassadors of Alfred;
 and their return with a cargo of pearls and spices rewarded
 the zeal of the English monarch, who entertained the largest
 projects of trade and discovery. (123)","('the end of the\r\n ninth century', 'DATE'), ('Madras', 'GPE'), ('Alfred', 'PERSON'), ('English', 'NORP'), ('123', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the head of an Italian
 synod, Celestine weighed the merits of the cause, approved
 the creed of Cyril, condemned the sentiments and person of
 Nestorius, degraded the heretic from his episcopal dignity,
 allowed a respite of ten days for recantation and penance,
 and delegated to his enemy the execution of this rash and
 illegal sentence.","('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Celestine', 'PERSON'), ('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('Nestorius', 'PERSON'), ('ten days', 'DATE')"
"At these words a furious multitude of monks and soldiers, with staves, and swords, and chains, burst into the church; the trembling bishops hid themselves behind the altar, or under the benches, and as they were not inspired with the zeal of martyrdom, they successively subscribed a blank paper, which was afterwards filled with the condemnation of the Byzantine pontiff.","('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"Before that period, the
 precarious truce of Constantinople and Egypt had been
 violated by the zeal of the rival prelates.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"Before the end of the seventh century, the creed of the
 incarnation, which had been defined at Rome and
 Constantinople, was uniformly preached in the remote islands
 of Britain and Ireland; (108) the same ideas were
 entertained, or rather the same words were repeated, by all
 the Christians whose liturgy was performed in the Greek or
 the Latin tongue.","('the end of the seventh century', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Ireland', 'GPE'), ('108', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE')"
"Benjamin, the Jacobite patriarch, A.D. 625-661.","('Benjamin', 'PERSON'), ('Jacobite', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 625-661', 'DATE')"
"But
 it may reasonably be questioned, whether their union has
 ever been perfect or sincere; and the learned Maronites of
 the college of Rome have vainly labored to absolve their
 ancestors from the guilt of heresy and schism.","('Maronites', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But his adversary Cyril was more powerful in the weapons
 both of the flesh and of the spirit.","('Cyril', 'PERSON')"
"But his principles were secretly
 entertained in the monasteries of Egypt, and his enemies
 felt the hatred of Theophilus and Cyril, the successive
 patriarchs of Alexandria.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Theophilus', 'PERSON'), ('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"But in the
 creed of Justinian, the guilt of murder could not be applied
 to the slaughter of unbelievers; and he piously labored to
 establish with fire and sword the unity of the Christian
 faith.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"But in the second year, their patron was cast
 headlong from the throne, the bishops of the East were
 released from their occasional conformity, the Roman faith
 was more firmly replanted by the orthodox successors of
 Bardanes, and the fine problems of the incarnation were
 forgotten in the more popular and visible quarrel of the
 worship of images. (107)
Union of the Greek and Latin churches.","('the second year', 'DATE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Bardanes', 'PERSON'), ('107', 'CARDINAL'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"But instead of a
 temporary and occasional alliance, they  established, and we 
 still embrace, the substantial, indissoluble, and
 everlasting union of a perfect God with a perfect man, of
 the second person of the trinity with a reasonable soul and
 human flesh.","('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"But it had been imagined by a Monophysite bishop; (77) the gift of an enemy was at first rejected as a dire and dangerous blasphemy, and the rash innovation had nearly cost the emperor Anastasius his throne and his life. (78)","('Monophysite', 'NORP'), ('77', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Anastasius', 'PERSON')"
"But the
 Nubians at length executed their threats of returning to the
 worship of idols; the climate required the indulgence of
 polygamy, and they have finally preferred the triumph of the
 Koran to the abasement of the Cross.","('Nubians', 'NORP'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"But the
 approximation of ideas could not abate the vehemence of
 passion; each party was the more astonished that their blind
 antagonist could dispute on so trifling a difference; the
 tyrant of Syria enforced the belief of his creed, and his
 reign was polluted with the blood of three hundred and fifty
 monks, who were slain, not perhaps without provocation or
resistance, under the walls of Apamea. (126)","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('three hundred and fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Apamea', 'ORG'), ('126', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the
 despotism of the Alexandrian patriarch again oppressed the
 freedom of debate: the same spiritual and carnal weapons
 were again drawn from the arsenals of Egypt: the Asiatic
 veterans, a band of archers, served under the orders of
 Dioscorus; and the more formidable monks, whose minds were
 inaccessible to reason or mercy, besieged the doors of the
 cathedral.","('Alexandrian', 'NORP'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Dioscorus', 'NORP')"
"But the
 prevailing doctrine of the eternity and inherent pravity of
 matter infected the primitive churches of the East.","('East', 'LOC')"
"But the Latin churches were more jealous of the
 honor of Leo and the synod of Chalcedon: and if they had
 fought as they usually did under the standard of Rome, they
 might have prevailed in the cause of reason and humanity.","('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Chalcedon', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But the Orientals refused to yield, and the Catholics, proud
 of their numbers and of their Latin allies, rejected all
 terms of union or toleration.","('Orientals', 'NORP'), ('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"But the Vatican received
 with open arms the messengers of Egypt.","('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"But the author of the twelve
 anathemas foresaw and dreaded the opposition of John of
 Antioch, who, with a small, but respectable, train of
 metropolitans and divines, was advancing by slow journeys
 from the distant capital of the East.","('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('John of\r\n Antioch', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"But the bishop and monks of Jerusalem sounded the
 alarm: in the language, or even in the silence, of the
 Greeks, the Latin churches detected a latent heresy: and the
 obedience of Pope Honorius to the commands of his sovereign
 was retracted and censured by the bolder ignorance of his
 successors.","('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Pope Honorius', 'PERSON')"
"But the characters of these Oriental bishops
 were tainted with the reproach of heresy; the first had been
 the master, the two others were the friends, of Nestorius;
 their most suspicious passages were accused under the title
 of the three chapters; and the condemnation of their memory
 must involve the honor of a synod, whose name was pronounced
 with sincere or affected reverence by the Catholic world.","('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nestorius', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"But the event was foreseen, the
 increase was denied: the episcopal office has been gradually
 confined to the abuna, (155) the head and author of the
 Abyssinian priesthood; the patriarch supplies each vacancy
 with an Egyptian monk; and the character of a stranger
 appears more venerable in the eyes of the people, less
 dangerous in those of the monarch.","('155', 'CARDINAL'), ('Abyssinian', 'NORP'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP')"
"But the justice and generosity of
 such a desertion are strongly questionable; and the fate of
 an innocent martyr, at first impelled, and at length
 abandoned, by his divine companion, might provoke the pity
 and indignation of the profane.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But the lieutenant of Justinian had not conquered in
 the cause of a heretic; Theodosius himself was speedily,
 though gently, removed; and A.D. 538 Paul of Tanis, an orthodox monk,
 was raised to the throne of Athanasius.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Tanis', 'PERSON'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"But the pageant
 of Oriental royalty was moved with equal dexterity by the
 hand of the eunuch; and Theodosius could pronounce, without
 hesitation, that the church was already peaceful and
 triumphant, and that the recent flame had been extinguished
 by the just punishment of the Nestorians.","('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Nestorians', 'NORP')"
"But the patriarch of Alexandria, while he
 darted the thunders of a god, exposed the errors and
 passions of a mortal; and his twelve anathemas (39) still
 torture the orthodox slaves, who adore the memory of a
 saint, without forfeiting their allegiance to the synod of
 Chalcedon.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('39', 'DATE'), ('Chalcedon', 'PERSON')"
"But the person of the
 aged bishop of Laedicea, his character and dignity, remained
 inviolate; and his rivals, since we may not suspect them of
 the weakness of toleration, were astonished, perhaps, by the
 novelty of the argument, and diffident of the final sentence
 of the Catholic church.","('Laedicea', 'GPE'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"But the public danger soon called for the instant
 and effectual aid of arms and soldiers, to defend an
 unwarlike people from the Barbarians who ravaged the inland
 country and the Turks and Arabs who advanced from the
 sea-coast in more formidable array.","('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"But the rashness of
 these concessions has encouraged a milder sentiment of those
 of the Docetes, who taught, not that Christ was a phantom,
 but that he was clothed with an impassible and incorruptible
 body.","('Docetes', 'NORP'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"But the religious discontent of the
 Italians had already promoted the conquests of the Lombards,
 and the Romans themselves were accustomed to suspect the
 faith and to detest the government of their Byzantine
 tyrant.","('Italians', 'NORP'), ('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"But the same faith, which has been confined to a narrow sect of the Syrians, was diffused over the mass of the Egyptian or Coptic nation; who, almost unanimously, rejected the decrees of the synod of Chalcedon.","('Syrians', 'NORP'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP'), ('Coptic', 'NORP'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE')"
"But the same invincible spirit survived in
 their successors; and the triumph of the Latins avenged
 their recent defeat, and obliterated the disgrace of the
 three chapters.","('Latins', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the secret and authentic history has been
 recorded in several copies of the Gospel according to St.
 Matthew, (4) which these sectaries long preserved in the
 original Hebrew, (5) as the sole evidence of their faith.","('Gospel', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('St.\r\n Matthew', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('4', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hebrew', 'LANGUAGE'), ('5', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the seeming tranquillity
 of the Nestorians was often endangered, and sometimes
 overthrown.","('Nestorians', 'NORP')"
"But the stubborn temper of the Egyptians
 maintained their opposition to the synod of Chalcedon, and
 the policy of Justinian condescended to expect and to seize
 the opportunity of discord.","('Egyptians', 'NORP'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
But the sword of persecution which Nestorius so furiously wielded was soon turned against his own breast.,"('Nestorius', 'PERSON')"
"But their
 incessant demands despoiled the sanctuaries of
 Constantinople and Alexandria; and the authority of the
 patriarch was unable to silence the just murmur of his
 clergy, that a debt of sixty thousand pounds had already
 been contracted to support the expense of this scandalous
 corruption. (50) Pulcheria, who relieved her brother from the
 weight of an empire, was the firmest pillar of orthodoxy;
 and so intimate was the alliance between the thunders of the
 synod and the whispers of the court, that Cyril was assured
 of success if he could displace one eunuch, and substitute
 another in the favor of Theodosius.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('sixty thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('Pulcheria', 'PERSON'), ('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"But their chief was a prisoner in the hands of the enemy;
 the throne of St. Peter, which had been disgraced by the
 simony, was betrayed by the cowardice, of Vigilius, who
 yielded, after a long and inconsistent struggle, to the
 despotism of Justinian and the sophistry of the Greeks.","('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('Vigilius', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"But when his
 pure and proper divinity had been established on the ruins
 of Arianism, the faith of the Catholics trembled on the edge
 of a precipice where it was impossible to recede, dangerous
 to stand, dreadful to fall and the manifold inconveniences
 of their creed were aggravated by the sublime character of
 their theology.","('Arianism', 'NORP'), ('Catholics', 'NORP')"
"But while Justinian strove to maintain the uniformity of
 faith and worship, his wife Theodora, whose vices were not
 incompatible with devotion, had listened to the Monophysite
 teachers; and the open or clandestine enemies of the church
 revived and multiplied at the smile of their gracious
 patroness.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('Monophysite', 'NORP')"
"By the special
 summons of Theodosius, the second synod of Ephesus was
 judiciously composed of ten metropolitans and ten bishops
 from each of the six dioceses of the Eastern empire: some
 exceptions of favor or merit enlarged the number to one
 hundred and thirty-five; and the Syrian Barsumas, as the
 chief and representative of the monks, was invited to sit
 and vote with the successors of the apostles.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Ephesus', 'GPE'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('one\r\n hundred and thirty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Syrian', 'NORP'), ('Barsumas', 'PERSON')"
"By the vigilance of Memnon, the churches
 were shut against them, and a strong garrison was thrown
 into the cathedral.","('Memnon', 'PERSON')"
"Candidian, in the emperor's name, requested a delay of four
 days; Condemnation of Nestorius, June 22.","('Candidian', 'PERSON'), ('four\r\n days', 'DATE'), ('Condemnation of Nestorius', 'ORG'), ('June 22', 'DATE')"
"Christianity was more deeply rooted in the Abyssinian
 empire; and, although the correspondence has been sometimes
 interrupted above seventy or a hundred years, the
 mother-church of Alexandria retains her colony in a state of
 perpetual pupilage.","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Abyssinian', 'NORP'), ('seventy or a hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"Christianity was successfully preached to the
 Bactrians, the Huns, the Persians, the Indians, the
 Persarmenians, the Medes, and the Elamites: the Barbaric
 churches, from the Gulf of Persia to the Caspian Sea, were
 almost infinite; and their recent faith was conspicuous in
 the number and sanctity of their monks and martyrs.","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Bactrians', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Indians', 'NORP'), ('Persarmenians', 'NORP'), ('Medes', 'NORP'), ('Elamites', 'NORP'), ('Barbaric', 'NORP'), ('the Gulf of Persia', 'LOC'), ('the Caspian Sea', 'LOC')"
"Conscious of their
 own indigence, the Abyssinians had formed the rational
 project of importing the arts and ingenuity of Europe; (157)
 and their ambassadors at Rome and Lisbon were instructed to
 solicit a colony of smiths, carpenters, tilers, masons,
 printers, surgeons, and physicians, for the use of their
 country.","('Abyssinians', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('157', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Lisbon', 'GPE')"
"Constantinople and the suburbs were
 sanctified with frequent monasteries, and the holy abbots,
 Dalmatius and Eutyches, (49) had devoted their zeal and
 fidelity to the cause of Cyril, the worship of Mary, and the
 unity of Christ.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Dalmatius', 'PERSON'), ('Eutyches', 'NORP'), ('49', 'DATE'), ('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('Mary', 'PERSON')"
"Conversion of the emperor, A.D. 1626.","('A.D. 1626', 'DATE')"
"Council of Chalcedon, A.D. 451, October 8-November 1.","('Council of Chalcedon', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 451', 'DATE'), ('October 8-November 1', 'DATE')"
"Cyril
 announced the opening of the synod sixteen days after the
 festival of Pentecost.","('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('sixteen days', 'DATE'), ('Pentecost', 'EVENT')"
"Cyril had repaired to Ephesus,
 where he was resisted, threatened, and confined, by the
 magistrates in the interest of Nestorius and the Orientals;
 who assembled the troops of Lydia and Ionia to suppress the
 fanatic and disorderly train of the patriarch.","('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('Ephesus', 'GPE'), ('Nestorius', 'PERSON'), ('Orientals', 'PERSON'), ('Lydia', 'PERSON'), ('Ionia', 'GPE')"
"Cyril prayed and fasted in the desert, but
 his thoughts (it is the reproach of a friend) (21) were still
 fixed on the world; and the call of Theophilus, who summoned
 him to the tumult of cities and synods, was too readily
 obeyed by the aspiring hermit.","('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('21', 'DATE'), ('Theophilus', 'PERSON')"
"Cyril, patriach of Alexandria, A.D. 412, October 18- A.D. 444, June 27.","('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 412', 'DATE'), ('October 18- A.D. 444', 'DATE'), ('June 27', 'DATE')"
"Discord of the East, A.D. 451-482.","('451-482', 'CARDINAL')"
"Disobedient to the
 letter, or at least to the meaning, of the royal summons, he
 was attended by fifty Egyptian bishops, who expected from
 their patriarch's nod the inspiration of the Holy Ghost.","('fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP'), ('the Holy Ghost', 'PERSON')"
"Divine incarnation of Apollinaris
 IV.","('Apollinaris\r\n IV', 'ORG')"
"Double nature of Cerinthus
 III.","('Cerinthus\r\n III', 'PERSON')"
"During a busy period of three months, the emperor
 tried every method, except the most effectual means of
 indifference and contempt, to reconcile this theological
 quarrel.","('three months', 'DATE')"
"During several ages, the bishops of Nubia
 were named and consecrated by the Jacobite patriarch of
 Alexandria: as late as the twelfth century, Christianity
 prevailed; and some rites, some ruins, are still visible in
 the savage towns of Sennaar and Dongola. (154)","('several ages', 'DATE'), ('Nubia', 'GPE'), ('Jacobite', 'NORP'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('as late as the twelfth century', 'DATE'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Sennaar', 'GPE'), ('Dongola', 'GPE'), ('154', 'CARDINAL')"
"During ten centuries of blindness and servitude, Europe received her religious opinions from the oracle of the Vatican; and the same doctrine, already varnished with the rust of antiquity, was admitted without dispute into the creed of the reformers, who disclaimed the supremacy of the Roman pontiff.","('ten centuries', 'DATE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Educated in the school of Jewish
 prophecy and prejudice, they had never been taught to
 elevate their hopes above a human and temporal Messiah.","('Jewish', 'NORP')"
"Encompassed on all sides by the enemies of
 their religion, the Aethiopians slept near a thousand years,
 forgetful of the world, by whom they were forgotten.","('Aethiopians', 'NORP'), ('a thousand years', 'DATE')"
"Ephesus, the city of the Virgin, was defiled with rage and
 clamor, with sedition and blood; the rival synods darted
 anathemas and excommunications from their spiritual engines;
 and the court of Theodosius was perplexed by the adverse and
 contradictory narratives of the Syrian and Egyptian
 factions.","('Ephesus', 'GPE'), ('Virgin', 'LOC'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Syrian', 'NORP'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP')"
"Far different was the temper of the Greeks and Egyptians
 under the orthodox reigns of Leo and Marcian.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Egyptians', 'NORP'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Marcian', 'PERSON')"
"Fifty-four bishops were swept from their thrones, eight
 hundred ecclesiastics were cast into prison, (128) and
 notwithstanding the ambiguous favor of Theodora, the
 Oriental flocks, deprived of their shepherds, must
 insensibly have been either famished or poisoned.","('Fifty-four', 'CARDINAL'), ('eight\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('Oriental', 'NORP')"
"Final expulsion of the Jesuits, A.D. 1632, etc.","('Jesuits', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 1632', 'DATE')"
"First council of Ephesus, A.D. 431, June-October.","('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Ephesus', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 431', 'DATE'), ('June-October', 'DATE')"
"First religious war, A.D. 514","('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('A.D. 514', 'DATE')"
"Five rebellions were extinguished in the blood of the insurgents: two abunas were slain in battle, whole legions were slaughtered in the field, or suffocated in their caverns; and neither merit, nor rank, nor sex, could save from an ignominious death the enemies of Rome.","('Five', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Flavian was instantly delivered to the wild beasts of this spiritual
 amphitheatre: the monks were stimulated by the voice and example of Barsumas to avenge the injuries of Christ: it is said that the patriarch of Alexandria reviled, and buffeted, and kicked, and trampled his brother of Constantinople: (61) it is certain, that the victim, before he could reach the place of his exile, expired on the third day of the wounds and bruises which he had received at Ephesus.","('Flavian', 'PERSON'), ('Barsumas', 'NORP'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'PERSON'), ('61', 'CARDINAL'), ('the third day', 'DATE'), ('Ephesus', 'GPE')"
"For accepting the
 communion of Alexandria, without a formal approbation of the
 same synod, the patriarchs of Constantinople were
 anathematized by the popes.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"For these scandalous offences, Dioscorus was deposed by the
 synod, and banished by the emperor; but the purity of his
 faith was declared in the presence, and with the tacit
 approbation, of the fathers.","('Dioscorus', 'PERSON')"
"Forty-seven archbishops, each of whom
 may claim the obedience of four or five suffragans, are
 consecrated by his hand; but the far greater part are only
 titular prelates, who dignify with their presence and
 service the simplicity of his court.","('Forty-seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('four or five', 'CARDINAL')"
"Fremona, a place of worship, or
 rather of exile, was assigned to the Jesuit missionaries.","('Fremona', 'PERSON'), ('Jesuit', 'NORP')"
"From
 his independent throne, the Roman bishop spoke and acted
 without danger as the head of the Christians, and his
 dictates were obsequiously transcribed by Placidia and her
 son Valentinian; who addressed their Eastern colleague to
 restore the peace and unity of the church.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Placidia', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"From the
 pulpit of Constantinople, a friend of the patriarch, and
 afterwards the patriarch himself, repeatedly preached
 against the use, or the abuse, of a word (35) unknown to the
 apostles, unauthorized by the church, and which could only
 tend to alarm the timorous, to mislead the simple, to amuse
 the profane, and to justify, by a seeming resemblance, the
 old genealogy of Olympus. (36)","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Olympus', 'ORG'), ('36', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the East, more especially from
 Antioch, he obtained the ambiguous counsels of toleration
 and silence, which were addressed to both parties while they
 favored the cause of Nestorius.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Nestorius', 'PERSON')"
"From the conquest of Persia they carried
 their spiritual arms to the north, the east, and the south;
 and the simplicity of the gospel was fashioned and painted
 with the colors of the Syriac theology.","('Persia', 'LOC'), ('Syriac', 'NORP')"
"From the earliest period to the present hour, Armenia has been the theatre of perpetual war: the lands between Tauris and Erivan were dispeopled by the cruel policy of the Sophis; and myriads of
 Christian families were transplanted, to perish or to propagate in the distant provinces of Persia.","('the present hour', 'TIME'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Tauris', 'GPE'), ('Erivan', 'GPE'), ('Sophis', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"From the first moment of their monastic
 life, they had never mingled with the world, or trod the
 profane ground of the city.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"From the holy
 confessors in their prison of Constantinople, he received
 the powers of bishop of Edessa and apostle of the East, and
 the ordination of fourscore thousand bishops, priests, and
 deacons, is derived from the same inexhaustible source.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Edessa', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('fourscore thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"From their partial
 decree, Eutyches appealed to a general council; and his
 cause was vigorously asserted by his godson Chrysaphius, the
 reigning eunuch of the palace, and his accomplice Dioscorus,
 who had succeeded to the throne, the creed, the talents, and
 the vices, of the nephew of Theophilus.","('Eutyches', 'PERSON'), ('Chrysaphius', 'PERSON'), ('Dioscorus', 'PERSON'), ('Theophilus', 'PERSON')"
"Had he invited to these synods a disinterested and rational spectator, Justinian might have learned, "" that  religious controversy is the offspring of arrogance and folly; that  true piety is most laudably expressed by silence and submission; that  man, ignorant of his own nature, should not presume to scrutinize the nature of his God; and that  it is sufficient for us to know, that power and benevolence are the perfect attributes of the Deity."" (83)","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('83', 'CARDINAL')"
"He
 had contracted an intimate alliance with Memnon, bishop of
 Ephesus.","('Memnon', 'PERSON'), ('Ephesus', 'GPE')"
"He acquiesced in the old distinction of
 the Greek philosophers between the rational and sensitive
 soul of man; that he might reserve the Logos for
 intellectual functions, and employ the subordinate human
 principle in the meaner actions of animal life.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Logos', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"He attempted to remove or intimidate the leaders
 by a common sentence, of acquittal or condemnation; he
 invested his representatives at Ephesus with ample power and
 military force; he summoned from either party eight chosen
 deputies to a free and candid conference in the neighborhood
 of the capital, far from the contagion of popular frenzy.","('Ephesus', 'GPE'), ('eight', 'CARDINAL')"
"He condemned the ancient practice of circumcision, which health, rather than superstition, had first invented in the climate of Aethiopia. (160)","('Aethiopia', 'GPE'), ('160', 'CARDINAL')"
"He first appeared on
 the banks of the Jordan in the form of perfect manhood; but
 it was a form only, and not a substance; a human figure
 created by the hand of Omnipotence to imitate the faculties
 and actions of a man, and to impose a perpetual illusion on
 the senses of his friends and enemies.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Jordan', 'GPE')"
"He lived and died for the service of mankind: but the
 life and death of Socrates had likewise been devoted to the
 cause of religion and justice; and although the stoic or the
 hero may disdain the humble virtues of Jesus, the tears
 which he shed over his friend and country may be esteemed
 the purest evidence of his humanity.","('Socrates', 'PERSON'), ('Jesus', 'PERSON')"
"He repaid their homage
 by magnifying their greatness; and it was boldly asserted
 that they could bring into the field a hundred thousand
 horse, with an equal number of camels; (150) that their hand
 could pour out or restrain the waters of the Nile; (151) and
 the peace and plenty of Egypt was obtained, even in this
 world, by the intercession of the patriarch.","('a hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('150', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('151', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"He still asserted his
 ancient title of metropolitan of India, but his real
 jurisdiction was exercised in fourteen hundred churches, and
 he was intrusted with the care of two hundred thousand
 souls.","('India', 'GPE'), ('fourteen hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('two hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"He stood erect on his
 throne, and, throwing aside the upper garment of a warrior,
 suddenly appeared before the eyes of the multitude in the
 robes of patriarch of Alexandria.","('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"He taught that
 the Godhead was united or mingled with the body of a man;
 and that the Logos, the eternal wisdom, supplied in the
 flesh the place and office of a human soul.","('Godhead', 'PERSON')"
"He was
 buried in a city of Upper Egypt, known by the names of
 Chemnis, or Panopolis, or Akmim; (56) but the immortal malice of the Jacobites has persevered for ages to cast stones
 against his sepulchre, and to propagate the foolish
 tradition, that it was never watered by the rain of heaven,
 which equally descends on the righteous and the ungodly. (57)","('Upper Egypt', 'LOC'), ('Chemnis', 'PERSON'), ('Panopolis', 'PERSON'), ('Akmim', 'PERSON'), ('56', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jacobites', 'PERSON')"
"Her judgment at length inclined in
 their favor; the heresy of Apollinaris was condemned, and
 the separate congregations of his disciples were proscribed
 by the Imperial laws.","('Apollinaris', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
Heresy of Eutyches —  Fourth General Council of Chalcedon — Civil and Ecclesiastical Discord — Intolerance of Justinian — Three  Chapters — Monothelite Controversy —  State of the Oriental Sects.,"('Fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Three', 'CARDINAL'), ('State of the Oriental Sects', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Heresy of Justinian, A.D. 564.","('A.D. 564', 'DATE')"
"His
 apostasy provoked the indignation of the Latins, and no more
 than two bishops could be found who would impose their hands
 on his deacon and successor Pelagius.","('Latins', 'NORP'), ('no more\r\n than two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pelagius', 'PERSON')"
"His
 enmity to the Byzantine pontiffs (29) was a sense of interest, not a sally of passion: he envied their fortunate
 station in the sunshine of the Imperial court; and he
 dreaded their upstart ambition.","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('29', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"His
 flight was punished as a new crime: the soul of the
 patriarch inspired the civil and ecclesiastical powers of
 Egypt; the magistrates, the soldiers, the monks, devoutly
 tortured the enemy of Christ and St. Cyril; and, as far as
 the confines of Aethiopia, the heretic was alternately
 dragged and recalled, till his aged body was broken by the
 hardships and accidents of these reiterated journeys.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('St. Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('Aethiopia', 'GPE')"
"His
 throne was distant and inaccessible; but they instantly
 resolved to bestow on the flock of Ephesus the blessing of a
 faithful shepherd.","('Ephesus', 'GPE')"
"His Tyranny, A.D. 413,414,415, etc","('413,414,415', 'CARDINAL')"
"His comely person adorned the pulpit; the
 harmony of his voice resounded in the cathedral; his friends
 were stationed to lead or second the applause of the
 congregation; (22) and the hasty notes of the scribes
 preserved his discourses, which in their effect, though not
 in their composition, might be compared with those of the
 Athenian orators.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('22', 'CARDINAL'), ('Athenian', 'NORP')"
"His death restored in some degree the peace of the church, and the reigns of his four successors, Justin Tiberius, Maurice, and Phocas, are distinguished by a rare, though fortunate, vacancy in the ecclesiastical history of the East. (100)","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Justin Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('Phocas', 'PERSON'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"His domestic synod was
 instantly convened, their proceedings were sullied with
 clamor and artifice, and the aged heretic was surprised into
 a seeming confession, that Christ had not derived his body
 from the substance of the Virgin Mary.","('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('the Virgin Mary', 'PERSON')"
"His heresy, A.D. 429-431.","('A.D. 429-431', 'DATE')"
"His opinions were favorably entertained in the palace and the city; the influence of Theodora assured him a safe conduct and honorable dismission; and he ended his days, though not on the throne, yet in the bosom, of his native country.","('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"His provincial synod annulled the
 irregular proceedings of Ephesus; but as this step was
 itself irregular, he solicited the convocation of a general
 council in the free and orthodox provinces of Italy.","('Ephesus', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"His rival EUTYCHES was
 the abbot, or archimandrite, or superior of three hundred
 monks, but the opinions of a simple and illiterate recluse
 might have expired in the cell, where he had slept above
 seventy years, if the resentment or indiscretion of Flavian,
 the Byzantine pontiff, had not exposed the scandal to the
 eyes of the Christian world.","('EUTYCHES', 'PERSON'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('seventy years', 'DATE'), ('Flavian', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
His successor A.D. 551.,"('A.D. 551', 'DATE')"
"Humanity may drop a tear on the fate of Nestorius; yet
 justice must observe, that he suffered the persecution which
 he had approved and inflicted. (58)
Heresy of Eutyches, A.D. 448.","('Nestorius', 'PERSON'), ('448', 'CARDINAL')"
"Hypatia, the daughter of Theon the
 mathematician, (25) was initiated in her father's studies;
 her learned comments have elucidated the geometry of
 Apollonius and Diophantus, and she publicly taught, both at
 Athens and Alexandria, the philosophy of Plato and
 Aristotle.","('Hypatia', 'PERSON'), ('Theon', 'PERSON'), ('25', 'DATE'), ('Apollonius', 'NORP'), ('Diophantus', 'PERSON'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('Aristotle', 'PERSON')"
"IIId of Constantinople, A.D. 680, Nov. 7- 681, Sept. 16.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 680', 'DATE'), ('Nov. 7- 681', 'DATE'), ('Sept. 16', 'DATE')"
"IId of Constantinople, A.D. 553, May 4-June 2.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 553', 'DATE'), ('May 4-June 2', 'DATE')"
"If it were urged,
 that such ideal mimicry, such incessant deception, was
 unworthy of the God of truth, the Docetes agreed with too
 many of their orthodox brethren in the justification of
 pious falsehood.","('Docetes', 'PERSON')"
"If these bishops, whether innocent or guilty, were
 annihilated in the sleep of death, they would not probably
 be awakened by the clamor which, after the a hundred years,
 was raised over their grave.","('the a hundred years', 'DATE')"
"If we fairly peruse the
 acts of Chalcedon as they are recorded by the orthodox
 party, (64) we shall find that a great majority of the
 bishops embraced the simple unity of Christ; and the
 ambiguous concession that he was formed","('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('64', 'DATE')"
"In Persia,
 notwithstanding the resistance of the Magi, Christianity had
 struck a deep root, and the nations of the East reposed
 under its salutary shade.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Magi', 'NORP'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"In Syria, in Egypt, in
 Ethiopia, the Jacobite monks have ever been distinguished by
 the austerity of their penance and the absurdity of their
 legends.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Ethiopia', 'GPE'), ('Jacobite', 'NORP')"
"In a chamber of the
 inn, before he had wiped the dust from his shoes, John of
 Antioch gave audience to Candidian, the Imperial minister;
 who related his ineffectual efforts to prevent or to annul
 the hasty violence of the Egyptian.","('John', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Candidian', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP')"
"In a later
 age the Lutherans have been burnt at Paris, and protected in
 Germany, by the superstition and policy of the most
 Christian king.","('Lutherans', 'NORP'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"In a moment of terror, the
 emperor had promised to reconcile himself and his subjects
 to the Catholic faith; a Latin patriarch represented the
 supremacy of the pope: (158) the empire, enlarged in a
 tenfold proportion, was supposed to contain more gold than
 the mines of America; and the wildest hopes of avarice and
 zeal were built on the willing submission of the Christians
 of Africa.","('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('158', 'CARDINAL'), ('America', 'GPE'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"In a subsequent age the zeal of the
 Nestorians overleaped the limits which had confined the
 ambition and curiosity both of the Greeks and Persians.","('Nestorians', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"In arms, in arts, and possibly
 in virtue, they excelled the natives of Hindostan; the
 husbandmen cultivated the palm-tree, the merchants were
 enriched by the pepper trade, the soldiers preceded the
 nairs or nobles of Malabar, and their hereditary privileges
 were respected by the gratitude or the fear of the king of
 Cochin and the Zamorin himself.","('Hindostan', 'NORP'), ('Malabar', 'NORP'), ('Cochin', 'GPE'), ('Zamorin', 'NORP')"
"In exile at
 Constantinople, Theodosius recommended to his patroness the
 conversion of the black nations of Nubia, from the tropic of
 Cancer to the confines of Abyssinia. (152)","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('Nubia', 'GPE'), ('Cancer', 'LOC'), ('Abyssinia', 'GPE'), ('152', 'CARDINAL')"
"In his
 last treaty, Justinian introduced some conditions which
 tended to enlarge and fortify the toleration of Christianity
 in Persia.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"In his
 public and private devotions, the emperor was assiduous and
 exemplary; his prayers, vigils, and fasts, displayed the
 austere penance of a monk; his fancy was amused by the hope,
 or belief, of personal inspiration; he had secured the
 patronage of the Virgin and St. Michael the archangel; and
 his recovery from a dangerous disease was ascribed to the
 miraculous succor of the holy martyrs Cosmas and Damian.","('St. Michael the archangel', 'PERSON'), ('Cosmas', 'PERSON'), ('Damian', 'PERSON')"
"In his calmer moments
 Nestorius confessed, that it might be tolerated or excused
 by the union of the two natures, and the communication of
 their idioms : (37) but he was exasperated, by contradiction,
 to disclaim the worship of a new-born, an infant Deity, to
 draw his inadequate similes from the conjugal or civil
 partnerships of life, and to describe the manhood of Christ
 as the robe, the instrument, the tabernacle of his Godhead.","('Nestorius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('37', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"In his death, his funeral was attended by
 his rival the Nestorian patriarch, with a train of Greeks
 and Armenians, who forgot their disputes, and mingled their
 tears over the grave of an enemy.","('Nestorian', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Armenians', 'NORP')"
"In his flight, Benjamin was encouraged by a voice, which bade him expect, at the end of ten years, the aid of a foreign nation, marked, like the Egyptians themselves, with the ancient rite of circumcision.","('Benjamin', 'PERSON'), ('the end of ten years', 'DATE'), ('Egyptians', 'NORP')"
"In his life he
 was an elegant writer of the Syriac and Arabic tongues, a
 poet, physician, and historian, a subtile philosopher, and a
 moderate divine.","('Syriac', 'NORP'), ('Arabic', 'NORP')"
"In his turn,
 the tyrant was excommunicated by the zeal and revenge of the
 people: and none except his servile Melchites would salute
 him as a man, a Christian, or a bishop.","('Melchites', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"In his youth he was, offended by the slightest
 deviation from the orthodox line; in his old age he
 transgressed the measure of temperate heresy, and the
 Jacobites, not less than the Catholics, were scandalized by
 his declaration, that the body of Christ was incorruptible,
 and that his manhood was never subject to any wants and
 infirmities, the inheritance of our mortal flesh.","('Jacobites', 'NORP'), ('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"In the
 language of antiquity, the title of God has not been
 severely confined to the first parent, and his incomparable
 minister, his only-begotten son, might claim, without
 presumption, the religious, though secondary, worship of a
 subject of a subject world.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('secondary', 'ORDINAL')"
"In the Persian school of Edessa, (114) the rising
 generations of the faithful imbibed their theological idiom:
 they studied in the Syriac version the ten thousand volumes
 of Theodore of Mopsuestia; and they revered the apostolic
 faith and holy martyrdom of his disciple Nestorius, whose
 person and language were equally unknown to the nations
 beyond the Tigris.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Edessa', 'GPE'), ('114', 'CARDINAL'), ('Syriac', 'LANGUAGE'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodore of Mopsuestia', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Nestorius', 'PERSON'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"In the Syrian school, Nestorius had been taught to abhor the
 confusion of the two natures, and nicely to discriminate the
 humanity of his master  Christ from the divinity of the Lord
 Jesus. (33)","('Syrian', 'NORP'), ('Nestorius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Jesus', 'PERSON'), ('33', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the age of religious freedom, which was
 determined by the council of Nice, the dignity of Christ was
 measured by private judgment according to the indefinite
 rule of Scripture, or reason, or tradition.","('Nice', 'GPE'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Scripture', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"In the beginning of the fifth century, the
 unity  of the two natures  was the prevailing doctrine of the
 church.","('the beginning of the fifth century', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the bloom of beauty, and in the maturity of
 wisdom, the modest maid refused her lovers and instructed
 her disciples; the persons most illustrious for their rank
 or merit were impatient to visit the female philosopher; and
 Cyril beheld, with a jealous eye, the gorgeous train of
 horses and slaves who crowded the door of her academy.","('Cyril', 'PERSON')"
"In the controversies of the incarnation they
 nicely threaded the orthodox line between the sects of
 Nestorians and Eutyches; but the unfortunate question of one will or operation in the two natures of Christ, was
 generated by their curious leisure.","('Nestorians', 'NORP'), ('Eutyches', 'ORG'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the defense of their religion and liberty, the Abyssinians rose in arms, with desperate but unsuccessful zeal.","('Abyssinians', 'NORP')"
"In the first moments of their interview, the subjects of
 Rome and Alexandria observed the resemblance, rather than
 the difference, of their faith; and each nation expected the
 most important benefits from an alliance with their
 Christian brethren.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"In the first years of his
 administration, he signalized his zeal as the disciple and
 patron of orthodoxy: the reconciliation of the Greeks and
 Latins established the tome of St. Leo as the creed of the
 emperor and the empire; the Nestorians and Eutychians were
 exposed.","('the first years', 'DATE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('St. Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Nestorians', 'NORP'), ('Eutychians', 'NORP')"
"In the fourscore thousand towns or villages of his
 spiritual empire, the patriarch receives a small and
 voluntary tax from each person above the age of fifteen; but
 the annual amount of six hundred thousand crowns is
 insufficient to supply the incessant demands of charity and
 tribute.","('thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('the age of fifteen', 'DATE'), ('six hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the house of his
 uncle, the archbishop Theophilus, he imbibed the orthodox
 lessons of zeal and dominion, and five years of his youth
 were profitably spent in the adjacent monasteries of Nitria.","('Theophilus', 'PERSON'), ('five years', 'DATE'), ('Nitria', 'GPE')"
"In the most abject
 state of ignorance, poverty, and servitude, the Nestorians
 and Monophysites reject the spiritual supremacy of Rome, and
 cherish the toleration of their Turkish masters, which
 allows them to anathematize, on the one hand, St. Cyril and
 the synod of Ephesus: on the other, Pope Leo and the council
 of Chalcedon.","('Nestorians', 'NORP'), ('Monophysites', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('St. Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('Ephesus', 'GPE'), ('Pope Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE')"
"In the name of the fourth general council, the Christ in one person, but in two natures, was announced to the Catholic world: an invisible line was drawn between the heresy of Apollinaris and the faith of St. Cyril; and the road to paradise, a bridge as sharp as a razor, was suspended over the abyss by the master-hand of the theological artist.","('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('general council', 'ORG'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Apollinaris', 'NORP'), ('St. Cyril', 'GPE')"
"In the next
 generation, when the son of Constantine was deposed and
 slain by the disciple of Macarius, they tasted the feast of
 revenge and dominion: the image or monument of the sixth
 council was defaced, and the original acts were committed to
 the flames.","('the next\r\n generation', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Macarius', 'PERSON'), ('sixth', 'ORDINAL')"
"In the rest of the Roman empire, the despotism of the
 prince might eradicate or silence the sectaries of an
 obnoxious creed.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the sixth
 century, according to the report of a Nestorian traveller,
 (116)","('the sixth\r\n century', 'DATE'), ('Nestorian', 'NORP'), ('116', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the sixth century,
 when the schism of Egypt was confirmed, the rival chiefs,
 with their patrons, Justinian and Theodora, strove to
 outstrip each other in the conquest of a remote and
 independent province.","('the sixth century', 'DATE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"In the style of the Oriental Christians, the
 Monothelites of every age are described under the
 appellation of Maronites, (133) a name which has been insensibly transferred from a hermit to a monastery, from a
 monastery to a nation.","('the Oriental Christians', 'NORP'), ('Monothelites', 'NORP'), ('Maronites', 'NORP'), ('133', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the system of the Gnostics, the Jehovah
 of Israel, the Creator of this lower world, was a
 rebellious, or at least an ignorant, spirit.","('Gnostics', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Israel', 'GPE')"
"In the twelfth century,
 the Maronites, abjuring the Monothelite error were
 reconciled to the Latin churches of Antioch and Rome, (137)
 and the same alliance has been frequently renewed by the
 ambition of the popes and the distress of the Syrians.","('the twelfth century', 'DATE'), ('Maronites', 'NORP'), ('Monothelite', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('137', 'CARDINAL'), ('Syrians', 'NORP')"
"In their Syriac liturgy
 the names of Theodore and Nestorius were piously
 commemorated: they united their adoration of the two persons
 of Christ; the title of Mother of God was offensive to their
 ear, and they measured with scrupulous avarice the honors of
 the Virgin Mary, whom the superstition of the Latins had
 almost exalted to the rank of a goddess.","('Syriac', 'NORP'), ('Theodore', 'PERSON'), ('Nestorius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Mother of God', 'PERSON'), ('the Virgin Mary', 'PERSON'), ('Latins', 'NORP')"
"In their eyes, Jesus of Nazareth was a mere mortal,
 the legitimate son of Joseph and Mary: but he was the best
 and wisest of the human race, selected as the worthy
 instrument to restore upon earth the worship of the true and
 supreme Deity.","('Jesus', 'PERSON'), ('Nazareth', 'GPE'), ('Joseph', 'PERSON'), ('Mary', 'PERSON')"
"In their lonely situation, the
 Aethiopians had almost relapsed into the savage life.","('Aethiopians', 'NORP')"
"In their progress by sea and land, the Nestorians entered
 China by the port of Canton and the northern residence of
 Sigan.","('Nestorians', 'NORP'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('Canton', 'GPE'), ('Sigan', 'GPE')"
"In these writings, the
 piercing eye of Justinian descried more than ten
 metaphysical errors; and the primitive doctor, in the
 company of Pythagoras and Plato, was devoted by the clergy
 to the eternity of hell-fire, which he had presumed to deny.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('more than ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pythagoras', 'PERSON'), ('Plato', 'PERSON')"
"In this
 spiritual distress, the expiring faction was revived, and
 united, and perpetuated, by the labors of a monk; and the
 name of James Baradaeus (129) has been preserved in the
 appellation of Jacobites, a familiar sound, which may
 startle the ear of an English reader.","('James Baradaeus', 'PERSON'), ('129', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jacobites', 'NORP'), ('English', 'LANGUAGE')"
"In this pious rebellion he depopulated Thrace, besieged Constantinople, exterminated sixty-five thousand of his fellow-Christians, till he obtained the recall of the bishops, the satisfaction of the pope, and the establishment of the council of Chalcedon, an orthodox treaty, reluctantly signed by the dying Anastasius, and more faithfully performed by the uncle of Justinian.","('Thrace', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('sixty-five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('Anastasius', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"In two natures; and this momentous particle
 (65) (which the memory, rather than the understanding, must
 retain) had almost produced a schism among the Catholic
 bishops.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('65', 'CARDINAL'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"Instead of
 owning themselves the subjects of the Roman pontiff, the
 spiritual and temporal monarch of the globe, they adhered,
 like their ancestors, to the communion of the Nestorian
 patriarch; and the bishops whom he ordained at Mosul,
 traversed the dangers of the sea and land to reach their
 diocese on the coast of Malabar.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Nestorian', 'NORP'), ('Mosul', 'GPE'), ('Malabar', 'GPE')"
"It has been computed that
 one hundred thousand Roman subjects were extirpated in the
 Samaritan war, (90) which converted the once fruitful
 province into a desolate and smoking wilderness.","('one hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('the\r\n Samaritan war', 'EVENT'), ('90', 'CARDINAL')"
"It is in
 ecclesiastical story, that Zeno appears least contemptible;
 and I am not able to discern any Manichaean or Eutychian
 guilt in the generous saying of Anastasius.","('Zeno', 'PERSON'), ('Manichaean', 'NORP'), ('Eutychian', 'NORP'), ('Anastasius', 'PERSON')"
"It is my design to comprise in the present chapter a religious war of two hundred and fifty years, to represent the ecclesiastical and political schism of the Oriental sects, and to introduce their clamorous or sanguinary contests, by a modest inquiry into the doctrines of the primitive church.","('two hundred and fifty years', 'DATE'), ('Oriental', 'NORP')"
"It might be fairly presumed, that the most
 sublime and virtuous of human spirits was infused into the
 offspring of Mary and the Holy Ghost; (9) that his abasement
 was the result of his voluntary choice; and that the object
 of his mission was, to purify, not his own, but the sins of
 the world.","('Mary', 'PERSON'), ('the Holy Ghost', 'PERSON'), ('9', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was
 insinuated, that if he suffered, he deserved to suffer; that
 human nature is never absolutely perfect; and that the cross
 and passion might serve to expiate the venial transgressions
 of the son of Joseph, before his mysterious union with the
 Son of God. (16)","('Joseph', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n Son of God.', 'PERSON'), ('16', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was affirmed, that these
 momentary, though real, pangs would be abundantly repaid by
 the temporal reign of a thousand years reserved for the
 Messiah in his kingdom of the new Jerusalem.","('a thousand years', 'DATE'), ('Messiah', 'PERSON'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
"It was alleged, that when Jesus
 was nailed to the cross, he was endowed with a miraculous
 apathy of mind and body, which rendered him insensible of
 his apparent sufferings.","('Jesus', 'PERSON')"
"It was in vain that a multitude of episcopal voices repeated in chorus, The legates threatened, the emperor was absolute, and a committee of eighteen bishops prepared a new decree, which was imposed on the reluctant assembly.","('eighteen', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was now three
 hundred years since the body of Origen (95) had been eaten by
 the worms: his soul, of which he held the preexistence, was
 in the hands of its Creator; but his writings were eagerly
 perused by the monks of Palestine.","('three\r\n hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Origen', 'PERSON'), ('95', 'DATE'), ('Palestine', 'GPE')"
"It was the duty of Cyril to
 enlighten the zeal and ignorance of his innumerable monks:
 in the school of Alexandria, he had imbibed and professed
 the incarnation of one nature; and the successor of
 Athanasius consulted his pride and ambition, when he rose in
 arms against another Arius, more formidable and more guilty,
 on the second throne of the hierarchy.","('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Arius', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"It was the first
 care of the ministers of Rome to intercept all
 correspondence with the Nestorian patriarch, and several of
 his bishops expired in the prisons of the holy office.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Nestorian', 'NORP')"
"Jerusalem was occupied by an army of
 monks; in the name of the one incarnate nature, they
 pillaged, they burnt, they murdered; the sepulchre of Christ
 was defiled with blood; and the gates of the city were
 guarded in tumultuous rebellion against the troops of the
 emperor.","('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"Jesus might
 share the repasts of his disciples without being subject to
 the calls of thirst or hunger; and his virgin purity was
 never sullied by the involuntary stains of sensual
 concupiscence.","('Jesus', 'PERSON')"
"John
 Maron, one of the most learned and popular of the monks,
 assumed the character of patriarch of Antioch; his nephew,
 Abraham, at the head of the Maronites, defended their civil
 and religious freedom against the tyrants of the East.","('John\r\n Maron', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antioch', 'PERSON'), ('Abraham', 'PERSON'), ('Maronites', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"Justinian has been already seen in the various lights of a
 prince, a conqueror, and a lawgiver: the theologian (80)
 still remains, and it affords an unfavorable prejudice, that
 his theology should form a very prominent feature of his
 portrait.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('80', 'CARDINAL')"
"Justinian was neither steady nor consistent in the nice
 process of fixing his volatile opinions and those of his
 subjects.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Language, the leading principle
 which unites or separates the tribes of mankind, soon
 discriminated the sectaries of the East, by a peculiar and
 perpetual badge, which abolished the means of intercourse
 Perpetual separation of the oriental sects.","('East', 'LOC')"
"Lydia and Caria, Sardes and Miletus, were purified with the blood of the obstinate Quartodecimans; and the edict of the emperor, or rather of the patriarch, enumerates three-and-twenty degrees and denominations in the guilt and punishment of heresy. (31)","('Lydia', 'PERSON'), ('Caria', 'PERSON'), ('Sardes', 'PERSON'), ('Miletus', 'PERSON'), ('Quartodecimans', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"Macedonius, who
 was suspected of the Nestorian heresy, asserted, in disgrace
 and exile, the synod of Chalcedon, while the successor of
 Cyril would have purchased its overthrow with a bribe of two
 thousand pounds of gold.","('Macedonius', 'PERSON'), ('Nestorian', 'NORP'), ('Chalcedon', 'ORG'), ('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('two\r\n thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"Many
 among the Gentile proselytes refused to believe that a
 celestial spirit, an undivided portion of the first essence,
 had been personally united with a mass of impure and
 contaminated flesh; and, in their zeal for the divinity,
 they piously abjured the humanity, of Christ.","('Gentile', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"Maron, a saint or savage of the
 fifth century, displayed his religious madness in Syria; the
 rival cities of Apamea and Emesa disputed his relics, a
 stately church was erected on his tomb, and six hundred of
 his disciples united their solitary cells on the banks of
 the Orontes.","('Maron', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n fifth century', 'DATE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Apamea', 'GPE'), ('Emesa', 'PERSON'), ('six hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Orontes', 'PRODUCT')"
"Mission of the Jesuits, A.D. 1557.","('Mission of the Jesuits', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 1557', 'DATE')"
Nestorians — Jacobites — Maronites —  Armenians — Abyssinians,"('Nestorians', 'NORP'), ('Jacobites', 'NORP'), ('Maronites', 'NORP'), ('Armenians', 'NORP'), ('Abyssinians', 'NORP')"
"Nestorius appeared not as a criminal, but as a
 judge; be depended on the weight rather than the number of
 his prelates, and his sturdy slaves from the baths of
 Zeuxippus were armed for every service of injury or defence.","('Nestorius', 'PERSON'), ('Zeuxippus', 'PRODUCT')"
"Nestorius, (30) native of Germanicia, and a monk of Antioch, was recommended by the austerity of his life, and the eloquence of his sermons; but the first homily which he preached before the devout
 Theodosius betrayed the acrimony and impatience of his zeal.","('Nestorius', 'PERSON'), ('30', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germanicia', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Nestorius, who depended on the near
 approach of his Eastern friends, persisted, like his
 predecessor Chrysostom, to disclaim the jurisdiction, and to
 disobey the summons, of his enemies: they hastened his
 trial, and his accuser presided in the seat of judgment.","('Nestorius', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Chrysostom', 'PERSON')"
"Nor could it seem strange or incredible, that the
 first of these aeons, the Logos, or Word of God, of the same
 substance with the Father, should descend upon earth, to
 deliver the human race from vice and error, and to conduct
 them in the paths of life and immortality.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Of a body thus singularly constituted, a
 question would arise, by what means, and of what materials,
 it was originally framed; and our sounder theology is
 startled by an answer which was not peculiar to the
 Gnostics, that both the form and the substance proceeded
 from the divine essence.","('Gnostics', 'NORP')"
"Of or From two
 natures, might imply either their previous existence, or
 their subsequent confusion, or some dangerous interval
 between the conception of the man and the assumption of the
 God.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Of the seventeen suffragans who sailed from Alexandria, four
 were tempted from their allegiance, and the thirteen,
 falling prostrate on the ground, implored the mercy of the
 council, with sighs and tears, and a pathetic declaration,
 that, if they yielded, they should be massacred, on their
 return to Egypt, by the indignant people.","('seventeen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"On a fatal day, in the holy season of Lent,
 Hypatia was torn from her chariot, stripped naked, dragged
 to the church, and inhumanly butchered by the hands of Peter
 the reader, and a troop of savage and merciless fanatics:
 her flesh was scraped from her bones with sharp cyster
 shells, (26) and her quivering limbs were delivered to the
 flames.","('a fatal day', 'DATE'), ('the holy season of Lent', 'DATE'), ('Hypatia', 'PERSON'), ('Peter', 'PERSON'), ('26', 'CARDINAL')"
"On either hand they were anxious to
 guard, they were jealous to defend, the union and the
 distinction of the two natures, and to invent such forms of
 speech, such symbols of doctrine, as were least susceptible
 of doubt or ambiguity.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
On either side of the Hellespont his episcopal vigour imposed a rigid formulary of faith and discipline; a chronological error concerning the festival of Easter was punished as an offence against the church and state.,"('Hellespont', 'PERSON'), ('Easter', 'DATE')"
"On his return to his native skies, he received
 the immense reward of his obedience; the everlasting kingdom
 of the Messiah, which had been darkly foretold by the
 prophets, under the carnal images of peace, of conquest, and
 of dominion.","('Messiah', 'PERSON')"
"On the approach of the Catholic priests and
 soldiers, they grasped with alacrity the crown of martyrdom
 the conventicle and the congregation perished in the flames,
 but these primitive fanatics were not extinguished three
 hundred years after the death of their tyrant.","('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('three\r\n hundred years', 'DATE')"
"On the death of his father, Basilides expelled the Latin patriarch, and restored to the wishes of the nation the faith and the discipline of Egypt.","('Basilides', 'PERSON'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"On the fifth day as if the treaty had been already signed, the patriarch of Constantinople discovered, surprised, and attacked a secret conventicle of the Arians: they preferred death to submission; the flames that were kindled by their despair, soon spread to the neighboring houses, and the triumph of
 Nestorius was clouded by the name of incendiary .","('the fifth day', 'DATE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Arians', 'NORP'), ('Nestorius', 'GPE')"
"On the fifth day, the triumph was clouded by the arrival and
 indignation of the Eastern bishops.","('the fifth day', 'DATE'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"On the news of his death, Apollinaris indecently feasted the nobles and the clergy; but his joy was checked by the intelligence
 of a new election; and while he enjoyed the wealth of Alexandria, his rivals reigned in the monasteries of Thebais, and were maintained by the voluntary oblations of the people.","('Apollinaris', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Thebais', 'GPE')"
"On the third day before the festival
 of Easter, the patriarch was besieged in the cathedral, and
 murdered in the baptistery.","('the third day', 'DATE'), ('Easter', 'EVENT')"
"On this momentous occasion, the blue and green factions of
 Constantinople suspended their discord, and the civil and military powers were annihilated in their presence.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"One of the most subtile disputants of the Manichaean school
 has pressed the danger and indecency of supposing, that the
 God of the Christians, in the state of a human foetus,
 emerged at the end of nine months from a female womb.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Manichaean', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('the end of nine months', 'DATE')"
"Opposition of the Orientals, June 27, etc","('Opposition of the Orientals', 'PERSON'), ('June 27', 'DATE')"
"Orestes complained; but his just complaints were
 too quickly forgotten by the ministers of Theodosius, and
 too deeply remembered by a priest who affected to pardon,
 and continued to hate, the praefect of Egypt.","('Orestes', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"Origen he detested; but the writings of Clemens
 and Dionysius, of Athanasius and Basil, were continually in
 his hands: by the theory and practice of dispute, his faith
 was confirmed and his wit was sharpened; he extended round
 his cell the cobwebs of scholastic theology, and meditated
 the works of allegory and metaphysics, whose remains, in
 seven verbose folios, now peaceably slumber by the side of
 their rivals. (20)","('Origen', 'PERSON'), ('Clemens', 'PERSON'), ('Dionysius', 'PERSON'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Basil', 'PERSON'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('20', 'CARDINAL')"
Orthodox consent and verbal disputes.,"('Orthodox', 'NORP')"
"Perhaps he
 might plead the insolence of their prosperity, and their
 deadly hatred of the Christians, whose blood they had
 recently shed in a malicious or accidental tumult.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Perhaps the
 Greeks would be still involved in the heresy of the
 Monophysites, if the emperor's horse had not fortunately
 stumbled; Theodosius expired; his orthodox sister Pulcheria,
 with a nominal husband, succeeded to the throne; Chrysaphius
 was burnt, Dioscorus was disgraced, the exiles were
 recalled, and the tome of Leo was subscribed by the Oriental
 bishops.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Monophysites', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Pulcheria', 'PERSON'), ('Chrysaphius', 'PERSON'), ('Dioscorus', 'PERSON'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Oriental', 'NORP')"
"Perhaps the monks and people of Constantinople (106) were
 favorable to the Lateran creed, which is indeed the least
 reasonable of the two: and the suspicion is countenanced by
 the unnatural moderation of the Greek clergy, who appear in
 this quarrel to be conscious of their weakness.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('106', 'CARDINAL'), ('Lateran', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"Placed on the confines of the Jewish and
 Gentile world, he labored to reconcile the Gnostic with the
 Ebionite, by confessing in the same Messiah the supernatural
 union of a man and a God; and this mystic doctrine was
 adopted with many fanciful improvements by Carpocrates,
 Basilides, and Valentine, (15) the heretics of the Egyptian
 school.","('Jewish', 'NORP'), ('Gentile', 'NORP'), ('Gnostic', 'NORP'), ('Ebionite', 'NORP'), ('Messiah', 'PERSON'), ('Carpocrates', 'NORP'), ('Basilides', 'NORP'), ('Valentine', 'PERSON'), ('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP')"
"Pope Martin
 ended his days on the inhospitable shore of the Tauric
 Chersonesus, and his oracle, the abbot Maximus, was
 inhumanly chastised by the amputation of his tongue and his
 right hand. (104)","('Pope Martin', 'PERSON'), ('the Tauric\r\n Chersonesus', 'LOC'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"Religion was the pretence; but, in the judgment of a contemporary saint, ambition was the genuine motive of episcopal warfare. (32)","('32', 'CARDINAL')"
"Second council of Ephesus, A.D. 449, August 8-11.","('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Ephesus', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 449', 'DATE'), ('August 8-11', 'DATE')"
"Segued listened to the voice of pity, of reason, perhaps of fear: and his edict of liberty of conscience instantly revealed the tyranny and weakness of the Jesuits.","('Segued', 'PERSON'), ('Jesuits', 'NORP')"
"Seven bishops once composed the
 Aethiopic synod: had their number amounted to ten, they
 might have elected an independent primate; and one of their
 kings was ambitious of promoting his brother to the
 ecclesiastical throne.","('Seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aethiopic', 'NORP'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"Seven thousand five hundred poor
 were maintained at his expense; on his accession he found
 eight thousand pounds of gold in the treasury of the church;
 he collected ten thousand from the liberality of the
 faithful; yet the primate could boast in his testament, that
 he left behind him no more than the third part of the
 smallest of the silver coins.","('Seven thousand five hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('eight thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL')"
"Since
 the first preaching of the gospel, the Sassanian kings
 beheld with an eye of suspicion a race of aliens and
 apostates, who had embraced the religion, and who might
 favor the cause, of the hereditary foes of their country.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Sassanian', 'NORP')"
"Since the age of Constantine, the ARMENIANS (139) had signalized their attachment to the religion and empire of the Christians.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('139', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
 Armenians have obtained a large and lucrative share of the
 commerce of the East: in their return from Europe, the
 caravan usually halts in the neighborhood of Erivan, the
 altars are enriched with the fruits of their patient
 industry; and the faith of Eutyches is preached in their
 recent congregations of Barbary and Poland. (143)","('the beginning of the last century', 'DATE'), ('Armenians', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Erivan', 'GPE'), ('Eutyches', 'ORG'), ('Barbary', 'GPE'), ('Poland', 'GPE'), ('143', 'CARDINAL')"
"Since the expulsion
 of the Portuguese, the Nestorian creed is freely professed
 on the coast of Malabar.","('Portuguese', 'NORP'), ('Nestorian', 'NORP'), ('Malabar', 'GPE')"
"Since the introduction of the
 Greek or Chaldean philosophy, (6) the Jews (7) were persuaded
 of the preexistence, transmigration, and immortality of
 souls; and providence was justified by a supposition, that
 they were confined in their earthly prisons to expiate the
 stains which they had contracted in a former state. (8)","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Chaldean', 'NORP'), ('6', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('7', 'CARDINAL')"
"Six hundred and thirty bishops were ranged in
 order in the nave of the church; but the patriarchs of the
 East were preceded by the legates, of whom the third was a
 simple priest; and the place of honor was reserved for
 twenty laymen of consular or senatorian rank.","('Six hundred and thirty', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('twenty', 'CARDINAL')"
"Sixty years of servitude and hypocrisy were patiently endured; but as soon as the Portuguese empire was shaken by
 the courage and industry of the Dutch, the Nestorians
 asserted, with vigor and effect, the religion of their
 fathers.","('Sixty years', 'DATE'), ('Portuguese', 'NORP'), ('Dutch', 'NORP'), ('Nestorians', 'NORP')"
"Sixty-eight bishops, twenty-two of metropolitan rank,
 defended his cause by a modest and temperate protest: they
 were excluded from the councils of their brethren.","('Sixty-eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty-two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Something may possibly be allowed for the rigor of
 the Monophysite theology; much more for the superior
 influence of the monastic order.","('Monophysite', 'NORP')"
"Such
 crimes would have deserved the animadversion of the
 magistrate; but in this promiscuous outrage, the innocent
 were confounded with the guilty, and Alexandria was
 impoverished by the loss of a wealthy and industrious
 colony.","('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"Such honors might incite the faithful
 to combat and die under the banners of the saint; and he
 soon prompted, or accepted, the sacrifice of a virgin, who
 professed the religion of the Greeks, and cultivated the
 friendship of Orestes.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Orestes', 'PERSON')"
Such were the fleeting shadows of the Docetes.,"('Docetes', 'PRODUCT')"
"Superstition, perhaps, would more gently expiate the blood
 of a virgin, than the banishment of a saint; and Cyril had
 accompanied his uncle to the iniquitous synod of the Oak.","('Cyril', 'PERSON')"
"THE JACOBITES
II.","('THE JACOBITES\r\nII', 'EVENT')"
"THE NESTORIANS
 I. Both in his native and his episcopal province, the
 heresy of the unfortunate Nestorius was speedily
 obliterated.","('Nestorius', 'PERSON')"
"THREE CHAPTERS, (94) which has filled more volumes than it deserves lines, is deeply marked with
 this subtile and disingenuous spirit.","('THREE', 'CARDINAL'), ('94', 'CARDINAL')"
"That it was
 unworthy of an emperor to persecute the worshippers of
 Christ and the citizens of Rome.","('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The
 Catholics observed with satisfaction, that the same synod
 was odious both to the Nestorians and the Monophysites; (68)
 but the Nestorians were less angry, or less powerful, and
 the East was distracted by the obstinate and sanguinary zeal
 of the Monophysites.","('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('Nestorians', 'NORP'), ('Monophysites', 'NORP'), ('68', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nestorians', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Monophysites', 'NORP')"
"The
 East, with some hesitation, consented to the voice of her
 sovereign: the fifth general council, of three patriarchs
 and one hundred and sixty-five bishops, was held at
 Constantinople; and the authors, as well as the defenders,
 of the three chapters were separated from the communion of
 the saints, and solemnly delivered to the prince of
 darkness.","('East', 'LOC'), ('fifth', 'ORDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred and sixty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 Samaritans were finally subdued by the regular forces of the
 East: twenty thousand were slain, twenty thousand were sold
 by the Arabs to the infidels of Persia and India, and the
 remains of that unhappy nation atoned for the crime of
 treason by the sin of hypocrisy.","('Samaritans', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('India', 'GPE')"
"The
 famous dispute of the A.D. 532-698.","('the A.D. 532-698', 'DATE')"
"The
 fleet which had transported Cyril from Alexandria was laden
 with the riches of Egypt; and he disembarked a numerous body
 of mariners, slaves, and fanatics, enlisted with blind
 obedience under the banner of St. Mark and the mother of
 God.","('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('St. Mark', 'PERSON')"
"The
 flock, without a shepherd, was assaulted by the power of the
 Portuguese, the arts of the Jesuits, and the zeal of Alexis
 de Menezes, archbishop of Goa, in his personal visitation of
 the coast of Malabar.","('Portuguese', 'NORP'), ('Jesuits', 'NORP'), ('Alexis\r\n de Menezes', 'PERSON'), ('Goa', 'GPE'), ('Malabar', 'GPE')"
"The
 loyal citizens of Alexandria hastened to his rescue; he
 instantly satisfied his justice and revenge against the monk
 by whose hand he had been wounded, and Ammonius expired
 under the rod of the lictor.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Ammonius', 'PERSON')"
"The
 missionaries of Balch and Samarcand pursued without fear the
 footsteps of the roving Tartar, and insinuated themselves
 into the camps of the valleys of Imaus and the banks of the
 Selinga.","('Balch', 'PERSON'), ('Samarcand', 'GPE'), ('Tartar', 'NORP'), ('Imaus', 'LOC'), ('Selinga', 'LOC')"
"The
 monophysite  doctrine (one incarnate nature) was rigorously
 preached in the churches of Egypt and the monasteries of the
 East; the primitive creed of Apollinarius was protected by
 the sanctity of Cyril; and the name of Eutyches, his
 venerable friend, has been applied to the sect most adverse
 to the Syrian heresy of Nestorius.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Apollinarius', 'PERSON'), ('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('Eutyches', 'PERSON'), ('Syrian', 'NORP'), ('Nestorius', 'PERSON')"
"The
 pepper coast of Malabar, and the isles of the ocean,
 Socotora and Ceylon, were peopled with an increasing
 multitude of Christians; and the bishops and clergy of those
 sequestered regions derived their ordination from the
 Catholic of Babylon.","('Malabar', 'GPE'), ('Socotora', 'LOC'), ('Ceylon', 'LOC'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Babylon', 'GPE')"
"The
 pious horror of his antagonists provoked them to disclaim
 all sensual circumstances of conception and delivery; to
 maintain that the divinity passed through Mary like a
 sunbeam through a plate of glass; and to assert, that the
 seal of her virginity remained unbroken even at the moment
 when she became the mother of Christ.","('Mary', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"The
 public and private charities of the city were blindly obeyed
 by his numerous and fanatic parabolani , (24) familiarized in their daily office with scenes of death; and the praefects
 of Egypt were awed or provoked by the temporal power of
 these Christian pontiffs.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The
 rival missionaries, a Melchite and a Jacobite, embarked at
 the same time; but the empress, from a motive of love or
 fear, was more effectually obeyed; and the Catholic priest
 was detained by the president of Thebais, while the king of
 Nubia and his court were hastily baptized in the faith of
 Dioscorus.","('Melchite', 'NORP'), ('Jacobite', 'NORP'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Thebais', 'GPE'), ('Nubia', 'GPE'), ('Dioscorus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 rule of the Monophysite faith was defined with exquisite
 discretion by Severus, patriarch of Antioch: he condemned,
 in the style of the Henoticon, the adverse heresies of
 Nestorius; and Eutyches maintained against the latter the
 reality of the body of Christ, and constrained the Greeks to
 allow that he was a liar who spoke truth. (125)","('Monophysite', 'NORP'), ('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Henoticon', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Nestorius', 'NORP'), ('Eutyches', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('125', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 son of the orthodox Constantine pursued with pious hatred a
 people of soldiers, who might have stood the bulwark of his
 empire against the common foes of Christ and of Rome.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The
 speed of the zealous missionary was promoted by the fleetest
 dromedaries of a devout chief of the Arabs; the doctrine and
 discipline of the Jacobites were secretly established in the
 dominions of Justinian; and each Jacobite was compelled to
 violate the laws and to hate the Roman legislator.","('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Jacobites', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'NORP'), ('Jacobite', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The
 successors of Severus, while they lurked in convents or
 villages, while they sheltered their proscribed heads in the
 caverns of hermits, or the tents of the Saracens, still
 asserted, as they now assert, their indefeasible right to
 the title, the rank, and the prerogatives of patriarch of
 Antioch: under the milder yoke of the infidels, they reside
 about a league from Merdin, in the pleasant monastery of
 Zapharan, which they have embellished with cells, aqueducts,
 and plantations.","('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Merdin', 'GPE'), ('Zapharan', 'GPE')"
"The
 superstition of the Jacobites is more abject, their fasts
 more rigid, (131) their intestine divisions are more
 numerous, and their doctors (as far as I can measure the
 degrees of nonsense) are more remote from the precincts of
 reason.","('Jacobites', 'NORP'), ('131', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Abyssinians still adhered with
 unshaken constancy to the Monophysite faith; their languid
 belief was inflamed by the exercise of dispute; they branded
 the Latins with the names of Arians and Nestorians, and
 imputed the adoration of four gods to those who separated
 the two natures of Christ.","('Abyssinians', 'NORP'), ('Monophysite', 'NORP'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('Arians', 'NORP'), ('Nestorians', 'NORP'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Anthropomorphites, who swarmed among the monks of
 Egypt and the Catholics of Africa, could produce the express
 declaration of Scripture, that man was made after the image
 of his Creator. (12)","('Anthropomorphites', 'NORP'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Scripture', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('12', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Armenians alone are the pure disciples of Eutyches, an unfortunate parent, who has been renounced by the greater part of his spiritual progeny.","('Armenians', 'NORP'), ('Eutyches', 'NORP')"
"The Blessed Virgin he revered as the mother of
 Christ, but his ears were offended with the rash and recent
 title of mother of God, (34) which had been insensibly
 adopted since the origin of the Arian controversy.","('The Blessed Virgin', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('34', 'DATE'), ('Arian', 'NORP')"
"The Byzantine pontiff had instilled into the royal ear a
 baleful prejudice against the character and conduct of his
 Egyptian rival.","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP')"
"The Catholics, before his face, rehearsed their genuine Trisagion; they exulted in the offer, which he proclaimed by the voice of a herald, of abdicating the purple; they listened to the admonition, that, since all could not reign, they should previously agree in the choice of a sovereign; and they accepted the blood of two unpopular ministers, whom their master, without hesitation, condemned to the lions.","('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('Trisagion', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Christians of St. Thomas in India, A.D. 883.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('St. Thomas', 'GPE'), ('India', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 883', 'DATE')"
"The Coptic patriarch, a rebel to the Caesars, or a
 slave to the khalifs, still gloried in the filial obedience
 of the kings of Nubia and Aethiopia.","('Coptic', 'NORP'), ('Caesars', 'NORP'), ('Nubia', 'GPE'), ('Aethiopia', 'NORP')"
"The Henoticon of Zeno, A.D. 482.","('The Henoticon of Zeno', 'PERSON'), ('482', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Henoticon was most
 pleasing to the Egyptians; yet the smallest blemish has not
 been described by the jealous, and even jaundiced eyes of
 our orthodox schoolmen, and it accurately represents the
 Catholic faith of the incarnation, without adopting or
 disclaiming the peculiar terms of tenets of the hostile
 sects.","('Henoticon', 'PERSON'), ('Egyptians', 'NORP'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"The Jesuits themselves
 deplore the fatal indiscretion of their chief, who forgot the mildness of the gospel and the policy of his order, to introduce with hasty violence the liturgy of Rome and the inquisition of Portugal.","('Jesuits', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Portugal', 'GPE')"
"The Jesuits were incapable of defending the power
 which they had abused; the arms of forty thousand Christians
 were pointed against their falling tyrants; and the Indian
 archdeacon assumed the character of bishop till a fresh
 supply of episcopal gifts and Syriac missionaries could be
 obtained from the patriarch of Babylon.","('Jesuits', 'NORP'), ('forty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Indian', 'NORP'), ('Syriac', 'NORP'), ('Babylon', 'GPE')"
