Sentence,Entities
(10),"('10', 'CARDINAL')"
"(11) Different cities of Ionia and Bithynia were 
 assigned for the places of their exile and education; but as
 soon as their growing years excited the jealousy of the
 emperor, he judged it more prudent to secure those unhappy
 youths in the strong castle of Macellum, near Caesarea.","('11', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ionia', 'GPE'), ('Bithynia', 'GPE'), ('Macellum', 'GPE'), ('Caesarea', 'GPE')"
"(17) The cruelty of Gallus was sometimes displayed in the
 undissembled violence of popular or military executions: and
 was sometimes disguised by the abuse of law and the forms of
 judicial proceedings.","('Gallus', 'PERSON')"
"(33) He trembled for his life, for his 
 fame, and even for his virtue; and his sole confidence was
 derived from the persuasion that Minerva inspired all his
 actions, and that he was protected by an invisible guard of
 angels, whom for that purpose she had borrowed from the Sun
 and Moon.","('Minerva', 'PERSON'), ('the Sun\r\n and Moon', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
(4),"('4', 'CARDINAL')"
(43),"('43', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 numerous swarm of Franks and Alemanni were invited to cross
 the Rhine by presents and promises, by the hopes of spoil,
 and by a perpetual grant of all the territories which they
 should be able to subdue.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"A count, a notary, and a sophist, had been selected for this important commission; and Constantius, who was secretly anxious for the conclusion of the peace, entertained some hopes that the dignity of the first of these ministers, the dexterity of the second, and
 the rhetoric of the third, (51) would persuade the Persian monarch to abate the rigour of his demands.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('51', 'DATE'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"A forest overspread the northern side of the Seine, but on the south; the ground which now bears the name of the University was insensibly covered with houses, and adorned with a palace and amphitheatre, baths, an aqueduct, and a field of Mars for the exercise of the Roman troops.","('Seine', 'LOC'), ('University', 'ORG'), ('Mars', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"A temper naturally morose and
 violent, instead of being corrected, was soured by solitude
 and adversity; the remembrance of what he had endured
 disposed him to retaliation rather than to sympathy; and the
 ungoverned sallies of his rage were often fatal to those who
 approached his person, or were subject to his power.(15) 
 Constantina, his wife, is described, not as a woman, but as
 one of the infernal furies tormented with an insatiate
 thirst of human blood.(16) Instead of employing her influence 
 to insinuate the mild counsels of prudence and humanity, she
 exasperated the fierce passions of her husband; and as she
 retained the vanity, though she had renounced the gentleness
 of her sex, a pearl necklace was esteemed an equivalent
 price for the murder of an innocent and virtuous nobleman.","('Constantina', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"A very judicious plan of operations was adopted for the
 approaching campaign Julian himself, at the head of the
 remains of the veteran bands, and of some new levies which
 he had been permitted to form, boldly penetrated into the
 centre of the German cantonments, and carefully
 re-established the fortifications of Saverne, in an
 advantageous post which would either check the incursions or
 intercept the retreat of the enemy.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('Saverne', 'PRODUCT')"
"A vessel of uncommon strength and
 capaciousness was provided to convey this enormous weight of
 granite, at least an hundred and fifteen feet in length,
 from the banks of the Nile to those of the Tiber.","('at least an hundred and fifteen feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Tiber', 'LOC')"
"Above all, the Persian monarch, elated by
 victory, again threatened the peace of Asia; and the
 presence of the emperor was indispensably required both in
 the West and in the East.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"After
 dismantling the walls of Singara, the conqueror abandoned
 that solitary and sequestered place; but he carefully
 restored the fortifications of Bezabde, and fixed in that
 important post a garrison or colony of veterans, amply
 supplied with every means of defence, and animated by high
 sentiments of honour and fidelity.","('Singara', 'GPE'), ('Bezabde', 'NORP')"
"After Julian had repulsed the Alemanni from the provinces of
 the Upper Rhine, he turned his arms against the Franks, who
 were seated nearer to the ocean, on the confines of Gaul and
 Germany; and who, from their numbers, and still more from
 their intrepid valour, had ever been esteemed the most
 formidable of the barbarians.(79)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('the Upper Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('79', 'CARDINAL')"
"After Sapor had tried,
 without success, the efficacy of force and of stratagem, he
 had recourse to the slower but more certain operations of a
 regular siege in the conduct of which he was instructed by
 the skill of the Roman deserters.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"After a formal interview, in which the two princes mutually engaged their faith never to undertake anything to the prejudice of each other, they repaired without delay to their respective stations.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a reign of only twenty-eight days Sylvanus was assassinated: the soldiers who, without any criminal intention, had blindly followed the example of their leader,
 immediately returned to their allegiance; and the flatterers of Constantius celebrated the wisdom and felicity of the monarch who had extinguished a civil war without the hazard of a battle.(40)
Constantius visits Rome, A.D. 357, April 28.","('only twenty-eight days', 'DATE'), ('Sylvanus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 357', 'DATE'), ('April 28', 'DATE')"
"After an obstinate combat the barbarians were repulsed; they
 incessantly returned to the charge; they were again driven
 back with a dreadful slaughter, and two rebel legions of
 Gauls, who had been banished into the East, signalised their
 undisciplined courage by a nocturnal sally into the heart of
 the Persian camp.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"After celebrating his own clemency, which was
 still inclined to pardon their repeated crimes, and to spare
 the remnant of a guilty nation, Constantius assigned for the
 place of their exile a remote country, where they might
 enjoy a safe and honourable repose.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"After so many reciprocal injuries, Gallus had
 reason to fear and to distrust.","('Gallus', 'PERSON')"
"After this victory a considerable body of
 Romans was landed on the opposite banks of the Danube; the
 Taifalae, a Gothic tribe engaged in the service of the
 empire, invaded the Limigantes on the side of the Theiss;
 and their former masters, the free Sarmatians, animated by
 hope and revenge, penetrated through the hilly country into
 the heart of their ancient possessions.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Taifalae', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Limigantes', 'NORP'), ('Theiss', 'NORP'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP')"
"Agriculture, manufactures, and commerce again flourished under the protection of the laws; and the curiaea, or civil corporations, were again filled with useful and respectable members: the youth were no longer apprehensive of marriage; and married persons were no longer apprehensive of posterity: the public and private festivals were celebrated with customary pomp; and the frequent and secure intercourse of the provinces displayed the image of national prosperity.(91) A mind like that of Julian must have felt the general happiness of which he was the author; but he viewed with peculiar satisfaction and complacency the city of
 Paris, the seat of his winter residence, and the object even of his partial affection. (92)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Paris', 'GPE')"
"Although the order which recalled him to court was probably
 accompanied by some intimation of his approaching greatness
 he appeals to the people of Athens to witness his tears of
 undissembled sorrow, when he was reluctantly torn away from
 his beloved retirement.","('Athens', 'GPE')"
"Although they were strongly 
 actuated by the allurements of rapine, they professed a
 disinterested love of war, which they considered as the
 supreme honour and felicity of human nature; and their minds
 and bodies were so completely hardened by perpetual action,
 that, according to the lively expression of an orator, the
 snows of winter were as pleasant to them as the flowers of
 spring.","('winter', 'DATE')"
"Amida was
 at length taken, its bravest defenders, who had escaped the
 sword of the barbarians, died in the Roman camp by the hand
 of the executioner; and Ursicinus himself, after supporting
 the disgrace of a partial inquiry, was punished for the
 misconduct of Sabinian by the loss of his military rank.","('Amida', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Ursicinus', 'PERSON'), ('Sabinian', 'PERSON')"
"An incident is related, interesting enough in
 itself, and by no means repugnant to the character of
 Julian, who ingeniously contrived both the plot and the
 catastrophe of the tragedy.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"As
 the lawful successor of Darius Hystaspes, Sapor asserted
 that the river Strymon, in Macedonia, was the true and
 ancient boundary of his empire; declaring, however, that, as
 an evidence of his moderation, he would content himself with
 the provinces of Armenia and Mesopotamia, which had been
 fraudulently extorted from his ancestors.","('Darius Hystaspes', 'PERSON'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Strymon', 'PERSON'), ('Macedonia', 'GPE'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Mesopotamia', 'GPE')"
"As he had discovered from his earliest youth a propensity, or rather passion, for the language, the manners, the learning, and the religion of the Greeks, he obeyed with pleasure an order so agreeable to his wishes.","('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"As long as the civil war suspended the fate of the Roman
 world, Constantius dissembled his knowledge of the weak and
 cruel administration to which his choice had subjected the
 East; and the discovery of some assassins, secretly
 despatched to Antioch by the tyrant of Gaul, was employed to
 convince the public that the emperor and the Caesar were
 united by the same interest, and pursued by the same
 enemies.(19) But when the victory was decided in favour of 
 Constantius, his dependent colleague became less useful and
 less formidable.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"As she perceived that the
 remembrance of Gallus dwelt on the emperor's mind, she
 artfully turned his attention to the opposite characters of
 the two brothers, which from their infancy had been compared
 to those of Domitian and of Titus.(31) She accustomed her 
 husband to consider Julian as a youth of a mild, unambitious
 disposition, whose allegiance and gratitude might be secured
 by the gift of the purple, and who was qualified to fill
 with.","('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON'), ('Titus', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as
 the ceremony of his investiture had been performed,
 Constantius addressed him with the tone of authority which
 his superior age and station permitted him to assume; and,
 exhorting the new Caesar to deserve, by heroic deeds, that
 sacred and immortal name, the emperor gave his colleague the
 strongest assurances of a friendship which should never be
 impaired by time, nor interrupted by their separation into
 the most distant climates.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as the first transports of victory had subsided,
 Sapor was at leisure to reflect that to chastise a
 disobedient city he had lost the flower of his troops and
 the most favourable season for conquest.(59)","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as the speech was ended,
 the troops, as a token of applause, clashed their shields
 against their knees; (36) while the officers who surrounded 
 the tribunal expressed, with decent reserve, their sense of
 the merits of the representative of Constantius.","('36', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'ORG')"
"As soon as the valour and conduct of Julian had secured an
 interval of peace, he applied himself to a work more
 congenial to his humane and philosophic temper.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as they were delivered from the fears of invasion,
 the Alemanni prepared to chastise the Roman youth who
 presumed to dispute the possession of that country which
 they claimed as their own by the right of conquest and of
 treaties.","('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"As the most effectual instrument of their 
 providence, he gratefully acknowledges the steady and
 generous friendship of the empress Eusebia,(28) a woman of 
 beauty and merit, who, by the ascendant which she had gained
 over the mind of her husband, counterbalanced in some
 measure the powerful conspiracy of the eunuchs.","('Eusebia', 'PERSON'), ('28', 'DATE')"
"At Vienna, where he passed a painful and
 anxious winter, in the hands of those ministers to whom
 Constantius had intrusted the direction of his conduct, the
 Caesar was informed of the siege and deliverance of Autun.","('Vienna', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Autun', 'PERSON')"
"At a
 still greater distance the open towns of Gaul were deserted,
 and the inhabitants of the fortified cities, who trusted to
 their strength and vigilance, were obliged to content
 themselves with such supplies of corn as they could raise on
 the vacant land within the enclosure of their walls.","('Gaul', 'LOC')"
"At length, however, the emergencies of the state compelled the emperor, or rather his eunuchs, Gallus declared Caesar, A.D. 351, March 5 to invest Gallus, in the twenty-fifth year of his age, with the title of Caesar, and to cement this political connection by his marriage with the princess Constantina.","('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 351', 'DATE'), ('March 5', 'DATE'), ('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('the twenty-fifth year', 'DATE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Constantina', 'PERSON')"
"At the expiration of the truce Julian
 undertook a second expedition beyond the Rhine, to humble
 the pride of Surmar and Hortaire, two of the kings of the
 Alemanni, who had been present at the battle of Strasburg.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Surmar', 'GPE'), ('Hortaire', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Strasburg', 'GPE')"
"At the head of a small body of archers and heavy cavalry, he
 preferred the shorter but the more dangerous of two roads;
 and sometimes eluding and sometimes resisting the attacks of
 the barbarians, who were masters of the field, he arrived
 with honour and safety at the camp near Rheims, where the
 Roman troops had been ordered to assemble.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rheims', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"At the same time
 Barbatio, general of the infantry, advanced from Milan with
 an army of thirty thousand men, and, passing the mountains,
 prepared to throw a bridge over the Rhine, in the
 neighbourhood of Basil.","('Barbatio', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Basil', 'LOC')"
"Before he
 took the field he devolved on the provincial governors most
 of the public and private causes which had been referred to
 his tribunal; but, on his return, he carefully revised their
 proceedings, mitigated the rigour of the law, and pronounced
 a second judgment on the judges themselves.","('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"Before the
 emperor returned into the East he indulged his pride and
 curiosity in a visit to the ancient capital.(41) He proceeded 
 from Milan to Rome along the Aemilian and Flaminian ways;
 and as soon as he approached within forty miles of the city,
 the march of a prince who had never vanquished a foreign
 enemy assumed the appearance of a triumphal procession.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Aemilian', 'NORP'), ('Flaminian', 'NORP'), ('forty miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"Before the
 inevitable disorder could be remedied, two legions were
 destroyed; and Julian was taught by experience that caution
 and vigilance are the most important lessons of the art of
 war.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Before the wounds of
 civil discord could be healed, the provinces of Gaul were
 overwhelmed by a deluge of barbarians.","('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"Both the style and substance were maturely weighed in the Imperial council, and he was
 dismissed with the following answer:  A few days after the departure of Narses, three ambassadors were sent to the court of Sapor, who was already returned from the Scythian expedition to his ordinary residence of Ctesiphon.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('A few days', 'DATE'), ('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Ctesiphon', 'GPE')"
"But
 Constantius soon experienced the truth of the prediction
 which honest indignation had extorted from his injured
 lieutenant, that, as long as such maxims of government were
 suffered to prevail, the emperor himself would find it no
 easy task to defend his eastern dominions from the invasion
 of a foreign enemy.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"But
 in the acquisition of this important science Julian was
 assisted by the active vigour of his own genius, as well as
 by the wisdom and experience of Sallust, an officer of rank,
 who soon conceived a sincere attachment for a prince so
 worthy of his friendship; and whose incorruptible integrity
 was adorned by the talent of insinuating the harshest truths
 without wounding the delicacy of a royal ear.(69)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Sallust', 'PERSON')"
"But
 the ceremony of shaving his beard, and his awkward demeanour
 when he first exchanged the cloak of a Greek philosopher for
 the military habit of a Roman prince, amused during a few
 days the levity of the Imperial court.(34)","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('a few\r\n days', 'DATE'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('34', 'CARDINAL')"
"But as it still
 appeared dangerous to arrest Gallus in his capital, the slow
 and safer arts of dissimulation were practised with success.","('Gallus', 'PERSON')"
"But he forgot that he was depriving himself of
 his only support, the affection of the people; whilst he
 furnished the malice of his enemies with the arms of truth,
 and afforded the emperor the fairest pretence of exacting
 the forfeit of his purple and of his life.(18)
Massacre of the Imperial ministers, A.D. 354","('18', 'CARDINAL'), ('A.D. 354', 'DATE')"
"But he had neglected the
 opportunities of flight and of resistance; he was seduced by
 the flattering assurances of the tribune Scudilo, who, under
 the semblance of a rough soldier, disguised the most artful
 insinuation; and he depended on the credit of his wife
 Constantina till the unseasonable death of that princess
 completed the ruin in which he had been involved by her
 impetuous passions.(22)
His disgrace and death, A.D. 354, December 
 After a long delay the reluctant Caesar set forwards on his
 journey to the Imperial court.","('Scudilo', 'PERSON'), ('Constantina', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 354', 'DATE'), ('December', 'DATE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"But his ranks
 were instantly broken by an irregular mixture of light-horse
 and of light-infantry, and he had the mortification of
 beholding the flight of six hundred of his: most renowned
 cuirassiers.(75)","('six hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"But in remarkable winters the Seine was deeply frozen; and
 the huge pieces of ice that floated down the stream might be
 compared, by an Asiatic, to the blocks of white marble which
 were extracted from the quarries of Phrygia.","('winters', 'DATE'), ('Seine', 'LOC'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Phrygia', 'GPE')"
"But in the school of adversity Julian 
 insensibly acquired the virtues of firmness and discretion.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"But the Persians were no sooner advanced into the
 plains of Mesopotamia than they discovered that every
 precaution had been used which could retard their progress
 or defeat their design.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Mesopotamia', 'LOC')"
"But the effects of a
 second interview were dreaded by the eunuchs; and Julian was
 advised to withdraw for a while into the neighbourhood of
 Milan, till the emperor thought proper to assign the city of He is sent to Athens, A.D. 355, May Athens for the place of his honourable exile.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 355', 'DATE'), ('May Athens', 'DATE')"
"But the emperor, who for a 
 temporary service had thus imprudently provoked the
 rapacious spirit of the barbarians, soon discovered and
 lamented the difficulty of dismissing these formidable
 allies, after they had tasted the richness of the Roman
 soil.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But the eunuchs were skilled in the arts of flattery and intrigue; and they alternately governed the mind of Constantius by his fears, his indolence, and his
 vanity.(8) Whilst he viewed in a deceitful mirror the fair appearance of public prosperity, he supinely permitted them to intercept the complaints of the injured provinces; to
 accumulate immense treasures by the sale of justice and of honours; to disgrace the most important dignities by the promotion of those who had purchased at their hands the powers of oppression; (9) and to gratify their resentment against the few independent spirits who arrogantly refused to solicit the protection of slaves.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('9', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the hopes
 of the campaign were defeated by the incapacity, or the
 envy, or the secret instructions of Barbatio, who acted as
 if he had been the enemy of the Caesar, and the secret ally
 of the barbarians.","('Barbatio', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"But the management of the finances was more safely intrusted to Florentius, Praetorian praefect of Gaul, an effeminate tyrant, incapable of pity or remorse: and the haughty minister complained of the most
 decent and gentle opposition, while Julian himself was rather inclined to censure the weakness of his own behaviour.","('Florentius', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"But the progress of their negotiation was opposed and defeated by the hostile
 arts of Antoninus, (52) a Roman subject of Syria, who had fled from oppression, and was admitted into the councils of Sapor, and even to the royal table, where, according to the
 custom of the Persians, the most important business was frequently discussed.(53)","('Antoninus', 'GPE'), ('52', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Sapor', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('53', 'CARDINAL')"
But the ruin of Amida was the safety of the Roman provinces.,"('Amida', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But they could not disguise to themselves that they were deprived of fortune, of freedom, and of safety; secluded from the society of all whom they could trust or esteem, and condemned to pass their melancholy hours in the company of slaves devoted to the commands of a tyrant who
 had already injured them beyond the hope of reconciliation.","('melancholy hours', 'TIME')"
"But whenever Ursicinus
 recommended any vigorous plan of operations; when he
 proposed, at the head of a light and active army, to wheel
 round the foot of the mountains, to intercept the convoys of
 the enemy, to harass the wide extent of the Persian lines,
 and to relieve the distress of Amida; the timid and envious
 commander alleged that he was restrained by his positive
 orders from endangering the safety of the troops.","('Ursicinus', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Amida', 'PERSON')"
"By a second order, which issued from the
 same jealous and inconstant counsels, Ursicinus was again
 despatched to the frontier of Mesopotamia, and condemned to
 sustain the labours of a war, the honours of which had been
 transferred to his unworthy rival.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Ursicinus', 'PERSON'), ('Mesopotamia', 'LOC')"
"By his artful suggestions, the emperor was persuaded to subscribe the condemnation of the unfortunate Gallus, and to add a new crime to the long list of unnatural murders which pollute the honour of the house of Constantine.","('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"By the
 intercession of his patroness Julian was admitted into the
 Imperial presence: he pleaded his cause with a decent
 freedom; he was heard with favour; and, notwithstanding the
 efforts of his enemies, who urged the danger of sparing an
 avenger of the blood of Gallus, the milder sentiment of
 Eusebia prevailed in the council.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('Eusebia', 'PERSON')"
"By the industry and courage of his friends the fraud was, however, detected, and in a great council of the civil and military officers, held in the presence of the  emperor himself, the innocence of Sylvanus was publicly acknowledged.","('Sylvanus', 'PERSON')"
"By this rash
 declaration of war the impatient temper of Gallus was
 provoked to embrace the most desperate counsels.","('Gallus', 'PERSON')"
"Chnodomar experienced an honourable treatment: but
 the impatient barbarian could not long survive his defeat,
 his confinement, and his exile.(78)
Julian subdues the Franks, A.D. 358.","('Chnodomar', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('358', 'CARDINAL')"
"Conduct of Julian 
 Under these melancholy circumstances, an inexperienced youth
 was appointed to save and to govern the provinces of Gaul,
 or rather.","('Julian \r\n Under', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'GPE')"
Constantius Sole Emperor —Elevation and Death of Gallus—Danger and Elevation of Julian—Sarmatian and Persian Wars—,"('Constantius Sole Emperor', 'PERSON'), ('Elevation and Death of Gallus', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Danger and Elevation of Julian', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Sarmatian and Persian Wars', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Constantius continued his march towards the West, and Gallus fixed his
 residence at Antioch; from whence, with a delegated authority, he administered the five great dioceses of the eastern praefecture.(13) In this fortunate change, the new Caesar was not unmindful of his brother Julian, who obtained the honours of his rank, the appearances of liberty, and the restitution of an ample patrimony.(14)
Cruelty and impudence of Gallus","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('13', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('14', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gallus', 'PERSON')"
"Constantius sat alone in a lofty car
 resplendent with gold and precious gems; and, except when he
 bowed his head to pass under the gates of the cities, he
 affected a stately demeanour of inflexible, and, as it might
 seem, of insensible gravity.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
Description of Paris,"('Paris', 'GPE')"
"During the
 rigour of a Gallic winter he never suffered a fire in his
 bedchamber; and after a short and interrupted slumber, he
 frequently rose in the middle of the night from a carpet
 spread on the floor, to despatch any urgent business, to
 visit his rounds, or to steal a few moments for the
 prosecution of his favourite studies. (67)","('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('a few moments', 'TIME'), ('67', 'CARDINAL')"
Education of Gallus and Julian,"('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Eusebia, rejoicing in the success
 of her benevolent schemes, embraced him with the tenderness
 of a sister, and endeavoured, by the most soothing caresses,
 to dispel his terrors and reconcile him to his fortune.","('Eusebia', 'PERSON')"
"Every apartment of the palace was adorned with
 the instruments of death and torture, and a general
 consternation was diffused through the capital of Syria.","('Syria', 'GPE')"
"Every circumstance of his conduct was
 severely and suspiciously examined, and it was privately
 resolved either to deprive Gallus of the purple, or at least
 to remove him from the indolent luxury of Asia to the
 hardships and dangers of a German war.","('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('German', 'NORP')"
"Every mode of resistance which art
 could suggest, or courage could execute, was employed in the
 defence of Amidas and the works of Sapor were more than once
 destroyed by the fire of the Romans.","('Amidas', 'NORP'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Far from the tumult of arms and the treachery of courts, he spent six months amidst the groves of the Academy, in a free intercourse with the philosophers of the age, who studied to cultivate the genius, to encourage the vanity, and to inflame the devotion of their royal pupil.","('six months', 'DATE'), ('Academy', 'ORG')"
"Fatal end of Sylvanus, A.D. 355, September.","('Sylvanus', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 355', 'DATE'), ('September', 'DATE')"
"Five Roman legions, of
 the diminutive size to which they had been reduced in the
 age of Constantine, were made prisoners, and sent into
 remote captivity on the extreme confines of Persia.","('Five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"Followed by twenty thousand captives, whom he
 had rescued from the chains of the barbarians, the Caesar
 repassed the Rhine, after terminating a war the success of
 which has been compared to the ancient glories of the Punic
 and Cimbric victories.","('twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Punic', 'NORP'), ('Cimbric', 'NORP')"
"For the first time Constantius
 sincerely acknowledged that his single strength was unequal
 to such an extent of care and dominion.(30) Insensible to the 
 voice of flattery, which assured him that his all-powerful
 virtue and celestial fortune would still continue to triumph
 over every obstacle, he listened with complacency to the
 advice of Eusebia, which gratified his indolence, without
 offending his suspicious pride.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Eusebia', 'PERSON')"
"Forty-five flourishing cities, Tongres, Cologne, Treves,
 Worms, Spires, Strasburg, etc., besides a far greater number
 of towns and villages, were pillaged, and for the most part
 reduced to ashes.","('Forty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tongres', 'GPE'), ('Cologne', 'GPE'), ('Treves', 'GPE'), ('Worms', 'GPE'), ('Spires', 'GPE'), ('Strasburg', 'GPE')"
"From Antioch to Hadrianople
 he traversed the wide extent of his dominions with a
 numerous and stately train; and, as he laboured to conceal
 his apprehensions from the world, and perhaps from himself,
 he entertained the people of Constantinople with an
 exhibition of the games of the circus.","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Hadrianople', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"From his retirement in the happy country of Ionia
 he was conveyed, under a strong guard, to the court of
 Milan, where he languished above seven months in the
 continual apprehension of suffering the same ignominious
 death which was daily inflicted, almost before his eyes, on
 the friends and adherents of his persecuted family.","('Ionia', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('seven months', 'DATE')"
"From the sources to the mouth of the Rhine, the conquests of
 the Germans extended above forty miles to the west of that
 river, over a country peopled by colonies of their own name
 and nation; and the scene of their devastations was three
 times more extensive than that of their conquests.","('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('forty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"He admired the awful majesty of the Capitol, the
 vast extent of the baths of Caracalla and Diocletian, the
 severe simplicity of the Pantheon, the massy greatness of
 the amphitheatre of Titus, the elegant architecture of the
 theatre of Pompey and the Temple of Peace, and, above all,
 the stately structure of the Forum and column of Trajan;
 acknowledging that the voice of fame, so prone to invent and
 to magnify, had made an inadequate report of the metropolis
 of the world.","('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('Caracalla', 'LOC'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Pantheon', 'FAC'), ('Titus', 'PERSON'), ('Pompey', 'PERSON'), ('the Temple of Peace', 'ORG'), ('Forum', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON')"
"He advanced, however, to the
 banks of the Rhine, surveyed the ruins of Cologne, convinced
 himself of the difficulties of the war, and retreated on the
 approach of winter, discontented with the court, with his
 army, and with his own success.(70)","('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Cologne', 'GPE'), ('winter', 'DATE')"
"He alleged that,
 without the restitution of these disputed countries, it was
 impossible to establish any treaty on a solid and permanent
 basis; and he arrogantly threatened that, if his ambassador
 returned in vain, he was prepared to take the field in the
 spring, and to support the justice of his cause by the
 strength of his invincible arms.","('the\r\n spring', 'DATE')"
"He approached with horror the palace of Milan; nor
 could the ingenuous youth conceal his indignation when he
 found himself accosted with false and servile respect by the
 assassins of his family.","('Milan', 'GPE')"
"He aspired to
 emulate the glory of the first and most illustrious of the
 emperors; after whose example he composed his own
 commentaries of the Gallic war.(84) Caesar has related, with 
 conscious pride, the manner in which he twice passed the
 Rhine.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the Gallic war', 'EVENT'), ('84', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"He assumed the purple at his headquarters of Cologne, and his active powers appeared to menace Italy with an invasion and Milan with a siege.","('Cologne', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"He conferred on him the title of
 King; and Zizais proved that he was not unworthy to reign,
 by a sincere and lasting attachment to the interest of his
 benefactor, who, after this splendid success, received the
 name of Sarmaticus from the acclamations of his victorious
 army.(48)","('King', 'PERSON'), ('Zizais', 'PERSON'), ('Sarmaticus', 'PERSON'), ('48', 'CARDINAL')"
"He declared his
 resolution of asserting the justice of their cause, and of
 securing the peace of the provinces by the extirpation, or
 at least the banishment, of the Limigantes, whose manners
 were still infected with the vices of their servile origin.","('Limigantes', 'NORP')"
"He devoted the 
 leisure of his winter-quarters to the offices of civil
 government; and affected to assume with more pleasure the
 character of a magistrate than that of a general.","('winter-quarters', 'DATE')"
"He had remarked the lofty
 stature and obsequious demeanour of Zizais, one of the
 noblest of their chiefs.","('Zizais', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"He incessantly urged the ambition of his new master to embrace
 the favourable opportunity when the bravest of the Palatine troops were employed with the emperor in a distant war on the Danube.","('Palatine', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"He indignantly contrasted the
 effeminate Syrians with the brave and honest simplicity of
 the Gauls, and almost forgave the intemperance which was the
 only stain of the Celtic character.(94)","('Syrians', 'NORP'), ('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('Celtic', 'NORP'), ('94', 'CARDINAL')"
"He ordered
 his guards to stand to their arms, assembled the populace of
 Antioch, and recommended to their zeal the care of his
 safety and revenge.","('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"He pressed Sapor to invade the exhausted and defenceless provinces of the East, with the numerous armies of Persia, now fortified by the alliance and accession of the fiercest barbarians.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Persia', 'LOC')"
"He was
 received by the magistrates and senate of Rome; and the
 emperor surveyed, with attention, the civil honours of the
 republic and the consular images of the noble families.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"He was 
 followed by six other kings, by ten princes of regal
 extraction, by a long train of high-spirited nobles, and by
 thirty-five thousand of the bravest warriors of the tribes
 of Germany.","('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirty-five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"He was conducted to a palace in the suburbs,
 where the general Barbatio, with a select band of soldiers,
 who could neither be moved by pity nor corrupted by rewards,
 expected the arrival of his illustrious victim.","('Barbatio', 'PERSON')"
"His first and most sanguine hopes depended on the 
 success of a general assault.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"His first campaign in Gaul, A.D. 356 
 Immediately after Julian had received the purple at Milan he
 was sent into Gaul with a feeble retinue of three hundred
 and sixty soldiers.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('A.D. 356', 'DATE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('three hundred\r\n and sixty', 'CARDINAL')"
"His first idea was to imitate the equestrian
 and colossal statue which he had seen in the Forum of
 Trajan; but, when he had maturely weighed the difficulties
 of the execution, (42) he chose rather to embellish the 
 capital by the gift of an Egyptian obelisk.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the Forum of\r\n Trajan', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('42', 'DATE'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP')"
"His proposals were
 answered by a general discharge, and his only son, a
 beautiful and valiant youth, was pierced through the heart
 by a javelin, shot from one of the balistae.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"His salutary influence restored the cities of Gaul, which had been so long exposed to the evils of civil discord, barbarian war, and domestic tyranny; and the spirit of industry was revived with the hopes of enjoyment.","('Gaul', 'LOC')"
"His second campaign, A.D. 357","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('A.D. 357', 'DATE')"
"His short visit of thirty days was
 employed in viewing the monuments of art and power which
 were scattered over the seven hills and the interjacent
 valleys.","('thirty days', 'DATE'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"His third expedition was still more splendid and
 important than the two former.","('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"If Julian could now 
 revisit the capital of France, he might converse with men of
 science and genius, capable of understanding and of
 instructing a disciple of the Greeks; he might excuse the
 lively and graceful follies of a nation whose martial spirit
 has never been enervated by the indulgence of luxury; and he
 must applaud the perfection of.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"If he aspired to deserve the esteem of his
 subjects, he was checked by the fear of displeasing his
 sovereign; and even the fruits of his marriage-bed were
 blasted by the jealous artifices of Eusebia(39) herself, who, on this occasion alone, seems to have been unmindful of the tenderness of her sex and the generosity of her character.","('Eusebia', 'PERSON'), ('39', 'DATE')"
"If the Caesar had dissembled in silence so dangerous
 an insult, his person and authority would have been exposed
 to the contempt of the world; and if an action so criminal
 had been suffered to pass with impunity, the emperor would
 have confirmed the suspicions which received a very specious
 colour from this conduct towards the princes of the Flavian
 family.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Flavian', 'PERSON')"
"In a remote but
 polished age, which seems to have preceded the invention of
 alphabetical writing, a great number of these obelisks had
 been erected, in the cities of Thebes and Heliopolis, by the
 ancient sovereigns of Egypt, in a just confidence that the
 simplicity of their form, and the hardness of their
 substance, would resist the injuries of time and violence.","('Thebes', 'GPE'), ('Heliopolis', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"In a second and more successful action he recovered and
 established his military fame; but as the agility of the
 barbarians saved them from the pursuit, his victory was
 neither bloody nor decisive.","('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"In a studied speech, conceived and delivered 
 with dignity, the emperor represented the various dangers
 which threatened the prosperity of the republic, the
 necessity of naming a Caesar for the administration of the
 West, and his own intention, if it was agreeable to their
 wishes, of rewarding with the honours of the purple the
 promising virtues of the nephew of Constantine.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"In his march from Autun, through
 the heart of the Gallic provinces, Julian embraced with
 ardour the earliest opportunity of signalising his courage.","('Autun', 'GPE'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"In his room Severus was appointed general of the cavalry; an experienced soldier, of approved courage and fidelity, who could advise with respect, and execute with zeal; and who submitted, without reluctance, to the supreme
 command which Julian, by the interest of his patroness Eusebia, at length obtained over the armies of Gaul.(72)","('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Eusebia', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('72', 'CARDINAL')"
"In one of the fiercest of these repeated
 assaults, Amida was betrayed by the treachery of a deserter,
 who indicated to the barbarians a secret and neglected
 staircase, scooped out of the rock that hangs over the
 stream of the Tigris.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Amida', 'PERSON'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"In the blind fury of civil discord, Constantius had
 abandoned to the barbarians of Germany the countries of
 Gaul, which still acknowledged the authority of his rival.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"In the close
 of the evening he was arrested, ignominiously stripped of
 the ensigns of Caesar, and hurried away to Pola, in Istria,
 a sequestered prison, which had been so recently polluted
 with royal blood.","('the close\r\n of the evening', 'TIME'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Pola', 'LOC'), ('Istria', 'GPE')"
"In the general administration of peace and war, the interest of the sovereign is commonly the same as that of his people; but Constantius would have thought himself deeply injured, if the virtues of Julian had defrauded him of any part of the tribute which he extorted from an oppressed and exhausted country.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"In the hour of danger Ursicinus(62) was removed 
 from his station by the intrigues of the eunuchs; and the
 military command of the East was bestowed, by the same
 influence, on Sabinian, a wealthy and subtle veteran, who
 had attained the infirmities, without acquiring the
 experience, of age.","('the hour', 'TIME'), ('Ursicinus', 'PERSON'), ('62', 'DATE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Sabinian', 'NORP')"
"In the midst of that severe season they sustained, with
 inflexible constancy, a siege of fifty-four days, till at
 length, exhausted by hunger, and satisfied that the
 vigilance of the enemy in breaking the ice of the river left
 them no hopes of escape, the Franks consented, for the first
 time, to dispense with the ancient law which commanded them
 to conquer or to die.","('fifty-four days', 'DATE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"In the month of December which followed the battle
 of Strasburg, Julian attacked a body of six hundred Franks
 who had thrown themselves into two castles on the Meuse.(80)","('the month of December', 'DATE'), ('Strasburg', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('six hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Meuse', 'PRODUCT'), ('80', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the room of these faithful servants an household
 was formed, such, indeed, as became the dignity of a Caesar;
 but it was filled with a crowd of slaves, destitute, and
 perhaps incapable, of any attachment for their new master,
 to whom, for the most part, they were either unknown or
 suspected.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"In the summer which preceded his own elevation that general had been chosen to deliver Gaul from the tyranny of the barbarians;
 but Sylvanus soon discovered that he had left his most dangerous enemies in the Imperial court.","('the summer', 'DATE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Sylvanus', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"In this emergency Ursicinus, a general of equal rank, regained, by an act of treachery, the favour which he had lost by his eminent services in the East.","('Ursicinus', 'ORG'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"In this extremity the bravest of
 the Limigantes were resolved to die in arms rather than to
 yield: but the milder sentiment, enforced by the authority
 of their elders, at length prevailed; and the suppliant
 crowd, followed by their wives and children, repaired to the
 Imperial camp to learn their fate from the mouth of the
 conqueror.","('Limigantes', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"In this rapid journey the profound respect which was
 due to the brother and colleague of Constantius was
 insensibly changed into rude familiarity; and Gallus, who
 discovered in the countenances of the attendants that they
 already considered themselves as his guards, and might soon
 be employed as his executioners, began to accuse his fatal
 rashness, and to recollect with terror and remorse the
 conduct by which he had provoked his fate.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Gallus', 'PERSON')"
"Instead
 of exhibiting the vanquished king of the Alemanni as a
 grateful spectacle to the cities of Gaul, he respectfully
 laid at the feet of the emperor this splendid trophy of his
 victory.","('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"Instead of aspiring to the conquest of the
 East, he was obliged to content himself with the reduction
 of two fortified cities of Mesopotamia, Singara and Bezabde;
 (60) the one situate in the midst of a sandy desert, the other 
 in a small peninsula, surrounded almost on every side by the
 deep and rapid stream of the Tigris.","('East', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mesopotamia', 'GPE'), ('Singara', 'GPE'), ('Bezabde', 'GPE'), ('60', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"Instead of assuming the title of Augustus,
 instead of employing in his defence the troops and treasures
 of the East, he suffered himself to be deceived by the
 affected tranquillity of Constantius, who, leaving him the
 vain pageantry of a court, imperceptibly recalled the
 veteran legions from the provinces of Asia.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"Instead of consulting his own experience of their
 incurable perfidy, Constantius listened to his flatterers,
 who were ready to represent the honour and advantage of
 accepting a colony of soldiers, at a time when it was much
 easier to obtain the pecuniary contributions than the
 military service of the subjects of the empire.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
Invasion of Gaul by the Germans,"('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"Invasion of Mesopotamia by Sapor, A.D. 359","('Mesopotamia', 'GPE'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 359', 'DATE')"
"It is more than
 probable that the inconstancy of his barbarian allies was
 tempted to relinquish a war in which they had encountered
 such unexpected difficulties; and that the aged king of the
 Chionites, satiated with revenge, turned away with horror
 from a scene of action where he had been deprived of the
 hope of his family and nation.","('Chionites', 'NORP')"
"It was designed by Constantine to adorn his new
 city;(45) and, after being removed by his order from the 
 pedestal where it stood before the Temple of the Sun at
 Heliopolis, was floated down the Nile to Alexandria.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('45', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Temple of the Sun', 'FAC'), ('Heliopolis', 'GPE'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"It was incumbent
 on the Caesar to provide for the subsistence as well as for
 the safety of the inhabitants and of the garrisons.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"It was not enough for Julian to have delivered the provinces
 of Gaul from the barbarians of Germany.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"It was provided with an arsenal of military engines,
 and the ordinary garrison had been reinforced to the amount
 of seven legions, when the place was invested by the arms of
 Sapor.(57)","('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('57', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was reasonable to expect that the
 Alemanni, pressed on either side by the Roman arms, would
 soon be forced to evacuate the provinces of Gaul, and to
 hasten to the defence of their native country.","('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'GPE')"
"Julian could boast that, before he assumed the title
 of Augustus, he had carried the Roman eagles beyond that
 great river in three successful expeditions. (85)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('85', 'CARDINAL')"
"Julian most devoutly ascribes his
 miraculous deliverance to the protection of the gods, who
 had exempted his innocence from the sentence of destruction
 pronounced by their justice against the impious house of
 Constantine.(27)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('27', 'CARDINAL')"
"Julian received him with
 military pomp in the council of his officers, and expressing
 a generous pity for the fallen state, dissembled his inward
 contempt for the abject humiliation of his captive.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Marcellus was recalled, and gently dismissed from
 his office.(71)","('Marcellus', 'PERSON')"
"Marcellus,
 master-general of the cavalry in Gaul, interpreting too
 strictly the jealous orders of the court, beheld with supine
 indifference the distress of Julian, and had restrained the
 troops under his command from marching to the relief of
 Sens.","('Marcellus', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Sens', 'ORG')"
Marha!,"('Marha', 'PERSON')"
"Narses, who was endowed
 with the most polite and amiable manners, endeavoured, as
 far as was consistent with his duty, to soften the harshness
 of the message. (50)","('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"Narses, whom he invested with that
 character, was honourably received in his passage through
 Antioch and Constantinople: he reached Sirmium after a long
 journey, and, at his first audience, respectfully unfolded
 the silken veil which covered the haughty epistle of his
 sovereign.","('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch and Constantinople', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Sirmium', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Of his former domestics four only were
 permitted to attend him - two pages, his physician, and his
 librarian; the last of whom was employed in the care of a
 valuable collection of books, the gifts of the empress, who
 studied the inclinations as well as the interest of her
 friend.","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Of these slaves the most distinguished was the chamberlain Eusebius, who ruled the monarch and the palace with such absolute sway, that Constantius, according to the sarcasm of an impartial historian, possessed some credit with this haughty favourite.","('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"On his arrival at
 Antioch, Domitian passed disdainfully before the gates of
 the palace; and, alleging a slight pretence of
 indisposition, continued several days in sullen retirement,
 to prepare an inflammatory memorial, which he transmitted to
 the Imperial court.","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON'), ('several days', 'DATE'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"On his left hand, the place of honour among the
 Orientals, Grumbates, king of the Chionites, displayed the
 stern countenance of an aged and renowned warrior.","('Orientals', 'NORP'), ('Grumbates', 'PERSON'), ('Chionites', 'NORP')"
"On the approach of
 Constantius the Limigantes tried the efficacy of prayers, of
 fraud, and of arms; but he sternly rejected their
 supplications, defeated their rude stratagems, and repelled
 with skill and firmness the efforts of their irregular
 valour.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Limigantes', 'PERSON')"
"On this solemn occasion the
 guards, with the other troops whose stations were in the
 neighbourhood of Milan, appeared under arms; and Constantius
 ascended his lofty tribunal, holding by the hand his cousin
 Julian, who entered the same day into the twenty-fifth year
 of his age. (35)","('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('the same day', 'DATE'), ('the twenty-fifth year', 'DATE'), ('35', 'DATE')"
"One of their most war-like tribes, established in a
 small island towards the conflux of the Theiss and the
 Danube, consented to pass the river with the intention of
 surprising the emperor during the security of an amicable
 conference.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theiss', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"Ordering his soldiers to provide
 themselves with biscuit for twenty days, he suddenly pitched
 his camp near Tongres, while the enemy still supposed him in
 his winter-quarters of Paris, expecting the slow arrival of
 his convoys from Aquitain.","('twenty days', 'DATE'), ('Tongres', 'GPE'), ('winter-quarters', 'DATE'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Aquitain', 'GPE')"
"Reduced in this extremity to the resources of
 his own mind, he displayed a prudent intrepidity which
 compensated for all the deficiencies of the place and
 garrison; and the barbarians, at the end of thirty days,
 were obliged to retire with disappointed rage.","('the end of thirty days', 'DATE')"
Restores the cities of Gaul.,"('Gaul', 'GPE')"
"Restrained by the severe edicts 
 of Domitian and Nerva,(5) cherished by the pride of Diocletian, reduced to an humble station by the prudence of Constantine, (6) they multiplied in the palaces of his degenerate sons, and insensibly acquired the knowledge, and at length the direction, of the secret councils of
 Constantius.","('Domitian', 'NORP'), ('Nerva', 'PERSON'), ('5', 'CARDINAL'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('6', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'ORG')"
"Sabinian fixed his
 indolent station under the walls of Edessa; and while he
 amused himself with the idle parade of military exercise,
 and moved to the sound of flutes in the Pyrrhic dance, the
 public defence was abandoned to the boldness and diligence
 of the former general of the East.","('Sabinian', 'PERSON'), ('Edessa', 'PERSON'), ('Pyrrhic', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"Sapor
 appeared in the front, conspicuous by the splendour of his
 purple.","('Sapor', 'PERSON')"
"Sapor overlooked, with prudent disdain, the strength
 of Nisibis; but as he passed under the walls of Amida, he
 resolved to try whether the majesty of his presence would
 not awe the garrison into immediate submission.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Nisibis', 'PERSON'), ('Amida', 'PERSON')"
"Sapor, King of Kings, and Brother of the Sun and
 Moon (such were the lofty titles affected by oriental
 vanity), expressed his satisfaction that his brother,
 Constantius Caesar, had been taught wisdom by adversity.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('King of Kings', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Brother of the Sun and\r\n Moon', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Constantius Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"Seventy chosen archers of the royal
 guard ascended in silence to the third story of a lofty
 tower, which commanded the precipice; they elevated on high
 the Persian banner, the signal of confidence to the
 assailants, and of dismay to the besieged and if this
 devoted band could have maintained their post a few minutes
 longer, the reduction of the place might have been purchased
 by the sacrifice of their lives.","('Seventy', 'CARDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('a few minutes', 'TIME')"
"Several of these extraordinary columns had been 
 transported to Rome by Augustus and his successors as the
 most durable monuments of their power and victory;(44) but 
 there remained one obelisk which, from its size or sanctity,
 escaped for a long time the rapacious vanity of the
 conquerors.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('44', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
Siege of Amida,"('Amida', 'GPE')"
"Siege of Singara, A.D. 360","('Singara', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 360', 'DATE')"
"Since Julian was not originally 
 designed for the character of a legislator or a judge, it is
 probable that the civil jurisprudence of the Romans had not
 engaged any considerable share of his attention: but he
 derived from his philosophic studies an inflexible regard
 for justice, tempered by a disposition to clemency, the
 knowledge of the general principles of equity and evidence,
 and the faculty of patiently investigating the most
 intricate and tedious questions which could be proposed for
 his discussion.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Six hundred large barques,
 framed in the forest of the Ardennes, made several voyages
 to the coast of Britain; and returning from thence, laden
 with corn, sailed up the Rhine, and distributed their
 cargoes to the several towns and fortresses along the banks
 of the river. (87)","('Six hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ardennes', 'LOC'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"Six thousand of the Alemanni
 were slain in the field, without including those who were
 drowned in the Rhine, or transfixed with darts whilst they
 attempted to swim across the river.(77) Chnodomar himself was 
 surrounded and taken prisoner, with three of his brave
 companions, who had devoted themselves to follow in life or
 death the fate of their chieftain.","('Six thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Chnodomar', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"Some of his fellow-students might perhaps examine his behaviour with an eye of prejudice and aversion; but Julian established in the schools of Athens a general prepossession in favour of his virtues and talents, which was soon diffused over the Roman world.(29)
Recalled to Milan, 
 Whilst his hours were passed in studious retirement, the
 empress, resolute to achieve the generous design which she
 had undertaken, was not unmindful of the care of his
 fortune.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('29', 'CARDINAL'), ('Milan', 'PERSON')"
"Superior to the
 last temptation of virtuous minds, an indiscreet and
 intemperate zeal for justice, he restrained, with calmness
 and dignity, the warmth of an advocate who prosecuted, for
 extortion the president of the Narbonnese province.","('Narbonnese', 'NORP')"
"That splendid capital, which now embraces an ample territory on either side of the Seine,
 was originally confined to the small island in the midst of the river, from whence the inhabitants derived a supply of pure and salubrious water.","('Seine', 'LOC')"
"The
 Germans despised an enemy who appeared destitute either of
 power or of inclination to offend them; and the ignominious
 retreat of Barbatio deprived Julian of the expected support,
 and left him to extricate himself from a hazardous
 situation, where he could neither remain with safety, nor
 retire with honour.(73)
Battle of Strasburgh, A.D. 357, August","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Barbatio', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Strasburgh', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 357', 'DATE'), ('August', 'DATE')"
"The
 Limigantes were permitted to pass the Danube; and the
 emperor gave audience to the multitude in a large plain near
 the!","('Limigantes', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"The
 approbation of the soldiers was testified by a respectful
 murmur: they gazed on the manly countenance of Julian, and
 observed with pleasure that the fire which sparkled in his
 eyes was tempered by a modest blush on being thus exposed
 for the first time to the public view of mankind.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The
 death of Constantine suspended the execution of his purpose,
 and this obelisk was destined by his son to the ancient
 capital of the empire.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The
 emperor, embracing a generous but artful system of policy,
 released the Sarmatians from the bands of this humiliating
 dependence, and restored them, by a separate treaty, to the
 dignity of a nation united under the government of a king,
 the friend and ally of the republic.","('Sarmatians', 'NORP')"
"The
 fierce Chnodomar, shaking the ponderous javelin which he had
 victoriously wielded against the brother of Magnentius, led
 the van of the barbarians, and moderated by his experience
 the martial ardour which his example inspired.(74)","('Chnodomar', 'NORP'), ('Magnentius', 'PERSON')"
"The
 following day Grumbates advanced towards the gates with a
 select body of troops, and required the instant surrender of
 the city, as the only atonement which could be accepted for
 such an act of rashness and insolence.","('The\r\n following day', 'DATE'), ('Grumbates', 'PERSON')"
"The
 licentiousness and corruption of Antioch recalled to the
 memory of Julian the severe and simple manners of his
 beloved Lutetia,(93) where the amusements of the theatre were 
 unknown or despised.","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Lutetia', 'PERSON'), ('93', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 misfortune of his royal birth involved him in the disgrace
 of Gallus.","('Gallus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 monarch had reserved a similar place on his right hand for
 the king of the Albanians, who led his independent tribes
 from the shores of the Caspian.","('Albanians', 'NORP'), ('Caspian', 'LOC')"
"The
 obelisk of Constantius was landed about three miles from the
 city, and elevated, by the efforts of art and labour, in the
 great circus of Rome.(46)","('Constantius', 'PRODUCT'), ('about three miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('46', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 prince of the East, as if he had been conscious how much he
 had to fear, and how little he deserved to reign, selected
 for the objects of his resentment the provincials accused of
 some imaginary treason, and his own courtiers; whom with
 more reason he suspected of incensing, by their secret
 correspondence, the timid and suspicious mind of
 Constantius.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The
 treatment which they experienced during a six years'
 confinement was partly such as they could hope from a
 careful guardian, and partly such as they might dread from a
 suspicious tyrant.(12) Their prison was an ancient palace, 
 the residence of the kings of Cappadocia; the situation was
 pleasant, the building stately, the enclosure spacious.","(""a six years'"", 'DATE'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE')"
"The 
 consternation of the Germans after the battle of Strasburg
 encouraged him to the first attempt; and the reluctance of
 the troops soon yielded to the persuasive eloquence of a
 leader who shared the fatigues and dangers which he imposed
 on the meanest of the soldiers.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Strasburg', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The 
 quaestor reproached Gallus, in haughty language, that a
 prince who was scarcely authorised to remove a municipal
 magistrate should presume to imprison a Praetorian praefect;
 convoked a meeting of the civil and military officers, and
 required them, in the name of their sovereign, to defend the
 person and dignity of his representatives.","('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP')"
"The 
 treaty was ratified by solemn oaths; and perpetual
 inspectors were appointed to reside among the Franks, with
 the authority of enforcing the strict observance of the
 conditions.","('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"The Alemanni were
 established in the modern countries of Alsace and Lorraine;
 the Franks occupied the island of the Batavians, together
 with an extensive district of Brabant, which was then known
 by the appellation of Toxandria, (65) and may deserve to be 
 considered as the original seat of their Gallic monarchy.(66)","('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Alsace', 'GPE'), ('Lorraine', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Batavians', 'LOC'), ('Brabant', 'GPE'), ('Toxandria', 'GPE'), ('65', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gallic', 'NORP')"
"The Alemanni, familiarised to the knowledge of the
 country, secretly collected their scattered forces, and,
 seizing the opportunity of a dark and rainy day, poured with
 unexpected fury on the rearguard of the Romans.","('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The Caesar had rejected with abhorrence a mandate for the levy of an extraordinary tax; a new super-indiction, which the praefect had offered for his signature; and the faithful picture of the public misery, by which he had been obliged to justify his refusal, offended the court of Constantius.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The Caesar immediately sent his
 captives to the court of Constantius, who, accepting them as
 a valuable present,(81) rejoiced in the opportunity of adding 
 so many heroes to the choicest troops of his domestic
 guards.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('81', 'DATE')"
"The Caesar sunk under the weight
 of shame and guilt, confessed all the criminal actions and
 all the treasonable designs with which he was charged; and,
 by imputing them to the advice of his wife, exasperated the
 indignation of Constantius, who reviewed with partial
 prejudice the minutes of the examination.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('the minutes', 'TIME')"
"The Caesar, who conducted in
 person his right wing, depended on the dexterity of his
 archers and the weight of his cuirassiers.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"The Chamavians submissively retired to their
 former habitations beyond the Rhine; but the Salians were
 permitted to possess their new establishment of Toxandria,
 as the subjects and auxiliaries of the Roman empire.(82)","('Chamavians', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Salians', 'NORP'), ('Toxandria', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('82', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Germans had collected
 their military powers, and moved along the opposite banks of
 the river, with a design of destroying the bridge, and of
 preventing the passage of the Romans.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The Germans possessed the
 superiority of strength and stature, the Romans that of
 discipline and temper, and as the barbarians who served
 under the standard of the empire united the respective
 advantages of both parties, their strenuous efforts, guided
 by a skilful leader, at length determined the event of the
 day.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('the\r\n day', 'DATE')"
"The Limigantes obeyed
 with reluctance; but before they could reach, at least
 before they could occupy, their destined habitations, they
 returned to the banks of the Danube, exaggerating the
 hardships of their situation, and requesting, with fervent
 professions of fidelity, that the emperor would grant them
 an undisturbed settlement within the limits of the Roman
 provinces.","('Limigantes', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Persian negotiation, A.D. 358","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 358', 'DATE')"
"The Persians repaired their
 losses and pushed their approaches; a large breach was made
 by the battering-ram, and the strength of the garrison,
 wasted by the sword and by disease, yielded to the fury of
 the assault.","('Persians', 'NORP')"
"The Quadian and Sarmatian war, A.D. 357,358,359.","('The Quadian and Sarmatian war', 'EVENT'), ('357,358,359', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Roman deserter, who in some measure guided the
 councils of Sapor, had prudently advised, that, instead of
 wasting the summer in tedious and difficult sieges, he
 should march directly to the Euphrates, and press forwards
 without delay to seize the feeble and wealthy metropolis of
 Syria.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Syria', 'GPE')"
"The Romans lost four tribunes, and two hundred and
 forty-three soldiers in this memorable battle of Strasburg,
 so glorious to the Caesar, (76) and so salutary to the 
 afflicted provinces of Gaul.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('two hundred and\r\n forty-three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Strasburg', 'GPE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('76', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The Romans marched in close order, and in two columns; the
 cavalry on the right, the infantry on the left; and the day
 was so far spent when they appeared in sight of the enemy,
 that Julian was desirous of deferring the battle till the
 next morning, and of allowing his troops to recruit their
 exhausted strength by the necessary refreshments of sleep
 and food.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('the day', 'DATE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n next morning', 'TIME')"
"The Sarmatians no
 longer respected the barrier of the Danube.","('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"The active zeal of
 Julian urged the prosecution of the work; and such was the
 spirit which he had diffused among the troops, that the
 auxiliaries themselves, waiving their exemption from any
 duties of fatigue, contended in the most servile labours
 with the diligence of the Roman soldiers.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The ambassadors of Rome retired without success, and a second embassy, of a still more honourable rank, was detained in strict confinement, and threatened either with death or exile.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"The ancient city of Amid or Amida, (55) which sometimes 
 assumes the provincial appellation of Diarbekir, (56) is 
 advantageously situate in a fertile plain, watered by the
 natural and artificial channels of the Tigris, of which the
 least inconsiderable stream bends in a semi-circular form
 round the eastern part of the city.","('Amid', 'GPE'), ('Amida', 'GPE'), ('55', 'CARDINAL'), ('Diarbekir', 'GPE'), ('56', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"The arms of Julian had restored a free and 
 secure navigation, which Constantius had offered to purchase
 at the expense of his dignity, and of a tributary present of
 two thousand pounds of silver.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('two thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"The aspect of
 their young prince revived the drooping spirit of the
 soldiers, and they marched from Rheims in search of the
 enemy with a confidence which had almost proved fatal to
 them.","('Rheims', 'GPE')"
"The barbarians of Germany, still faithful
 to the maxims of their ancestors, abhorred the confinement
 of walls, to which they applied the odious names of prisons
 and sepulchres; and, fixing their independent habitations on
 the banks of rivers, the Rhine, the Moselle, and the Meuse,
 they secured themselves against the danger of a surprise, by
 a rude and hasty fortification of large trees, which were
 felled and thrown across the roads.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Moselle', 'NORP'), ('Meuse', 'LOC')"
"The barbarians withdrew from his presence, impressed with the warmest sentiments of gratitude and admiration.(83)
Makes three expiditions beyond the Rhine, A.D. 357, 358, 359.","('83', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('357', 'CARDINAL'), ('358', 'CARDINAL'), ('359', 'CARDINAL')"
"The cities
 of Gaul, which had suffered from the inroads of the
 barbarians, he diligently repaired; and seven important
 posts, between Mentz and the mouth of the Rhine, are
 particularly mentioned as having been rebuilt and fortified
 by the order of Julian. (86)","('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mentz', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The confidence derived from the view of their
 own strength was increased by the intelligence which they
 received from a deserter, that the Caesar, with a feeble
 army of thirteen thousand men, occupied a post about
 one-and-twenty miles from their camp of Strasburg.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('thirteen thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('about\r\n one-and-twenty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Strasburg', 'GPE')"
"The conflict between the two lines of
 infantry was obstinate and bloody.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The conscious pride of Julian, who was indebted only to his
 sword for this signal deliverance, was embittered by the
 reflection that he was abandoned, betrayed, and perhaps
 devoted to destruction, by those who were bound to assist
 him by every tie of honour and fidelity.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The danger and escape of Julian 
 Besides the reigning emperor, Julian alone survived of all
 the numerous posterity of Constantius Chlorus.","('Julian \r\n Besides', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius Chlorus', 'PERSON')"
"The death of
 Theophilus, consular of the provinces of Syria, who in a
 time of scarcity had been massacred by the people of
 Antioch, with the connivance and almost at the instigation
 of Gallus, was justly resented, not only as an act of wanton
 cruelty, but as a dangerous insult on the supreme majesty of
 Constantius.","('Theophilus', 'PERSON'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The death of the late Caesar had left Constantius
 invested with the sole command, and oppressed by the
 accumulated weight, of a mighty empire.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'ORG')"
"The defence of the East against the arms of Sapor 
 required, and would have exercised, the abilities of the
 most consummate general; and it seemed fortunate for the
 state that it was the actual province of the brave
 Ursicinus, who alone deserved the confidence of the soldiers
 and people.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Ursicinus', 'PERSON')"
"The departure of Constantius from Rome was hastened by the
 alarming intelligence of the distress and danger of the
 Illyrian provinces.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP')"
"The dexterity,
 as well as the firmness of Julian, was put to a severe
 trial, when he took the field with a discontented army,
 which had already served two campaigns without receiving any
 regular pay or any extraordinary donative.(88)
Civil administration of Julian 
 A tender regard for the peace and happiness of his subjects
 was the ruling principle which directed, or seemed to
 direct, the administration of Julian. (89)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('89', 'CARDINAL')"
"The disgrace which had
 been incurred by a treacherous surprise was soon retrieved
 by the numbers and discipline of the Romans; and the combat
 was only terminated by the extinction of the name and nation
 of the Limigantes.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Limigantes', 'NORP')"
"The dissimulation
 which had hitherto been preserved was laid aside at Petovio
 in Pannonia.","('Petovio', 'GPE'), ('Pannonia', 'GPE')"
"The distractions of civil war, and the
 irreparable loss which the Roman legions had sustained in
 the battle of Mursa, exposed those countries, almost without
 defence, to the light cavalry of the barbarians; and
 particularly to the inroads of the Quadi, a fierce and
 powerful nation, who seem to have exchanged the institutions
 of Germany for the arms and military arts of their Sarmatian
 allies.(47)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Mursa', 'GPE'), ('Quadi', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Sarmatian', 'NORP'), ('47', 'CARDINAL')"
"The emperor Constantius
 had recently conferred on Amida the honour of his own name,
 and the additional fortifications of strong walls and lofty
 towers.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Amida', 'PERSON')"
"The emperor passed the Danube on a
 bridge of boats, cut in pieces all that encountered his
 march, penetrated into the heart of the country of the
 Quadi, and severely retaliated the calamities which they had
 inflicted on the Roman province.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Quadi', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The emperor was
 easily convinced that his own safety was incompatible with
 the life of his cousin: the sentence of death was signed,
 despatched, and executed; and the nephew of Constantine,
 with his hands tied behind his back, was beheaded in prison,
 like the vilest malefactor. (24)","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The emperors of the age of Constantine no longer deigned to
 consult with the senate in the choice of a colleague; but
 they were anxious that their nomination should be ratified
 by the consent of the army.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The four and twenty days 
 which the Caesar spent at Milan after his investiture, and
 the first months of his Gallic reign, were devoted to a
 splendid but severe captivity; nor could the acquisition of
 honour compensate for the loss of freedom.(38) His steps were 
 watched, his correspondence was intercepted; and he was
 obliged, by prudence, to decline the visits of his most
 intimate friends.","('The four and twenty days', 'DATE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('the first months', 'DATE'), ('Gallic', 'NORP')"
"The free Sarmatians were reinstated in
 the possession of their ancient seats; and although
 Constantius distrusted the levity of their character, he
 entertained some hopes that a sense of gratitude might 
 influence their future conduct.","('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The frequent and pressing epistles of Constantius were
 filled with professions of confidence and friendship,
 exhorting the Caesar to discharge the duties of his high
 station, to relieve his colleague from a part of the public
 cares, and to assist the West by his presence, his counsels,
 and his arms.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"The fugitives were stopped and rallied by 
 the presence and authority of Julian, who, careless of his
 own safety, threw himself before them, and urging every
 motive of shame and honour, led them back against the
 victorious enemy.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The funeral of
 the prince of the Chionites was celebrated according to the
 rite of his country; and the grief of his aged father was
 alleviated by the solemn promise of Sapor, that the guilty
 city of Amida should serve as a funeral pile to expiate the
 death, and to perpetuate the memory, of his son.","('Chionites', 'PERSON'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Amida', 'GPE')"
"The garrisons of the frontier were insufficient 
 to check their progress; and the indolent monarch was at
 length compelled to assemble, from the extremities of his
 dominions, the flower of the Palatine troops, to take the
 field in person, and to employ a whole campaign, with the
 preceding autumn and the ensuing spring, in the serious
 prosecution of the war.","('Palatine', 'NORP'), ('the ensuing spring', 'DATE')"
"The generous courtesy which was shown to the first
 among their chieftains who implored the clemency of
 Constantius encouraged the more timid, or the more
 obstinate, to imitate their example; and the Imperial camp
 was crowded with the princes and ambassadors of the most
 distant tribes, who occupied the plains of the Lesser
 Poland, and who might have deemed themselves secure behind
 the lofty ridge of the Carpathian mountains.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('the Lesser\r\n Poland', 'LOC'), ('the Carpathian mountains', 'LOC')"
"The ground was already covered with snow; and
 Julian, after repairing an ancient castle which had been
 erected by Trajan, granted a truce of ten months to the
 submissive barbarians.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('ten months', 'DATE')"
"The horror which he felt was soon
 increased by the appearance of his implacable enemy the
 eunuch Eusebius, who, with the assistance of a notary and a
 tribune, proceeded to interrogate him concerning the
 administration of the East.","('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The impunity of
 rapine had increased the boldness and numbers of the wild
 Isaurians; those robbers descended from their craggy
 mountains to ravage the adjacent country, and had even
 presumed, though without success, to besiege the important
 city of Seleucia,. which was defended by a garrison of three
 Roman legions.","('Isaurians', 'NORP'), ('Seleucia', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The inhabitants with their cattle
 were secured in places of strength, the green forage
 throughout the country was set on fire, the fords of the
 river were fortified by sharp stakes, military engines were
 planted on the opposite banks, and a seasonable swell of the
 waters of the Euphrates deterred the barbarians from
 attempting the ordinary passage of the bridge of Thapsacus.","('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Thapsacus', 'GPE')"
"The memory of his father and of his brothers reminded Julian of his own danger, and his apprehensions were increased by the recent and unworthy fate of Sylvanus.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Sylvanus', 'PERSON')"
"The military historian, (54) who was himself despatched to 
 observe the army of the Persians, as they were preparing to
 construct a bridge of boats over the Tigris, beheld from an
 eminence the plain of Assyria, as far as the edge of the
 horizon, covered with men, with horses, and with arms.","('54', 'DATE'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Assyria', 'GPE')"
"The negligence with which he permitted a
 troop of pillagers freely to pass, and to return, almost
 before the gates of his camp, may be imputed to his want of
 abilities; but the treasonable act of burning a number of
 boats, and a superfluous stock of provisions, which would
 have been of the most essential service to the army of Gaul,
 was an evidence of his hostile and criminal intentions.","('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The nephew and
 daughter of Constantine, who could ill brook the insolence
 of a subject, expressed their resentment by instantly
 delivering Domitian to the custody of a guard.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON')"
"The obstinate resistance of this handful of Franks
 apprised Julian of the difficulties of the expedition which
 he meditated for the ensuing spring against the whole body
 of the nation.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('the ensuing spring', 'DATE')"
"The persons despatched to secure the
 provinces which he left behind passed him with cold
 salutations or affected disdain; and the troops whose
 station lay along the public road were studiously removed on
 his approach, lest they might be tempted to offer their
 swords for the service of a civil war.(23) After Gallus had 
 been permitted to repose himself a few days at Hadrianople
 he received a mandate, expressed in the most haughty and
 absolute style, that his splendid retinue should halt in
 that city, while the Caesar himself, with only ten
 post-carriages, should hasten to the Imperial residence at
 Milan.","('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('a few days', 'DATE'), ('Hadrianople', 'ORG'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('only ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"The power of the enemy 
 was yet unbroken; and the Caesar had no sooner separated his
 troops, and fixed his own quarters at Sens, in the centre of
 Gaul, than he was surrounded and besieged by a numerous host
 of Germans.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Sens', 'ORG'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
The precarious and dependent situation of Julian displayed his virtues and concealed his defects.,"('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The precepts of 
 eloquence, which he had hitherto practised on fancied topics
 of declamation, were more usefully applied to excite or to
 assuage the passions of an armed multitude: and although
 Julian, from his early habits of conversation and
 literature, was more familiarly acquainted with the beauties
 of the Greek language, he had attained a competent knowledge
 of the Latin tongue. (68)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Greek', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE')"
"The pride of Constantius, and 
 the ingenuity of his courtiers, were at a loss to discover
 any materials for panegyric in the events of the Persian
 war; while the glory of his cousin Julian, to whose military
 command he had intrusted the provinces of Gauls was
 proclaimed to the world in the simple and concise narrative
 of his exploits.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('the Persian\r\n war', 'EVENT'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Gauls', 'NORP')"
"The principal
 houses, constructed with some imitation of Roman elegance,
 were consumed by the flames; and the Caesar boldly advanced
 about ten miles, till his progress was stopped by a dark and
 impenetrable forest, undermined by subterraneous passages,
 which threatened with secret snares and ambush every step of
 the assailant.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('about ten miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"The private houses of Antioch, and the
 palaces of public resort, were besieged by spies and
 informers; and the Caesar himself, concealed in a plebeian
 habit, very frequently condescended to assume that odious
 character.","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"The protection of the Rhaetian frontier, and the persecution
 of the Catholic church, detained Constantius in Italy above
 eighteen months after the departure of Julian.","('Rhaetian', 'NORP'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('eighteen months', 'DATE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The retired scholastic
 education of Julian, in which he had been more conversant
 with books than with arms, with the dead than with the
 living, left him in profound ignorance of the practical arts
 of war and government; and when he awkwardly repeated some
 military exercise which it was necessary for him to learn,
 he exclaimed with a sigh, ""0 Plato, Plato, what a task for a
 philosopher!""","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('Plato', 'PERSON')"
The river bathed the foot of the walls; and the town was accessible only by two wooden bridges.,"('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The satisfaction which Constantius had received from this
 journey excited him to the generous emulation of bestowing
 on the Romans some memorial of his own gratitude and
 munificence.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The satraps and generals
 were distributed according to their several ranks, and the
 whole army, besides the numerous train of oriental luxury,
 consisted of more than one hundred thousand effective men,
 inured to fatigue, and selected from the bravest nations of
 Asia.","('more than one hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The severe discipline of the
 Persian youth had been introduced by the eunuchs into the
 Imperial palace; and such were the habits of patience which
 they had inculcated, that, during a slow and sultry march,
 he was never seen to move his hand towards his face, or to
 turn his eyes either to the right or to the left.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"The son
 of Constantine was lodged in the ancient palace of Augustus:
 he presided in the senate, harangued the people from the
 tribunal which Cicero had so often ascended, assisted with
 unusual courtesy at the games of the circus, and accepted
 the crowns of gold, as well as the panegyrics, which had
 been prepared for this ceremony by the deputies of the
 principal cities.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Cicero', 'PERSON')"
"The strength as well as
 spirit of the army with which Sapor took the field in the
 ensuing spring was no longer equal to the unbounded views of
 his ambition.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n ensuing spring', 'DATE')"
"The territory of the Limigantes was
 protected against the Romans by the Danube, against the
 hostile barbarians by the Theiss.","('Limigantes', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Theiss', 'PERSON')"
"The tillage of the provinces of Gaul had been interrupted by
 the calamities of war; but the scanty harvests of the
 continent were supplied, by his paternal care, from the
 plenty of the adjacent island.","('Gaul', 'LOC')"
"The traveller who has contemplated the ruins
 of ancient Rome may conceive some imperfect idea of the
 sentiments which they must have inspired when they reared
 their heads in the splendour of unsullied beauty.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The trumpets sounded, the military shout was
 heard through the field, and the two armies rushed with
 equal fury to the charge.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The two princes returned to the palace in the same chariot;
 and, during the slow procession, Julian repeated to himself
 a verse of his favourite Homer, which he might equally apply
 to his fortune and to his fears.(37)","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Homer', 'PERSON')"
"The vanquished Germans had 
 submitted to the just but humiliating condition of preparing
 and conveying the necessary materials.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"The villages on either side
 of the Main, which were plentifully stored with corn and
 cattle, felt the ravages of an invading army.","('Main', 'LOC')"
"The walls were shaken by the reiterated
 efforts of the most enormous of the battering-rams; the town
 was reduced to the last extremity; but it was still defended
 by the patient and intrepid valour of the garrison, till the
 approach of the rainy season obliged the emperor to raise
 the siege, and ingloriously to retreat into his
 winter-quarters at Antioch.(63)","('winter-quarters', 'DATE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"The writers the most indulgent to the memory of Gallus, and
 even Julian himself, though he wished to cast a veil over
 the frailties of his brother, are obliged to confess that
 the Caesar was incapable of reigning.","('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"The young hero who supported, in Gaul, the throne of Constantius, was not permitted to reform the vices of the government; but he had courage to alleviate or to pity the distress of the people.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"Their
 repeated acclamations expressed their joy at beholding,
 after an absence of thirty-two years, the sacred person of
 their sovereign; and Constantius himself expressed, with
 some pleasantry, his affected surprise that the human race
 should thus suddenly be collected on the same spot.","('thirty-two years', 'DATE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
Their labours were not unsuccessful; and Julian inviolably preserved for Athens that tender regard which seldom fails to arise in a liberal mind from the recollection of the place where it has discovered and exercised its growing powers.,"('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Athens', 'GPE')"
"Their skilful guide, changing his plan of operations, then
 conducted the army by a longer circuit, but through a
 fertile territory, towards the head of the Euphrates, where
 the infant river is reduced to a shallow and accessible
 stream.","('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"These overtures of peace, translated into the 
 servile and flattering language of Asia, were transmitted to
 the camp of the Great King, who resolved to signify, by an
 ambassador, the terms which he was inclined to grant to the
 suppliant Romans.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('the Great King', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"They
 pursued their studies, and practised their exercises, under
 the tuition of the most skilful masters; and the numerous
 household appointed to attend, or rather to guard, the
 nephews of Constantine, was not unworthy of the dignity of
 their birth.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"They employed three days, and as many nights, in
 transporting over the Rhine their military powers.","('three days', 'DATE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"They executed their orders with so much boldness and
 celerity, that they had almost surprised the barbarian
 chiefs, who returned in the fearless confidence of
 intoxication from one of their nocturnal festivals.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"They promised to restore all the Roman captives who yet
 remained alive; and as the Caesar had procured an exact
 account from the cities and villages of Gaul of the
 inhabitants whom they had lost, he detected every attempt to
 deceive him with a degree of readiness and accuracy which
 almost established the belief of his super-natural
 knowledge.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'LOC')"
"They rudely seized the praefect and the quaestor, and, tying
 their legs together with ropes, they dragged them through
 the streets of the city, inflicted a thousand insults and a
 thousand wounds on these unhappy victims, and at last
 precipitated their mangled and lifeless bodies into the
 stream of the Orontes.(21)
Dangerous situation of Gallus 
After such a deed, whatever might have been the designs of
 Gallus, it was only in a field of battle that he could
 assert his innocence with any hope of success.","('a thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('a\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Orontes', 'PERSON'), ('21', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('Gallus', 'PRODUCT')"
"They rushed with fury to seize the person of the emperor;
 his royal throne and golden couch were pillaged by these
 rude hands; but the faithful defence of his guards, who died
 at his feet, allowed him a moment to mount a fleet horse,
 and to escape from the confusion.","('a moment', 'TIME')"
"They surrounded the tribunal, and
 seemed to hear with respect an oration full of mildness and
 dignity; when one of the barbarians, casting his shoe into
 the air, exclaimed with a loud voice, Marha!","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Marha', 'PERSON')"
"They were
 rendered impracticable by the imprudent behaviour of
 Montius, a statesman whose art and experience were
 frequently betrayed by the levity of his disposition.(20)","('Montius', 'PERSON')"
"They were instructed to behave towards
 Gallus with moderation and respect, and, by the gentlest
 arts of persuasion, to engage him to comply with the
 invitation of his brother and colleague.","('Gallus', 'PERSON')"
"Thirty thousand 
 of his veterans had fallen under the walls of Amida during
 the continuance of a siege which lasted seventy-three days;
 and the disappointed monarch returned to his capital with
 affected triumph and secret mortification.","('Thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Amida', 'GPE'), ('seventy-three days', 'DATE')"
"Those unhappy beings, the
 ancient production of Oriental jealousy and despotism,(1) were introduced into Greece and Rome by the contagion of Asiatic luxury.(2) Their progress was rapid; and the eunuchs, who, in the time of Augustus, had been abhorred, as the monstrous retinue of an Egyptian queen, (3) were gradually admitted into the families of matrons, of senators, and of the emperors themselves.","('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP'), ('3', 'CARDINAL')"
"Those who are inclined to 
 palliate the cruelties of Constantius assert that he soon
 relented, and endeavoured to recall the bloody mandate; but
 that the second messenger, intrusted with the reprieve, was
 detained by the eunuchs, who dreaded the unforgiving temper
 of Gallus, and were desirous of reuniting to their empire
 the wealthy provinces of the East.(25)","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('25', 'CARDINAL')"
"Three hundred light-armed and active soldiers were detached
 in forty small boats, to fall down the stream in silence,
 and to land at some distance from the posts of the enemy.","('Three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('forty', 'CARDINAL')"
"To the several nations which
 followed his standard their respective posts were assigned;
 the south to the Vertae; the north to the Albanians; the
 east to the Chionites, inflamed with grief and indignation;
 the west to the Segestans, the bravest of his warriors, who
 covered their front with a formidable line of Indian
 elephants.(58) The Persians, on every side, supported their 
 efforts, and animated their courage; and the monarch
 himself, careless of his rank and safety, displayed, in the
 prosecution of the siege, the ardour of a youthful soldier.","('Vertae', 'LOC'), ('Albanians', 'NORP'), ('Chionites', 'NORP'), ('Segestans', 'NORP'), ('Indian', 'NORP'), ('58', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"Towards the close of the
 campaign the arms of Sapor incurred some disgrace by an
 unsuccessful enterprise against Virtha, or Tecrit, a strong,
 or, as it was universally esteemed till the age of
 Tamerlane, an impregnable fortress of the independent Arabs.
 (61)
Conduct of the Romans","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Virtha', 'PERSON'), ('Tecrit', 'ORG'), ('Tamerlane', 'GPE'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Two ministers of illustrious rank, Domitian the
 Oriental praefect, and Montius, quaestor of the palace, were
 empowered by a special commission to visit and reform the
 state of the East.","('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON'), ('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('Montius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"Two of the eastern
 ministers of Constantius, the Praetorian praefect Musonian,
 whose abilities were disgraced by the want of truth and
 integrity, and Cassian duke of Mesopotamia, a hardy and
 veteran soldier, opened a secret negotiation with the satrap
 Tamsapor.(49)","('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'GPE'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Musonian', 'NORP'), ('Cassian', 'NORP'), ('Mesopotamia', 'GPE'), ('Tamsapor', 'PERSON'), ('49', 'CARDINAL')"
"Unless he had been able o revive the martial spirit of the Romans, or to introduce the arts of industry and refinement among their savage enemies, he could not entertain any rational hopes of securing the public tranquillity, either by the peace or conquest of Germany.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"Victories of Julian in GaulPower of the eunuchs 
 THE divided provinces of the empire were again united by the
 victory of Constantius; but as that feeble prince was
 destitute of personal merit either in peace or war; as he
 feared his generals, and distrusted his ministers; the
 triumph of his arms served only to establish the reign of
 the eunuchs over the Roman world.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('GaulPower', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"We may enjoy the pleasure of reading the sentiments of Julian, as he expresses them with warmth and
 freedom in a letter to one of his most intimate friends.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"When he had subdued or pacified the
 barbarians of the Danube, Constantius proceeded by slow
 marches into the East; and after he had wept over the
 smoking ruins of Amida, he formed, with a powerful army, the
 siege of Bezabde.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Amida', 'GPE'), ('Bezabde', 'GPE')"
"When the Chamavians sued for
