Sentence,Entities
"""It is our pleasure  (such is the Imperial style)   that all the nations which are governed by our clemency and moderation should steadfastly adhere to the religion which was taught by St. Peter to the Romans, which faithful tradition has preserved, and which is now professed by the pontiff Damasus, and by Peter, bishop of Alexandria, a man of apostolic holiness.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('St. Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Damasus', 'PERSON'), ('Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"""My authority,"" replied Arbogastes, with insulting coolness,   ""does not depend on the smile or the frown of a monarch;"" 
 and he contemptuously threw the paper on the ground.","('Arbogastes', 'PERSON')"
"""The prince,"" says Montesquieu,   ""who is actuated by the
 hopes and fears of religion, may be compared to a lion, docile only to the voice, and tractable to the hand, of his keeper."" (100)","('Montesquieu', 'PERSON'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"""You have
 imitated David in his crime, imitate then his repentance,""  
 was the reply of the undaunted Ambrose.","('David', 'PERSON'), ('Ambrose', 'PERSON')"
(1),"('1', 'CARDINAL')"
(11),"('11', 'CARDINAL')"
(114),"('114', 'CARDINAL')"
"(13) The emperor, in 
 his peaceful residence of Paris, was alarmed by their
 hostile approach, and the darts which he idly wasted on
 lions and bears might have been employed more honourably
 against the rebels.","('Paris', 'GPE')"
"(15) These executions might be necessary to the 
 public safety, but the successful usurper, whose power was
 acknowledged by all the provinces of the West, had the merit
 and the satisfaction of boasting that, except those who had
 perished by the chance of war, his triumph was not stained
 by the blood of the Romans.(16)
Treaty of peace between Maximus and Theodosius, A.D. 383-387.","('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('16)\r\nTreaty', 'LAW'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('383-387', 'CARDINAL')"
(19),"('19', 'CARDINAL')"
(3),"('3', 'CARDINAL')"
"(38) In the East, A.D. 381, January 10.","('381', 'CARDINAL'), ('January 10', 'DATE')"
"(44)
Retreat of Gregory Nazianzen, A.D. 381.","('44', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gregory Nazianzen', 'PERSON'), ('381', 'CARDINAL')"
"(5) Among the various arts which had exercised the youth 
 of Gratian, he had applied himself, with singular
 inclination and success, to manage the horse, to draw the
 bow, and to dart the javelin; and these qualifications,
 which might be useful to a soldier, were prostituted to the
 viler purposes of hunting.","('Gratian', 'PERSON')"
"A bishop, Amphilochius of Iconium, approached the throne, and, after saluting with due reverence the person of his sovereign, he accosted the royal youth with the same familiar tenderness which he might have used towards a
 plebeian child.","('Amphilochius', 'PERSON'), ('Iconium', 'GPE')"
"A body of the Alani was received into
 the military and domestic service of the palace, and the
 admirable skill which they were accustomed to display in the
 unbounded plains of Scythia was exercised on a more narrow
 theatre in the parks and enclosures of Gaul.","('Alani', 'PERSON'), ('Scythia', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'LOC')"
"A character 
 thus accomplished might almost excuse the extravagant
 supposition of the orator Pacatus that, if the elder Brutus
 could be permitted to revisit the earth, the stern
 republican would abjure, at the feet of Theodosius, his
 hatred of kings; and ingenuously confess that such a monarch
 was the most faithful guardian of the happiness and dignity
 of the Roman people.(81)
Faults of Theodosius.","('Pacatus', 'PERSON'), ('Brutus', 'PERSON'), ('republican', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('81', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"A few days after this extraordinary quarrel, in which he had exposed his resentment and his weakness, the unfortunate Valentinian was found strangled in his apartment, and some pains were employed to disguise the manifest guilt of Arbogastes, and to persuade the world that the death of the young emperor had been the voluntary effect of his own despair. (106)","('A few days', 'DATE'), ('Valentinian', 'PERSON'), ('Arbogastes', 'NORP'), ('106', 'CARDINAL')"
"A final and unanimous sentence was pronounced to
 ratify the equal Deity of the Holy Ghost: the mysterious
 doctrine has been received by all the nations, and all the
 churches, of the Christian world; and their grateful
 reverence has assigned to the bishops of Theodosius the
 second rank among the general councils.(42)","('the Holy Ghost', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('42', 'CARDINAL')"
"A fine of ten pounds of gold
 (above four hundred pounds sterling) was imposed on every
 person who should dare to confer, or receive, or promote, an
 heretical ordination: and it was reasonably expected that,
 if the race of pastors could be extinguished, their helpless
 flocks would be compelled, by ignorance and hunger, to
 return within the pale of the Catholic church.","('ten pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('four hundred pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"A fine of two hundred pounds of gold was imposed
 on the corporate body of merchants and manufacturers: an
 order was signified, in the name of the emperor, to all the
 officers and inferior servants of the courts of justice,
 that, during the continuance of the public disorders, they
 should strictly confine themselves to their houses: and the
 ministers of Valentinian imprudently confessed that the most
 respectable part of the citizens of Milan was attached to
 the cause of their archbishop.","('two hundred pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"A foreign
 merchant, who had probably no concern in his murder, offered
 his own life and all his wealth to supply the place of one
 of his two sons; but while the father hesitated with equal
 tenderness, while he was doubtful to choose, and unwilling
 to condemn, the soldiers determined his suspense by plunging
 their daggers at the same moment into the breasts of the
 defenceless youths.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"A free and general pardon was granted to the city and citizens of Antioch; the prison-doors were thrown open; the senators, who despaired of their lives, recovered the possession of their houses and estates; and the capital of the East was restored to the enjoyment of her ancient dignity and splendour.","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"A large body of Goths had marched to occupy the Basilica, which was the object of the dispute: and it might be expected from the Arian principles and barbarous manners of these foreign mercenaries, that they would not entertain any scruples in the execution of the most sanguinary orders.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Basilica', 'FAC'), ('Arian', 'NORP')"
"A long period of calamity or decay
 must have checked the industry and diminished the wealth of
 the people; and their profuse luxury must have been the
 result of that indolent despair which enjoys the present
 hour and declines the thoughts of futurity.","('the present\r\n hour', 'TIME')"
"A loud and licentious murmur was echoed
 through the camps and garrisons of the West; and as the mild
 indolence of Gratian neglected to extinguish the first
 symptoms of discontent, the want of love and respect was not
 supplied by the influence of fear.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Gratian', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
A more attentive view of the life of Gratian may perhaps suggest the true cause of the disappointment of the public hopes.,"('Gratian', 'PERSON')"
"A powerful
 fleet was equipped in the harbours of Greece and Epirus,
 with an apparent design that, as soon as the passage had
 been opened by a naval victory, Valentinian and his mother
 should land in Italy, proceed without delay to Rome, and
 occupy the majestic seat of religion and empire.","('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Epirus', 'LOC'), ('Valentinian', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"A sentence of easy and honourable banishment was pronounced, which enjoined Ambrose to depart from Milan without delay, whilst it permitted him to choose the place of his exile and the number of his companions.","('Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"A stranger, who assumed the name of Maximus(34) and the cloak of a Cynic philosopher, insinuated himself into the confidence of Gregory, deceived and abused his
 favourable opinion, and, forming a secret connection with
 some bishops of Egypt, attempted, by a clandestine
 ordination, to supplant his patron in the episcopal seat of
 Constantinople.","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('34', 'DATE'), ('Cynic', 'NORP'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"A thousand new statues arose to the clemency of Theodosius; the applause of his subjects was ratified by the approbation of his own heart; and the emperor confessed
 that, if the exercise of justice is the most important duty, the indulgence of mercy is the most exquisite pleasure of a sovereign.(90)
Sedition and massacre of Thessalonica, A.D. 390.","('A thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Thessalonica', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 390', 'DATE')"
"A vessel was secretly provided to transport the Imperial family; they embarked with precipitation in one of the obscure harbours of Venetia, or Istria; traversed the whole extent of the Hadriatic and Ionian seas, turned the
 extreme promontory of Peloponnesus; and, after a long but successful navigation, reposed themselves in the port of Thessalonica.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Venetia', 'LOC'), ('Istria', 'LOC'), ('Hadriatic', 'LOC'), ('Ionian', 'NORP'), ('Peloponnesus', 'LOC'), ('Thessalonica', 'GPE')"
"A.D. 383, August 25.","('A.D. 383', 'DATE'), ('August 25', 'DATE')"
A.D. 386.,"('A.D. 386', 'DATE')"
"About six weeks afterwards, Theodosius declared his resolution of expelling from all the churches of his dominions the bishops
 and their clergy who should obstinately refuse to believe, or at least to profess, the doctrine of the council of Nice.","('About six weeks', 'DATE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Nice', 'GPE')"
Accident is commonly the parent of disorder: the seeds of rebellion happened to fall on a soil which was supposed to be more fruitful than any other in tyrants and usurpers;(8)Revolt of Maximus in Britain the legions of that sequestered island had been long famous for a spirit of presumption and arrogance;(9) and the name of Maximus was proclaimed by the tumultuary but unanimous voice both of the soldiers and of the provincials.,"('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"According to 
 the duty of his office, the governor of the province
 despatched a faithful narrative of the whole transaction,
 while the trembling citizens intrusted the confession of
 their crime and the assurances of their repentance to the
 zeal of Flavian their bishop, and to the eloquence of the
 senator Hilarius, the friend, and most probably the
 disciple, of Libanius, (85) whose genius on this melancholy 
 occasion was not useless to his country.","('Flavian', 'NORP'), ('Hilarius', 'PERSON'), ('Libanius', 'PERSON'), ('85', 'DATE')"
"According to the custom of the age, the images of the three
 Imperial colleagues were exhibited to the veneration of the
 people; nor should it be lightly supposed that, in the
 moment of a solemn reconciliation, Theodosius secretly
 cherished the intention of perfidy and revenge.(18)
Baptism and orthodox edicts of Theodosius, A.D. 380, February 28.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('380', 'CARDINAL'), ('February 28', 'DATE')"
"According to the discipline of the apostles, and the doctrine of the Gospel, let us believe the sole deity of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Ghost, under an equal majesty and a pious Trinity.","('Gospel', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('the Holy Ghost', 'PERSON')"
"According to the mildest rules of ecclesiastical discipline which were established in the fourth century, the crime of homicide was expiated by the penitence of twenty years:(97) and as it was impossible in the period of human life to purge the accumulated guilt of the massacre of Thessalonica, the murderer should have been excluded from the holy communion till the hour of his death.","('the fourth century', 'DATE'), ('twenty years', 'DATE'), ('97', 'DATE'), ('Thessalonica', 'GPE'), ('the hour', 'TIME')"
"After 
 this remarkable experience of the ingratitude of princes and
 prelates, Gregory retired once more to his obscure solitude
 of Cappadocia, where he employed the remainder of his life,
 about eight years, in the exercises of poetry and devotion.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE'), ('about eight years', 'DATE')"
"After a delay of about eight months Theodosius was restored to the communion of the faithful;
 and the edict, which interposes a salutary interval of thirty days between the sentence and the execution, may be accepted as the worthy fruits of his repentance. (99)","('about eight months', 'DATE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('thirty days', 'DATE')"
"After his tragic death, at a time when the empress
 Justina trembled for her own safety, and for that of her son
 Valentinian, the archbishop of Milan was despatched on two
 different embassies to the court of Treves.","('Justina', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Treves', 'GPE')"
"After the defeat and death of the tyrant of Gaul, the Roman
 world was in the possession of Theodosius.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"After the defeat of Eugenius, the merit, as well as the
 authority, of Theodosius was cheerfully acknowledged by all
 the inhabitants of the Roman world.","('Eugenius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"After the fatigue of a long march in the heat of
 summer they spurred their foaming horses into the waters of
 the Save, swam the river in the presence of the enemy, and
 instantly charged and routed the troops who guarded the high
 ground on the opposite side.","('summer', 'DATE'), ('Save', 'PRODUCT')"
"After the first tender expressions of
 friendship and sympathy, the pious emperor of the East
 gently admonished Justina that the guilt of heresy was
 sometimes punished in this world as well as in the next; and
 that the public profession of the Nicene faith would be the
 most efficacious step to promote the restoration of her son,
 by the satisfaction which it must occasion both on earth and
 in heaven.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Justina', 'PERSON'), ('Nicene', 'PERSON')"
"All the subjects of Valentinian deserted the cause of a prince who, by his abdication, had absolved them from the duty of allegiance; and if the little city of Aemona, on the verge of Italy, had not presumed to stop the career of his inglorious victory, Maximus would have obtained without a struggle the sole possession of the Western empire.","('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Aemona', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"Although he was
 born of a Christian family, the maxims, or at least the
 practice, of the age encouraged him to delay the ceremony of
 his initiation till he was admonished of the danger of delay
 by the serious illness which threatened his life towards the
 end of the first year of his reign.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('the\r\n end of the first year of his reign', 'DATE')"
"Ambrose archbishop of Milan, A.D. 374-397.","('Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 374-397', 'DATE')"
"Ambrose considers the
 toleration of the Jewish as the persecution of the Christian
 religion; boldly declares that he himself and every true
 believer would eagerly dispute with the bishop of Callinicum
 the merit of the deed and the crown of martyrdom; and
 laments, in the most pathetic terms, that the execution of
 the sentence would be fatal to the fame and salvation of
 Theodosius.","('Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('Jewish', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Callinicum', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Ambrose had 
 devoted his life and his abilities to the service of the
 church.","('Ambrose', 'PERSON')"
"Among the
 benefactors of the church, the fame of Constantine has been
 rivalled by the glory of Theodosius.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Among the ecclesiastics who illustrated the reign of
 Theodosius, Gregory Nazianzen was distinguished by the
 talents of an eloquent preacher; the reputation of
 miraculous gifts added weight and dignity to the monastic
 virtues of Martin of Tours; (60) but the palm of episcopal 
 vigour and ability was justly claimed by the intrepid
 Ambrose.(61)","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Gregory Nazianzen', 'PERSON'), ('Martin of Tours', 'PERSON'), ('60', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('61', 'CARDINAL')"
"An historian
 perpetually adverse to the fame of Theodosius has
 exaggerated his vices and their pernicious effects, he
 boldly asserts that every rank of subjects imitated the
 effeminate manners of their sovereign; that every species of
 corruption polluted the course of public and private life;
 and that the feeble restraints of order and decency were
 insufficient to resist the progress of that degenerate
 spirit which sacrifices, without a blush, the consideration
 of duty and interest to the base indulgence of sloth and
 appetite.(124)","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('124', 'CARDINAL')"
"An immediate and peremptory answer was
 required, but it was extremely difficult for Theodosius to
 satisfy, on this important occasion, either the feelings of
 his own mind or the expectations of the public.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
April 25.,"('April 25', 'DATE')"
"Arbogastes, after the loss of a battle in which
 he had discharged the duties of a soldier and a general,
 wandered several days among the mountains.","('Arbogastes', 'PERSON'), ('several days', 'DATE')"
"Arbogastes,(104) a gallant soldier of 
 the nation of the Franks, held the second rank in the
 service of Gratian.","('Arbogastes', 'ORG'), ('104', 'CARDINAL'), ('Franks', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gratian', 'ORG')"
"Arianism of Constantinople, A.D. 340-380.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('340-380', 'CARDINAL')"
"As she desired to perform her public
 devotions on the approaching festival of Easter, Ambrose was
 ordered to appear before the council.","('Easter', 'EVENT'), ('Ambrose', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as time and accident had
 removed those faithful counsellors from the throne, the
 emperor of the West insensibly descended to the level of his
 natural genius, abandoned the reins of government to the
 ambitious hands which were stretched forwards to grasp them,
 and amused his leisure with the most frivolous
 gratifications.","('West', 'LOC')"
"As this private admonition did not produce an
 immediate effect, the archbishop from his pulpit(93) publicly 
 addressed the emperor on his throne;(94) nor would he consent 
 to offer the oblation of the altar till he had obtained from
 Theodosius a solemn and positive declaration which secured
 the impunity of the bishop and monks of Callinicum.","('93', 'DATE'), ('94', 'DATE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Callinicum', 'GPE')"
"At length,
 twenty-four days after the sedition, the general Hellebicus,
 and Caesarius, master of the offices, declared the will of
 the emperor and the sentence of Antioch.","('twenty-four days', 'DATE'), ('Hellebicus', 'PERSON'), ('Caesarius', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"At the
 time when he might have hoped to enjoy the fruits of his
 victory, his episcopal throne was filled by the senator
 Nectarius; and the new archbishop, accidentally recommended
 by his easy temper and venerable aspect, was obliged to
 delay the ceremony of his consecration till he had
 previously despatched the rites of his baptism.(46)","('Nectarius', 'PERSON')"
"At the age of thirty-four, and before he had received
 the sacrament of baptism, Ambrose, to his own surprise and
 to that of the world, was suddenly transformed from a
 governor to an archbishop.","('the age of thirty-four', 'DATE'), ('Ambrose', 'PERSON')"
"Baptism and orthodox edicts of Theodosius, A.D. 380, February 28.","('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 380', 'DATE'), ('February 28', 'DATE')"
"Before he again took the
 field against the Goths, he received the sacrament of
 baptism (20) from Acholius, the orthodox bishop of 
 Thessalonica:(21) and as the emperor ascended from the holy 
 font, still glowing with the warm feelings of regeneration,
 he dictated a solemn edict, which proclaimed his own faith,
 and prescribed the religion of his subjects.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('20', 'CARDINAL'), ('Acholius', 'PERSON'), ('Thessalonica', 'GPE'), ('21', 'CARDINAL')"
"Before he formed any decisive resolution the pious emperor was anxious to discover the will of Heaven; and as the progress of Christian Laity had silenced the oracles of Delphi and Dodona, he consulted an Egyptian monk, who possessed, in the opinion of the age, the gift of miracles and the knowledge of futurity.","('Christian Laity', 'PERSON'), ('Delphi', 'ORG'), ('Dodona', 'PERSON'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP')"
"Besides the condemnation of Divine justice, they must expect to suffer the severe penalties, which our authority, guided by heavenly wisdom, shall think proper to inflict upon them."" (22)","('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"Both parties in the schools, as well as in the temples, acknowledged and worshipped the divine majesty of Christ; and, as we are always prone to impute our own sentiments and passions to the Deity, it would be deemed more prudent and respectful to exaggerate than to circumscribe the adorable
 perfections of the Son of God.","('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('the Son of God', 'PERSON')"
"Botheric and
 several of his principal officers were inhumanly murdered;
 their mangled bodies were dragged about the streets; and the
 emperor, who then resided at Milan, was surprised by the
 intelligence of the audacious and wanton cruelty of the
 people of Thessalonica.","('Botheric', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Thessalonica', 'GPE')"
"Botheric, the general of those troops, and, as it
 should seem from his name, a barbarian, had among his slaves
 a beautiful boy, who excited the impure desires of one of
 the charioteers of the circus.","('Botheric', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"But
 some remains of pride and prejudice still opposed the
 elevation of Arbogastes himself, and the judicious
 barbarians thought it more advisable to reign under the name
 of some dependent Roman.","('Arbogastes', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But Gregory soon became the
 victim of malice and envy.","('Gregory', 'PERSON')"
"But an accurate, or rather a candid inquiry, will discover that, if the Priscillianists violated the laws of nature, it was not by the licentiousness, but by the austerity of their lives.","('Priscillianists', 'NORP')"
"But as Maximus wished to
 occupy, without resistance, the passes of the Alps, he
 received, with perfidious smiles, Domninus of Syria, the
 ambassador of Valentinian, and pressed him to accept the aid
 of a considerable body of troops for the service of a
 Pannonian war.","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Domninus', 'PERSON'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('a\r\n Pannonian war', 'EVENT')"
"But as he was still conscious that he deserved another audience and another theatre, he accepted,
 with no unworthy ambition, the honourable invitation which was addressed to him from the orthodox party of Constantinople.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"But as the second conquest of the West was a task of
 difficulty and danger, he dismissed, with splendid presents and an ambiguous answer, the ambassadors of Eugenius, and almost two years were consumed in the preparations of the civil war.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Eugenius', 'PERSON'), ('almost two years', 'DATE'), ('the civil war', 'EVENT')"
"But he
 proceeded, in a firm and equal tone, to offer Theodosius the
 alternative of peace or war.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"But he
 stipulated that Maximus should content himself with the
 possession of the countries beyond the Alps.","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC')"
"But his cause was supported by
 the Western churches; and the bishops of the synod resolved
 to perpetuate the mischiefs of discord, by the hasty
 ordination of a perjured candidate,(43) rather than to betray 
 the imagined dignity of the East, which had been illustrated
 by the birth and death of the Son of God.","('Western', 'NORP'), ('43', 'DATE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('the Son of God', 'PERSON')"
"But his fatigues were rewarded by the daily increase of his
 fame and his congregation; and he enjoyed the pleasure of
 observing that the greater part of his numerous audience
 retired from his sermons satisfied with the eloquence of the
 preacher,(35) or dissatisfied with the manifold imperfections of their faith and practice.(36)
Ruin of Arianism at Constantinople, A.D. 380, November 26.","('35', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 380', 'DATE'), ('November 26', 'DATE')"
"But in the midst of the tumult he artfully or
 modestly refused to ascend the throne, and some credit appears to have been given to his own positive declaration that he was compelled to accept the dangerous present of the Imperial purple.(12)
Flight and death of Gratian.","('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON')"
"But it
 was not confirmed by the archbishop of Milan.(92)","('Milan', 'GPE'), ('92', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the
 conduct of Ambrose was governed by very different
 principles.(63)","('Ambrose', 'PERSON')"
"But the
 feeble emotion of involuntary pity was checked by his regard
 for public justice and the memory of Gratian; and he
 abandoned the victim to the pious zeal of the soldiers, who
 drew him out of the Imperial presence and instantly
 separated his head from his body.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"But the
 painful virtue which claims the merit of victory is exposed
 to the danger of defeat; and the reign of a wise and
 merciful prince was polluted by an act of cruelty which
 would stain the annals of Nero or Domitian.","('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON')"
"But the
 victory was not purchased by their blood; the Gauls
 maintained their advantage, and the approach of night
 protected the disorderly flight, or retreat, of the troops
 of Theodosius.","('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('night', 'TIME'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE')"
"But the authority of the saints, who have preached and practised the maxims of passive loyalty, appeared to Ambrose of less moment than the extreme and pressing danger of the church.","('Ambrose', 'PERSON')"
"But the contest with his successor, who, like
 him, had usurped the throne of the West, was easily decided
 in the term of two months,(76) and within the space of two 
 hundred miles.","('West', 'LOC'), ('two months', 'DATE'), ('76', 'CARDINAL'), ('two \r\n hundred miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"But the crafty tyrant followed,
 with hasty and silent footsteps, in the rear; and as he
 diligently intercepted all intelligence of his motions, the
 gleam of armour and the dust excited by the troops of
 cavalry first announced the hostile approach of a stranger
 to the gates of Milan.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"But the dangerous interview was prevented by the prayers of the empress Flacilla, who trembled for the salvation of her husband; and the mind of Theodosius was confirmed by a theological argument adapted to the rudest capacity.","('Flacilla', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"But the exaltation
 of Basil, from a private life to the archiepiscopal throne
 of Caesarea, discovered to the world, and perhaps to
 himself, the pride of his character; and the first favour
 which he condescended to bestow on his friend was received,
 and perhaps was intended, as a cruel insult.(29) Instead of 
 employing the superior talents of Gregory in some useful and
 conspicuous station, the haughty prelate selected, among the
 fifty bishoprics of his extensive province, the wretched
 village of Sasima, (30) without water, without verdure, 
 without society, situate at the junction of three highways
 and frequented only by the incessant passage of rude and
 clamorous waggoners.","('Basil', 'PERSON'), ('Caesarea', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sasima', 'GPE'), ('30', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the gates could not long
 resist the effort of a victorious enemy; and the despair,
 the disaffection, the indifference of the soldiers and
 people hastened the downfall of the wretched Maximus.","('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"But the indulgence of ease and luxury had
 secretly nourished the principles of disease. (122)","('122', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the ministers of
 Theodosius performed with reluctance the cruel task which
 had been assigned them; they dropped a gentle tear over the
 calamities of the people, and they listened with reverence
 to the pressing solicitations of the monks and hermits, who
 descended in swarms from the mountains.(89) Hellebicus and 
 Caesarius were persuaded to suspend the execution of their
 sentence; and it was agreed that the former should remain at
 Antioch, while the latter returned, with all possible speed,
 to Constantinople, and presumed once more to consult the
 will of his sovereign.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Hellebicus', 'PERSON'), ('Caesarius', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"But the promises which Ambrose
 received and communicated were soon violated by a perfidious
 court; and, during six of the most solemn days which
 Christian piety has set apart for the exercise of religion,
 the city was agitated by the irregular convulsions of tumult
 and fanaticism.","('Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"But the subversion of an
 established government is always a work of some real, and of
 much apparent difficulty; and the throne of Gratian was
 protected by the sanctions of custom, law, religion, and the
 nice balance of the civil and military powers which had been established by the policy of Constantine.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"But the two
 capitals, Antioch and Constantinople, were separated by the
 distance of eight hundred miles; and, notwithstanding the
 diligence of the Imperial posts, the guilty city was
 severely punished by a long and dreadful interval of
 suspense.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('eight hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"But there was danger likewise in refusing the empire, and,
 from the moment that Maxim had violated his allegiance to
 his lawful sovereign, he could not hope to reign, or even to
 live if he confined his moderate ambition within the narrow
 limits of Britain.","('Maxim', 'PERSON'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"But this amiable youth, before he had
 accomplished the twentieth year of his age, was oppressed by
 domestic treason, and the empire was again involved in the
 horrors of a civil war.","('the twentieth year', 'DATE')"
"But when he was
 convinced that his cause was desperate, and his escape
 impracticable, the intrepid barbarian imitated the example
 of the ancient Romans, and turned his sword against his own
 breast.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"But while he laboured to restrain the effects of their zeal,
 the pathetic vehemence of his sermons continually inflamed
 the angry and seditious temper of the people of Milan.","('Milan', 'GPE')"
"But while the guards were forcing him to the door, the dexterous polemic had time to execute his design, by exclaiming, with a loud voice, Theodosius immediately embraced the bishop of Iconium, and never forgot the important lesson which he received from this dramatic parable. (23)
Arianism of Constantinople, A.D. 340-380.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Iconium', 'PERSON'), ('23', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arianism of Constantinople', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('340-380', 'CARDINAL')"
"But, after Gratian more freely indulged
 his prevailing taste for hunting and shooting, he naturally
 connected himself with the most dexterous ministers of his
 favourite amusement.","('Gratian', 'PERSON')"
"By the influence of Justina, an edict of toleration was promulgated in all the provinces which were subject to the court of Milan; the free exercise of their religion was granted to those who professed the faith of Rimini; and the emperor declared that all persons who should infringe this sacred and salutary constitution should be capitally punished, as the enemies of the public peace. (65)","('Justina', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Rimini', 'PERSON')"
"Character and conduct of the emperor Gratian (A.D. 379-383)
 THE fame of Gratian, before he had accomplished the twentieth year of his age, was equal to that of the most celebrated princes.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('383', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('the twentieth year', 'DATE')"
"Character of Valentinian, A.D. 391.","('Valentinian', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 391', 'DATE')"
Clemency of Theodosius.,"('Clemency of Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Constantinople was the principal seat and fortress of
 Arianism; and, in a long interval of forty years,(24) the 
 faith of the princes and prelates who reigned in the capital
 of the East was rejected in the purer schools of Rome and
 Alexandria.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Arianism', 'NORP'), ('forty years', 'DATE'), ('24', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"Death of Gratian—Ruin of Arianism—St. Ambrose— First Civil War, against Maximus—","('Death of Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('St. Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Civil War', 'EVENT'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"Death of Theodosius, A.D. 395, January 17.","('Death of Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 395', 'DATE'), ('January 17', 'DATE')"
"Defeat and death of Maximus, A.D. 388, June-August.","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 388', 'DATE'), ('June-August', 'DATE')"
"Discontents of the Roman troops, A.D. 383.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 383', 'FAC')"
"During the partial reigns of Constantius and Valens, the feeble remnant of the Homoousians was deprived of the public and private exercise of their religion; and it has been observed, in pathetic language, that the scattered flock was left without a shepherd to wander on the mountains, or to be devoured by rapacious wolves.(26) But as their zeal, instead of being subdued, derived strength and vigour from oppression, they seized the first moments of imperfect freedom, which they acquired by the death of Valens, to form themselves into a regular congregation, under the conduct of an episcopal pastor.","('Constantius', 'EVENT'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Homoousians', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"During the season
 of sincere grief or ostentatious mourning the Eastern
 emperor was interrupted by the arrival of the principal
 chamberlain of Maximus, and the choice of a venerable old
 man for an office which was usually exercised by eunuchs
 announced to the court of Constantinople the gravity and
 temperance of the British usurper.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('British', 'NORP')"
"Edicts of Theodosius against the heretics, A.D. 380-394.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('380-394', 'CARDINAL')"
"Eutropius, one of the favourite eunuchs of the palace of Constantinople, embarked for Alexandria, from whence he sailed up the Nile
 as far as the city of Lycopolis, or of Wolves, in the remote province of Thebais. (112)","('Eutropius', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Lycopolis', 'GPE'), ('Wolves', 'LOC'), ('Thebais', 'GPE'), ('112', 'CARDINAL')"
"Even the Germans, so strong and formidable in the armies 
 of the empire, affected to disdain the strange and horrid
 appearance of the savages of the North, who, in the space of
 a few years, had wandered from the banks of the Volga to
 those of the Seine.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('a few years', 'DATE'), ('Volga', 'LOC'), ('Seine', 'LOC')"
"Even the principles of justice and the interest of
 society would receive a fatal blow from the impunity of
 Maximus, and the example of successful usurpation would tend
 to dissolve the artificial fabric of government, and once
 more to replunge the empire in the crimes and calamities of
 the preceding age.","('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"Every Roman might exercise the
 right of public accusation; but the office of Inquisitors of
 the Faith, a name so deservedly abhorred, was first
 instituted under the reign of Theodosius.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Inquisitors of\r\n the Faith', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Every rumour agitated the hopes and fears of the
 Antiochians, and they heard with terror that their
 sovereign, exasperated by the insult which had been offered
 to his own statues, and more especially to those of his
 beloved wife, had resolved to level with the ground the
 offending city, and to massacre, without distinction of age
 or sex, the criminal inhabitants, (86) many of whom were 
 actually driven, by their apprehensions, to seek a refuge in
 March 22.","('Antiochians', 'NORP'), ('86', 'CARDINAL'), ('March 22', 'DATE')"
"Execution of Priscillian and his associates, A.D. 385.","('Priscillian', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 385', 'DATE')"
Faults of Theodosius.,"('Theodosius', 'GPE')"
February 26.,"('February 26', 'DATE')"
"Five days of the week he spent in prayer and meditation, but on Saturdays and Sundays he regularly opened a small window, and gave audience to the crowd of suppliants who successively flowed from every part of the Christian world.","('Five days', 'DATE'), ('the week', 'DATE'), ('Saturdays', 'DATE'), ('Sundays', 'DATE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
Flight and death of Gratian.,"('Gratian', 'PERSON')"
Flight of Valentinian.,"('Flight of Valentinian', 'PRODUCT')"
"Flight was their only hope; Aquileia their only
 refuge: and, as Maximus now displayed his genuine character,
 the brother of Gratian might expect the same fate from the
 hands of the same assassin.","('Aquileia', 'PERSON'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON')"
From the cathedral of St. Sophia there issued a motley crowd,"('St. Sophia', 'GPE')"
"From the cathedral of St. Sophia there issued a motley crowd
 ""of common beggars, who had forfeited their claim to pity; of
 monks, who had the appearance of goats or satyrs; and of women, more terrible than so many Jezebels.""","('St. Sophia', 'GPE'), ('Jezebels', 'NORP')"
"From the liberality of Gratian he had received the
 Imperial diadem; his patience would encourage the odious
 suspicion that he was more deeply sensible of former
 injuries than of recent obligations; and if he accepted the
 friendship, he must seem to share the guilt, of the
 assassin.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"From the summit of the Julian Alps he descended with such
 incredible speed into the plain of Italy that he reached
 Aquileia on the evening of the first day; and Maximus, who
 found himself encompassed on all sides, had scarcely time to
 shut the gates of the city.","('the Julian Alps', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Aquileia', 'PERSON'), ('the first day', 'DATE'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"Generosity of Theodosius, A.D. 388-391.","('Generosity of Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 388-391', 'DATE')"
"Gratian admired
 the talents and customs of these favourite guards, to whom
 alone he intrusted the defence of his person; and, as if he
 meant to insult the public opinion, he frequently showed
 himself to the soldiers and people with the dress and arms,
 the long bow, the sounding quiver, and the fur garments of a
 Scythian warrior.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'NORP')"
"Gratian loved and revered him
 as a father; and the elaborate treatise on the faith of the
 Trinity was designed for the instruction of the young
 prince.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Trinity', 'PRODUCT')"
"Gratian survived those memorable events only four or five years, but he survived his reputation, and, before he fell a victim to rebellion, he had lost, in a great measure, the respect and confidence of the Roman world.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('four or five years', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Gratian was
 amused by protestations of doubtful fidelity, and the hopes
 of a support which could not be effectual, till the arrival
 of Andragathius, the general of the cavalry of Maximus, put
 an end to his suspense.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Andragathius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"Gratian, as he rose from supper, was delivered into the hands of the assassin, and his body was denied to the
 pious and pressing entreaties of his brother Valentinian.(14)","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'PERSON'), ('14', 'CARDINAL')"
"Gregory Nazianzen
 himself.","('Gregory Nazianzen', 'PERSON')"
"Gregory Nazianzen,(27) were distinguished above all their contemporaries(28) by the rare union of profane eloquence and of orthodox piety.","('Gregory Nazianzen', 'PERSON'), ('27', 'DATE'), ('28', 'CARDINAL')"
Gregory submitted with reluctance to this humiliating exile: he was ordained bishop of Sasima; but he solemnly protests that he never consummated his spiritual marriage with this disgusting bride.,"('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Sasima', 'PERSON')"
"He
 beheld the innumerable multitude, of either sex, and of
 every age, who crowded the streets, the windows, and the
 roofs of the houses; he heard the tumultuous voice of rage,
 grief, astonishment, and despair; and Gregory fairly
 confesses that on the memorable day of his installation the
 capital of the East wore the appearance of a city taken by
 storm, and in the hands of a barbarian conqueror.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('the memorable day', 'DATE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"He
 contrived to apprise the emperor of the East of his helpless
 situation, and he declared that, unless Theodosius could
 speedily march to his assistance, he must attempt to escape
 from the palace, or rather prison, of Vienne, in Gaul, where
 he had imprudently fixed his residence in the midst of the
 hostile faction.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Vienne', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'LOC')"
"He
 had reason to fear that a chosen body of troops, under the
 command of the intrepid Arbogastes, would direct their march
 along the banks of the Danube, and boldly penetrate through
 the Rhaetian provinces into the centre of Gaul.","('Arbogastes', 'PRODUCT'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Rhaetian', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'LOC')"
"He
 seated Valentinian on the throne of Milan. and, without
 stipulating any present or future advantages, restored him
 to the absolute dominion of all the provinces from which he
 had been driven by the arms of Maximus.","('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"He afterwards consented to undertake the government of his native church of Nazianzus,(31) of which his father had been bishop above five-and-forty years.","('Nazianzus', 'GPE'), ('31', 'CARDINAL'), ('five-and-forty years', 'DATE')"
"He bestowed the purple on the
 rhetorician Eugenius,(109) whom he had already raised from 
 the place of his domestic secretary to the rank of master of
 the offices.","('Eugenius', 'PERSON'), ('109', 'CARDINAL')"
"He boldly and wisely resolved to prevent
 the designs of Gratian; the youth of the island crowded to
 his standard, and he invaded Gaul with a fleet and army
 which were long afterwards remembered as the emigration of a
 considerable part of the British nation.","('Gratian', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('British', 'NORP')"
"He derived from
 the choice of Gratian his honourable title to the provinces
 of the East; he had acquired the West by the right of
 conquest; and the three years which he spent in Italy were
 usefully employed to restore the authority of the laws and
 to correct the abuses which had prevailed with impunity
 under the usurpation of Maximus and the minority of
 Valentinian.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('the three years', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"He descended from
 the hills, and beheld, with some astonishment, the
 formidable camp of the Gauls and Germans that covered with
 arms and tents the open country which extends to the walls
 of Aquileia and the banks of the Frigidus, (117) or Cold 
 River.(118)","('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Aquileia', 'GPE'), ('Frigidus', 'FAC'), ('117', 'CARDINAL'), ('Cold \r\n River', 'LOC'), ('118', 'CARDINAL')"
"He exercised,
 with equal firmness and dexterity, the powers of his
 spiritual and political characters; and perhaps contributed,
 by his authority and eloquence, to check the ambition of
 Maximus, and to protect the peace of Italy.(62)","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"He had lately bestowed on his eldest son Arcadius the name and honours of Augustus, and the two princes were seated on a stately throne to receive the homage of their subjects.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"He obeyed the summons
 with the respect of a faithful subject, but he was followed,
 without his consent, by an innumerable people: they pressed,
 with impetuous zeal, against the gates of the palace; and
 the affrighted ministers of Valentinian, instead of
 pronouncing a sentence of exile on the archbishop of Milan,
 humbly requested that he would interpose his authority to
 protect the person of the emperor, and to restore the
 tranquillity of the capital.","('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"He received Arbogastes on the throne, and, as the
 count approached with some appearance of respect, delivered
 to him a paper which dismissed him from all his employments.","('Arbogastes', 'PERSON')"
"He retired into
 the country to indulge his grief and to avoid the presence
 of Theodosius.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"He secretly invited the archbishop of
 Milan to undertake the office of a mediator, as the pledge
 of his sincerity and the guardian of his safety.","('Milan', 'GPE')"
"He was
 dragged from his throne, rudely stripped of the Imperial
 ornaments, the robe, the diadem, and the purple slippers;
 and conducted, like a malefactor, to the camp and presence
 of Theodosius, at a place about three miles from Aquileia.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('about three miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Aquileia', 'GPE')"
"He was descended from a noble family of Romans; 
 his father had exercised the important office of Praetorian
 praefect of Gaul; and the son, after passing through the
 studies of a liberal education, attained, in the regular
 gradation of civil honours, the station of consular of
 Liguria, a province which included the Imperial residence of
 Milan.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Liguria', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"He was one of the most pious and eloquent
 bishops of the age; a saint, and a doctor of the church; the
 scourge of Arianism, and the pillar of the orthodox faith; a
 distinguished member of the council of Constantinople, in
 which, after the death of Meletius, he exercised the
 functions of president: in a word—","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arianism', 'NORP'), ('the council of Constantinople', 'ORG'), ('Meletius', 'PERSON')"
"He was stopped in the porch by the
 archbishop, who, in the tone and language of an ambassador
 of Heaven, declared to his sovereign that private contrition
 was not sufficient to atone for a public fault or to appease
 the justice of the offended Deity.","('Deity', 'PERSON')"
"His
 disinterested opinion of past events was usefully applied as
 the rule of his own actions, and Theodosius has deserved the
 singular commendation that his virtues always seemed to
 expand with his fortune; the season of his prosperity was
 that of his moderation, and his clemency appeared the most
 conspicuous after the danger and success of the civil war.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"His
 growing zeal for the faith of Nice, and his filial reverence
 for the character and authority of Ambrose, disposed the
 catholics to entertain the most favourable opinion of the
 virtues of the young emperor of the West.(103)","('Nice', 'PERSON'), ('Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('103', 'CARDINAL')"
"His abilities and even his integrity are acknowledged by the partial writers of the age, and the merit must indeed have been conspicuous that could extort
 such a confession in favour of the vanquished enemy of Theodosius.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"His body was conducted with decent 
 pomp to the sepulchre of Milan, and the archbishop pronounced a funeral oration to commemorate his virtue and his misfortunes.(107)","('Milan', 'GPE'), ('107', 'CARDINAL')"
"His death, A.D. 392, May 15.","('A.D. 392', 'DATE'), ('May 15', 'DATE')"
"His death, only four months after his
 victory, was considered by the people as an unforeseen and
 fatal event, which destroyed in a moment the hopes of the
 rising generation.","('only four months', 'DATE'), ('a moment', 'TIME')"
"His familiar friends were judiciously selected from
 among those persons who, in the equal intercourse of private
 life, had appeared before his eyes without a mask; the
 consciousness of personal and superior merit enabled him to
 despise the accidental distinction of the purple, and he
 proved by his conduct that he had forgotten all the
 injuries, while he most gratefully remembered all the
 favours and services which he had received before he
 ascended the throne of the Roman empire.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"His gentle and amiable disposition endeared him to his private friends, the graceful affability of his manners engaged the affection of the people; the men of letters, who enjoyed the liberality, acknowledged the taste and eloquence, of their sovereign; his valour and dexterity in arms were equally applauded by the soldiers; and the clergy considered the humble piety of Gratian as the first and most useful of his virtues.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"His lieutenant Sapor was armed with the ample powers of a general law, a special commission, and a military force;(39) and this ecclesiastical revolution was conducted with so much discretion and vigour, that the religion of the emperor was established, without tumult or bloodshed, in all the provinces of the East.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('39', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"His preceptors gradually rose to the rank and consequence of ministers of state, (2) and, as they wisely dissembled their  secret authority, he seemed to act with firmness, with
 propriety, and with judgment on the most important occasions
 of his life and reign.","('2', 'CARDINAL')"
"His profound
 veneration for the Christian clergy was rewarded by the
 applause and gratitude of a powerful order, which has
 claimed in every age the privilege of dispensing honours,
 both on earth and in heaven.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"His real merit and apparent fidelity had gained the
 confidence both of the prince and people; his boundless
 liberality corrupted the allegiance of the troops; and,
 whilst he was universally esteemed as the pillar of the
 state, the bold and crafty barbarian was secretly determined
 either to rule or to ruin the empire of the West.","('West', 'LOC')"
"His succesful opposition to the empress Justina, A.D. 385, April 3-10.","('Justina', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 385', 'DATE'), ('April 3-10', 'DATE')"
"His victory
 was decisive, and the deaths of his two rivals were
 distinguished only by the difference of their characters.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"His victory over Eugenius, A.D. 394, September 6.","('Eugenius', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 394', 'DATE'), ('September 6', 'DATE')"
"Honorius supplied, during the rest of the day, the
 place of his father; and the great Theodosius expired in the
 ensuing night.","('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"If Constantine had the
 advantage of erecting the standard of the cross, the
 emulation of his successor assumed the merit of subduing the
 Arian heresy, and of abolishing the worship of idols in the
 Roman world.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"If Theodosius had
 consulted the rigid maxims of interest and policy, his
 conduct would have been justified by his friends, but the
 generosity of his behaviour on this memorable occasion has
 extorted the applause of his most inveterate enemies.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"If any credit could be allowed to confessions extorted by fear or pain, and to vague reports, the offspring of malice and credulity, the heresy of the Priscillianists would be found to include the various abominations of magic, of impiety, and of lewdness. (56)  Priscillian, who wandered about the world in the company of his spiritual sisters, was accused of praying stark-naked in the midst of the congregation; and it was confidently asserted, that the effects of his criminal intercourse with the daughter of Euchrocia had been suppressed by means still more odious and criminal.","('Priscillianists', 'NORP'), ('Priscillian', 'PERSON'), ('Euchrocia', 'PERSON')"
"If it
 can be affirmed, with any degree of truth, that the luxury
 of the Romans was more shameless and dissolute in the reign
 of Theodosius than in the age of Constantine, perhaps, or of
 Augustus, the alteration cannot be ascribed to any
 beneficial improvements which had gradually increased the
 stock of national riches.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"If the mind of Gregory was susceptible of pride, he
 must have felt a very lively satisfaction when the emperor
 conducted him through the streets in solemn triumph, and,
 with his own hand, respectfully placed him on the
 archiepiscopal throne of Constantinople.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"If you desire a man to change a piece of silver, he informs you wherein the Son differs from the Father; if you ask the price of a loaf, you are told, by way of reply, that the Son is inferior to the Father; and if you inquire whether the bath is ready, the answer is, that the Son was
 made out of nothing."" (25)","('25', 'CARDINAL')"
"Immediately under the pavement of the church two perfect skeletons were found,(68) with the heads separated from their bodies, and a plentiful effusion of blood.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('68', 'CARDINAL')"
"In such a cause he was prepared to suffer whatever the malice of the daeman could inflict; and he only wished to die in the presence of his faithful flock, and at the foot of the altar; 'he' had not contributed to excite, but it was in the power of God alone to appease, the rage of the people: he deprecated the scenes of blood and confusion which were likely to ensue; and it was his fervent prayer that he might not survive to behold the ruin of a flourishing city, and perhaps the desolation of all Italy."" (64)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('64', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the
 meanwhile Theodosius himself advanced, at the head of a
 brave and disciplined army, to encounter his unworthy rival,
 who, after the siege of Aemona, had fixed his camp in the
 neighbourhood of Siscia, a city of Pannonia, strongly
 fortified by the broad and rapid stream of the Save.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Aemona', 'GPE'), ('Siscia', 'GPE'), ('Pannonia', 'GPE')"
"In the course both of his private and public
 service the count had always approved the attachment and
 abilities of Eugenius, his learning and eloquence, supported
 by the gravity of his manners, recommended him to the esteem
 of the people, and the reluctance with which he seemed to
 ascend the throne may inspire a favourable prejudice of his
 virtue and moderation.","('Eugenius', 'PERSON')"
"In the faithful picture of the virtues of Theodosius, his
 imperfections have not been dissembled; the act of cruelty,
 and the habits of indolence, which tarnished the glory of
 one of the greatest of the Roman princes.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the heat of the
 battle a violent tempest, (120) such as is often felt among 
 the Alps, suddenly arose from the East.","('120', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"In the neighbourhood of that city, and on the summit of a lofty mountain, the holy John(113) had constructed with his own hands an humble cell, in which he had dwelt above fifty years, without opening his door, without seeing the face of a woman, and without tasting any food that had been prepared by fire or any human art.","('John', 'PERSON'), ('113', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifty years', 'DATE')"
"In the space of fifteen years he promulgated at
 least fifteen severe edicts against the heretics,(48) more 
 especially against those who rejected the doctrine of the
 Trinity; and to deprive them of every hope of escape, he
 sternly enacted that, if any laws or rescripts should be
 alleged in their favour, the judges should consider them as
 the illegal productions either of fraud or forgery.","('the space of fifteen years', 'DATE'), ('at\r\n least fifteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('48', 'CARDINAL'), ('Trinity', 'ORG')"
"In this extremity, Justina and her
 son might accuse their own imprudence and the perfidious
 arts of Maximus; but they wanted time, and force, and
 resolution to stand against the Gauls and Germans, either in
 the field or within the walls of a large and disaffected
 city.","('Justina', 'PERSON'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"In this moment of anxious doubt, while
 the fate of the Roman world depended on the resolution of a
 single man, the charms of the princess Galla most powerfully
 pleaded the cause of her brother Valentinian.(75)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Galla', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'PERSON'), ('75', 'CARDINAL')"
In this spiritual cure Ambrose employed the various methods of mildness and severity.,"('Ambrose', 'PERSON')"
"Influence and conduct of Ambrose, A.D. 388.","('Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('388', 'CARDINAL')"
"Instead of inviting his royal guests to the palace of
 Constantinople, Theodosius had some unknown reasons to fix
 their residence at Thessalonica; but these reasons did not
 proceed from contempt or indifference, as he speedily made a
 visit to that city, accompanied by the greatest part of his
 court and senate.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Thessalonica', 'GPE')"
It is not very important to inquire from what causes the revolt of Britain was produced.,"('Britain', 'GPE')"
"It is the just and important observation of
 Vegetius, that the infantry was invariably covered with
 defensive armour from the foundation of the city to the
 reign of the emperor Gratian.","('Vegetius', 'PRODUCT'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON')"
"It is with pleasure that we can observe the humane inconsistency of the most illustrious saints and bishops, Ambrose of Milan (57) and Martin of Tours,(58) who, on this 
 occasion, asserted the cause of toleration.","('Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('57', 'DATE'), ('Martin', 'PERSON'), ('58', 'DATE')"
"It was not enough that Theodosius had suppressed the
 insolent reign of Arianism, or that he had abundantly
 revenged the injuries which the catholics sustained from the
 zeal of Constantius and Valens.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Arianism', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"It was sufficient that the emperor of the Romans, stripped of the ensigns of royalty, should appear in a mournful and suppliant posture; and that, in the midst of the church of Milan, he should humbly solicit, with sighs and tears, the pardon of his sins.(98)","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"Justina was
 persuaded that a Roman emperor might claim, in his own
 dominions, the public exercise of his religion; and she
 proposed to the archbishop, as a moderate and reasonable
 concession, that he should resign the use of a single
 church, either in the city or suburbs of Milan.","('Justina', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"Large parks were enclosed for the
 Imperial pleasures, and plentifully stocked with every
 species of wild beasts, and Gratian neglected the duties and
 even the dignity of his rank to consume whole days in the
 vain display of his dexterity and boldness in the chase.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON')"
"Many of the same prelates who
 now applauded the orthodox piety of Theodosius had
 repeatedly changed, with prudent flexibility, their creeds
 and opinions; and in the various revolutions of the church
 and state, the religion of their sovereign was the rule of
 their obsequious faith.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Marcellinus, the tyrant's
 brother, advanced to support them with the select cohorts,
 which were considered as the hope and strength of the army.","('Marcellinus', 'PERSON')"
"Maximus entered Milan in
 triumph; and if the wise archbishop refused a dangerous and
 criminal connection with the usurper, he might indirectly
 contribute to the success of his arms by inculcating from
 the pulpit the duty of resignation rather than that of
 resistance.(74)","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"Maximus invades Italy, A.D. 387, August.","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 387', 'DATE'), ('August', 'DATE')"
"Neither oaths nor treaties could restrain
 the boundless ambition of Maximus; and the delay of vigorous
 and decisive measures, instead of prolonging the blessings
 of peace, would expose the Eastern empire to the danger of
 an hostile invasion.","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"Notwithstanding
 these specious and solid reasons, which were approved by a
 majority of the council, Theodosius still hesitated whether
 he should draw the sword in a contest which could no longer
 admit any terms of reconciliation; and his magnanimous
 character was not disgraced by the apprehensions which he
 felt for the safety of his infant sons, and the welfare of
 his exhausted people.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"On his arrival in the capital, Gregory was entertained in the house of a pious and charitable kinsman; the most spacious room was consecrated to the uses of religious worship; and the name of Anastasia was chosen to express the resurrection of the Nicene faith.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Anastasia', 'PERSON'), ('Nicene', 'NORP')"
"On the death of his master he joined the
 standard of Theodosius, contributed, by his valour and
 military conduct, to the destruction of the tyrant, and was
 appointed, after the victory, master-general of the armies
 of Gaul.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"On this occasion the humanity of Ambrose tempted him to make a singular breach in his theological system, and to comfort the weeping sisters of Valentinian by the firm assurance that their pious brother, though he had not received the sacrament of baptism, was introduced, without difficulty, into the mansions of eternal bliss.(108)
Usurpation of Eugenius, A.D. 392-394.","('Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('108', 'CARDINAL'), ('392-394', 'CARDINAL')"
"Once indeed he expressed a faint inclination to converse with the eloquent and learned Eunomius, who lived in retirement at a small distance from Constantinople.","('Eunomius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Pennance of Theodosius, A.D. 390.","('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 390', 'DATE')"
"Posterity has applauded the virtuous firmness of the archbishop: and the example of Theodosius may prove the beneficial influence of those principles which could force a monarch, exalted above the apprehension of human punishment, to respect the laws and ministers of an invisible Judge.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Retreat of Gregory Nazianzen, A.D. 381.","('Gregory Nazianzen', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 381', 'DATE')"
"Ruin of Arianism at Constantinople, A.D. 380, November 26.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 380', 'DATE'), ('November 26', 'DATE')"
"Satisfied with the glory which he had acquired by 
 revenging the death of his benefactor and delivering the
 West from the yoke of tyranny, the emperor returned from
 Milan to Constantinople, and, in the peaceful possession of
 the East, insensibly relapsed into his former habits of
 luxury and indolence.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"Second Civil War, against Eugenius—Death of Theodosius","('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Civil War', 'EVENT'), ('Eugenius—Death of Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Sedition and massacre of Thessalonica, A.D. 390.","('Thessalonica', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 390', 'DATE')"
"Since the death of Priscillian, the rude attempts
 of persecution have been refined and methodised in the holy
 office, which assigns their distinct parts to the
 ecclesiastical and secular powers.","('Priscillian', 'NORP')"
"Ten
 thousand of those auxiliaries, and Bacurius, general of the
 Iberians, died bravely on the field of battle.","('Ten\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bacurius', 'PERSON'), ('Iberians', 'NORP')"
"That great city, the metropolis of all the
 Illyrian provinces, had been protected from the dangers of
 the Gothic war by strong fortifications and a numerous
 garrison.","('Illyrian', 'NORP'), ('the Gothic war', 'EVENT')"
"That proud capital
 was degraded from the rank of a city; and the metropolis of
 the East, stripped of its lands, its privileges, and its
 revenues, was subjected, under the humiliating denomination
 of a village, to the jurisdiction of Laodicea.(87)","('East', 'LOC'), ('Laodicea', 'ORG'), ('87', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 Arian subjects of Theodosius deplored the loss of their
 churches; and, as three rival bishops disputed the throne of
 Antioch, the sentence which decided their pretensions
 excited the murmurs of the two unsuccessful congregations.","('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 characters of Eve, of the wife of Job, of Jezebel, of
 Herodias, were indecently applied to the mother of the
 emperor; and her desire to obtain a church for the Arians
 was compared to the most cruel persecutions which
 Christianity had endured under the reign of Paganism.","('Eve', 'PERSON'), ('Job', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Jezebel', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Herodias', 'GPE'), ('Arians', 'NORP'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Paganism', 'NORP')"
"The
 guilt of the Manichaean heresy was esteemed of such
 magnitude that it could be expiated only by the death of the
 offender; and the same capital punishment was inflicted on
 the Audians, or Quartodecimans, (49) who should dare to perpetrate the atrocious crime of celebrating on an improper
 day the festival of Easter.","('Manichaean', 'NORP'), ('Audians', 'PERSON'), ('Quartodecimans', 'PERSON'), ('49', 'CARDINAL'), ('an improper\r\n day', 'DATE'), ('Easter', 'DATE')"
"The
 important commands of the army were distributed among the
 Franks; the creatures of Arbogastes were promoted to all the
 honours and offices of the civil government; the progress of
 the conspiracy removed every faithful servant from the
 presence of Valentinian; and the emperor, without power and
 without intelligence, insensibly sunk into the precarious
 and dependent condition of a captive.(105)","('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Arbogastes', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('105', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 pride and wish of the Roman emperor to excel in an art in
 which he might be surpassed by the meanest of his slaves
 reminded the numerous spectators of the examples of Nero and
 Commodus; but the chaste and temperate Gratian was a
 stranger to their monstrous vices, and his hands were
 stained only with the blood of animals.(6)
Discontents of the Roman troops, A.D. 383.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Commodus', 'PERSON'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('383', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 privileges of Christianity, temporal as well as spiritual,
 were confined to the true believers; and the mind of Ambrose
 was satisfied that his own theological opinions were the
 standard of truth and orthodoxy.","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Ambrose', 'PERSON')"
"The
 recantation of Theodosius was sincere; (95) and, during the 
 term of his residence at Milan, his affection for Ambrose
 was continually increased by the habits of pious and
 familiar conversation.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('95', 'CARDINAL'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Ambrose', 'PERSON')"
"The
 rigorous prohibition of conventicles was carefully extended
 to every possible circumstance in which the heretics could
 assemble with the intention of worshipping God and Christ
 according to the dictates of their conscience.","('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"The
 tribunal of Hellebicus and Caesarius, encompassed with armed
 soldiers, was erected in the midst of the Forum.","('Hellebicus', 'GPE'), ('Caesarius', 'GPE'), ('Forum', 'ORG')"
"The
 troops whose station more immediately attached them to the
 service of the palace abandoned the standard of Gratian the
 first time that it was displayed in the neighbourhood of
 Paris.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Paris', 'GPE')"
"The
 unfeeling critic, who consider every amorous weakness as an
 indelible stain on the memory of a great and orthodox
 emperor, are inclined on this occasion to dispute the
 suspicious evidence of the historian Zosimus.","('Zosimus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 virtuous mind of Theodosius was often relaxed by indolence,
 (82) and it was sometimes inflamed by passion.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The 
 pernicious attachment to the Arian sect which Valentinian
 had imbibed from her example and instructions was soon
 erased by the lessons of a more orthodox education.","('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"The 
 strength of Theodosius was unable to support the sudden and
 violent transition from the palace to the camp; and the
 increasing symptoms of a dropsy announced the speedy
 dissolution of the emperor.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The Arian ecclesiastics who
 ventured to show themselves in the streets were exposed to
 the most imminent danger of their lives; and Ambrose enjoyed
 the merit and reputation of rescuing his personal enemies
 from the hands of the enraged multitude","('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Ambrose', 'PERSON')"
"The Arians might complain, with some appearance of justice, that an
 inconsiderable congregation of sectaries should usurp the
 hundred churches which they were insufficient to fill,
 whilst the far greater part of the people was cruelly
 excluded from every place of religious worship.","('Arians', 'PERSON'), ('hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Arians, who were provoked by the boldness of his enterprise, represented his doctrine as if he had preached three distinct and equal Deities; and the devout populace was excited to suppress, by violence and tumult, the irregular assemblies of the Athanasian heretics.","('Arians', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Athanasian', 'NORP')"
"The Huns, the Alani, and, after their
 example, the Goths themselves, were formed into squadrons of
 archers, who fought on horseback, and confounded the steady
 valour of the Gauls and Germans by the rapid motions of a
 Tartar war.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Alani', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('a\r\n Tartar war', 'EVENT')"
"The Iberian,
 the Arab, and the Goth, who gazed on each other with mutual
 astonishment, were enlisted in the service of the same
 prince; and the renowned Alaric acquired, in the school of
 Theodosius, the knowledge of the art of war which he
 afterwards so fatally exerted for the destruction of Rome.
 (115)","('Iberian', 'NORP'), ('Arab', 'NORP'), ('Goth', 'NORP'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('115', 'CARDINAL')"
The Infantry lay aside their armour.,"('Infantry', 'ORG')"
"The Moorish guards of the tyrant had been massacred in the
 first heat of the victory, and a small number of the most
 obnoxious criminals suffered the punishment of the law.","('Moorish', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The Romans were
 terrified by the impending dangers of a feeble and divided
 administration; and every disgraceful moment of the
 unfortunate reigns of Arcadius and Honorius revived the
 memory of their irreparable loss.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('Honorius', 'PERSON')"
"The action, which had been interrupted by the approach of
 night, was renewed in the morning; and, after a sharp
 conflict, the surviving remnant of the bravest soldiers of
 Maximus threw down their arms at the feet of the conqueror.","('night', 'TIME'), ('the morning', 'TIME'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"The alliance of the Persian king was secured by the
 faith of treaties; the martial barbarians were persuaded to
 follow the standard or to respect the frontiers of an active
 and liberal monarch; and the dominions of Theodosius, from
 the Euphrates to the Hadriatic, resounded with the
 preparations of war both by land and sea.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Hadriatic', 'NORP')"
"The ambassador
 condescended to justify or excuse the conduct of his master,
 and to protest, in specious language, that the murder of
 Gratian had been perpetrated, without his knowledge or
 consent, by the precipitate zeal of the soldiers.","('Gratian', 'PERSON')"
"The ambassadors of the new emperor
 were immediately despatched to the court of Theodosius, to
 communicate, with affected grief, the unfortunate accident
 of the death of Valentinian, and, without mentioning the
 name of Arbogastes, to request that the monarch of the East
 would embrace as his lawful colleague the respectable
 citizen who had obtained the unanimous suffrage of the
 armies and provinces of the West.(110)","('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Arbogastes', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('110', 'CARDINAL')"
"The annals of Rome, in the long period of
 eleven hundred years, presented him with a various and
 splendid picture of human life; and it has been particularly
 observed that, whenever he perused the cruel acts of Cinna,
 of Marius, or of Sylla, he warmly expressed his generous
 detestation of those enemies of humanity and freedom.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('eleven hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Cinna', 'PERSON'), ('Marius', 'PERSON'), ('Sylla', 'PERSON')"
"The apology of the assassins, that they
 were obliged to produce the prescribed number of heads,
 serves only to increase, by an appearance of order and
 design, the horrors of the massacre, which was executed by
 the commands of Theodosius.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The archbishop, who refused
 to hold any conference or negotiation with the instruments
 of Satan, declared, with modest firmness, his resolution to
 die a martyr rather than to yield to the impious sacrilege;
 and Justina, who resented the refusal as an act of insolence
 and rebellion, hastily determined to exert the Imperial
 prerogative of her son.","('Satan', 'PERSON'), ('Justina', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The archiepiscopal throne of Macedonius, which
 had been polluted with so much Christian blood, was
 successively filled by Eudoxus and Damophilus.","('Macedonius', 'PRODUCT'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Eudoxus', 'PERSON'), ('Damophilus', 'NORP')"
"The armies of Gaul,
 instead of opposing the march of Maximus.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"The army of
 Theodosius was sheltered by their position from the
 impetuosity of the wind, which blew a cloud of dust in the
 faces of the enemy, disordered their ranks, wrested their
 weapons from their hands, and diverted or repelled their
 ineffectual javelins.","('Theodosius', 'GPE')"
"The arrival of Honorius at Milan was welcomed by a
 splendid exhibition of the games of the circus; and the
 emperor, though he was oppressed by the weight of his
 disorder, contributed by his presence to the public joy.","('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"The assassin of
 Gratian had usurped, but he actually possessed, the most
 warlike provinces of the empire; the East was exhausted by
 the misfortunes, and even by the success, of the Gothic war;
 and it was seriously to be apprehended that, after the vital
 strength of the republic had been wasted in a doubtful and
 destructive contest, the feeble conqueror would remain an
 easy prey to the barbarians of the north.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('the Gothic war', 'EVENT')"
"The auspicious period
 now approached of the tenth year of his reign; a festival
 more grateful to the soldiers, who received a liberal
 donative, than to the subjects, whose voluntary offerings
 had been long since converted into an extraordinary and
 oppressive burden.","('the tenth year', 'DATE')"
"The barbarians who had passed the
 Danube had lately assumed the character of soldiers and
 subjects, but their native fierceness was yet untamed; and
 the operations of a war, which would exercise their valour
 and diminish their numbers, might tend to relieve the
 provinces from an intolerable oppression.","('Danube', 'LOC')"
"The baths, 
 the circus, and the theatres were shut and, that every
 source of plenty and pleasure might at the same time be
 intercepted, the distribution of corn was abolished by the
 severe instructions of Theodosius.","('Theodosius', 'GPE')"
"The behaviour of Gratian, which degraded his character in
 the eyes of mankind, could not have disturbed the security
 of his reign if the army had not been provoked to resent
 their peculiar injuries.","('Gratian', 'PERSON')"
"The behaviour of the emperor was not intended to insult, and
 he showed some disposition to pity and forgive the tyrant of
 the West, who had never been his personal enemy, and was now
 become the object of his contempt.","('West', 'LOC')"
"The bishops of
 Tours and Milan pronounced, without hesitation, the eternal
 damnation of heretics; but they were surprised and shocked
 by the bloody image of their temporal death, and the honest
 feelings of nature resisted the artificial prejudices of
 theology.","('Tours', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"The bishops of the East, his strenuous adherents, provoked
 by his moderation in the affairs of Antioch, abandoned him,
 without support, to the adverse faction of the Egyptians,
 who disputed the validity of his election and rigorously
 asserted the obsolete canon that prohibited the licentious
 practice of episcopal translations.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Egyptians', 'NORP')"
"The brother of
 Gratian was confirmed and secured in the sovereignty of
 Italy, Africa, and the Western Illyricum, and some
 honourable conditions were inserted in the treaty to protect
 the memory and the laws of the deceased emperor. (17)","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('the Western Illyricum', 'LOC'), ('17', 'CARDINAL')"
"The catholics of Constantinople were animated with joyful
 confidence by the baptism and edict of Theodosius; and they
 impatiently waited the effects of his gracious promise.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The cause
 of the Priscillianists, (51) a recent sect of heretics who 
 disturbed the provinces of Spain, was transferred, by
 appeal, from the synod of Bordeaux to the Imperial
 consistory of Treves; and by the sentence of the Praetorian
 praefect, seven persons were tortured, condemned, and
 executed.","('Priscillianists', 'NORP'), ('51', 'CARDINAL'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Bordeaux', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Treves', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'PERSON'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
The cause of humanity and that of persecution have been asserted by the same Ambrose with equal energy and with equal success.,"('Ambrose', 'PERSON')"
"The cavalry of the
 Goths, the Huns, and the Alani, had felt the benefits and
 adopted the use of defensive armour; and, as they excelled
 in the management of missile weapons, they easily
 overwhelmed the naked and trembling legions, whose heads and
 breasts were exposed, without defence, to the arrows of the
 barbarians.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Alani', 'NORP')"
"The character and language of the archbishop of Milan may justify the suspicion that his conduct soon afforded a reasonable ground, or at least a specious pretence, to the Arian ministers, who watched the opportunity of surprising him in some act of disobedience to a law which he strangely represents as a law of blood and tyranny.","('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Arian', 'NORP')"
"The clergy and people of Milan were attached to
 their archbishop, and he deserved the esteem, without
 soliciting the favour, or apprehending the displeasure, of
 his feeble sovereigns.","('Milan', 'GPE')"
"The conquest of Italy was the object of
 his hopes and preparations; and he secretly meditated the
 ruin of an innocent youth, whose government was abhorred and
 despised by his catholic subjects.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The conscience of the credulous prince was directed by saints and bishops,(4) who procured an Imperial edict to punish, as a capital offence, the
 violation, the neglect, or even the ignorance of the divine
 law.","('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"The contempt of Gratian for the Roman soldiers had exposed
 him to the fatal effects of their resentment.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The council of Constantinople, A.D. 381, May.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 381', 'DATE'), ('May', 'DATE')"
"The cruelty of Ithacius,(59) who 
 beheld the tortures, and solicited the death of the
 heretics, provoked the just indignation of mankind; and the
 vices of that profligate bishop were admitted as a proof
 that his zeal was instigated by the sordid motives of
 interest.","('Ithacius', 'PERSON'), ('59', 'DATE')"
"The dawn of day
 discovered to the eyes of Theodosius the extent and the
 extremity of his danger, but his apprehensions were soon
 dispelled by a friendly message from the leaders of those
 troops, who expressed their inclination to desert the
 standard of the tyrant.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The death of Meletius, which happened at the
 council of Constantinople, presented the most favourable
 opportunity of terminating the schism of Antioch, by
 suffering his aged rival, Paulinus, peaceably to end his
 days in the episcopal chair.","('Meletius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Paulinus', 'PERSON')"
"The death of the emperor was followed by that of his
 powerful general Mellobaudes, the king of the Franks, who
 maintained to the last moment of his life the ambiguous
 reputation which is the just recompense of obscure and
 subtle policy.","('Mellobaudes', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"The decrees of the council of
 Constantinople had ascertained the true standard of the
 faith; and the ecclesiastics who governed the conscience of
 Theodosius suggested the most effectual methods of
 persecution.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The disciple of Athanasius exulted in the proud confidence that he had entitled himself to the divine favour, while the follower of Arius must have been tormented by the secret apprehension that he was guilty perhaps of an unpardonable offence by the scanty praise and parsimonious honours which he bestowed on the Judge of the World.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Arius', 'PERSON'), ('the Judge of the World', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"The discontent of Maximus might incline him to censure the conduct of his sovereign, and to encourage, perhaps without any views of ambition, the murmurs of the troops.","('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"The doors of the Anastasia were broke open; much mischief was perpetrated, or attempted, with sticks, stones, and firebrands; and as a man lost his life in the affray, Gregory, who was summoned the next morning before the magistrate, had the satisfaction of supposing that he publicly confessed the name of Christ.","('Anastasia', 'FAC'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('the next morning', 'TIME'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"The edicts of taxation interrupted the
 repose and pleasures of Antioch; and the tribunal of the
 magistrate was besieged by a suppliant crowd, who, in
 pathetic, but at first in respectful language, solicited the
 redress of their grievances.","('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"The effeminate luxury, which infected the manners of courts
 and cities, had instilled a secret and destructive poison
 into the camps of the legions; and their degeneracy has been
 marked by the pen of a military writer, who had accurately
 studied the genuine and ancient principles of Roman
 discipline.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The emperor of the West fled towards Lyons with a
 train of only three hundred horse, and in the cities along
 the road, where he hoped to find a refuge, or at least a
 passage, he was taught by cruel experience that every gate
 is shut against the unfortunate.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Lyons', 'GPE'), ('only three hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The emperor of the West, or, to speak more properly, his
 general Arbogastes, was instructed by the misconduct and
 misfortune of Maximus how dangerous it might prove to extend
 the line of defence against a skilful antagonist, who was
 free to press or to suspend, to contract or to multiply, his
 various methods of attack.(116) Arbogastes fixed his station 
 on the confines of Italy; the troops of Theodosius were
 permitted to occupy, without resistance, the provinces of
 Pannonia, as far as the foot of the Julian Alps; and even
 the passes of the mountains were negligently, or perhaps
 artfully, abandoned to the bold invader.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Arbogastes', 'PERSON'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Arbogastes', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('Pannonia', 'GPE'), ('the Julian Alps', 'LOC')"
"The emperor retired to the adjacent hills,
 where he passed a disconsolate night, without sleep, without
 provisions, and without hopes, (119) except that strong 
 assurance which, under the most desperate circumstances, the
 independent mind may derive from the contempt of fortune and
 of life.","('night', 'TIME'), ('119', 'CARDINAL')"
"The emperor was deeply
 affected by his own reproaches and by those of his spiritual
 father; and after he had bewailed the mischievous and
 irreparable consequences of his rash fury, he proceeded in
 the accustomed manner to perform his devotions in the great
 church of Milan.","('Milan', 'GPE')"
"The emperor, or the rebel, for his title was not yet ascertained by fortune, was a native of Spain, the countryman, the fellow-soldier, and the rival of Theodosius, whose elevation he had not seen without some emotions of envy and resentment; the events of his life had long since fixed him in Britain, and I should not be unwilling to find some evidence; for the marriage which he is said to have contracted with the daughter of a wealthy lord of Caernarvonshire.(10) But this provincial rank might justly be considered as a state of exile and obscurity, and, if Maximus had obtained any civil or military office, he was not invested with the authority either of governor or general.","('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Caernarvonshire', 'PERSON'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"The empress Justina did not long survive her return to Italy
 and, though she beheld the triumph of Theodosius, she was
 not allowed to influence the government of her son.(102)","('Justina', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('102', 'CARDINAL')"
"The enervated soldiers abandoned
 their own and the public defence; and their pusillanimous
 indolence may be considered as the immediate cause of the
 downfall of the empire.(125)","('125', 'CARDINAL')"
"The episcopal vigour of Ambrose was tempered by
 prudence; and he contented himself with signifying(96) an 
 indirect sort of excommunication, by the assurance that he
 had been warned in a vision not to offer the oblation in the
 name or in the presence of Theodosius, and by the advice
 that he would confine himself to the use of prayer, without
 presuming to approach the altar of Christ, or to receive the
 holy eucharist with those hands that were still polluted
 with the blood of an innocent people.","('Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('96', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"The eunuch of Theodosius approached the window with respectful steps, proposed his questions concerning the event of the civil war, and soon returned with a favourable
 oracle, which animated the courage of the emperor by the assurance of a bloody but infallible victory.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('the civil war', 'EVENT')"
"The events of this revolution had passed in such rapid
 succession that it would have been impossible for Theodosius
 to march to the relief of his benefactor before he received
 the intelligence of his defeat and death.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The exigencies of the Gothic war, and the inevitable expense
 that accompanied the conclusion of the peace, had
 constrained the emperor to aggravate the weight of the
 public impositions; and the provinces of Asia, as they had
 not been involved in the distress, were the less inclined to
 contribute to the relief of Europe.","('the Gothic war', 'EVENT'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"The experience of his
 past conduct encouraged the most pleasing expectations of
 his future reign; and the age of the emperor, which did not
 exceed fifty years, seemed to extend the prospect of the
 public felicity.","('fifty years', 'DATE')"
"The extraordinary cure of a blind man,(69) and the  reluctant confessions of several daemoniacs, appeared to justify the faith and sanctity of Ambrose; and the truth of those miracles is attested by Ambrose himself, by his secretary Paulinus, and by his proselyte, the celebrated Augustin, who, at that time, professed the art of rhetoric in Milan.","('69', 'DATE'), ('Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('Paulinus', 'PERSON'), ('Augustin', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"The faith and virtues of
 Paulinus were unblemished.","('Paulinus', 'PERSON')"
"The faith of a soldier is commonly the fruit of instruction, rather than of inquiry; but as the emperor always fixed his eyes on the visible landmarks of orthodoxy which he had so prudently constituted, his religious opinions were never affected by the specious texts, the subtle arguments, and the ambiguous creeds of the Arian doctors.","('Arian', 'NORP')"
"The fate of the empire was determined in a narrow
 corner of Italy; and the legitimate successor of the house
 of Valentinian embraced the archbishop of Milan, and
 graciously received the submission of the provinces of the
 West.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"The fiery and choleric temper of Theodosius was
 impatient of the dilatory forms of a judicial inquiry; and
 he hastily resolved that the blood of his lieutenant should
 be expiated by the blood of the guilty people.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The first of these was Priscillians(52) himself, 
 bishop of Avila, (53) in Spain, who adorned the advantages of birth and fortune by the accomplishments of eloquence and learning.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Priscillians', 'PERSON'), ('52', 'CARDINAL'), ('Avila', 'PERSON'), ('53', 'DATE'), ('Spain', 'GPE')"
"The frequent examples of ruin
 and desolation tempted them not to spare the remains of a
 patrimony which might, every hour, become the prey of the
 rapacious Goth.","('every hour', 'TIME'), ('Goth', 'NORP')"
"The friends and ministers of Theodosius
 imitated the example of their sovereign; and he observed,
 with more surprise than displeasure, that all his secret
 counsels were immediately communicated to the archbishop,
 who acted from the laudable persuasion that every measure of
 civil government may have some connection with the glory of
 God and the interest of the true religion.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The government of Italy, and of the young emperor, naturally
 devolved to his mother Justina, a woman of beauty and
 spirits but who, in the midst of an orthodox people, had the
 misfortune of professing the Arian heresy, which she
 endeavoured to instil into the mind of her son.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Justina', 'PERSON'), ('Arian', 'NORP')"
"The guilt of the emperor is
 aggravated by his long and frequent residence at
 Thessalonica.","('Thessalonica', 'GPE')"
"The harsh and ungenerous treatment which he
 experienced,(45) instead of derogating from the truth of his 
 evidence, affords an additional proof of the spirit which
 actuated the deliberations of the synod.","('45', 'DATE')"
"The heart 
 of Theodosius was softened by the tears of beauty; his
 affections were insensibly engaged by the graces of youth
 and innocence; the art of Justina managed and directed the
 impulse of passion; and the celebration of the royal
 nuptials was the assurance and signal of the civil war.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Justina', 'PERSON')"
"The heretical teachers, who
 usurped the sacred titles of Bishops or Presbyters, were not
 only excluded from the privileges and emoluments so
 liberally granted to the orthodox clergy, but they were
 exposed to the heavy penalties of exile and confiscation, if
 they presumed to preach the doctrine, or to practise the
 rites, of their accursed sects.","('Bishops', 'ORG'), ('Presbyters', 'PERSON')"
"The heretics, of various denominations, subsisted in peace under the protection of the Arians of Constantinople, who endeavoured to secure the attachment of those obscure sectaries, while they abused, with unrelenting severity, the victory which they had obtained over the followers of the council of Nice.","('the Arians of Constantinople', 'ORG'), ('Nice', 'GPE')"
"The holy relics were presented, in solemn pomp, to the veneration of the people; and every circumstance of this fortunate discovery was admirably adapted to promote the designs of Ambrose.","('Ambrose', 'PERSON')"
"The hope that truth and wisdom would be found in the
 assemblies of the orthodox clergy induced the emperor to
 convene, at Constantinople, a synod of one hundred and fifty
 bishops, who proceeded, without much difficulty or delay, to
 complete the theological system which had been established
 in the council of Nice.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('one hundred and fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nice', 'GPE')"
"The houses of the criminals were exposed to
 sale, their wives and children were suddenly reduced from
 affluence and luxury to the most abject distress, and a
 bloody execution was expected to conclude the horrors of a
 day (88) which the preacher of Antioch, the eloquent 
 Chrysostom, has represented as a lively image of the last
 and universal judgment of the world.","('a\r\n day (88', 'DATE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Chrysostom', 'PERSON')"
"The humanity of Ambrose and Martin was confirmed
 by the scandalous irregularity of the proceedings against
 Priscillian and his adherents.","('Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('Martin', 'PERSON'), ('Priscillian', 'PERSON')"
"The indignant monarch snatched at the sword of one of the guards, which he struggled to draw from its scabbard, and it was not without some degree of violence that he was prevented from using the deadly weapon against his enemy or against himself.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The industry of the two master-generals, Stilicho and Timasius, was directed to recruit the numbers and to revive the discipline of the Roman legions.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Stilicho', 'PERSON'), ('Timasius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The insolent and brutal lover
 was thrown into prison by the order of Botheric; and he
 sternly rejected the importunate clamours of the multitude,
 who, on the day of the public games, lamented the absence of
 their favourite, and considered the skill of a charioteer as
 an object of more importance than his virtue.","('Botheric', 'PERSON')"
"The intelligence of his
 defeat and death was received with sincere or well
 dissembled joy: his son Victor, on whom he had conferred the
 title of Augustus, died by the orders perhaps by the hand,
 of the bold Arbogastes; and all the military plans of
 Theodosius were successfully executed.","('Victor', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Arbogastes', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The laws of the empire, some of which were inscribed with the name of Valentinian, still condemned the Arian heresy, and seemed to excuse the resistance of the Catholics.","('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Catholics', 'NORP')"
"The lively impatience of the inhabitants of Antioch was
 never satisfied with their own situation, or with the
 character and conduct of their successive sovereigns.","('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"The loss of armies, the destruction of cities,
 and the dishonour of the Roman name, ineffectually solicited
 the successors of Gratian to restore the helmets and
 cuirasses of the infantry.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Gratian', 'NORP')"
"The march of the auxiliaries was guided by the
 ambassador; and they were admitted, without distrust, into
 the fortresses of the Alps.","('Alps', 'LOC')"
"The merit of Ambrose was
 applauded by the conqueror, who secured the attachment of
 the people by his alliance with the church: and the clemency
 of Theodosius is ascribed to the humane intercession of the
 archbishop of Milan.(121)
Death of Theodosius, A.D. 395, January 17.","('Ambrose', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('121', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 395', 'DATE'), ('January 17', 'DATE')"
"The momentous question of peace or war was
 referred by Theodosius to the deliberation of his council;
 and the arguments which might be alleged on the side of
 honour and justice had acquired, since the death of Gratian,
 a considerable degree of additional weight.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Gratian', 'NORP')"
"The monks and
 populace of Callinicum, an obscure town on the frontier of
 Persia, excited by their own fanaticism, and by that of
 their bishop, had tumultuously burnt a conventicle of the
 Valentinians and a synagogue of the Jews.","('Callinicum', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'LOC'), ('Valentinians', 'NORP'), ('Jews', 'NORP')"
"The mother of Valentinian could never forgive the triumph of Ambrose; and the royal youth uttered a passionate exclamation, that his own servants were ready to betray him into the hands of an insolent priest.","('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Ambrose', 'PERSON')"
"The name of Valentinian was regularly inserted
 in the public acts, but the tender age and doubtful faith of
 the son of Justina appeared to require the prudent care of
 an orthodox guardian, and his specious ambition might have
