Sentence,Entities
"""Constantia, the daughter of Sicily, nursed from her cradle in the pleasures and plenty, and educated in the arts and manners, of this fortunate isle, departed long since to enrich the Barbarians with our treasures, and now returns, with her savage allies, to contaminate the beauties of her venerable parent.","('Constantia', 'PERSON'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"""The Normans,"" says Malaterra,   ""are a cunning
 and revengeful people; eloquence and dissimulation appear to be their hereditary qualities: they can stoop to flatter; but unless they are curbed by the restraint of law, they indulge the licentiousness of nature and passion.","('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Malaterra', 'PERSON')"
(41),"('41', 'CARDINAL')"
(51),"('51', 'CARDINAL')"
(53),"('53', 'CARDINAL')"
"1. It was the amusement of the Saracens to profane, as well as to pillage, the monasteries and churches.","('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saracens', 'NORP')"
"2. The Saracens besieged the cities of Beneventum and Capua: after a vain appeal to the successors of Charlemagne, the Lombards implored the clemency and aid of the Greek emperor. (11) A fearless citizen dropped from the walls, passed the entrenchments, accomplished his
 commission, and fell into the hands of the Barbarians as he
 was returning with the welcome news.","('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Beneventum', 'GPE'), ('Capua', 'GPE'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('11', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
3. The recital of a third incident may provoke a smile amidst the horrors of war.,"('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL')"
"A
 series of rebellions might dart a ray of truth into the
 palace of Constantinople; and the illusions of flattery were
 dispelled by the easy and rapid success of the Norman
 adventurers.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Norman', 'PERSON')"
"A Greek, who
 styled himself the father of Constantine, soon appeared at
 Salerno, and related the adventures of his fall and flight.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Salerno', 'PERSON')"
"A colony of  Saracens had been planted at Bari, which commands the
 entrance of the Adriatic Gulf; and their impartial depredations provoked the resentment, and conciliated the union of the two emperors.","('Saracens', 'PRODUCT'), ('Bari', 'GPE'), ('the Adriatic Gulf', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"A conscious superiority of power and
 merit prompted him to disdain the titles of duke and of
 count; and the Isle of Sicily, with a third perhaps of the
 continent of Italy, might form the basis of a kingdom (99)
 which would only yield to the monarchies of France and
 England.","('the Isle of Sicily', 'GPE'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('99', 'CARDINAL'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('England', 'GPE')"
"A general laugh applauded her eloquence; the savage Franks, inaccessible to pity, were moved by her ridiculous, yet rational despair; and with the deliverance of the captives, she obtained the restitution of her effects.","('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"A harder trial was reserved for the valour of
 Count Humphrey, who led the cavalry of the right wing.","('Humphrey', 'PERSON')"
"A movable turret, of a size and capacity to
 contain five hundred soldiers, had been rolled forwards to
 the foot of the rampart: but the descent of the door or
 drawbridge was checked by an enormous beam, and the wooden
 structure was constantly consumed by artificial flames.","('five hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"A multitude of Italians had been the victims
 of their own fears; but only thirty of his knights were
 slain in this memorable day.","('Italians', 'NORP'), ('only thirty', 'CARDINAL'), ('this memorable day', 'DATE')"
"A prince of such a temper could not be satisfied with having
 repelled the insolence of a Barbarian.","('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
"A remnant of Christian natives had promoted the success of the Normans: they were rewarded by the triumph of
 the cross.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Normans', 'NORP')"
"A revolution which punished the crimes of Andronicus, had united against the Franks the zeal and courage of the successful insurgents: ten thousand were slain in battle, and Isaac Angelus, the new emperor, might indulge his vanity or vengeance in the treatment of four thousand captives.","('Andronicus', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Isaac Angelus', 'PERSON'), ('four thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"A school, the first that arose in the darkness of Europe, was
 consecrated to the healing art: the conscience of monks and
 bishops was reconciled to that salutary and lucrative
 profession; and a crowd of patients, of the most eminent
 rank, and most distant climates, invited or visited the
 physicians of Salerno.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Salerno', 'GPE')"
"A seasonable relief was poured into
 Durazzo, and as soon as the besiegers had lost the command
 of the sea, the islands and maritime towns withdrew from the
 camp the supply of tribute and provision.","('Durazzo', 'GPE')"
"A synod of one hundred bishops was convened at
 Melphi; and the count interrupted an important enterprise to
 guard the person and execute the decrees of the Roman
 pontiff.","('one hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Melphi', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
A.D. 1194.,"('A.D. 1194', 'DATE')"
A.D. 873.,"('A.D. 873', 'DATE')"
"About the end of that period, the throne of Manuel was usurped by an inhuman tyrant, who had deserved the abhorrence of his country and mankind: the sword of William the Second, the grandson of Roger, was drawn by a fugitive of the Comnenian race; and the subjects of Andronicus might salute the strangers as friends, since they
 detested their sovereign as the worst of enemies.","('About the end of that period', 'DATE'), ('Manuel', 'PERSON'), ('William the Second', 'PERSON'), ('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('Comnenian', 'NORP'), ('Andronicus', 'PERSON')"
"Above twenty years after the first emigration, the Normans took the field with no more than seven hundred horse and five hundred foot; and after the recall of the Byzantine
 legions (23) from the Sicilian war, their numbers are magnified to the amount of threescore thousand men.","('twenty years', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('no more than seven hundred horse and five hundred foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('23', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Sicilian war', 'EVENT'), ('threescore thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"According to the
 Greeks, he departed from Normandy with only five followers
 on horseback and thirty on foot; yet even this allowance
 appears too bountiful: the sixth son of Tancred of
 Hauteville passed the Alps as a pilgrim; and his first
 military band was levied among the adventurers of Italy.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Normandy', 'GPE'), ('only five', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirty', 'CARDINAL'), ('sixth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Tancred', 'PERSON'), ('Hauteville', 'GPE'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"After
 a reign of two hundred years, the Saracens were ruined by
 their divisions. (21)","('two hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('21', 'CARDINAL')"
"After
 evacuating the conquests which he could no longer defend,
 the son of Guiscard embarked for Italy, and was embraced by
 a father who esteemed his merit, and sympathized in his
 misfortune.","('Guiscard', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"After a gallant resistance, the Norman
 prince was driven from the continent of Italy: a new duke of
 Apulia was invested by the pope and the emperor, each of
 whom held one end of the gonfanon, or flagstaff, as a token
 that they asserted their right, and suspended their quarrel.","('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a long indulgence of rapine
 and slaughter, a fair and ample territory was accepted,
 occupied, and named, by the Normans of France: they
 renounced their gods for the God of the Christians; (16) and
 the dukes of Normandy acknowledged themselves the vassals of
 the successors of Charlemagne and Capet.","('Normans', 'NORP'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('16', 'CARDINAL'), ('Normandy', 'GPE'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Capet', 'PERSON')"
"After a pilgrimage of
 thirty-nine years, Constantine, an African Christian,
 returned from Bagdad, a master of the language and learning
 of the Arabians; and Salerno was enriched by the practice,
 the lessons, and the writings of the pupil of Avicenna.","('thirty-nine years', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('an African Christian', 'NORP'), ('Bagdad', 'GPE'), ('Arabians', 'NORP'), ('Salerno', 'PERSON'), ('Avicenna', 'PERSON')"
"After a war of thirty years, (55)","('thirty years', 'DATE'), ('55', 'CARDINAL')"
"After his death, that sword was broken; and these transmarine possessions were neglected, evacuated, or lost, under the troubled reign of his successor. (108)","('108', 'CARDINAL')"
"After his decease, the kingdom of his widow and infant son fell without a struggle; and Henry pursued his victorious march from Capua to
 Palermo.","('Henry', 'PERSON'), ('Capua', 'GPE'), ('Palermo', 'GPE')"
"After the
 defeat of his foreign enemies, the Greeks, Lombards, and
 Saracens, their broken forces retreated to the strong and
 populous cities of the sea-coast.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP')"
"After the
 reunion with Frederic, he spoke a more peremptory language,
 confirmed the acts of his predecessors, excommunicated the
 adherents of Manuel, and pronounced the final separation of
 the churches, or at least the empires, of Constantinople and
 Rome. (120)","('Frederic', 'PERSON'), ('Manuel', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('120', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the death of Humphrey, the tender age of
 his sons excluded them from the command; they were reduced
 to a private estate, by the ambition of their guardian and
 uncle; and Guiscard was exalted on a buckler, and saluted
 count of Apulia and general of the republic.","('Humphrey', 'PERSON'), ('Guiscard', 'PERSON'), ('Apulia', 'PERSON')"
"After the defeat and
 death of his Swabian rebel, Henry descended into Italy, to
 assume the Imperial crown, and to drive from the Vatican the
 tyrant of the church. (84)","('Swabian', 'NORP'), ('Henry', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Vatican', 'FAC')"
"After the means of persuasion had
 failed, Argyrus resolved to compel or to destroy: the Latin
 powers were solicited against the common enemy; and an
 offensive alliance was formed of the pope and the two
 emperors of the East and West.","('Argyrus', 'PERSON'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"After the retreat
 of the Greeks, the idolaters, a most audacious reproach of
 the Catholics, had retrieved their losses and possessions;
 but the deliverance of the island, so vainly undertaken by
 the forces of the Eastern empire, was achieved by a small
 and private band of adventurers.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"After their defeat,
 they still persevered in the defence of Durazzo; and a
 Venetian commander supplied the place of George Palaeologus,
 who had been imprudently called away from his station.","('Durazzo', 'PERSON'), ('Venetian', 'NORP'), ('George Palaeologus', 'PERSON')"
"After this
 inauguration, Robert styled himself, ""By the grace of God
 and St. Peter, duke of Apulia, Calabria, and hereafter of
 Sicily;"" and it was the labour of twenty years to deserve and
 realize these lofty appellations.","('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('St. Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Calabria', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('twenty years', 'DATE')"
"After three hundred years of prosperity, Amalphi was
 oppressed by the arms of the Normans, and sacked by the
 jealousy of Pisa; but the poverty of one thousand fisherman is yet dignified by the remains of an arsenal, a cathedral, and the palaces of royal merchants.","('three hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Amalphi', 'PERSON'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Pisa', 'GPE'), ('one thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"After two years'
 incessant preparations the land and naval forces were
 assembled at Otranto, at the heel, or extreme promontory, of
 Italy; and Robert was accompanied by his wife, who fought by
 his side, his son Bohemond, and the representative of the
 emperor Michael.","(""two years'"", 'DATE'), ('Otranto', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON'), ('Michael', 'PERSON')"
"After winning two
 battles against the emperor, he descended into the plain of
 Thessaly, and besieged Larissa, the fabulous realm of
 Achilles, (79) which contained the treasure and magazines of
 the Byzantine camp.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Thessaly', 'PERSON'), ('Larissa', 'PERSON'), ('Achilles', 'PERSON'), ('79', 'CARDINAL'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"Against the Normans, A.D. 1053.","('Normans', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 1053', 'DATE')"
"Against the advice of his wisest captains, Alexius resolved
 to risk the event of a general action, and exhorted the
 garrison of Durazzo to assist their own deliverance by a
 well-timed sally from the town.","('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('Durazzo', 'GPE')"
"Against the unanimous wish of a free people, this inheritance could only be acquired by arms; and I am pleased to transcribe the style and sense of the historian Falcandus, who writes at the moment, and on the spot, with the feelings of a patriot, and the prophetic eye of a statesman.","('Falcandus', 'PERSON')"
"Alexius had been taught by experience, that the
 formidable cavalry of the Franks on foot was unfit for
 action, and almost incapable of motion; (80) his archers were
 directed to aim their arrows at the horse rather than the
 man; and a variety of spikes and snares were scattered over
 the ground on which he might expect an attack.","('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('80', 'CARDINAL')"
"Alexius returned to Constantinople with the
 advantage, rather than the honour, of victory.","('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Alexius was
 not deficient in the duties of a soldier or a general; but
 he no sooner beheld the slaughter of the Varangians, and the
 flight of the Turks, than he despised his subjects, and
 despaired of his fortune.","('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('Varangians', 'NORP'), ('Turks', 'NORP')"
"Alexius,
 apprehensive of a second attack, had assiduously labored to
 restore the naval forces of the empire; and obtained from
 the republic of Venice an important succour of thirty-six
 transports, fourteen galleys, and nine galiots or ships of
 extra-ordinary strength and magnitude.","('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('thirty-six', 'CARDINAL'), ('fourteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL')"
"All night the galleys of the republic lay on their anchors
 in the form of a crescent; and the victory of the second day
 was decided by the dexterity of their evolutions, the
 station of their archers, the weight of their javelins, and
 the borrowed aid of the Greek fire.","('All night', 'TIME'), ('the second day', 'DATE'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
All the calamities which the prophetic orator had deplored were surpassed by the cruelty and avarice of the German conqueror.,"('German', 'NORP')"
"Already I behold the swarms of angry Barbarians: our opulent cities, the places flourishing in a long peace, are shaken with fear, desolated by slaughter, consumed by rapine, and polluted by intemperance and lust.","('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"Among the
 new acquisitions of Guiscard, the science of Salerno, (47)
 and the trade of Amalphi, (48) may detain for a moment the
 curiosity of the reader.","('Guiscard', 'ORG'), ('Salerno', 'ORG'), ('47', 'CARDINAL'), ('Amalphi', 'ORG'), ('48', 'CARDINAL')"
"Among the hostilities of the Arabs, the Franks, and the Greeks, in the southern Italy, I shall select two or three anecdotes expressive of their national manners.","('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"An eloquent historian of the times (126) has delineated the misfortunes of his country: (127) the ambition and fall of the ungrateful Majo; the revolt and punishment of his assassins; the imprisonment and deliverance of the king himself; the private feuds that arose from the public confusion; and the various forms of calamity and discord which afflicted Palermo, the island, and the continent, during the reign of William the First, and the minority of his son.","('126', 'CARDINAL'), ('127', 'CARDINAL'), ('Majo', 'PERSON'), ('Palermo', 'GPE'), ('William the First', 'PERSON')"
"An offensive alliance was concluded between Basil the Macedonian, the first of his race, and Lewis the great-grandson of Charlemagne; (3) and each party supplied the deficiencies of his associate.","('Basil', 'PERSON'), ('Macedonian', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Lewis', 'PERSON'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('3', 'CARDINAL')"
"Anne, who drops a
 tear on this melancholy event, is reduced to praise the
 strength and swiftness of her father's horse, and his
 vigorous struggle when he was almost overthrown by the
 stroke of a lance, which had shivered the Imperial helmet.","('Anne', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"Arms and horses, the luxury of dress,
 the exercises of hunting and hawking (27)  are the delight of
 the Normans; but, on pressing occasions, they can endure with incredible patience the inclemency of every climate, and the toil and absence of a military life."" (28) 
Oppression of Apulia,A.D. 1046 etc.","('27', 'CARDINAL'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('28', 'CARDINAL'), ('A.D. 1046', 'DATE')"
"As a
 German of noble birth and royal kindred, Leo had free access
 to the court and confidence of the emperor Henry the Third;
 and in search of arms and allies, his ardent zeal
 transported him from Apulia to Saxony, from the Elbe to the
 Tyber.","('German', 'NORP'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Henry', 'PERSON'), ('Third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Saxony', 'GPE'), ('Elbe', 'LOC'), ('Tyber', 'LOC')"
"As a penance for his impious war against the successor of
 St. Peter, that monarch might have promised to display the
 banner of the cross, and he accomplished with ardour a vow so
 propitious to his interest and revenge.","('St. Peter', 'PERSON')"
"As he
 pressed the citadel of Salerno, a huge stone from the
 rampart shattered one of his military engines; and by a
 splinter he was wounded in the breast.","('Salerno', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"As he wrestled with a reluctant maid, a beam in the roof was accidentally or dexterously thrown down on his head; and the death of the lustful emir was imputed to the wrath of Christ, which was at length awakened to the defence of his faithful spouse. (10) A.D. 874.","('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('874', 'CARDINAL')"
"As long as the sceptre was disputed by the princes of Italy, their efforts were feeble and adverse; and the Greeks resisted or eluded the forces of Germany, which descended from the Alps under the Imperial standard of the Othos.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Othos', 'PRODUCT')"
"As she returned in triumph to the castle, she was overtaken by a messenger, to inquire, in the name of Theobald, what punishment should be inflicted on her husband, were he again taken in arms.","('Theobald', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as the
 besiegers had surmounted the labor (their sole labor) of climbing the hill, their general, from the commanding eminence, admired his own victory, and testified his gratitude to Heaven, by tearing from the altar the precious
 image of Theodore, the tutelary saint.","('Theodore', 'PERSON')"
"As the genius of Robert expanded with his fortune, he
 awakened the jealousy of his elder brother, by whom, in a
 transient quarrel, his life was threatened and his liberty
 restrained.","('Robert', 'PERSON')"
"At the dead of night, several rope-ladders were
 dropped from the walls; the light Calabrians ascended in
 silence; and the Greeks were awakened by the name and
 trumpets of the conqueror.","('the dead of night', 'TIME'), ('Calabrians', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"At the former period, the coast of Great Greece (as it was then styled) was planted with free and opulent cities: these cities were peopled with soldiers, artists, and philosophers; and the military strength of Tarentum; Sybaris, or Crotona, was not inferior to that of a powerful kingdom.","('Great Greece', 'GPE'), ('Tarentum', 'NORP'), ('Sybaris', 'NORP'), ('Crotona', 'PERSON')"
"At the mouth of the Adriatic Gulf, the shores of Italy and
 Epirus incline towards each other.","('the Adriatic Gulf', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Epirus', 'GPE')"
"At the second aera, these once flourishing provinces were clouded with ignorance impoverished by tyranny, and depopulated by Barbarian war nor can we severely accuse the exaggeration of a contemporary, that a fair and ample district was reduced to the same desolation which had covered the earth after the general deluge.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
"At the siege of Salerno, a Mussulman chief spread his couch on the communion-table, and on that altar sacrificed each night the virginity of a Christian nun.","('Salerno', 'GPE'), ('Mussulman', 'NORP'), ('each night', 'TIME'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"Battle of Durazzo, A.D. 1081, October 18.","('Durazzo', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1081', 'DATE'), ('October 18', 'DATE')"
"Before the gates of
 Bari, he lodged in a miserable hut or barrack, composed of
 dry branches, and thatched with straw; a perilous station,
 on all sides open to the inclemency of the winter and the
 spears of the enemy. (45)","('Bari', 'GPE'), ('45', 'CARDINAL')"
"Before the general embarkation, the
 Norman duke despatched Bohemond with fifteen galleys to
 seize or threaten the Isle of Corfu, to survey the opposite
 coast, and to secure a harbour in the neighbourhood of Vallona
 for the landing of the troops.","('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON'), ('fifteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Isle of Corfu', 'GPE'), ('Vallona', 'GPE')"
"Before their landing, the brothers were reconciled; the
 union of Sicily and Africa was restored; and the island was
 guarded to the water's edge.","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"Beyond that line, the dukes or republics of Amalfi (5) and Naples, who had never forfeited their voluntary allegiance, rejoiced in the neighbourhood of their lawful sovereign; and Amalfi was enriched by supplying Europe with
 the produce and manufactures of Asia.","('Amalfi', 'GPE'), ('5', 'CARDINAL'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Amalfi', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"Birth and character of Robert Guiscard, A.D. 1020-1085.","('Robert Guiscard', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 1020-1085', 'DATE')"
"But
 his arts were baffled by the sense and spirit of the
 conquerors of Apulia: his gifts, or at least his proposals,
 were rejected; and they unanimously refused to relinquish
 their possessions and their hopes for the distant prospect
 of Asiatic fortune.","('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP')"
"But
 the pope was inexorable; his lofty Germans affected to
 deride the diminutive stature of their adversaries; and the
 Normans were informed that death or exile was their only
 alternative.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Normans', 'NORP')"
"But his spirit
 survived in his brother Humphrey, the third count of Apulia.","('Humphrey', 'PERSON'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Apulia', 'PERSON')"
"But if the Saracens, fatigued by a repetition of injuries, should now retire and rebel; if they should occupy the castles of the mountains and sea-coast, the unfortunate Christians, exposed to a double attack, and placed as it were between the hammer and the anvil, must resign themselves to hopeless and inevitable servitude."" (136)","('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('136', 'CARDINAL')"
"But let my (14)  lord be pleased to spare what his little handmaid presumes to claim as her peculiar and lawful property.""","('14', 'CARDINAL')"
"But such jealous friendship was of short and precarious
 duration: the German armies soon vanished in disease and
 desertion: (102) the Apulian duke, with all his adherents,
 was exterminated by a conqueror who seldom forgave either
 the dead or the living; like his predecessor Leo the Ninth,
 the feeble though haughty pontiff became the captive and
 friend of the Normans; and their reconciliation was
 celebrated by the eloquence of Bernard, who now revered the
 title and virtues of the king of Sicily.","('German', 'NORP'), ('102', 'CARDINAL'), ('Apulian', 'NORP'), ('Leo the Ninth', 'PERSON'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Bernard', 'PERSON'), ('Sicily', 'GPE')"
"But the
 throne of Constantinople was shaken by a revolution: the
 Imperial family of Ducas was confined to the palace or the
 cloister; and Robert deplored, and resented, the disgrace of
 his daughter and the expulsion of his ally.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Ducas', 'PERSON'), ('Robert', 'PERSON')"
"But the Lombard princes of Benevento, Salerno, and Capua, (6) were reluctantly torn from the communion of the Latin world, and too often violated their oaths of servitude and tribute.","('Lombard', 'GPE'), ('Benevento', 'GPE'), ('Salerno', 'GPE'), ('Capua', 'GPE'), ('6', 'CARDINAL'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"But the Roman people adhered to
 the cause of Gregory: their resolution was fortified by
 supplies of men and money from Apulia; Besieges Rome, A.D. 1081-1084.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Besieges Rome', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1081-1084', 'DATE')"
"But the contemptuous treatment of his ambassadors
 exasperated the vanity of the new monarch; and the insolence of the Byzantine court was expiated, according to the laws of nations, by the sufferings of a guiltless people. (109)","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('109', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the power of Constantine was distracted by a Turkish
 war; the mind of Henry was feeble and irresolute; and the
 pope, instead of repassing the Alps with a German army, was
 accompanied only by a guard of seven hundred Swabians and
 some volunteers of Lorraine.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('a Turkish\r\n war', 'EVENT'), ('Henry', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('seven hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Swabians', 'NORP'), ('Lorraine', 'PERSON')"
"But the subtle policy, for which the Vatican has so often been praised or arraigned, was on this occasion blind and inactive; and if it were true that Celestine the Third
 had kicked away the Imperial crown from the head of the prostrate Henry, (137) such an act of impotent pride could
 serve only to cancel an obligation and provoke an enemy.","('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Celestine', 'PERSON'), ('Third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Henry', 'PERSON'), ('137', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the triumph of Robert was clouded by the calamities of
 Rome.","('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But these Italian conquests, this universal reign, soon
 escaped from the hand of the Greek emperor.","('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"But victory was the only
 argument that could determine the belief of the Greeks; and
 the ardour of the Latins was much inferior to their
 credulity: the Norman veterans wished to enjoy the harvest
 of their toils, and the unwarlike Italians trembled at the
 known and unknown dangers of a transmarine expedition.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('Norman', 'NORP'), ('Italians', 'NORP')"
"But, in the Isle of Cephalonia, his projects were fatally blasted by an epidemical disease:","('the Isle of Cephalonia', 'GPE')"
"By his
 policy and vigour, Guiscard discovered their plots,
 suppressed their rebellions, and punished the guilty with
 death or exile: but in these domestic feuds, his years, and
 the national strength, were unprofitably consumed.","('Guiscard', 'PERSON'), ('years', 'DATE')"
"By his own avarice, or the complaints of his subjects, the Greek emperor was provoked to arrest the persons, and confiscate the effects, of the Venetian merchants.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Venetian', 'NORP')"
"By shipwreck, pestilence, and the sword, his army
 was reduced to a third of the original numbers; and instead
 of being recruited from Italy, he was informed, by plaintive
 epistles, of the mischiefs and dangers which had been
 produced by his absence: the revolt of the cities and barons
 of Apulia; the distress of the pope; and the approach or
 invasion of Henry king of Germany.","('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Henry', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"By some acts of
 rapine or sacrilege, he had incurred a papal
 excommunication; but Nicholas the Second was easily
 persuaded that the divisions of friends could terminate only
 in their mutual prejudice; that the Normans were the
 faithful champions of the Holy See; and it was safer to
 trust the alliance of a prince than the caprice of an
 aristocracy.","('Nicholas', 'PERSON'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('the Holy See', 'ORG')"
"By the aid of the friends of Gregory, the walls had
 been perforated or scaled; but the Imperial faction was
 still powerful and active; on the third day, the people rose
 in a furious tumult; and a hasty word of the conqueror, in
 his defence or revenge, was the signal of fire and pillage.
 (86)","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('the third day', 'DATE')"
"By the artful
 speeches, liberal gifts, and unbounded promises, of their
 Eastern ally, the free cities were encouraged to persevere
 in their generous struggle against the despotism of Frederic
 Barbarossa: the walls of Milan were rebuilt by the
 contributions of Manuel; and he poured, says the historian,
 a river of gold into the bosom of Ancona, whose attachment
 to the Greeks was fortified by the jealous enmity of the
 Venetians. (114)","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Frederic\r\n Barbarossa', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Manuel', 'PERSON'), ('Ancona', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Venetians', 'NORP'), ('114', 'CARDINAL')"
"By the first arms of
 Roger, the island or rock of Malta, which has been since
 ennobled by a military and religious colony, was inseparably
 annexed to the crown of Sicily.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('Malta', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE')"
"By the policy of Frederic the Second, sixty thousand Saracens were transplanted to Nocera in Apulia.","('Frederic', 'PERSON'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Nocera', 'GPE'), ('Apulia', 'GPE')"
"By the unanimous election of a king of valour and experience, Sicily and Calabria might yet be preserved; (130) for in the levity of the Apulians, ever eager for new revolutions, I can repose neither confidence nor hope. (131)","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Calabria', 'GPE'), ('130', 'CARDINAL'), ('Apulians', 'NORP'), ('131', 'CARDINAL')"
"By the union of the Greeks and Venetians, the
 Adriatic was covered with a hostile fleet; but their own
 neglect, or the vigilance of Robert, the change of a wind,
 or the shelter of a mist, opened a free passage; and the
 Norman troops were safely disembarked on the coast of
 Epirus.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Venetians', 'NORP'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Norman', 'NORP'), ('Epirus', 'LOC')"
"By whatever hands they had been usurped, the
 provinces of Apulia and Calabria were a part of the donation
 of Constantine and the patrimony of St. Peter: the grant and
 the acceptance confirmed the mutual claims of the pontiff
 and the adventurers.","('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Calabria', 'GPE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE')"
"Catana has again been overwhelmed by an earthquake: the ancient virtue of Syracuse expires in poverty and solitude; (135) but Palermo is still crowned with a diadem, and her triple walls enclose the active multitudes of Christians and Saracens.","('Catana', 'PERSON'), ('Syracuse', 'GPE'), ('135', 'CARDINAL'), ('Palermo', 'GPE'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP')"
"Character and Conquest of Robert Guiscard, Duke of Apulia.","('Robert Guiscard', 'PERSON'), ('Duke of Apulia', 'GPE')"
"Conflict of the Saracens, Latins and Greeks, in Italy, A.D. 840-1017","('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Conquest of Bari, A.D. 871.","('Bari', 'GPE'), ('871', 'CARDINAL')"
"Conquest of Sicily by count Roger, A.D. 1060-1090.","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('1060-1090', 'DATE')"
Conquest of the kingdom of Sicily by the emperor Henry VI.,"('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Henry VI', 'PERSON')"
"Constantia herself was touched with sympathy for the miseries of her country; and the heiress of the Norman line might struggle to check her despotic husband, and to save the patrimony of her new-born son, of an emperor so famous in the next age under the name of Frederic the Second.","('Constantia', 'PERSON'), ('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('Frederic', 'PERSON'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL')"
"Defeat of Otho III, A.D.983.","('A.D.983', 'ORG')"
Deliverance of Sicily by his Brother Roger.,"('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Roger', 'PERSON')"
"Duke of Apulia, A.D. 1127.","('Duke of Apulia', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 1127', 'DATE')"
"Durazzo taken, A.D. 1082, February 8.","('Durazzo', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 1082', 'DATE'), ('February 8', 'DATE')"
"During a calamitous period of two hundred years, Italy was exposed to a repetition of wounds, which the invaders were not capable of healing by the union and tranquility of a perfect conquest.","('two hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"During four years, the term of his life and reign, he stood in arms on the farthest verge of the Apulian frontier, against the powers of Germany; and the restitution of a royal captive, of Constantia herself,
 without injury or ransom, may appear to surpass the most liberal measure of policy or reason.","('four years', 'DATE'), ('Apulian', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Constantia', 'PERSON')"
"During the quarrel between Frederic and
 Alexander the Third, the pope twice received in the Vatican
 the ambassadors of Constantinople.","('Frederic', 'PERSON'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"During these hostile preparations, Argyrus indulged
 himself in the use of secret and guilty weapons: a crowd of
 Normans became the victims of public or private revenge; A.D. 1051and
 the valiant Drogo was murdered in a church.","('Argyrus', 'PERSON'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 1051', 'DATE'), ('Drogo', 'PERSON')"
"Eight miles from his residence, as a bulwark against Capua, the town of Aversa was built and fortified for their use; and they enjoyed as their own the corn and fruits, the meadows and groves, of that fertile district.","('Eight miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Capua', 'GPE'), ('Aversa', 'GPE')"
"Every object of desire, a horse, a woman, a garden, tempted
 and gratified the rapaciousness of the strangers; (29) and
 the avarice of their chiefs was only colored by the more
 specious names of ambition and glory.","('29', 'CARDINAL')"
Expedition of pope Leo IX.,"('Leo IX', 'PERSON')"
Extinction of the Normans.,"('Normans', 'NORP')"
"Fifty thousand
 citizens were numbered in the walls of Amalphi; nor was any
 city more abundantly provided with gold, silver, and the
 objects of precious luxury.","('Fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Amalphi', 'GPE')"
"Final extinction of the Normans, A.D. 1204.","('Normans', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 1204', 'DATE')"
First Adventures and  Settlement of the Normans.,"('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Normans', 'NORP')"
"First king of Sicily, A.D. 1130, Dec. 25- A.D. 1139, July 25.","('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1130', 'DATE'), ('Dec. 25- A.D. 1139', 'DATE'), ('July 25', 'DATE')"
"Flight they disdained, and, as many of them
 had been three days without tasting food, they embraced the
 assurance of a more easy and honourable death.","('three days', 'DATE')"
"Foundation of Aversa, A.D. 1029.","('Foundation of Aversa', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 1029', 'DATE')"
"From
 this aera we may date the establishment of the Norman power,
 which soon eclipsed the infant colony of Aversa.","('Norman', 'NORP'), ('Aversa', 'PRODUCT')"
"From Durazzo, the
 Norman duke advanced into the heart of Epirus or Albania;
 traversed the first mountains of Thessaly; surprised three
 hundred English in the city of Castoria; approached
 Thessalonica; and made Constantinople tremble.","('Durazzo', 'GPE'), ('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('Epirus', 'LOC'), ('Albania', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Thessaly', 'GPE'), ('three\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('English', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Castoria', 'GPE'), ('Thessalonica', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"From a city,
 where he was now hated, and might be no longer feared,
 Gregory retired to end his days in the palace of Salerno.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Salerno', 'GPE')"
"From his first wife, the
 partner of his humble fortune, he had been divorced under
 the pretence of consanguinity; and her son Bohemond was
 destined to imitate, rather than to succeed, his illustrious
 father.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON')"
"From the Arabian conquest, Sicily had imbibed a deep tincture of Oriental manners; the despotism, the pomp, and even the harem, of a sultan; and a Christian people was oppressed and insulted by the ascendant of the eunuchs, who openly professed, or secretly cherished, the religion of Mahomet.","('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"Gaita, the
 wife of Robert, is painted by the Greeks as a warlike
 Amazon, a second Pallas; less skilful in arts, but not less
 terrible in arms, than the Athenian goddess: (73) though
 wounded by an arrow, she stood her ground, and strove, by
 her exhortation and example, to rally the flying troops. (74)","('Gaita', 'PERSON'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Amazon', 'ORG'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Pallas', 'LOC'), ('Athenian', 'NORP'), ('73', 'CARDINAL'), ('74', 'CARDINAL')"
"Had Roger been
 content with his fruitful patrimony, a happy and grateful
 people might have blessed their benefactor; and if a wise
 administration could have restored the prosperous times of
 the Greek colonies, (98) the opulence and power of Sicily
 alone might have equalled the widest scope that could be
 acquired and desolated by the sword of war.","('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('98', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sicily', 'GPE')"
"He
 accepted the welcome summons; hastened to the Apulian camp;
 and deserved at first the esteem, and afterwards the envy,
 of his elder brother.","('Apulian', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"He
 sprang from a race of valvassors or bannerets, of the
 diocese of Coutances, in the Lower Normandy: the castle of
 Hauteville was their honourable seat: his father Tancred was
 conspicuous in the court and army of the duke; and his
 military service was furnished by ten soldiers or knights.","('Coutances', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('the Lower Normandy', 'GPE'), ('Hauteville', 'GPE'), ('Tancred', 'PERSON'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL')"
"He affected to yield, but as soon as he was
 conducted within hearing of the Christians on the rampart, 
""Friends and brethren,"" he cried with a loud voice,   ""be bold and patient, maintain the city; your sovereign is informed of your distress, and your deliverers are at hand.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"He affected to yield, but as soon as he was
 conducted within hearing of the Christians on the rampart,  The rage of the Arabs confirmed his evidence; and the self-devoted patriot was transpierced with a hundred spears.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('a hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"He congratulates Henry on his
 success in a just and pious war; and complains that the
 prosperity of his own empire is disturbed by the audacious
 enterprises of the Norman Robert.","('Henry', 'PERSON'), ('the Norman Robert', 'PERSON')"
"He deserves to live in the memory of the virtuous, but the repetition of the same story in ancient and modern times, may sprinkle some doubts on the reality of this generous deed. (12)  A.D. 930.","('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('930', 'CARDINAL')"
"He landed some soldiers to rifle the fruits of the royal gardens, and pointed with silver, or most probably with fire, the arrows which he discharged against the palace of the Caesars. (111)","('Caesars', 'PERSON'), ('111', 'CARDINAL')"
"He marched in two columns
 to surprise the Normans before daybreak on two different
 sides: his light cavalry was scattered over the plain; the
 archers formed the second line; and the Varangians claimed
 the honours of the vanguard.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Varangians', 'NORP')"
"He reduces Apulia and Calabria, A.D. 1155.","('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Calabria', 'GPE'), ('1155', 'CARDINAL')"
"He sought to obtain the undivided possession of Palermo, of
 which one moiety had been ceded to the elder branch;
 struggled to enlarge his Calabrian limits beyond the measure
 of former treaties; and impatiently watched the declining
 health of his cousin William of Apulia, the grandson of
 Robert.","('Palermo', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Calabrian', 'NORP'), ('William of Apulia', 'PERSON'), ('Robert', 'PERSON')"
"He violated the royal sepulchres and  explored the secret treasures of the palace, Palermo, and the whole kingdom: the pearls and jewels, however precious, might be easily removed; but one hundred and sixty horses were laden with the gold and silver of Sicily. (140)","('Palermo', 'GPE'), ('one hundred and sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('140', 'CARDINAL')"
"He was
 dismissed with a fresh horse; the insult was concealed from
 the Imperial troops; but in two successive battles they were
 more fatally instructed of the prowess of their adversaries.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Henry was the severe adversary of the
 Normans, the allies and vassals of Gregory the Seventh, his
 implacable foe.","('Henry', 'PERSON'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Gregory the Seventh', 'PERSON')"
"Henry, invincible in sixty-six battles, trembled at his
 approach; recollected some indispensable affairs that
 required his presence in Lombardy; exhorted the Romans to
 persevere in their allegiance; Flies before Robert, May.  and hastily retreated three days before the entrance of the Normans.","('Henry', 'PERSON'), ('sixty-six', 'DATE'), ('Lombardy', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('three days', 'DATE'), ('Normans', 'NORP')"
"Her female voice was seconded by the more powerful voice and arm of the Norman duke, as calm in action as he was magnanimous in council:","('the Norman duke', 'PERSON')"
"Her female voice was seconded by the more powerful voice and arm of the Norman duke, as calm in action as he was magnanimous in council: 
 ""Whither,"" he cried aloud,   ""whither do ye fly?","('the Norman duke', 'PERSON')"
"Highly presuming that
 his person was sufficient for the public safety, he repassed
 the sea in a single brigantine, and left the remains of the
 army under the command of his son and the Norman counts,
 exhorting Bohemond to respect the freedom of his peers, and
 the counts to obey the authority of their leader.","('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON')"
"His
 brothers and countrymen had divided the fertile lands of
 Apulia; but they guarded their shares with the jealousy of
 avarice; the aspiring youth was driven forwards to the
 mountains of Calabria, and in his first exploits against the
 Greeks and the natives, it is not easy to discriminate the
 hero from the robber.","('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Calabria', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"His
 complexion was ruddy, his shoulders were broad, his hair and
 beard were long and of a flaxen colour, his eyes sparkled
 with fire, and his voice, like that of Achilles, could
 impress obedience and terror amidst the tumult of battle.","('Achilles', 'PERSON')"
His Italian conquests.,"('Italian', 'NORP')"
His admiral delivers LouisVII of France.,"('LouisVII', 'PERSON'), ('France', 'GPE')"
"His ambition and success, A.D. 1054-1080.","('A.D. 1054', 'DATE')"
"His captives of the
 Greek nation or party were castrated without mercy, and the
 outrage was aggravated by a cruel jest, that he wished to
 present the emperor with a supply of eunuchs, the most
 precious ornaments of the Byzantine court.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"His conquests in Africa, A.D. 1122-1152.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('1122-1152', 'CARDINAL')"
"His conversations with Robert were frequent
 and familiar; and their mutual promises were justified by
 the valour of the Normans and the treasures of the East.","('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"His death, A.D. 1085, July 17.","('A.D. 1085', 'DATE'), ('July 17', 'DATE')"
"His defeat and captivity, June 18.","('June 18', 'DATE')"
"His design of acquiring Italy and the Western empire, A.D. 1155-1174, etc.  but the successor of Constantine soon renounced this ignominious pretence, claimed the
 indefeasible dominion of Italy, and professed his design of
 chasing the Barbarians beyond the Alps.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 1155-1174', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Alps', 'LOC')"
"His desperate valour broke through a squadron of Franks who
 opposed his flight; and after wandering two days and as many
 nights in the mountains, he found some repose, of body,
 though not of mind, in the walls of Lychnidus.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('two days and as many\r\n nights', 'DATE'), ('Lychnidus', 'GPE')"
"His first
 demands were eluded by the prudence of Alexander the Third,
 who paused on this deep and momentous revolution; (119) nor could the pope be seduced by a personal dispute to renounce
 the perpetual inheritance of the Latin name.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Alexander the Third', 'PERSON'), ('119', 'CARDINAL'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE')"
"His genuine descent may be ascribed to
 the second or middle order of private nobility. (40)","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('40', 'CARDINAL')"
"His gratitude and policy conferred on Robert and
 his posterity the ducal title, (43) with the investiture of
 Apulia, Calabria, and all the lands, both in Italy and
 Sicily, which his sword could rescue from the schismatic
 Greeks and the unbelieving Saracens. (44)","('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('43', 'CARDINAL'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Calabria', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('44', 'CARDINAL')"
"His humanity was affected by the complaints, perhaps the
 calumnies, of an injured people: the impious Normans had
 interrupted the payment of tithes; and the temporal sword
 might be lawfully unsheathed against the sacrilegious
 robbers, who were deaf to the censures of the church.","('Normans', 'NORP')"
"His invasion of Greece, A.D. 1146.","('Greece', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1146', 'DATE')"
"His name
 was Melo; a noble citizen of Bari, who, after an
 unsuccessful revolt, was compelled to seek new allies and
 avengers of his country.","('Melo', 'PERSON'), ('Bari', 'PERSON')"
"His prophecy was soon verified: the death of Palaeologus devolved the command on several chiefs, alike eminent in rank, alike defective in military talents; the Greeks were oppressed by land and sea; and a captive remnant that escaped the swords of the Normans and Saracens, abjured all future hostility against the person or dominions of their conqueror.","('Palaeologus', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP')"
"His prophecy was soon verified: the death of Palaeologus devolved the command on several chiefs, alike eminent in rank, alike defective in military talents; the Greeks were oppressed by land and sea; and a captive remnant that escaped the swords of the Normans and Saracens, abjured all future hostility against the person or dominions of their conqueror. (122)","('Palaeologus', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('122', 'CARDINAL')"
"His rear was covered by a small river; his right wing extended to the sea; his left to the hills: nor was he conscious, perhaps, that on the same ground Caesar and Pompey had formerly disputed the empire of the world. (72)
Battle of Durazzo, A.D. 1081, October 18.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Pompey', 'PERSON'), ('72', 'CARDINAL'), ('Battle of Durazzo', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('1081', 'CARDINAL'), ('October 18', 'DATE')"
"His reply is expressed with the eloquence of indignation and truth: New provinces of the Greeks in Italy, A.D. 890.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 890', 'DATE')"
"His spirit emerged from poverty and disgrace:
 from these base practices he rose to the merit and glory of
 a holy war; and the invasion of Sicily was seconded by the
 zeal and policy of his brother Guiscard.","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Guiscard', 'PERSON')"
"His troops were levied in Europe and Asia,
 from Peloponnesus to the Black Sea; his majesty was
 displayed in the silver arms and rich trappings of the
 companies of Horse-guards; and the emperor was attended by a
 train of nobles and princes, some of whom, in rapid
 succession, had been clothed with the purple, and were
 indulged by the lenity of the times in a life of affluence
 and dignity.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Peloponnesus', 'LOC'), ('the Black Sea', 'LOC')"
"I see the massacre or captivity of our citizens, the rapes of our virgins and matrons. (129)","('129', 'CARDINAL')"
"I. the Bad king of Sicily, A.D. 1154, Feb.26 -A.D. 1166, May 7.","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1154', 'DATE'), ('Feb.26 -A.D. 1166', 'DATE'), ('May 7', 'DATE')"
"If the savage Germans coalesce with the pirates of Messina; if they destroy with fire the fruitful region, so often wasted by the fires of Mount Aetna, (133) what resource will be left for the interior parts of the island, these noble cities which should never be violated by the hostile footsteps of a Barbarian? (134)","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Messina', 'GPE'), ('Mount Aetna', 'LOC'), ('133', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('134', 'CARDINAL')"
"If the two nations, under one king, can unite for their common safety, they may rush on the Barbarians with invincible arms.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"In
 every service of danger the Normans were prompt and useful;
 and five hundred knights, or warriors on horseback, were
 enrolled by Arduin, the agent and interpreter of the Greeks,
 under the standard of Maniaces, governor of Lombardy.","('Normans', 'NORP'), ('five hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arduin', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Maniaces', 'PERSON'), ('Lombardy', 'GPE')"
"In
 his new levies, Robert exerted the influence of gifts and
 promises, the terrors of civil and ecclesiastical authority;
 and some acts of violence might justify the reproach, that
 age and infancy were pressed without distinction into the
 service of their unrelenting prince.","('Robert', 'PERSON')"
"In
 the fourth year he corrupted, as it is said, with Byzantine
 gold, the nobles of Rome, whose estates and castles had been
 ruined by the war.","('the fourth year', 'DATE'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In
 the ruder ages of chivalry, such qualifications are not
 below the notice of the poet or historians: they may observe
 that Robert, at once, and with equal dexterity, could wield
 in the right hand his sword, his lance in the left; that in
 the battle of Civitella he was thrice unhorsed; and that in
 the close of that memorable day he was adjudged to have
 borne away the prize of valour from the warriors of the two
 armies.","('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Civitella', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In
 these actions the Norman duke was the foremost in every
 danger; in every fatigue the last and most patient.","('Norman', 'PERSON')"
"In a
 second action the emir of Syracuse was unhorsed and
 transpierced by the iron arm of William of Hauteville.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Syracuse', 'GPE'), ('William of Hauteville', 'PERSON')"
"In a
 third engagement, his intrepid companions discomfited the
 host of sixty thousand Saracens, and left the Greeks no more
 than the labor of the pursuit: a splendid victory; but of
 which the pen of the historian may divide the merit with the
 lance of the Normans.","('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Normans', 'NORP')"
"In his
 return by sea from an unfortunate crusade, Louis the Seventh
 was intercepted by the Greeks, who basely violated the laws
 of honour and religion.","('Louis the Seventh', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"In his long progress from
 Mantua to Beneventum, a vile and promiscuous multitude of
 Italians was enlisted under the holy standard: (33) the
 priest and the robber slept in the same tent; the pikes and
 crosses were intermingled in the front; and the martial
 saint repeated the lessons of his youth in the order of
 march, of encampment, and of combat.","('Mantua', 'GPE'), ('Beneventum', 'GPE'), ('Italians', 'NORP'), ('33', 'CARDINAL')"
"In his old age he related with
 pleasure, that, by the distress of the siege, himself, and
 the countess his wife, had been reduced to a single cloak or
 mantle, which they wore alternately; that in a sally his
 horse had been slain, and he was dragged away by the
 Saracens; but that he owed his rescue to his good sword, and
 had retreated with his saddle on his back, lest the meanest
 trophy might be left in the hands of the miscreants.","('Saracens', 'NORP')"
"In less than three
 years, the son of Tancred of Hauteville enjoyed the glory of
 delivering the pope, and of compelling the two emperors, of
 the East and West, to fly before his victorious arms. (85)","('less than three\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Tancred of Hauteville', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('85', 'CARDINAL')"
"In one of
 these pious visits to the cavern of Mount Garganus in
 Apulia, which had been sanctified by the apparition of the
 archangel Michael, (18) they were accosted by a stranger in
 the Greek habit, but who soon revealed himself as a rebel, a
 fugitive, and a mortal foe of the Greek empire.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mount Garganus', 'LOC'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Michael', 'PERSON'), ('18', 'DATE'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"In successive expeditions, the king of Sicily or his
 lieutenants reduced the cities of Tunis, Safax, Capsia, Bona, and a long tract of the sea-coast; (106) the fortresses
 were garrisoned, the country was tributary, and a boast that it held Africa in subjection might be inscribed with some flattery on the sword of Roger. (107)","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Tunis', 'GPE'), ('Safax', 'GPE'), ('Capsia', 'GPE'), ('Bona', 'GPE'), ('106', 'CARDINAL'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('107', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the
 neighbourhood of Larissa the events of war were protracted
 and balanced.","('Larissa', 'GPE')"
"In the
 siege of Trani, three hundred Normans withstood and repulsed
 the forces of the island.","('Trani', 'GPE'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Normans', 'NORP')"
"In the Roman host, the loss of
 Greeks, Turks, and English, amounted to five or six
 thousand: (76) the plain of Durazzo was stained with noble
 and royal blood; and the end of the impostor Michael was
 more honorable than his life.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('English', 'LANGUAGE'), ('five or six\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('76', 'CARDINAL'), ('Durazzo', 'PERSON'), ('Michael', 'PERSON')"
"In the absence of the emperor, Constantinople and the Hellespont were left without defence and without the suspicion of danger.","('Constantinople', 'PERSON'), ('Hellespont', 'PERSON')"
"In the calm
 of retirement, the well-meaning pope deplored the effusion
 of Christian blood, which must be imputed to his account: he
 felt, that he had been the author of sin and scandal; and as
 his undertaking had failed, the indecency of his military
 character was universally condemned. (35)","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"In the centre of
 the province, the common habitation of Melphi was reserved
 as the metropolis and citadel of the republic; a house and
 separate quarter was allotted to each of the twelve counts:
 and the national concerns were regulated by this military
 senate.","('Melphi', 'GPE'), ('quarter', 'CARDINAL'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the field of Ceramio, fifty
 thousand horse and foot were overthrown by one hundred and
 thirty-six Christian soldiers, without reckoning St. George,
 who fought on horseback in the foremost ranks.","('Ceramio', 'GPE'), ('fifty\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred and\r\n thirty-six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('St. George', 'PERSON')"
"In the first attempt,
 Roger braved, in an open boat, the real and fabulous dangers
 of Scylla and Charybdis; landed with only sixty soldiers on
 a hostile shore; drove the Saracens to the gates of Messina
 and safely returned with the spoils of the adjacent country.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('Scylla', 'PRODUCT'), ('Charybdis', 'PRODUCT'), ('only sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saracens', 'PRODUCT'), ('Messina', 'GPE')"
"In the first conflict, their valour prevailed; but
 in the second engagement they were overwhelmed by the
 numbers and military engines of the Greeks, and indignantly
 retreated with their faces to . the enemy.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"In the first onset, the
 battle-axes of the strangers made a deep and bloody
 impression on the army of Guiscard, which was now reduced to
 fifteen thousand men.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Guiscard', 'PRODUCT'), ('fifteen thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the fortress of Trani, his active and patient courage
 were equally conspicuous.","('Trani', 'GPE')"
"In the hour of triumph, he assembled
 his troops, and solicited the Normans to confirm by their
 suffrage the judgment of the vicar of Christ: Duke of Apulia, A.D. 1060.","('the hour', 'TIME'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Duke of Apulia', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 1060', 'DATE')"
"In the most propitious season of the year, as
 his fleet passed along the coast, a storm of wind and snow
 unexpectedly arose: the Adriatic was swelled by the raging
 blast of the south, and a new shipwreck confirmed the old
 infamy of the Acroceraunian rocks. (67)","('the most propitious season of the year', 'DATE'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC'), ('Acroceraunian', 'NORP'), ('67', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the plains of Cannae, the Asiatics fled before the
 adventurers of France; the duke of Lombardy was made
 prisoner; the Apulians acquiesced in a new dominion; and the
 four places of Bari, Otranto, Brundusium, and Tarentum, were
 alone saved in the shipwreck of the Grecian fortunes.","('Cannae', 'GPE'), ('Asiatics', 'NORP'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Lombardy', 'GPE'), ('Apulians', 'NORP'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bari', 'GPE'), ('Otranto', 'GPE'), ('Brundusium', 'GPE'), ('Tarentum', 'GPE'), ('Grecian', 'NORP')"
"In the poverty
 of the state, he presumed to borrow the superfluous
 ornaments of the churches: the desertion of the Manichaeans
 was supplied by some tribes of Moldavia: a reinforcement of
 seven thousand Turks replaced and revenged the loss of their
 brethren; and the Greek soldiers were exercised to ride, to
 draw the bow, and to the daily practice of ambuscades and
 evolutions.","('Manichaeans', 'NORP'), ('Moldavia', 'GPE'), ('seven thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"In the prosecution of his enterprise, the courage
 of Guiscard was assailed by every form of danger and
 mischance.","('Guiscard', 'PERSON')"
"In the revolution of human events, a new ambuscade was concealed in the Caudine Forks, the fields of
 Cannae were bedewed a second time with the blood of the Africans, and the sovereign of Rome again attacked or defended the walls of Capua and Tarentum.","('the Caudine Forks', 'LOC'), ('Cannae', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Africans', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Capua', 'GPE'), ('Tarentum', 'GPE')"
"In their wars against the Roman church, the emperor and his son Mainfroy were strengthened and disgraced by the service of the enemies of Christ; and this national colony maintained their religion and manners in the heart of Italy, till they were extirpated, at the end of the thirteenth century, by the zeal and revenge of the house of Anjou. (139)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Mainfroy', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('the end of the thirteenth century', 'DATE'), ('Anjou', 'GPE'), ('139', 'CARDINAL')"
"In this
 emergency, the emperor had not disdained the impure aid of
 the Paulicians or Manichaeans of Thrace and Bulgaria; and
 these heretics united with the patience of martyrdom the
 spirit and discipline of active valour. (71)","('Paulicians', 'NORP'), ('Manichaeans', 'NORP'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Bulgaria', 'GPE'), ('71', 'CARDINAL')"
In this extremity (he interrogates a friend) how must the Sicilians act?,"('Sicilians', 'NORP')"
"In this invasion, of some moment in the annals of commerce, the Normans spread themselves by sea, and over the provinces of Greece; and the venerable age of Athens, Thebes, and Corinth, was violated by rapine and cruelty.","('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Thebes', 'GPE'), ('Corinth', 'GPE')"
"Instead of resigning
 the investiture of benefices, he dexterously applied to his
 own profit the papal claims: the supremacy of the crown was
 secured and enlarged, by the singular bull, which declares
 the princes of Sicily hereditary and perpetual legates of
 the Holy See. (58)","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('the Holy See.', 'PERSON'), ('58', 'CARDINAL')"
"It is more than probable that Guiscard was not afflicted by
 the loss of a costly pageant, which had merited only the
 contempt and derision of the Greeks.","('Guiscard', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"It is, however, true, that they
 essentially promoted the success of Maniaces, who reduced
 thirteen cities, and the greater part of Sicily, under the
 obedience of the emperor.","('Maniaces', 'NORP'), ('thirteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sicily', 'GPE')"
"It was the
 design of Constantine to transplant the warlike colony from
 the Italian provinces to the Persian war; and the son of
 Melo distributed among the chiefs the gold and manufactures
 of Greece, as the first-fruits of the Imperial bounty.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('the Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('Melo', 'PERSON'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"It was the right and
 duty, it might be the interest and glory, of Manuel to
 restore the ancient majesty of the empire, to recover the
 provinces of Italy and Sicily, and to chastise this
 pretended king, the grandson of a Norman vassal. (112)","('Manuel', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Norman', 'NORP'), ('112', 'CARDINAL')"
"It would have been imprudent in the Byzantine monarch to transport his stationary troops of Asia to an Italian campaign; and the Latin arms would have been insufficient if
 his superior navy had not occupied the mouth of the Gulf.","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Gulf', 'LOC')"
Lamentation of the historian Falcandus.,"('Falcandus', 'PERSON')"
"Last war of the Greeks and Normans, A.D. 1185.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 1185', 'DATE')"
"League of the Pope and the two empires, A.D. 1049-1054.","('League of the Pope', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('A.D. 1049-1054', 'DATE')"
"Mahadia was besieged by George the Sicilian admiral, with a fleet of one hundred and fifty galleys, amply provided with men and the instruments of mischief: the sovereign had fled, the Moorish governor refused to
 capitulate, declined the last and irresistible assault, and secretly escaping with the Moslem inhabitants abandoned the place and its treasures to the rapacious Franks.","('Mahadia', 'PERSON'), ('George', 'PERSON'), ('Sicilian', 'NORP'), ('one hundred and fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moorish', 'NORP'), ('Moslem', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"Of the Latin princes, the allies of Alexius and enemies of
 Robert, the most prompt and powerful was Henry the Third or
 Fourth, king of Germany and Italy, and future emperor of the
 West.","('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Henry', 'PERSON'), ('Third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"Of the fashionable superstitions, they
 embraced with ardour the pilgrimages of Rome, Italy, and the Holy Land.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('the Holy Land', 'GPE')"
"Of the wrongs of Athens, no memorial remains.","('Athens', 'GPE')"
"On his
 accession, Alexius found the camp without soldiers, and the
 treasury without money; yet such were the vigour and activity
 of his measures, that in six months he assembled an army of
 seventy thousand men, (69) and performed a march of five
 hundred miles.","('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('six months', 'DATE'), ('seventy thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('69', 'DATE'), ('five\r\n hundred miles', 'QUANTITY')"
On that day the scale of war was turned against the Franks by the valour of the Saracens. (8),"('that day', 'DATE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('8', 'CARDINAL')"
"On the approach of the Normans, the lower town of Corinth was evacuated; the Greeks retired
 to the citadel, which was seated on a lofty eminence, abundantly watered by the classic fountain of Pirene; an impregnable fortress, if the want of courage could be balanced by any advantages of art or nature.","('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Corinth', 'GPE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Pirene', 'GPE')"
"On the first intelligence of his premature death, Roger sailed from Palermo with seven galleys, cast anchor in
 the Bay of Salerno, received, after ten days' negotiation,
 an oath of fidelity from the Norman capital, commanded the
 submission of the barons, and extorted a legal investiture
 from the reluctant popes, who could not long endure either
 the friendship or enmity of a powerful vassal.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('Palermo', 'GPE'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Bay of Salerno', 'ORG'), (""ten days'"", 'DATE'), ('Norman', 'NORP')"
"On the hostile approach of Leo, they knelt without
 disgrace or reluctance before their spiritual father.","('Leo', 'PERSON')"
"On the left, and in the centre, Richard count of Aversa, and Robert the
 famous Guiscard, attacked, broke, routed, and pursued the
 Italian multitudes, who fought without discipline, and fled
 without shame.","('Richard', 'PERSON'), ('Aversa', 'PERSON'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Guiscard', 'PERSON'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
"On the report and distant prospect
 of these formidable numbers, Robert assembled a council of
 his principal officers.","('Robert', 'PERSON')"
"On the side of the
 land, they were pressed by the Almohades, the fanatic
 princes of Morocco, while the sea-coast was open to the
 enterprises of the Greeks and Franks, who, before the close
 of the eleventh century, had extorted a ransom of two
 hundred thousand pieces of gold.","('Almohades', 'NORP'), ('Morocco', 'GPE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('the close\r\n of the eleventh century', 'DATE'), ('two\r\n hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"On their return to Normandy, they
 kindled a spark of enterprise, and a small but intrepid band
 was freely associated for the deliverance of Apulia.","('Normandy', 'GPE'), ('Apulia', 'GPE')"
"Oppression of Apulia,A.D. 1046 etc.","('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1046', 'DATE')"
"Origin of the Normans in Italy, A.D. 1016.","('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1016', 'DATE')"
Origin of the papal investitures to the Normans.,"('Normans', 'NORP')"
"Perhaps
 he already trusted to his secret correspondence with a
 Venetian noble, who sold the city for a rich and honorable
 marriage.","('Venetian', 'NORP')"
"Reign and ambition of Roger, great count of Sicily , A.D. 1101-1154, February 26.","('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('1101-1154', 'DATE'), ('February 26', 'DATE')"
"Return of Robert, and the actions of Bohemond.","('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON')"
"Robert himself, in the seventieth year of his age, expired
 in his tent; and a suspicion of poison was imputed, by
 public rumour, to his wife, or to the Greek emperor. (92)","('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('the seventieth year', 'DATE'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('92', 'CARDINAL')"
"Robert invades the Eastern empire, A.D. 1081.","('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 1081', 'DATE')"
"Robert was the
 eldest of the seven sons of the second marriage; and even
 the reluctant praise of his foes has endowed him with the
 heroic qualities of a soldier and a statesman.","('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"Roger, his second son and successor,
 immediately sunk to the humble station of a duke of Apulia:
 the esteem or partiality of his father left the valiant
 Bohemond to the inheritance of his sword.","('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON')"
"Roger, the twelfth and last of the sons of Tancred, had been
 long detained in Normandy by his own and his father' age.","('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('twelfth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Tancred', 'PERSON'), ('Normandy', 'GPE')"
"Roger, with the
 title of great count, obtained the sovereignty of the
 largest and most fruitful island of the Mediterranean; and
 his administration displays a liberal and enlightened mind,
 above the limits of his age and education.","('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC')"
"Salerno, and some places along the western coast,
 maintained their fidelity to the Norman king; but he lost in
 two campaigns the greater part of his continental
 possessions; and the modest emperor, disdaining all flattery
 and falsehood, was content with the reduction of three
 hundred cities or villages of Apulia and Calabria, whose
 names and titles were inscribed on all the walls of the
 palace.","('Salerno', 'GPE'), ('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('three\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Calabria', 'GPE')"
School of Salerno.,"('School of Salerno', 'ORG')"
"Second expedition of Robert into Greece, A.D. 1084, October.","('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1084', 'DATE'), ('October', 'DATE')"
"Seven miles to the west of Salerno, and thirty to the south of Naples, the obscure town of Amalphi displayed the power and rewards of industry.","('Seven miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Salerno', 'GPE'), ('thirty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Amalphi', 'GPE')"
"Several of the nobles
 embraced the cause of the Greek monarch; the splendid
 nuptials of his niece with Odo Frangipani secured the
 support of that powerful family, (116) and his royal standard
 or image was entertained with due reverence in the ancient
 metropolis. (117)","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Odo Frangipani', 'PERSON'), ('117', 'CARDINAL')"
"Should Calabria be lost, the lofty towers, the numerous youth, and the naval strength, of Messina, (132) might guard the passage against a foreign invader.","('Calabria', 'GPE'), ('Messina', 'PERSON'), ('132', 'CARDINAL')"
"Siege of Durazzo, A.D. 1081, June 17.","('Durazzo', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1081', 'DATE'), ('June 17', 'DATE')"
"Since the conquest of Sicily by the Arabs, the Grecian
 emperors had been anxious to regain that valuable
 possession; but their efforts, however strenuous, had been
 opposed by the distance and the sea.","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Grecian', 'NORP')"
"Since the decease of Robert Guiscard, the Normans had relinquished, above sixty years, their hostile designs against the empire of the East.","('Robert Guiscard', 'PERSON'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('sixty years', 'DATE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"So scanty was his allowance for himself and forty followers,
 that he descended from conquest to robbery, and from robbery
 to domestic theft; and so loose were the notions of
 property, that, by his own historian, at his special
 command, he is accused of stealing horses from a stable at
 Melphi. (52)","('forty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Melphi', 'ORG')"
"Such tardy progress, in a
 narrow space, may seem unworthy of the abilities of the
 chief and the spirit of the nation; but the Normans were few
 in number; their resources were scanty; their service was
 voluntary and precarious.","('Normans', 'NORP')"
"Such was the event of the last contest between the Greeks and Normans: before the expiration of twenty years, the rival nations were lost or degraded in foreign servitude; and the successors of Constantine did not long survive to insult the fall of the Sicilian monarchy.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('twenty years', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Sicilian', 'NORP')"
"Ten years after this revolution, the French monarchs annexed to their crown the duchy of Normandy: the sceptre of her ancient dukes had been transmitted, by a granddaughter of William the Conqueror, to the house of Plantagenet; and the adventurous Normans, who had raised so many trophies in France, England, and Ireland, in Apulia, Sicily, and the East, were lost, either in victory or servitude, among the vanquished nations.","('Ten years', 'DATE'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Normandy', 'GPE'), ('William the Conqueror', 'PERSON'), ('Plantagenet', 'NORP'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('Ireland', 'GPE'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"That camp was
 soon afflicted with a pestilential disease; five hundred
 knights perished by an inglorious death; and the list of
 burials (if all could obtain a decent burial) amounted to
 ten thousand persons.","('five hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"That city, the western key of the empire,
 was guarded by ancient renown, and recent fortifications, by
 George Palaeologus, a patrician, victorious in the Oriental
 wars, and a numerous garrison of Albanians and Macedonians,
 who, in every age, have maintained the character of
 soldiers.","('George Palaeologus', 'PERSON'), ('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('Albanians', 'NORP'), ('Macedonians', 'NORP')"
"That unfortunate friend was acknowledged by the duke, and
 adorned with the pomp and titles of Imperial dignity: in his
 triumphal progress through Apulia and Calabria, Michael (62)
 was saluted with the tears and acclamations of the people;
 and Pope Gregory the Seventh exhorted the bishops to preach,
 and the Catholics to fight, in the pious work of his
 restoration.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Calabria', 'PERSON'), ('Michael', 'PERSON'), ('62', 'DATE'), ('Pope Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Seventh', 'ORDINAL'), ('Catholics', 'NORP')"
"The
 Germans (34) have been described as unskillful in the
 management of the horse and the lance, but on foot they
 formed a strong and impenetrable phalanx; and neither man,
 nor steed, nor armour, could resist the weight of their long
 and two-handed swords.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('34', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 fraud had been contrived by the subtle Guiscard; and he
 trusted, that after this pretender had given a decent colour
 to his arms, he would sink, at the nod of the conqueror,
 into his primitive obscurity.","('Guiscard', 'PERSON')"
"The
 government was popular, under the administration of a duke
 and the supremacy of the Greek emperor.","('Greek', 'NORP')"
"The
 independent standard of Aversa afforded shelter and encouragement to the outlaws of the province, to every fugitive who had escaped from the injustice or justice of his superiors; and these foreign associates were quickly
 assimilated in manners and language to the Gallic colony.","('Aversa', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP')"
"The
 natives of Calabria were still attached to the Greek
 language and worship, which had been inexorably proscribed
 by the Latin clergy: after the loss of her dukes, Apulia was
 chained as a servile appendage to the crown of Sicily; the
 founder of the monarchy had ruled by the sword; and his
 death had abated the fear, without healing the discontent,
 of his subjects: the feudal government was always pregnant
 with the seeds of rebellion; and a nephew of Roger himself
 invited the enemies of his family and nation.","('Calabria', 'LOC'), ('Greek', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Apulia', 'PERSON'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Roger', 'PERSON')"
"The
 pride of Anacletus was pleased to confer a title, which the
 pride of the Norman had stooped to solicit; (101) but his own
 legitimacy was attacked by the adverse election of Innocent
 the Second; and while Anacletus sat in the Vatican, the
 successful fugitive was acknowledged by the nations of
 Europe.","('Anacletus', 'PERSON'), ('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('101', 'CARDINAL'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Anacletus', 'PERSON'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"The
 pride of Manuel disdained and rejected a Barbarian
 colleague; his ambition was excited by the hope of stripping
 the purple from the German usurpers, and of establishing, in
 the West, as in the East, his lawful title of sole emperor
 of the Romans.","('Manuel', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The
 school of medicine has long slept in the name of a
 university; but her precepts are abridged in a string of
 aphorisms, bound together in the Leonine verses, or Latin
 rhymes, of the twelfth century. (50) Trade of Amalphi.","('Leonine', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('the twelfth century', 'DATE'), ('50', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 strength of the Greek army consisted in the Varangians, the
 Scandinavian guards, whose numbers were recently augmented
 by a colony of exiles and volunteers from the British Island
 of Thule.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Varangians', 'NORP'), ('Scandinavian', 'NORP'), ('the British Island\r\n of Thule', 'ORG')"
"The
 tents of the besiegers were converted into barracks, to
 sustain the inclemency of the winter; and in answer to the
 defiance of the garrison, Robert insinuated, that his
 patience was at least equal to their obstinacy. (77)","('Robert', 'PERSON')"
"The
 victorious Robert reproached the tardy and feeble pursuit
 which had suffered the escape of so illustrious a prize: but
 he consoled his disappointment by the trophies and standards
 of the field, the wealth and luxury of the Byzantine camp,
 and the glory of defeating an army five times more numerous
 than his own.","('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('five', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Apulian and
 Ragusian vessels fled to the shore, several were cut from
 their cables, and dragged away by the conqueror; and a sally
 from the town carried slaughter and dismay to the tents of
 the Norman duke.","('Apulian', 'NORP'), ('Ragusian', 'NORP'), ('Norman', 'PERSON')"
"The Arabs of Sicily derived a frequent and powerful
 succour from their countrymen of Africa: in the siege of
 Palermo, the Norman cavalry was assisted by the galleys of
 Pisa; and, in the hour of action, the envy of the two
 brothers was sublimed to a generous and invincible
 emulation.","('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Palermo', 'GPE'), ('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('Pisa', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Archipelago and Ionian Sea were covered with his squadrons and those of Venice; but I know
 not by what favourable allowance of transports, victuallers, and pinnaces, our reason, or even our fancy, can be reconciled to the stupendous account of fifteen hundred vessels, which is proposed by a Byzantine historian.","('Archipelago', 'LOC'), ('Ionian Sea', 'LOC'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('fifteen hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"The Byzantine Caesars acquiesced in this shadow of dominion, without expecting, perhaps without desiring, the service of a Norman army; and the truce of thirty years was not disturbed by any hostilities between Sicily and Constantinople.","('The Byzantine Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Norman', 'NORP'), ('thirty years', 'DATE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
The Emperor Manuel Comnenus.,"('Manuel Comnenus', 'PERSON')"
"The Genoese, who enjoyed a beneficial trade and establishment in Sicily, listened to the promise of his boundless gratitude and speedy departure: (138) their fleet commanded the straits of Messina, and opened the harbour of Palermo; and the first act of his government was to abolish the privileges, and to seize the property, of these imprudent allies.","('Genoese', 'PERSON'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('138', 'CARDINAL'), ('Messina', 'GPE'), ('Palermo', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The German, (82) who was already in Lombardy at the head of an army and a faction,
 accepted these liberal offers, and marched towards the
 south: his speed was checked by the sound of the battle of
 Durazzo; but the influence of his arms, or name, in the
 hasty return of Robert, was a full equivalent for the
 Grecian bribe.","('German', 'NORP'), ('82', 'DATE'), ('Lombardy', 'GPE'), ('Durazzo', 'PERSON'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Grecian', 'NORP')"
"The Greeks (125) accuse and magnify the wanton and sacrilegious cruelties that were perpetrated in the sack of Thessalonica, the second city of the empire.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('125', 'CARDINAL'), ('Thessalonica', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"The Greeks assumed as their own the merit of the conquest and the pomp of the triumph; extolled the greatness of their powers, and affected to deride the intemperance and sloth of the handful of Barbarians who appeared under the banners of the Carlovingian prince.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Carlovingian', 'NORP')"
"The Italian conquests of Robert correspond with the limits
 of the present kingdom of Naples; and the countries united
 by his arms have not been dissevered by the revolutions of
 seven hundred years. (46)","('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('seven hundred years', 'DATE'), ('46', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Latin historians (124) expatiate on the rapid progress of the four counts who invaded Romania with a fleet and army, and reduced many castles and cities to the obedience of the king of Sicily.","('Latin', 'NORP'), ('124', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romania', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE')"
"The Lombards and Calabrians
 ignominiously turned their backs; they fled towards the
 river and the sea; but the bridge had been broken down to
 check the sally of the garrison, and the coast was lined
 with the Venetian galleys, who played their engines among
 the disorderly throng.","('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('Calabrians', 'NORP'), ('Venetian', 'NORP')"
"The Moslems were
 maintained in the free enjoyment of their religion and
 property: (56) a philosopher and physician of Mazara, of the
 race of Mahomet, harangued the conqueror, and was invited to
 court; his geography of the seven climates was translated
 into Latin; and Roger, after a diligent perusal, preferred
 the work of the Arabian to the writings of the Grecian
 Ptolemy. (57)","('Moslems', 'NORP'), ('56', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mazara', 'PERSON'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('the Grecian\r\n Ptolemy', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('57', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Normans led the van and
 the Arabs of Messina felt the valour of an untried foe.","('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Messina', 'GPE')"
"The Normans of Apulia
 could muster in the field no more than three thousand horse,
 with a handful of infantry: the defection of the natives
 intercepted their provisions and retreat; and their spirit,
 incapable of fear, was chilled for a moment by superstitious
 awe.","('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('no more than three thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Normans of Apulia were seated on the verge of the two
 empires; and, according to the policy of the hour, they
 accepted the investiture of their lands, from the sovereigns
 of Germany or Constantinople.","('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('the hour', 'TIME'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The Normans serve in Sicily, A.D. 1038.","('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1038', 'DATE')"
"The Normans were no
 longer the bold and experienced mariners who had explored
 the ocean from Greenland to Mount Atlas, and who smiled at
 the petty dangers of the Mediterranean.","('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Greenland', 'LOC'), ('Mount Atlas', 'LOC'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC')"
"The Saracens of Sicily, the subjects of Roger, and
 auxiliaries of his brother, embraced this fair occasion of
 rifling and profaning the holy city of the Christians: many
 thousands of the citizens, in the sight, and by the allies,
 of their spiritual father were exposed to violation,
 captivity, or death; and a spacious quarter of the city,
 from the Lateran to the Coliseum, was consumed by the
 flames, and devoted to perpetual solitude. (87)","('The Saracens of Sicily', 'PERSON'), ('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('quarter', 'CARDINAL'), ('Lateran', 'NORP'), ('Coliseum', 'FAC')"
"The Saracens, Franks, and Greeks, in Italy.","('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The Varangians were supported by some
 companies of Franks or Latins; and the rebels, who had fled
 to Constantinople from the tyranny of Guiscard, were eager
 to signalize their zeal and gratify their revenge.","('Varangians', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Guiscard', 'ORG')"
"The Zeirides, (103) the descendants of
 Joseph, forgot their allegiance and gratitude to a distant
 benefactor, grasped and abused the fruits of prosperity; and
 after running the little course of an Oriental dynasty, were
 now fainting in their own weakness.","('Zeirides', 'PERSON'), ('103', 'CARDINAL'), ('Joseph', 'PERSON'), ('Oriental', 'NORP')"
"The ancient walls, which encompassed, without guarding, the opulence of Thebes, were scaled by the Latin Christians; but their sole use of the gospel was to sanctify an oath, that the lawful owners had not secreted any relic of their inheritance or industry.","('Thebes', 'GPE'), ('the Latin Christians', 'NORP')"
"The army and the march of the emperor Alexius, April-September.","('Alexius', 'PERSON'), ('April-September', 'DATE')"
"The artful pontiff might flatter the vanity of Guiscard with
 the hope of a Roman or Imperial crown; but this dangerous
 measure, which would have inflamed the ambition of the
 Norman, must forever have alienated the most faithful
 princes of Germany.","('Guiscard', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"The assassins were chastised; and the son of Melo,
 overthrown and wounded, was driven from the field, to hide
 his shame behind the walls of Bari, and to await the tardy
 succour of his allies.","('Melo', 'PERSON'), ('Bari', 'PERSON')"
"The bold appearance of the Normans
 revived his hopes and solicited his confidence: they
 listened to the complaints, and still more to the promises,
 of the patriot.","('Normans', 'NORP')"
"The bravest designs of the duke
 were sometimes opposed by the free voice of his parliament
 of barons: the twelve counts of popular election conspired
 against his authority; and against their perfidious uncle,
 the sons of Humphrey demanded justice and revenge.","('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('Humphrey', 'PERSON')"
"The broken provinces of the Greeks,
 Lombards, and Saracens, were exposed to every invader, and
 every sea and land were invaded by the adventurous spirit of
 the Scandinavian pirates.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Scandinavian', 'NORP')"
"The capital of the Zeirides was named Africa
 from the country, and Mahadia (105) from the Arabian founder: it is strongly built on a neck of land, but the imperfection of the harbour is not compensated by the fertility of the
 adjacent plain.","('Zeirides', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Mahadia', 'PERSON'), ('105', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabian', 'NORP')"
"The captive
 banners, with four camels, were reserved for the successor
 of St. Peter; and had these barbaric spoils been exposed,
 not in the Vatican, but in the Capitol, they might have
 revived the memory of the Punic triumphs.","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('Punic', 'NORP')"
"The chiefs of the nation who attended his
 coronation at Palermo might doubtless pronounce under what
 name he should reign over them; but the example of a Greek
 tyrant or a Saracen emir was insufficient to justify his
 regal character; and the nine kings of the Latin world (100)
 might disclaim their new associate, unless he were
 consecrated by the authority of the supreme pontiff.","('Palermo', 'GPE'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Saracen', 'NORP'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"The city and
 immediate territory of Benevento had been transferred, by
 gift or exchange, from the German emperor to the Roman
 pontiff; and although this holy land was sometimes invaded,
 the name of St. Peter was finally more potent than the sword
 of the Normans.","('Benevento', 'GPE'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('Normans', 'NORP')"
"The city of Bari rose to dignity and wealth, as the metropolis of the new theme or province of Lombardy: the title of patrician, and afterwards the singular name of Catapan, (7) was assigned to the supreme governor; and the policy both of the church and state was modelled in exact subordination to
 the throne of Constantinople.","('Bari', 'GPE'), ('Lombardy', 'GPE'), ('Catapan', 'PERSON'), ('7', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The clergy and people (for the soldiers had followed the standard of Manuel) were astonished and dismayed at the hostile appearance of a line of galleys, which boldly cast anchor in the front of the Imperial city.","('Manuel', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"The courage of Bohemond was always
 conspicuous, and often successful; but his camp was pillaged
 by a stratagem of the Greeks; the city was impregnable; and
 the venal or discontented counts deserted his standard,
 betrayed their trusts, and enlisted in the service of the
 emperor.","('Bohemond', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"The deliverer and scourge of Rome might have indulged
 himself in a season of repose; but in the same year of the
 flight of the German emperor, the indefatigable Robert
 resumed the design of his eastern conquests.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('Robert', 'PERSON')"
"The division of this flourishing state produced the rival principalities of Benevento, Salerno, and Capua; and the thoughtless ambition or revenge of the
 competitors invited the Saracens to the ruin of their common inheritance.","('Benevento', 'GPE'), ('Salerno', 'GPE'), ('Capua', 'GPE'), ('Saracens', 'NORP')"
"The dominion of the sea was
 disputed in three engagements, in sight of the Isle of
 Corfu: in the two former, the skill and numbers of the
 allies were superior; but in the third, the Normans obtained
 a final and complete victory.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Isle of\r\n Corfu', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Normans', 'NORP')"
"The ducal galley was laboriously
 rescued from the waves, and Robert halted seven days on the
 adjacent cape, to collect the relics of his loss, and revive
 the drooping spirits of his soldiers.","('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('seven days', 'DATE')"
"The dukes
 of Naples, the present metropolis, maintained the popular
 freedom, under the shadow of the Byzantine empire.","('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"The elder were
 prompted by native spirit; their success encouraged their
 younger brethren, and the three first in seniority, William,
 Drogo, and Humphrey, deserved to be the chiefs of their
 nation and the founders of the new republic.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('William', 'PERSON'), ('Drogo', 'PERSON'), ('Humphrey', 'PERSON')"
"The emir disclaimed the authority of
 the king of Tunis; the people rose against the emir; the
 cities were usurped by the chiefs; each meaner rebel was
 independent in his village or castle; and the weaker of two
 rival brothers implored the friendship of the Christians.","('Tunis', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"The emperor Henry III invited by the Greeks, A.D. 1081.","('Henry III', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 1081', 'DATE')"
"The emperor Manuel repulses the Normans, A.D. 1148, 1149.","('Manuel', 'PERSON'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 1148', 'DATE'), ('1149', 'CARDINAL')"
"The enumeration
 of provinces recalls a sad comparison of the past and
 present limits of the Roman world: the raw levies were drawn
 together in haste and terror; and the garrisons of Anatolia,
 or Asia Minor, had been purchased by the evacuation of the
 cities which were immediately occupied by the Turks.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Anatolia', 'LOC'), ('Asia Minor', 'LOC'), ('Turks', 'NORP')"
"The epistle of the Greek monarch (81) to his brother
 is filled with the warmest professions of friendship, and
 the most lively desire of strengthening their alliance by
 every public and private tie.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('81', 'CARDINAL')"
"The establishment of the Normans in the kingdoms of Naples
 and Sicily (15) is an event most romantic in its origin, and
 in its consequences most important both to Italy and the
 Eastern empire.","('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"The first
 day's action was not disadvantageous to Bohemond, a
 beardless youth, (68) who led the naval powers of his father.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Bohemond', 'PERSON'), ('68', 'DATE')"
"The first and greatest of those Saxon princes was compelled to relinquish the siege of Bari: the second, after the loss of his stoutest bishops and barons, escaped with honour from the bloody field of Crotona.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Saxon', 'NORP'), ('Bari', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Crotona', 'PERSON')"
"The first leader of the Normans was Count Rainulf; and, in the origin of society, pre-eminence of rank is the reward and the proof of superior merit. (19)","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Normans', 'NORP'), ('Rainulf', 'PERSON'), ('19', 'CARDINAL')"
"The first of his peers, their president and
 general, was entitled count of Apulia; and this dignity was
 conferred on William of the iron arm, who, in the language
 of the age, is styled a lion in battle, a lamb in society,
 and an angel in council. (25) Character of the Normans.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Apulia', 'PERSON'), ('William', 'PERSON'), ('25', 'CARDINAL'), ('Character of the Normans', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"The forces of the Sicilian admiral were inadequate to the siege or assault of an immense and populous metropolis; but George enjoyed the glory of humbling the Greek arrogance, and of marking the path of conquest to the navies of the West.","('Sicilian', 'NORP'), ('George', 'PERSON'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"The fortress of Bari was invested by the infantry of the Franks, and by the cavalry and galleys of the Greeks; and, after a defence of four years, the Arabian emir submitted to  the clemency of Lewis, who commanded in person the operations of the siege.","('Bari', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('four years', 'DATE'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('Lewis', 'PERSON')"
"The fortunate encounter of the
 Norman fleet delivered the royal captive; and after a free
 and honorable entertainment in the court of Sicily, Louis
 continued his journey to Rome and Paris. (110) insults Constantinople","('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Louis', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('110', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The free cities of Lombardy no longer remembered their foreign benefactor, and without preserving the
 friendship of Ancona, he soon incurred the enmity of Venice. (121)","('Lombardy', 'GPE'), ('Ancona', 'PERSON'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('121', 'CARDINAL')"
"The galley which transported
 the remains of Guiscard was ship-wrecked on the Italian
 shore; but the duke's body was recovered from the sea, and
 deposited in the sepulchre of Venusia, (94) a place more
 illustrious for the birth of Horace (95) than for the burial
 of the Norman heroes.","('Guiscard', 'PRODUCT'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Venusia', 'NORP'), ('94', 'CARDINAL'), ('Horace', 'PERSON'), ('95', 'DATE'), ('Norman', 'PERSON')"
"The gates of Civitella were shut
 against the flying pope, and he was overtaken by the pious
 conquerors, who kissed his feet, to implore his blessing and
 the absolution of their sinful victory.","('Civitella', 'PERSON')"
"The gates, the bridges, and fifty
 hostages, were delivered into his hands: A.D. 1081-1084, March 21.","('fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('March 21', 'DATE')"
"The heir of that Norman
 adventurer was born in Sicily; and, at the age of only four
 years, he succeeded to the sovereignty of the island, a lot
 which reason might envy, could she indulge for a moment the
 visionary, though virtuous wish of dominion.","('Norman', 'PERSON'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('only four\r\n years', 'DATE')"
The hills are covered with arms and standards; and the emperor of the Greeks is accustomed to wars and triumphs.,"('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"The hopes, or at least the wishes, of Falcandus were at first gratified by the free and unanimous election of Tancred, the grandson of the first king, whose birth was illegitimate, but whose civil and military virtues shone
 without a blemish.","('Falcandus', 'PERSON'), ('Tancred', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The infant monarchy of Roger was shaken, and almost
 overthrown, by the unlucky choice of an ecclesiastical
 patron; and the sword of Lothaire the Second of Germany, the
 excommunications of Innocent, the fleets of Pisa, and the
 zeal of St. Bernard, were united for the ruin of the
 Sicilian robber.","('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('Lothaire', 'PERSON'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Pisa', 'GPE'), ('St. Bernard', 'GPE'), ('Sicilian', 'NORP')"
"The island was restored to the jurisdiction of
 the Roman pontiff; new bishops were planted in the principal
 cities; and the clergy was satisfied by a liberal endowment
 of churches and monasteries.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The islands of Epirus and the maritime towns were
 subdued by the arms or the name of Robert, who led his fleet
 and army from Corfu (I use the modern appellation) to the
 siege of Durazzo.","('Epirus', 'LOC'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Corfu', 'GPE'), ('Durazzo', 'GPE')"
"The land, however fertile, was of narrow extent;
 but the sea was accessible and open: the inhabitants first
