Sentence,Entities
(3),"('3', 'CARDINAL')"
"(31)
Character and elevation of Majorian, A.D. 457.","('31', 'CARDINAL'), ('457', 'CARDINAL')"
"(4) Whatever abilities Maximus might have 
 shown in a subordinate station, he was found incapable of
 administering an empire: and though he might easily have
 been informed of the naval preparations which were made on
 the opposite shores of Africa, he expected with supine
 indifference the approach of the enemy, without adopting any
 measures of defence, of negotiation, or of a timely retreat.","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"(5)
Sack of Rome, A.D. 455, June15-29.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('455', 'CARDINAL'), ('June15-29', 'DATE')"
"A brave and numerous army was attached to his standard and though he was prevented by
 the arts of Ricimer and the arms of the Visigoths from
 marching to the gates of Rome, he maintained his independent
 sovereignty beyond the Alps and rendered the name of
 Aegidius respectable both in peace and war.","('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Aegidius', 'PERSON')"
"A copious
 stream, issuing from the mountain, and falling headlong in
 many a loud and foaming cascade, discharged its waters into
 a lake about two miles in length, and the villa was
 pleasantly seated on the margin of the lake.","('about two miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"A decent respect was still
 observed for the Praefectorian rank; and on his arrival at
 Rome Arvandus was committed to the hospitality, rather than
 to the custody, of Flavius Asellus, the count of the sacred
 largesses, who resided in the Capitol. (98)","('Praefectorian', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Arvandus', 'PERSON'), ('Flavius Asellus', 'PERSON'), ('Capitol', 'FAC')"
"A fleet of Vandals and Moors landed
 at the mouth of the Liris or Garigliano; but the Imperial
 troops surprised and attacked the disorderly barbarians, who
 were encumbered with the spoils of Campania, they were
 chased with slaughter to their ships, and their leader, the
 king's brother-in-law, was found in the number of the slain.
 (45)","('Vandals', 'PRODUCT'), ('Moors', 'PRODUCT'), ('Liris', 'PRODUCT'), ('Garigliano', 'PRODUCT'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Campania', 'GPE')"
"A patriot would have hesitated before he plunged himself and
 his country into those inevitable calamities which must
 follow the extinction of the royal house of Theodosius.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"A tradition that,
 in the same place, Romulus and Remus were suckled by the
 wolf, rendered it still more sacred and venerable in the
 eyes of the Romans; and this sylvan spot was gradually
 surrounded by the stately edifices of the Forum.(81) After 
 the conversion of the Imperial city, the Christians still
 continued, in the month of February, the annual celebration
 of the Lupercalia; to which they ascribed a secret and
 mysterious influence on the genial powers of the animal and
 vegetable world.","('Romulus', 'PERSON'), ('Remus', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Forum', 'ORG'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('the month of February', 'DATE'), ('Lupercalia', 'EVENT')"
"A vacant throne, which he might ascend
 without guilt or danger, tempted his ambition:(15) and the 
 Visigoths were easily persuaded to support his claim by
 their irresistible suffrage.","('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('Visigoths', 'PERSON')"
"A.D. 455, August 15.","('A.D. 455', 'DATE'), ('August 15', 'DATE')"
"About twenty years after that great revolution it
 was converted into a church and monastery, to receive the
 bones of St. Severinus.","('About twenty years', 'DATE'), ('St. Severinus', 'LOC')"
"Actuated by a
 far different spirit, Basiliscus, whose station was the most
 remote from danger, disgracefully fled in the beginning of
 the engagement, returned to Constantinople with the loss of
 more than half of his fleet and army, and sheltered his
 guilty head in the sanctuary of St. Sophia, till his sister,
 by her tears and entreaties, could obtain his pardon from
 the indignant emperor.","('Basiliscus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('more than half', 'CARDINAL'), ('St. Sophia', 'GPE')"
"Aegidius, the master-general of Gaul, who equalled, or at least who imitated, the heroes of ancient Rome,(60) proclaimed his immortal resentment against the assassins of his beloved master.","('Aegidius', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('60', 'DATE')"
"After
 the establishment of the Goths in Aquitain, and the passage
 of the Vandals into Africa, the Suevi, who had fixed their
 kingdom in Gallicia, aspired to the conquest of Spain, and
 threatened to extinguish the feeble remains of the Roman
 dominion.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Aquitain', 'GPE'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Suevi', 'PERSON'), ('Gallicia', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"After a fortnight's adjournment the senate was again
 convened to pronounce the sentence of his death: but while
 he expected, in the island of Alsculapius, the expiration of
 the thirty days allowed by an ancient law to the vilest
 malefactors, (100) his friends interposed, the emperor 
 Anthemius relented, and the praefect of Gaul obtained the
 milder punishment of exile and confiscation.","('Alsculapius', 'LOC'), ('the thirty days', 'DATE'), ('100', 'CARDINAL'), ('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"After a reign
 of fourteen years Odoacer was oppressed by the superior
 genius of Theodoric, king of the Ostrogoths; a hero alike
 excellent in the arts of war and of government, who restored
 an age of peace and prosperity, and whose name still excites
 and deserves the attention of mankind.","('fourteen years', 'DATE'), ('Odoacer', 'PERSON'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP')"
"After an interval of seven years, Odoacer restored the
 consulship of the West.","('seven years', 'DATE'), ('Odoacer', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"After extinguishing such a competitor, the emperor
 Nepos was acknowledged by the senate, by the Italians, and
 by the provincials of Gaul; his moral virtues and military
 talents were loudly celebrated, and those who derived any
 private benefit from his government announced in prophetic
 strains the restoration of the public felicity.(114)","('Nepos', 'PERSON'), ('Italians', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('114', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the death
 of Attila he renewed his alliance with the Visigoths of
 Gaul; and the sons of the elder Theodoric, who successively
 reigned over that warlike nation, were easily persuaded, by
 the sense of interest, to forget the cruel affront which
 Genseric had inflicted on their sister.(91)","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Genseric', 'PERSON')"
"After this bloody sacrifice to policy or resentment, Theodoric carried his victorious arms as far as Merida, the principal town of Lusitania, without meeting any resistance, except from the miraculous powers of St. Eulalia; but he was stopped in the full career of success, and recalled from Spain before he could provide for the security of his conquests.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Merida', 'GPE'), ('Lusitania', 'GPE'), ('St. Eulalia', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE')"
"After this event the behaviour of the two 
 antagonists showed them superior to their fortune.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"All serious business was suspended
 during this festival; the courts of justice were shut; the
 streets of Rome, the theatres, the places of public and
 private resort, resounded with hymenaeal song and dances:
 and the royal bride, clothed in silken robes, with a crown
 on her head, was conducted to the palace of Ricimer, who had
 changed his military dress for the habit of a consul and a
 senator.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Ricimer', 'PERSON')"
"Among
 the spoils, the splendid relics of two temples, or rather of
 two religions, exhibited a memorable example of the
 vicissitudes of human and divine things.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Among the events of that
 disastrous night, the heroic, or rather desperate, courage
 of John, one of the principal officers of Basiliscus, has
 rescued his name from oblivion.","('night', 'TIME'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Basiliscus', 'ORG')"
"An
 epistle was addressed, by their unanimous decree, to the
 emperor Zeno, the son-in-law and successor of Leo, who had
 lately been restored, after a short rebellion, to the
 Byzantine throne.","('Zeno', 'PERSON'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"An adequate, or at least a valuable,
 compensation was offered by the Eastern emperor to purchase
 a necessary peace.","('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"An army of Isaurians(70) was secretly levied and introduced into Constantinople; and while Leo undermined the authority, and prepared the disgrace, of the family of Aspar, his mild and cautious behaviour restrained them from any rash and desperate attempts, which might have been fatal to themselves or their enemies.","('Isaurians', 'NORP'), ('70', 'DATE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Aspar', 'PERSON')"
"An early day was fixed for his trial; and
 Arvandus appeared, with his accusers, before a numerous
 assembly of the Roman senate.","('An early day', 'DATE'), ('Arvandus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Anthemius acknowledged the truth of his maxims; but he deeply felt, with grief and indignation, the behaviour of Ricimer; and his passion gave eloquence and energy to his discourse.","('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('Ricimer', 'PERSON')"
"Anthemius, emperor of the West, A.D. 467 -472.","('Anthemius', 'PERSON')"
"Anxious to
 explore with his own eyes the state of the Vandals, he
 ventured, after disguising the colour of his hair, to visit
 Carthage in the character of his own ambassador: and
 Genseric was afterwards mortified by the discovery that he
 had entertained and dismissed the emperor of the Romans.","('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Genseric', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"As long as Aspar degraded the majesty of the throne, the secret correspondence of religion and interest engaged him to favour the cause of Genseric.","('Aspar', 'PERSON'), ('Genseric', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as the Romans breathed from the 
 toils of the Punic war, they were attracted by the beauties
 and the pleasures of Campania; and the country-house of the
 elder Scipio at Liternum exhibited a lasting model of their
 rustic simplicity.(128)","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('the Punic war', 'EVENT'), ('Campania', 'GPE'), ('Scipio', 'PERSON'), ('Liternum', 'GPE'), ('128', 'CARDINAL')"
"Aspar was astonished to
 find that his influence could no longer appoint a praefect
 of Constantinople: he presumed to reproach his sovereign
 with a breach of promise, and, insolently shaking his
 purple,  After this extraordinary scene, it was impossible that the reconciliation of the emperor and the patrician could be sincere; or, at least, that it could be solid and permanent.","('Aspar', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"At
 his solicitation they rose in arms against the obscure Greek
 who presumed to claim their obedience; and when Orestes,
 from some secret motive, declined the purple, they
 consented, with the same facility, His son Augustulus, the last emperor of the West, A.D. 476  to acknowledge his son Augustulus as the emperor of the West.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Orestes', 'PERSON'), ('Augustulus', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('A.D. 476', 'DATE'), ('Augustulus', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"At each revolution their pay and
 privileges were augmented; but their insolence increased in
 a still more extravagant degree; they envied the fortune of
 their brethren in Gaul, Spain, and Africa, whose victorious
 arms had acquired an independent and perpetual inheritance;
 and they insisted on their peremptory demand that a third
 part of the lands of Italy should be immediately divided
 among them.","('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"At his command the
 obsequious senate of Rome bestowed the Imperial title on
 Libius Severus, who ascended the throne of the West without
 emerging from the obscurity of a private condition.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Libius Severus', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"At length
 Ricimer made a furious assault on the bridge of Hadrian, or
 St. Angelo; and the narrow pass was defended with equal
 valour by the Goths till the death of Gilimer, their leader.","('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('Hadrian', 'FAC'), ('St. Angelo', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Gilimer', 'PERSON')"
"At the head of a
 band of faithful followers the intrepid Marcellinus occupied
 the province of Dalmatia, assumed the title of patrician of
 the West, secured the love of his subjects by a mild and
 equitable reign, built a fleet which claimed the dominion of
 the Hadriatic, and alternately alarmed the coasts of Italy
 and of Africa. (59) and of Aegidius in Gaul.","('Marcellinus', 'PERSON'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Hadriatic', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('59', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aegidius', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
Augustulus is banished to the Lucullan villa.,"('Augustulus', 'PERSON'), ('Lucullan', 'NORP')"
"Avitus left only one daughter, the 
 wife of Sidonius Apollinaris, who inherited the patrimony of
 his father-in-law; lamenting, at the same time, the
 disappointment of his public and private expectations.","('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('only one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sidonius Apollinaris', 'PERSON')"
"Avitus, after a decent resistance,
 accepted the Imperial diadem from the representatives of
 Gaul; and his election was ratified by the acclamations of
 the barbarians and provincials.","('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"Avitus, at a time when the
 Imperial dignity was reduced to a pre-eminence of toil and
 danger, indulged himself in the pleasures of Italian luxury:
 age had not extinguished his amorous inclinations; and he is
 accused of insulting, with indiscreet and ungenerous
 raillery, the husbands whose wives he had seduced or
 violated.(25) But the Romans were not inclined either to 
 excuse his faults or to acknowledge his virtues.","('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Avitus,(12) the stranger whose merit was so nobly rewarded, 
 descended from a wealthy and honourable family in the
 diocese of Auvergne.","('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('Auvergne', 'LOC')"
"Basiliscus, the brother of the empress Verina, was intrusted
 with this important command.","('Basiliscus', 'PERSON'), ('Verina', 'PERSON')"
"Besides the
 confederates who were already engaged in the service of the
 empire, the fame of his liberality and valour attracted the
 nations of the Danube, the Borysthenes, and perhaps of the
 Tanais.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Borysthenes', 'NORP'), ('Tanais', 'NORP')"
"But
 Rome and its inhabitants were delivered to the
 licentiousness of the Vandals and Moors, whose blind
 passions revenged the injuries of Carthage.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Moors', 'NORP'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"But Genseric
 was saved from impending and inevitable ruin by the
 treachery of some powerful subjects, envious or apprehensive
 of their master's success.","('Genseric', 'PERSON')"
"But Majorian was not ignorant that these Corporate bodies were too much inclined to retaliate the injustice and oppression which they had suffered, and he therefore revives the useful office of the defenders of cities.","('Majorian', 'PERSON')"
"But Odoacer had
 resolved to abolish that useless and expensive office; and
 such is the weight of antique prejudice, that it required
 some boldness and penetration to discover the extreme
 facility of the enterprise.","('Odoacer', 'PERSON')"
"But he possessed the more valuable qualifications of
 learning, virtue, and courage; (58) the study of the Latin 
 literature had improved his taste, and his military talents
 had recommended him to the esteem and confidence of the
 great Aetius, in whose ruin he was involved.","('58', 'CARDINAL'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON')"
"But no sooner did
 Maximus appear in the streets than he was assaulted by a
 shower of stones: a Roman or a Burgundian soldier claimed
 the honour of the first wound; his mangled body was
 ignominiously cast into the Tiber; the Roman people rejoiced
 in the punishment which they had inflicted on the author of
 the public calamities; and the domestics of Eudoxia
 signalised their zeal in the service of their mistress.","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Burgundian', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Tiber', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Eudoxia', 'PERSON')"
"But the
 fate of Gaul depended on the Visigoths; and the Roman
 general, less attentive to his dignity than to the public
 interest, did not disdain to visit Toulouse in the character
 of an ambassador.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Toulouse', 'GPE')"
"But the Christian churches,
 enriched and adorned by the prevailing superstition of the
 times, afforded more plentiful materials for sacrilege; and
 the pious liberality of pope Leo, who melted six silver
 vases, the gift of Constantine, each of an hundred pounds
 weight, is an evidence of the damage which he attempted to
 repair.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('an hundred pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"But the anger of Anthemius evaporated in these passionate exclamations: he insensibly yielded to the proposals of Epiphanius; and the bishop returned to his diocese with the satisfaction of restoring the peace of Italy by a reconciliation,(105) of which the sincerity and continuance might be reasonably suspected.","('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('Epiphanius', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('105', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the body of the senate and people firmly adhered to the
 cause of Anthemius; and the more effectual support of a
 Gothic army enabled him to prolong his reign, and the public
 distress, by a resistance of three months, which produced
 the concomitant evils of famine and pestilence.","('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('three months', 'DATE')"
"But the bravest of their youth enlisted in the army of
 confederates, who formed the defence and the terror of
 Italy;(117) and in this promiscuous multitude, the names of 
 the Heruli, the Sciri, the Alani, the Turcilingi, and the
 Rugians, appear to have predominated.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('117', 'CARDINAL'), ('Heruli', 'NORP'), ('Sciri', 'NORP'), ('Alani', 'NORP'), ('Turcilingi', 'NORP'), ('Rugians', 'NORP')"
"But the calamities of Italy had gradually subdued
 the proud consciousness of freedom and glory.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"But the day of his inauguration was the
 last day of his happiness.","('the day', 'DATE'), ('the\r\n last day', 'DATE')"
"But the discovery of his guilt, or incapacity,
 was reserved for the African war; and his friends could only
 save his military reputation by asserting that he had
 conspired with Aspar to spare Genseric, and to betray the
 last hope of the Western empire.","('the African war', 'EVENT'), ('Aspar', 'PERSON'), ('Genseric', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"But the measures of the
 Byzantine court were so languid and irresolute, that many
 months elapsed after the death of Anthemius, and even of
 Olybrius, before their destined successor could show
 himself, with a respectable force, to his Italian subjects.","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('many\r\n months', 'DATE'), ('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('Olybrius', 'PERSON'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
"But the merit of his immediate parents, their honours, 
 and their riches, rendered Anthemius one of the most
 illustrious subjects of the East, His father, Procopius,
 obtained, after his Persian embassy, the rank of general and
 patrician; and the name of Anthemius was derived from his
 maternal grandfather, the celebrated praefect, who
 protected, with so much ability and success, the infant
 reign of Theodosius.","('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"But the perpetual
 division of the two empires had alienated their interest and
 their inclinations; the faith of a recent treaty was
 alleged; and the Western Romans, instead of arms and ships,
 could only obtain the assistance of a cold and ineffectual
 mediation.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Western Romans', 'NORP')"
"But the powers of
 the Eastern empire were strenuously exerted to deliver Italy
 and the Mediterranean from the Vandals; and Genseric, who
 had so long oppressed both the land and sea, was threatened
 from every side with a formidable invasion.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC'), ('Vandals', 'LOC'), ('Genseric', 'PERSON')"
But the prudent Zeno soon deserted the hopeless cause of his abdicated colleague.,"('Zeno', 'PERSON')"
"But their intentions
 were discovered by the zeal of Sidonius.","('Sidonius', 'PERSON')"
"But this apparent guilt was expiated by his
 merit or repentance: his rank was eminent and conspicuous;
 he enjoyed the favour of Attila; and the troops under his
 command, who guarded in their turn the royal village,
 consisted of a tribe of Sciri, his immediate and hereditary
 subjects.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Sciri', 'NORP')"
"By
 his order, two spacious churches were converted into
 hospitals: the sick were distributed in convenient beds, and
 liberally supplied with food and medicines; and the aged
 prelate repeated his visits both in the day and night, with
 an assiduity that surpassed his strength, and a tender
 sympathy which enhanced the value of his services.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"By a timely
 flight Marcellinus escaped the rage of Valentinian, and
 boldly asserted his liberty amidst the convulsions of the
 Western empire.","('Marcellinus', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"By the abdication of Nepos, Orestes had now attained the summit of his ambitious
 hopes; but he soon discovered, before the end of the first
 year, that the lessons of perjury and ingratitude which a
 rebel must inculcate will be retorted against himself, and
 that the precarious sovereign of Italy was only permitted to
 choose whether he would be the slave or the victim of his
 barbarian mercenaries.","('Nepos', 'PERSON'), ('Orestes', 'PERSON'), ('the end of the first\r\n year', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"By the clemency, however,
 or the contempt of Ricimer,(28) he was permitted to descend 
 from the throne to the more desirable station of bishop of
 Placentia: but the resentment of the senate was still
 unsatisfied; and their inflexible severity pronounced the
 sentence of his death.","('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('28', 'DATE'), ('Placentia', 'GPE')"
"By this shameful abdication he protracted his
 life about five years, in a very ambiguous state between an
 emperor and an exile, till he was assassinated at Salona by
 the ungrateful Glycerius, who was translated, perhaps as the
 reward of his crime, to the archbishopric of Milan.(116)","('about five years', 'DATE'), ('Salona', 'PERSON'), ('Glycerius', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('116', 'CARDINAL')"
"Character and reign of Odoacer, A.D. 476-490.","('Odoacer', 'PERSON'), ('476-490', 'CARDINAL')"
"Character of Theoderic, king of the Visigoths, A.D. 453-466.","('Character of Theoderic', 'PERSON'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('453-466', 'CARDINAL')"
"Compare
 this scene with the field of Cannae; and judge between
 Hannibal and the successor of St. Cyprian.(11)
The emperor Avitus, A.D. 455, July 10th.","('Cannae', 'PERSON'), ('Hannibal', 'PERSON'), ('St. Cyprian', 'PERSON'), ('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 455', 'DATE'), ('July 10th', 'DATE')"
"Count Fronto was despatched, in the
 name of the emperor Avitus, with advantageous offers of
 peace and alliance; and Theodoric interposed his weighty
 mediation to declare that, unless his brother-in-law, the
 king of the Suevi, immediately retired, he should be obliged
 to arm in the cause of justice and of Rome.","('Fronto', 'PERSON'), ('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Suevi', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"During his long and active reign the African monarch had
 studiously cultivated the friendship of the barbarians of
 Europe, whose arms he might employ in a seasonable and
 effectual diversion against the two empires.","('African', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"During that interval, Glycerius, an obscure soldier, was
 invested with the purple by his patron Guniobald; but the
 Burgundian prince was unable or unwilling to support his
 nomination by a civil war: the pursuits of domestic ambition
 recalled him beyond the Alps, (113) and his client was 
 permitted to exchange the Roman sceptre for the bishopric of
 Salona.","('Glycerius', 'PERSON'), ('Guniobald', 'PERSON'), ('Burgundian', 'NORP'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('113', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Salona', 'PERSON')"
"During that period the government
 was in the hands of Ricimer alone; and although the modest
 barbarian disclaimed the name of king, he accumulated
 treasures, formed a separate army, negotiated private
 alliances, and ruled Italy with the same independent and
 despotic authority which was afterwards exercised by Odoacer
 and Theodoric But his dominions were bounded by the Alps;
 and two Roman generals, Marcellinus and Agidius, maintained
 their allegiance to the republic, by rejecting with disdain
 the phantom which he styled an emperor.","('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Odoacer', 'PERSON'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Marcellinus', 'PERSON'), ('Agidius', 'PERSON')"
"During the same period, the barbarians had
 emerged from obscurity and contempt, and the warriors of
 Germany and Scythia were introduced into the provinces, as
 the servants, the allies, and at length the masters, of the
 Romans, whom they insulted or protected.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"During the vacancy that succeeded the
 abdication of Avitus, the ambitious barbarian, whose birth
 excluded him from the Imperial dignity, governed Italy, with
 the title of Patrician; resigned to his friend the
 conspicuous station of master-general of the cavalry and
 infantry, and, after an interval of some months, consented
 to the unanimous wish of the Romans, whose favour Majorian
 had solicited by a recent victory over the Alemanni.(35)","('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Patrician', 'PERSON'), ('some months', 'DATE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Majorian', 'PERSON'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('35', 'CARDINAL')"
"During this short interval the wind
 became favourable to the designs of Genseric.","('Genseric', 'PRODUCT')"
"During three generations the armies of the East were
 successively commanded by his father, by himself, and by his
 son Ardaburius his barbarian guards formed a military force
 that overawed the palace and the capital; and the liberal
 distribution of his immense treasures rendered Aspar as
 popular as he was powerful.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Ardaburius', 'PERSON'), ('Aspar', 'PERSON')"
"Either the merit of
 Avitus excited envy, or his moderation was desirous of
 repose, since he calmly retired to an estate which he
 possessed in the neighbourhood of Clermont.","('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('Clermont', 'GPE')"
"Eudoxia and her younger daughter Placidia
 were honourably restored, and the fury of the Vandals was
 confined to the limits of the Western empire.","('Eudoxia', 'PERSON'), ('Placidia', 'PERSON'), ('Vandals', 'PRODUCT'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"Eudoxia herself,
 who advanced to meet her friend and deliverer, soon bewailed
 the imprudence of her own conduct.","('Eudoxia', 'PERSON')"
"Extinction of the Western empire, A.D. 476 or 479.","('476', 'CARDINAL'), ('479', 'CARDINAL')"
"For himself he modestly, or proudly,
 declined an honour which was still accepted by the emperors
 of the East; but the curule chair was successively filled by
 eleven of the most illustrious senators;(133) and the list is 
 adorned by the respectable name of Basilius, whose virtues
 claimed the friendship and grateful applause of Sidonius,
 his client.(134)","('East', 'LOC'), ('eleven', 'CARDINAL'), ('133', 'CARDINAL'), ('Basilius', 'PERSON'), ('Sidonius', 'PERSON'), ('134', 'CARDINAL')"
"Forty days after this calamitous event, the subject, not of glory, but of guilt, Italy was
 delivered, by a painful disease, from the tyrant Ricimer, who bequeathed the command of his army to his nephew Gundobald, one of the princes of the Burgundians.","('Forty days', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('Gundobald', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP')"
"From
 the East, however, Eudoxia could not hope to obtain any
 effectual assistance: her father and her aunt Pulcheria were
 dead; her mother languished at Jerusalem in disgrace and
 exile; and the sceptre of Constantinople was in the hands of
 a stranger.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Eudoxia', 'PERSON'), ('Pulcheria', 'PERSON'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"From all the camps and garrisons of Italy
 the confederates, actuated by the same resentment and the
 same hopes, impatiently flocked to the standard of this
 popular leader; and the unfortunate patrician, overwhelmed
 by the torrent, hastily retreated to the strong city of
 Pavia, the episcopal seat of the holy Epiphanites.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Pavia', 'GPE'), ('Epiphanites', 'NORP')"
"From his virtues alone the faithful
 citizens of Gaul derived any hopes of safety or freedom; and
 even such virtues were insufficient to avert the impending
 ruin of their country, since they were anxious to learn,
 from his authority and example, whether they should prefer
 the alternative of exile or servitude. (95)","('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"From the conversation of Philotheus, a
 Macedonian sectary, he had imbibed the spirit of religious
 toleration and the heretics of Rome would have assembled
 with impunity, if the bold and vehement censure which pope
 Hilary pronounced in the church of St. Peter had not obliged
 him to abjure the unpopular indulgence.(77) Even the Pagans, 
 a feeble and obscure remnant, conceived some vain hopes,
 from the indifference, or partiality, of Anthemius; and his
 singular friendship for the philosopher Severus, whom he
 promoted to the consulship, was ascribed to a secret project
 of reviving the ancient worship of the gods.(78)","('Philotheus', 'PERSON'), ('Macedonian', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Hilary', 'PERSON'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('Pagans', 'NORP'), ('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('78', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the field of battle Theodoric advanced to Braga, their metropolis, which still retained the splendid vestiges of its ancient commerce and dignity.(22)","('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Braga', 'GPE')"
"From the perils which he had escaped, 
 Arvandus imbibed confidence rather than wisdom; and such was
 the various, though uniform, imprudence of his behaviour,
 that his prosperity must appear much more surprising than
 his downfall.","('Arvandus', 'PERSON')"
"Genseric beheld the danger
 with firmness, and eluded it with his veteran dexterity.","('Genseric', 'PERSON')"
Glycerius & Nepos—,"('Glycerius & Nepos', 'ORG')"
"Guided by their secret
 intelligence, he surprised the unguarded fleet in the bay of
 Carthagena: many of the ships were sunk, or taken, or burnt;
 and the preparations of three years were destroyed in a
 single day.(53)","('Carthagena', 'PRODUCT'), ('three years', 'DATE'), ('a\r\n single day', 'DATE'), ('53', 'CARDINAL')"
"He
 followed the standard of Aetius, contributed to his success,
 shared, and sometimes eclipsed, his glory, and at last
 excited the jealousy of the patrician, or rather of his
 wife, who forced him to retire from the service. (34) 
 Majorian, after the death of Aetius, was recalled and
 promoted: and his intimate connection with Count Ricimer was
 the immediate step by which he ascended the throne of the
 Western empire.","('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Majorian', 'PERSON'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"He
 protested, in the most respectful language, that he was
 ready to submit his person and his dominions to the will of
 the emperor; but he requested a truce of five days to
 regulate the terms of his submission; and it was universally
 believed that his secret liberality contributed to the
 success of this public negotiation Instead of obstinately
 refusing whatever indulgence his enemy so earnestly
 solicited, the guilty, or the credulous, Basiliscus
 consented to the fatal truce; and his imprudent security
 seemed to proclaim that he already considered himself as the
 conqueror of Africa.","('five days', 'DATE'), ('Basiliscus', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"He 
 generously sold the gold and silver plate of the church to
 purchase the freedom of some, to alleviate the slavery of
 others, and to assist the wants and infirmities of a captive
 multitude, whose health was impaired by the hardships which
 they had suffered in the passage from Italy to Africa.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"He chose that moment to signify to Avitus that his reign was
 at an end; and the feeble emperor, at a distance from his
 Gothic allies, was compelled, after a short and unavailing
 struggle, to abdicate the purple.","('that moment', 'TIME'), ('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"He fled towards the Alps, with the
 humble hope, not of arming the Visigoths in his cause, but
 of securing his person and treasures in the sanctuary of
 Julian, one of the tutelar saints of Auvergne.(29) Disease, 
 or the hand of the executioner, arrested him on the road;
 yet his remains were decently transported to Brivas, or
 Brioude, in his native province, and he reposed at the feet
 of his holy patron. (30)","('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Auvergne', 'LOC'), ('29', 'CARDINAL'), ('Brivas', 'LOC'), ('Brioude', 'LOC')"
"He gave his daughter in marriage to the
 father of Majorian, a respectable officer, who administered
 the revenues of Gaul with skill and integrity; and
 generously preferred the friendship of Aetius to the
 tempting offers of an insidious court.","('Majorian', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON')"
"He had
 married Placidia, the younger daughter of Valentinian, after
 she was restored by Genseric, who still detained her sister
 Eudoxia, as the wife, or rather as the captive, of his son.","('Placidia', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Genseric', 'PERSON'), ('Eudoxia', 'PERSON')"
"He immediately
 apprised the unsuspecting criminal of his danger; and
 sincerely lamented, without any mixture of anger, the
 haughty presumption of Arvandus, who rejected, and even
 resented, the salutary advice of his friends.","('Arvandus', 'PERSON')"
"He immediately equipped a numerous
 fleet of Vandals and Moors, and cast anchor at the mouth of
 the Tiber, about three months after the death of Valentinian
 and the elevation of Maximus to the Imperial throne.","('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Moors', 'PRODUCT'), ('Tiber', 'LOC'), ('about three months', 'DATE'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"He landed his
 troops at Cape Bona, or the promontory of Mercury, about
 forty miles from Carthage.(87)","('Cape Bona', 'FAC'), ('Mercury', 'LOC'), ('about\r\n forty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('87', 'CARDINAL')"
"He landed without obstacle (for Genseric was
 master of the sea) either at Ravenna or the port of Ostia,
 and immediately proceeded to the camp of Ricimer, where he
 was received as the sovereign of the Western world.(107)
Sack of Rome and death of Anthemius, A.D. 472, July 11.","('Genseric', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Ostia', 'GPE'), ('Ricimer', 'GPE'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('107', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 472', 'DATE'), ('July 11', 'DATE')"
"He left one daughter, the off-spring of his marriage with Placidia; and the family of the great Theodosius, transplanted from Spain to Constantinople, was propagated in the female line as far as the eighth generation.(111)
Julius Nepos and Glycerius emperors of the West, A.D. 472-475 .","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Placidia', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('eighth', 'ORDINAL'), ('111', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julius Nepos', 'PERSON'), ('Glycerius', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('472-475', 'CARDINAL')"
"He manned his
 largest ships of war with the bravest of the Moors and
 Vandals; and they towed after them many large barks filled
 with combustible materials.","('Moors', 'LOC'), ('Vandals', 'PRODUCT')"
"He passed the Alps, to
 rescue the remains of Noricum from Fava, or Feletheus, king
 of the Rugians, who held his residence beyond the Danube.","('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Noricum', 'PERSON'), ('Fava', 'PERSON'), ('Feletheus', 'PERSON'), ('Rugians', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"He passed the Pyrenees at the head of a numerous army,
 subdued the cities of Saragossa and Pampeluna, vanquished in
 battle the martial nobles of the Tarragonese province,
 carried his victorious arms into the heart of Lusitania, and
 permitted the Suevi to hold the kingdom of Gallicia under
 the Gothic monarchy of Spain.(92)","('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('Saragossa', 'GPE'), ('Pampeluna', 'GPE'), ('Tarragonese', 'NORP'), ('Lusitania', 'GPE'), ('Suevi', 'NORP'), ('Gallicia', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('92', 'CARDINAL')"
"He preferred the service
 of the Italian princes, the successors of Valentinian; and,
 as he possessed the qualifications of courage, industry, and
 experience, he advanced with rapid steps in the military
 profession, till he was elevated, by the favour of Nepos
 himself, to the dignities of patrician and master-general of
 the troops.","('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Nepos', 'PERSON')"
"He recommended the obscure name
 of Leo of Thrace, a military tribune, and the principal
 steward of his household.","('Leo of Thrace', 'PERSON')"
"He rejected the audacious
 demand; and his refusal was favourable to the ambition of
 Odoacer, a bold barbarian, who assured his fellow-soldiers
 that, if they dared to associate under his command, they
 might soon extort the justice which had been denied to their
 dutiful petitions.","('Odoacer', 'PERSON')"
"He reserved 
 to the prince and senate the sole cognisance of the extreme
 cases which might justify the destruction of an ancient
 edifice; imposed a fine of fifty pounds of gold (two
 thousand pounds sterling) on every magistrate who should
 presume to grant such illegal and scandalous licence; and
 threatened to chastise the criminal obedience of their
 subordinate officers by a severe whipping and the amputation
 of both their hands.","('fifty pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('two\r\n thousand pounds sterling', 'MONEY')"
"He vanquished
 Theodoric in the field, and admitted to his friendship and
 alliance a king whom he had found not unworthy of his arms.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON')"
"He was
 compelled to abdicate the Imperial purple;","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"He was eagerly 
 pursued by his accusers, the four deputies of Gaul, who were
 all distinguished by their birth, their dignities, or their
 eloquence.","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"He was imprisoned (such is the
 lively expression of Sidonius) in the palace; and after passing a sleepless night, he sighed that he had attained the summit of his wishes, and aspired only to descend from the dangerous elevation.","('Sidonius', 'PERSON'), ('a sleepless night', 'TIME')"
He was invested with the purple at Ravenna: and the epistle which he addressed to the senate will best describe his situation and his sentiments.,"('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"He was received with courteous hospitality
 by Theodoric, the king of the Goths; but while Avitus laid
 the foundations of a solid alliance with that powerful
 nation, he was astonished by the intelligence that the
 emperor Maximus was slain, and that Rome had been pillaged
 by the Vandals.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Vandals', 'PRODUCT')"
"Heraclius
 landed on the coast of Tripoli, surprised and subdued the
 cities of that province, and prepared, by a laborious march,
 which Cato had formerly executed, (85) to join the Imperial 
 army under the walls of Carthage.","('Heraclius', 'GPE'), ('Tripoli', 'GPE'), ('Cato', 'PERSON'), ('85', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"Heraclius effected his retreat
 through the desert; Marcellinus retired to Sicily, where he
 was assassinated, perhaps at the instigation of Ricimer, by
 one of his own captains; and the king of the Vandals
 expressed his surprise and satisfaction that the Romans
 themselves should remove from the world his most formidable
 antagonists.(89) After the failure of this great expedition, 
 Genseric again became the tyrant of the sea: the coasts of
 Italy, Greece, and Asia, were again exposed to his revenge
 and avarice; Tripoli and Sardinia returned to his obedience;
 he added Sicily to the number of his provinces; and, before
 he died, in the fulness of years and of glory, he beheld the
A.D. 477.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Marcellinus', 'PERSON'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Vandals', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('89', 'CARDINAL'), ('Genseric', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Tripoli', 'GPE'), ('Sardinia', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('the\r\nA.D. 477', 'DATE')"
"His
 applications for peace became each hour more submissive, and
 perhaps more sincere; but the inflexible Majorian had
 adopted the ancient maxim that Rome could not be safe as
 long as Carthage existed in a hostile state.","('each hour', 'TIME'), ('Majorian', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"His
 own wife, the cause of these tragic events, had been
 seasonably removed by death; and the widow of Valentinian
 was compelled to violate her decent mourning, perhaps her
 real grief, and to submit to the embraces of a presumptuous
 usurper, whom she suspected as the assassin of her deceased
 husband.","('Valentinian', 'PERSON')"
"His
 resentment prompted him to join, or at least to countenance,
 the measures of a rebellious faction in Gaul; and the poet
 had contracted some guilt, which it was incumbent on him to
 expiate by a new tribute of flattery to the succeeding
 emperor.","('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"His 
 brother Paul was slain in an action near Ravenna; and the
 helpless Augustulus, who could no longer command the
 respect, was reduced to implore the clemency, of Odoacer.","('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Augustulus', 'PERSON'), ('Odoacer', 'PERSON')"
"His birth
 was noble and illustrious, since he descended from the
 Anician family; his dignity was supported by an adequate
 patrimony in land and money; and these advantages of fortune
 were accompanied with liberal arts and decent manners, which
 adorn or imitate the inestimable gifts of genius and virtue.","('Anician', 'NORP')"
"His birth and fortunes rendered
 him one of the most illustrious subjects of Pannonia.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pannonia', 'PERSON')"
"His brother Odoacer led a
 wandering life among the barbarians of Noricum, with a mind
 and a fortune suited to the most desperate adventures; and
 when he had fixed his choice, he piously visited the cell of
 Severinus, the popular saint of the country, to solicit his
 approbation and blessing.","('Odoacer', 'PERSON'), ('Noricum', 'NORP'), ('Severinus', 'PERSON')"
"His camp was
 filled with barbarian allies; his throne was supported by
 the zeal of an affectionate people; but the emperor had
 foreseen that it was impossible without a maritime power to
 achieve the conquest of Africa.","('Africa', 'LOC')"
"His charity was equal to his courage: in a time of extreme
 scarcity four thousand poor were fed at his expense; and his
 private influence levied an army of Burgundians for the
 deliverance of Auvergne.","('four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Auvergne', 'LOC')"
"His death, A.D. 455, June 12","('A.D. 455', 'DATE'), ('June 12', 'DATE')"
"His death, A.D. 461, August 7. five days after his abdication it was reported that he died of a dysentery, (54) and the humble tomb which covered his remains was 
 consecrated by the respect and gratitude of succeeding
 generations.(55) The private character of Majorian inspired love and respect.","('A.D. 461', 'DATE'), ('August 7', 'DATE'), ('five days', 'DATE'), ('54', 'DATE'), ('Majorian', 'PERSON')"
"His easy temper
 was corrupted by flattery and exasperated by opposition; he
 was forced to satisfy his importunate creditors with the
 spoils of the province; his capricious insolence offended
 the nobles of Gaul; and he sunk under the weight of the
 public hatred.","('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"His entrance was not polluted with blood; and the Goths respected the chastity of their female captives, more especially of the consecrated virgins: but the greatest part of the clergy and people were made slaves, and even the churches and altars were confounded in the universal pillage.","('Goths', 'NORP')"
"His expedition into Spain, A.D. 456.","('Spain', 'GPE'), ('456', 'CARDINAL')"
"His faithful and important services
 against the common enemy rendered him still more formidable;
 (27) and, after destroying on the coast of Corsica a fleet of 
 Vandals, which consisted of sixty galleys, Ricimer returned
 in triumph with the appellation of the 'Deliverer of Italy'.","('27', 'CARDINAL'), ('Corsica', 'GPE'), ('Vandals', 'PRODUCT'), ('sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"His manners were gradually polished, his military skill was improved, and the confederates of Italy would not have elected him for their general unless the exploits of Odoacer had established a high opinion of his courage and capacity. (122)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Odoacer', 'PERSON'), ('122', 'CARDINAL')"
"His merit was rewarded by the
 favour of the prince and senate; he thrice exercised the
 office of Praetorian praefect of Italy; he was twice
 invested with the consulship, and he obtained the rank of
 patrician.","('Praetorian', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"His nomination was unanimously
 ratified by the senate; and the servant of Aspar received
 the Imperial crown from the hands of the patriarch or
 bishop, who was permitted to express, by this unusual
 ceremony, the suffrage of the Deity.(68)","('Aspar', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('68', 'CARDINAL')"
"His sister, the wife of Leo,
 had exaggerated the merit of his former exploits against the
 Scythians.","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Scythians', 'PERSON')"
"His vanity was gratified by the title of sole emperor, and by the statues erected to his honour in the several quarters of Rome; he entertained a friendly, though ambiguous, correspondence with the patrician Odoacer; and he gratefully accepted the Imperial ensigns, the sacred ornaments of the throne and palace, which the barbarian was not unwilling to remove from the sight of the people. (124)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Odoacer', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('124', 'CARDINAL')"
"His voluntary or reluctant submission to the
 authority of Majorian was rewarded by the government of
 Sicily and the command of an army stationed in that island
 to oppose or to attack the Vandals; but his barbarian
 mercenaries, after the emperor's death, were tempted to
 revolt by the artful liberality of Ricimer.","('Majorian', 'PERSON'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Ricimer', 'PERSON')"
"I. From the first hour of his reign he was solicitous (I translate his own words) to relieve the weary fortunes of the provincials, oppressed by the accumulated weight of indictions and superindictions. (41)","('the first hour', 'TIME')"
"If the intrepid emperor
 could have infused his own spirit into the youth of Italy;
 if he could have revived in the field of Mars the manly
 exercises in which he had always surpassed his equals; he
 might have marched against Genseric at the head of a Roman
 army.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Mars', 'LOC'), ('Genseric', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Ignorant of
 his real situation, Arvandus showed himself in the Capitol
 in the white robe of a candidate, accepted indiscriminate
 salutations and offers of service, examined the shops of the
 merchants, the silks, and gems, sometimes with the
 indifference of a spectator and sometimes with the attention
 of a purchaser; and complained of the times, of the senate,
 of the prince, and of the delays of justice.","('Arvandus', 'PERSON'), ('Capitol', 'FAC')"
"In 
 the spring of each year they equipped a formidable navy in
 the port of Carthage, and Genseric himself, though in a very
 advanced age, still commanded in person the most important
 expeditions.","('the spring of each year', 'DATE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Genseric', 'GPE')"
"In all his public declarations the emperor Leo assumes the
 authority, and professes the affection of a father for his
 son Anthemius, with whom he had divided the administration
 of the universe. (83)","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Anthemius', 'PERSON')"
"In an epistle,
 dated from the court of Toulouse, the orator satisfies the
 curiosity of one of his friends, in the following
 description : (17)","('Toulouse', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('17', 'CARDINAL')"
"In his retreat towards the Pyrenees he revenged his disappointment on the country through which he passed; and, in the sack of Polentia and Astorga he showed himself a faithless ally, as well as a cruel enemy.","('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('Polentia', 'PERSON'), ('Astorga', 'PERSON')"
"In the age of
 Roman virtue the provinces were subject to the arms, and the
 citizens to the laws, of the republic, till those laws were
 subverted by civil discord, and both the city and the
 provinces became the servile property of a tyrant.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the assessment and collection of taxes Majorian restored the ordinary jurisdiction of the provincial magistrates, and suppressed the extraordinary commissions which had been introduced in the name of the emperor himself or of the Praetorian praefects.","('Majorian', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP')"
"In the defence of Clermont, their principal town, the 
 inhabitants of Auvergne sustained with inflexible resolution
 the miseries of war, pestilence, and famine; and the
 Visigoths, relinquishing the fruitless siege, suspended the
 hopes of that important conquest.","('Clermont', 'GPE'), ('Auvergne', 'LOC'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP')"
"In the division and the decline of the empire, the tributary harvests of Egypt and Africa were withdrawn; the numbers of the inhabitants continually
 diminished with the means of subsistence; and the country
 was exhausted by the irretrievable losses of war, famine,
 (139) and pestilence.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('139', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the first Punic war the
 republic had exerted such incredible diligence that, within
 sixty days after the first stroke of the axe had been given
 in the forest, a fleet of one hundred and sixty galleys
 proudly rode at anchor in the sea.(48)","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Punic war', 'EVENT'), ('sixty days', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('one hundred and sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('48', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the forty-five years that had elapsed since the
 Gothic invasion, the pomp and luxury of Rome were in some
 measure restored; and it was difficult either to escape, or
 to satisfy, the avarice of a conqueror who possessed leisure
 to collect, and ships to transport, the wealth of the
 capital.","('the forty-five years', 'DATE'), ('the\r\n Gothic invasion', 'EVENT'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In the last instance the legislator
 might seem to forget the proportion of guilt and punishment;
 but his zeal arose from a generous principle, and Majorian
 was anxious to protect the monuments of those ages in which
 he would have desired and deserved to live.","('Majorian', 'PERSON')"
"In the name of a great province, and according to
 the forms of Roman jurisprudence, they instituted a civil
 and criminal action, requiring such restitution as might
 compensate the losses of individuals, and such punishment as
 might satisfy the justice of the state.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the obscurity of the night,
 these destructive vessels were impelled against the
 unguarded and unsuspecting fleet of the Romans, who were
 awakened by the sense of their instant danger.","('the obscurity of the night', 'TIME'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"In the revolt of the nations they still adhered to
 the Huns; and, more than twelve years afterwards, the name
 of Edecon is honourably mentioned in their unequal contest
 with the Ostrogoths; which was terminated, after two bloody
 battles, by the defeat and dispersion of the Sciri.(120)","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('more than twelve years afterwards', 'DATE'), ('Edecon', 'PERSON'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sciri', 'NORP'), ('120', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the same year all the principal actors in this great revolution were removed from the stage; and the whole reign of Olybrius, and of Olybrius, October 23.","('the same year', 'DATE'), ('Olybrius', 'GPE'), ('Olybrius', 'GPE'), ('October 23', 'DATE')"
"In the space of twenty years since the death of Valentinian,
 nine emperors had successively disappeared; and the son of
 Orestes, a youth recommended only by his beauty, would be
 the least entitled to the notice of posterity, if his reign,
 which was marked by the extinction of the Roman empire in
 the West, did not leave a memorable era in the history of
 mankind.(125)","('the space of twenty years', 'DATE'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('Orestes', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('125', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the treatment of his unhappy prisoners he sometimes consulted his avarice, and sometimes indulged his cruelty; and the massacre of five hundred noble citizens of Zante or Zacynthus, whose mangled bodies he cast into the Ionian Sea, was imputed by the public indignation to his latest posterity.","('five hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Zante', 'PERSON'), ('Zacynthus', 'PERSON'), ('the Ionian Sea', 'LOC')"
"In this memorable
 judgment, which presented a lively image of the old
 republic, the Gauls exposed, with force and freedom, the
 grievances of the province; and as soon as the minds of the
 audience were sufficiently inflamed, they recited the fatal
 epistle.","('Gauls', 'NORP')"
"Instead of a sally of the Roman youth, there issued from the
 gates an unarmed and venerable procession of the bishop at
 the head of his clergy. (6)","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It is not the purpose of the present 
 chapter, or even of the present volume, to continue the
 distinct series of the Byzantine history; but a concise view
 of the reign and character of the emperor Leo may explain
 the last efforts that were attempted to save the falling
 empire of the West.(64)
Leo, emperor of the East, A.D. 457-474.","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('457-474', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was adorned by the new proprietor with Grecian arts 
 and Asiatic treasures; and the houses and gardens of
 Lucullus obtained a distinguished rank in the list of
 Imperial palaces.(131)","('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Lucullus', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('131', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was not perhaps without some regret that Ricimer
 sacrificed his friend to the interest of his ambition: but
 he resolved in a second choice to avoid the imprudent
 preference of superior virtue and merit.","('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"Italy 
 was gradually divided into two independent and hostile
 kingdoms; and the nobles of Liguria, who trembled at the
 near approach of a civil war, fell prostrate at the feet of
 the patrician, and conjured him to spare their unhappy
 country.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Liguria', 'GPE')"
"Italy was protected by the arms of its 
 conqueror; and its frontiers were respected by the
 barbarians of Gaul and Germany, who had so long insulted the
 feeble race of Theodosius.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Like the rest of the barbarians, he 
 had been instructed in the Arian heresy; but he revered the
 monastic and episcopal characters; and the silence of the
 catholics attests the toleration which they enjoyed.","('Arian', 'NORP')"
"Majorian returned to
 Italy to prosecute his labours for the public happiness; and
 as he was conscious of his own integrity, he might long
 remain ignorant of the dark conspiracy which threatened his
 throne and his life.","('Majorian', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Majorian,
 like the weakest of his predecessors, was reduced to the
 disgraceful expedient of substituting barbarian auxiliaries
 in the place of his unwarlike subjects: and his superior
 abilities could only be displayed in the vigour and
 dexterity with which he wielded a dangerous instrument, so
 apt to recoil on the hand that used it.","('Majorian', 'PERSON')"
"Majorian,
 who had often sighed over the desolation of the city,
 applied a severe remedy to the growing evil.(43)","('Majorian', 'PERSON')"
"Malicious calumny and satire excited his indignation, or if he himself were the object, his contempt;
 but he protected the freedom of wit, and in the hours which
 the emperor gave to the familiar society of his friends he
 could indulge his taste for pleasantry without degrading the
 majesty of his rank.(56)
Ricimer reigns under the name of Severus, A.D. 461-467.","('56', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('461-467', 'CARDINAL')"
"Many 
 thousand Romans of both sexes, chosen for some useful or
 agreeable qualifications, reluctantly embarked on board the
 fleet of Genseric; and their distress was aggravated by the
 unfeeling barbarians, who, in the division of the booty,
 separated the wives from their husbands, and the children
 from their parents.","('Many \r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Genseric', 'PRODUCT')"
"Many thousands of the bravest subjects of Attila,
 the Gepidae, the Ostrogoths, the Rugians, the Burgundians,
 the Suevi, the Alani, assembled in the plains of Liguria,
 and their formidable strength was balanced by their mutual
 animosities.(46)","('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Gepidae', 'NORP'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP'), ('Rugians', 'NORP'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Suevi', 'NORP'), ('Alani', 'NORP'), ('Liguria', 'GPE')"
Miserable state of Italy.,"('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Naval power of the Vandals, A.D. 439-455THE loss or desolation of the provinces from the Ocean to
 the Alps impaired the glory and greatness of Rome: her
 internal prosperity was irretrievably destroyed by the
 separation of Africa.","('Vandals', 'PRODUCT'), ('Ocean', 'LOC'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"Negotiations with the Eastern empire, A.D. 462 etc.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 462', 'DATE')"
"Nepos trembled at their approach; and,
 instead of placing a just confidence in the strength of
 Ravenna, he hastily escaped to his ships, and retired to his
 Dalmatian principality, on the opposite coast of the
 Hadriatic.","('Nepos', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Dalmatian', 'NORP'), ('Hadriatic', 'LOC')"
"Notwithstanding the prudence and success of Odoacer, his
 kingdom exhibited the sad prospect of misery and desolation.","('Odoacer', 'PERSON')"
"Odoacer devolved on the Roman magistrates the
 odious and oppressive task of collecting the public revenue;
 but he reserved for himself the merit of seasonable and
 popular indulgence.(135)","('Odoacer', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('135', 'CARDINAL')"
"Odoacer king of Italy, A.D. 476-490.","('Odoacer', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 476-490', 'DATE')"
"Odoacer passed the Hadriatic, to
 chastise the assassins of the emperor Nepos, and to acquire
 the maritime province of Dalmatia.","('Odoacer', 'PERSON'), ('Hadriatic', 'NORP'), ('Nepos', 'PERSON'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE')"
"Odoacer was the first barbarian who reigned in Italy, over a
 people who had once asserted their just superiority above
 the rest of mankind.","('Odoacer', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Olybrius emperor of the West, A.D. 472, March 23.","('West', 'LOC'), ('A.D. 472', 'DATE'), ('March 23', 'DATE')"
"On the
 first day of January, his son-in-law, Sidonius Apollinaris,
 celebrated his praises in a panegyric of six hundred verses;
 but this composition, though it was rewarded with a brass
 statue,(24) seems to contain a very moderate proportion 
 either of genius or of truth.","('the\r\n first day of January', 'DATE'), ('Sidonius Apollinaris', 'PERSON'), ('six hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('24', 'CARDINAL')"
"On the third day after the tumult, Genseric boldly advanced
 from the port of Ostia to the gates of the defenceless city.","('the third day', 'DATE'), ('Genseric', 'GPE'), ('Ostia', 'GPE')"
"On this memorable occasion, Sidonius, whose early
 ambition had been so fatally blasted, appeared as the orator
 of Auvergne, among the provincial deputies who addressed the
 throne with congratulations or complaints.(74)  A.D. 468, January 1st.","('Sidonius', 'PERSON'), ('Auvergne', 'LOC'), ('468', 'CARDINAL'), ('January 1st', 'DATE')"
One instance of their extortion would appear incredible were it not authenticated by the legislator himself.,"('One', 'CARDINAL')"
"One of the last acts of jurisdiction which the Roman senate
 exercised over their subjects of Gaul was the trial and
 condemnation of Arvandus, the Praetorian praefect.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Arvandus', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP')"
"One third of those ample estates, to which the ruin
 of Italy is originally imputed,(142) was extorted for the use 
 of the conquerors.","('One third', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('142', 'CARDINAL')"
"Onulf
 directed his steps towards Constantinople, where he sullied,
 by the assassination of a generous benefactor, the fame
 which he had acquired in arms.","('Onulf', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Oppressed by the weight of the diadem, he communicated his anxious thoughts to his friend and quaestor Fulgentius; and when he looked back with unavailing regret on the secure pleasures of his former life, the emperor exclaimed, ""O fortunate Damocles, thy reign began and ended with the same dinner;""   a well-known allusion, which Fulgentius afterwards repeated as an
 instructive lesson for princes and subjects.","('Fulgentius', 'PERSON'), ('Damocles', 'PERSON'), ('Fulgentius', 'PERSON')"
"Orestes, who has been already mentioned in this history, had
 never deserted his country.","('Orestes', 'PERSON')"
"Orestes, with a spirit which, in another
 situation, might be entitled to our esteem, chose rather to
 encounter the rage of an armed multitude than to subscribe
 the ruin of an innocent people.","('Orestes', 'PERSON')"
"Pavia was
 immediately besieged, the fortifications were stormed, the
 town was pillaged; and although the bishop might labour,
 with much zeal and some success, to save the property of the
 church and the chastity of female captives, the tumult could
 only be appeased by the execution of Orestes. (119)","('Pavia', 'PERSON'), ('Orestes', 'PERSON'), ('119', 'CARDINAL')"
"Pulcheria had bestowed her hand, and the sceptre
 of the East, on the modest virtue of Marcian: he gratefully
 reverenced her august rank and virgin chastity; and, after
 her death, he gave his people the example of the religious
 worship that was due to the memory of the Imperial saint.(65) 
 Attentive to the prosperity of his own dominions, Marcian
 seemed to behold with indifference the misfortunes of Rome;
 and the obstinate refusal of a brave and active prince to
 draw his sword against the Vandals was ascribed to a secret
 promise which had formerly been exacted from him when he was
 a captive in the power of Genseric.(66)","('Pulcheria', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Marcian', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Marcian', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Vandals', 'PERSON'), ('Genseric', 'PRODUCT'), ('66', 'CARDINAL')"
"Reign of Odoacer, the First Barbarian King of Italy.","('Odoacer', 'PERSON'), ('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Revolt of Marcellinus in Dalmatia Marcellinus still
 adhered to the old religion; and the devout Pagans, who
 secretly disobeyed the laws of the church and state,
 applauded his profound skill in the science of divination.","('Marcellinus', 'NORP'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('Marcellinus', 'PERSON'), ('Pagans', 'NORP')"
"Ricimer, apprehensive or impatient of a superior, retired
 from Rome and fixed his residence at Milan; an advantageous
 situation, either to invite or to repel the warlike tribes
 that were seated between the Alps and the Danube.(102)","('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('102', 'CARDINAL')"
"Riothamus, one of the
 independent kings or chieftains of the island, was persuaded
 to transport his troops to the continent of Gaul: he sailed
 up the Loire and established his quarters in Berry, where
 the people complained of these oppressive allies, till they
 were destroyed or dispersed by the arms of the Visigoths.(96)
Trial of Arvandus, A.D. 468.","('Riothamus', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Loire', 'LOC'), ('Berry', 'PERSON'), ('Visigoths', 'PRODUCT'), ('96', 'CARDINAL'), ('468', 'CARDINAL')"
"Rome expected from him alone the
 restitution of Africa, and the design which he formed of
 attacking the Vandals in their new settlements was the
 result of bold and judicious policy.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Vandals', 'PRODUCT')"
"Royalty was familiar to the barbarians, and the submissive
 people of Italy was prepared to obey, without a murmur, the
 authority which he should condescend to exercise as the
 vicegerent of the emperor of the West.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"Sack of Rome by Genseric, king of the Vandals.—","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Genseric', 'PERSON'), ('Vandals', 'NORP')"
"Severus expired as soon as his life
 became inconvenient to his patron; (57) and it would be 
 useless to discriminate his nominal reign in the vacant
 interval of six years between the death of Majorian and the
 elevation of Anthemius.","('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('57', 'DATE'), ('six years', 'DATE'), ('Majorian', 'NORP'), ('Anthemius', 'PERSON')"
"She directed her eyes towards Carthage; secretly
 implored the aid of the king of the Vandals; and persuaded
 Genseric to improve the fair opportunity of disguising his
 rapacious designs by the specious names of honour, justice,
 and compassion.","('Carthage', 'PERSON'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Genseric', 'PERSON')"
"She was rudely stripped
 of her jewels; and the unfortunate empress, with her two
 daughters, the only surviving remains of the great
 Theodosius, was compelled, as a captive, to follow the
 haughty Vandal, who immediately hoisted sail, and returned
 with a prosperous navigation to the port of Carthage.(9)","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Vandal', 'PERSON'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('9', 'CARDINAL')"
"Sidonius pronounced, with assurance
 and success, a panegyric which is still extant; and whatever
 might be the imperfections, either of the subject or of the
 composition, the welcome flatterer was immediately rewarded
 with the praefecture of Rome; a dignity which placed him
 among the illustrious personages of the empire, till he
 wisely preferred the more respectable character of a bishop,
 and a saint.(75)
Festival of the Lupercalia.","('Sidonius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('75', 'CARDINAL'), ('Festival of the Lupercalia', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Sidonius,
 who rejoices that he lived under a reign in which he might
 pity and assist a state-criminal, has expressed, with
 tenderness and freedom, the faults of his indiscreet and
 unfortunate friend.(97)","('Sidonius', 'PERSON')"
"Since the abolition
 of Paganism, the Capitol had been violated and abandoned;
 yet the statues of the gods and heroes were still respected,
 and the curious roof of gilt bronze was reserved for the
 rapacious hands of Genseric. (7)","('Paganism', 'NORP'), ('Capitol', 'ORG'), ('Genseric', 'PERSON')"
"Since the age of Tiberius, the decay of agriculture had been
 felt in Italy; and it was a just subject of complaint that
 the life of the Roman people depended on the accidents of
 the winds and waves.(138)","('the age of Tiberius', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('138', 'CARDINAL')"
"Since the death of the younger Theodosius, the domestic
 repose of Constantinople had never been interrupted by war
 or faction.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Specious petitions were continually addressed to the
 easy magistrates of Rome which stated the want of stones or
 bricks for some necessary service: the fairest forms of
 architecture were rudely defaced for the sake of some paltry
 or pretended repairs; and the degenerate Romans, who
 converted the spoil to their own emolument, demolished, with
 sacrilegious hands, the labours of their ancestor.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"St. Ambrose has deplored the ruin of a populous district, which had been once adorned with the flourishing cities of Bologna, Modena, Rhegium, and
 Placentia.(140) Pope Gelasius was a subject of Odoacer; and he affirms, with strong exaggeration, that in Aemilia, Tuscany, and the adjacent provinces, the human species was
 almost extirpated.(141)","('St. Ambrose', 'GPE'), ('Bologna', 'GPE'), ('Modena', 'GPE'), ('Rhegium', 'GPE'), ('Placentia', 'GPE'), ('140', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pope Gelasius', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Odoacer', 'PERSON'), ('Aemilia', 'GPE'), ('Tuscany', 'GPE'), ('141', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such a challenge urged Theodoric to prevent the bold designs of his enemy: he passed the Pyrenees at the head of the Visigoths; the Franks and Burgundians served under his standard; and though he professed himself the dutiful servant of Avitus, he privately stipulated, for himself and his successors, the absolute possession of his Spanish conquests.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('Spanish', 'NORP')"
"Such a crime might not be 
 incompatible with the virtues of a barbarian; but the
 manners of Theodoric were gentle and humane; and posterity
 may contemplate without terror the original picture of a
 Gothic king, whom Sidonius had intimately observed in the
 hours of peace and of social intercourse.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Sidonius', 'PERSON')"
"Such an anecdote may be rejected as an improbable fiction,
 but it is a fiction which would not have been imagined
 unless in the life of a hero.(50)","('50', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such crimes could not be excused by any provocations, but
 the war which the king of the Vandals prosecuted against the
 Roman empire was justified by a specious and reasonable
 motive.","('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Such criminals were not beyond the reach of justice; but
 whatever might be the guilt of Ricimer, that powerful
 barbarian was able to contend or to negotiate with the
 prince whose alliance he had condescended to accept.","('Ricimer', 'PERSON')"
"Such vigilance might announce the character of the new 
 reign, but the strictest vigilance and the most numerous
 forces were insufficient to protect the long-extended coast
 of Italy from the depredations of a naval war.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"That flagitious minister, the Catiline of his age
 and country, held a secret correspondence with the Visigoths
 to betray the province which he oppressed: his industry was
 continually exercised in the discovery of new taxes and
 obsolete offences; and his extravagant vices would have
 inspired contempt if they had not excited fear and
 abhorrence.(101)
Discord of Anthemius and Ricimer, A.D. 471.","('Catiline', 'PERSON'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('101', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('471', 'CARDINAL')"
"That successful barbarian was the son of Edecon; who, in
 some remarkable transactions, particularly described in a
 preceding chapter had been the colleague of Orestes himself.","('Edecon', 'PERSON'), ('Orestes', 'PERSON')"
"The
 Vandal, instead of being elated by this accidental victory,
 immediately renewed his solicitations for peace.","('Vandal', 'PERSON')"
"The
 daughter of Wallia, king of the Visigoths, was the mother of
 Ricimer; but he was descended, on the father's side, from
 the nation of the Suevi:(26) his pride or patriotism might be 
 exasperated by the misfortunes of his countrymen; and he
 obeyed with reluctance an emperor in whose elevation he had
 not been consulted.","('Wallia', 'PERSON'), ('Visigoths', 'PERSON'), ('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('Suevi', 'PERSON'), ('26', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 patrician Aspar might have placed the diadem on his own
 head, if he would have subscribed the Nicene creed.(67)","('Aspar', 'PERSON'), ('Nicene', 'NORP'), ('67', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 peace of the city required the interposition of his praefect
 Basilius in the choice of a Roman pontiff: the decree which
 restrained the clergy from alienating their lands was
 ultimately designed for the benefit of the people, whose
 devotion would have been taxed to repair the dilapidations
 of the church. (136)","('Basilius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('136', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 peaceful and prosperous reign which Anthemius had promised
 to the West was soon clouded by misfortune and discord.","('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"The
 stern Ricimer, who trampled on the ruins of Italy, had
 exercised the power, without assuming the title, of a king;
 and the patient Romans were insensibly prepared to
 acknowledge the royalty of Odoacer and his barbaric
 successors.","('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Odoacer', 'PERSON')"
"The
 success of the Vandals, the conquest of Sicily, the sack of
 Palermo, and the frequent descents on the coast of Lucania,
 awakened and alarmed the mother of Valentinian and the
 sister of Theodosius.","('Vandals', 'PRODUCT'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Palermo', 'GPE'), ('Lucania', 'GPE'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The
 tempest of war might strike some lofty turrets to the
 ground; but the destruction which undermined the foundations
 of those massy fabrics was prosecuted, slowly and silently,
 during a period of ten centuries; and the motives of
 interest, that afterwards operated without shame or control,
 were severely checked by the taste and spirit of the emperor
 Majorian.","('ten centuries', 'DATE'), ('Majorian', 'PERSON')"
"The
 whole expense, by whatsoever means it was defrayed, of the
 African campaign, amounted to the sum of one hundred and
 thirty thousand pounds of gold, about five millions two
 hundred thousand pounds sterling, at a time when the value
 of money appears, from the comparative price of corn, to
 have been somewhat higher than in the present age.(86)","('African', 'NORP'), ('one hundred and\r\n thirty thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('about five millions two\r\n hundred thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('the present age.(86', 'DATE')"
"The 
 emperor led the way on foot and in complete armour, sounding
 with his long staff the depth of the ice or snow, and
 encouraging the Scythians, who complained of the extreme
 cold, by the cheerful assurance that they should be
 satisfied with the heat of Africa.","('Scythians', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"The 
 fleet that sailed from Constantinople to Carthage consisted
 of eleven hundred and thirteen ships, and the number of
 soldiers and mariners exceeded one hundred thousand men.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('eleven hundred and thirteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The 
 solemn inauguration of Anthemius was followed by the
 nuptials of his daughter and the patrician Ricimer; a
 fortunate event, which was considered as the firmest
 security of the union and happiness of the state.","('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('Ricimer', 'PERSON')"
"The Franks, who
 had punished with exile the youthful follies of Childeric,
 elected the Roman general for their king; his vanity rather
 than his ambition was gratified by that singular honour; and
 when the nation at the end of four years repented of the
 injury which they had offered to the Merovingian family, he
 patiently acquiesced in the restoration of the lawful
 prince.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Childeric', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('the end of four years', 'DATE'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP')"
"The Greeks ambitiously commend the piety and catholic faith
 of the emperor whom they gave to the West; nor do they
 forget to observe that, when he left Constantinople, he
 converted his palace into the pious foundation of a public
 bath, a church, and an hospital for old men.(76)","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The Imperial ornaments of the palace, the
 magnificent furniture and wardrobe, the sideboards of massy
 plate, were accumulated with disorderly rapine: the gold and
 silver amounted to several thousand talents; yet even the
 brass and copper were laboriously removed.","('several thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Italians,
 destitute of a naval force, which alone was capable of
 protecting their coasts, implored the aid of the more
 fortunate nations of the East, who had formerly acknowledged
 in peace and war the supremacy of Rome.","('Italians', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The Royal demesnes, or private patrimony of the
 prince, supplied seventeen thousand pounds of gold;
 forty-seven thousand pounds of gold, and seven hundred
 thousand of silver, were levied and paid into the treasury
 by the Praetorian praefects.","('seventeen thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('forty-seven thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('seven hundred\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP')"
"The Vandals and Alani, who followed the
 successful standard of Genseric, had acquired a rich and
 fertile territory, which stretched along the coast above
 ninety days' journey from Tangier to Tripoli; but their
 narrow limits were pressed and confined, on either side, by
 the sandy desert and the Mediterranean.","('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Alani', 'PERSON'), ('Genseric', 'PRODUCT'), (""ninety days'"", 'DATE'), ('Tangier', 'GPE'), ('Tripoli', 'GPE'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC')"
"The Vandals repeatedly visited the coasts of Spain, Liguria, Tuscany, Campania, Lucania, Bruttium, Apulia, Calabria, Venetia Dalmatia, Epirus, Greece, and Sicily: they were tempted to subdue the island of Sardinia, so advantageously placed in the centre of the Mediterranean; and their arms spread desolation or terror from the Columns of Hercules to the mouth of the Nile.","('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Liguria', 'GPE'), ('Tuscany', 'GPE'), ('Campania', 'GPE'), ('Lucania', 'GPE'), ('Bruttium', 'GPE'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Calabria', 'GPE'), ('Venetia Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('Epirus', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Sardinia', 'LOC'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC'), ('Hercules', 'LOC'), ('Nile', 'LOC')"
"The altar of Pan was 
 erected, perhaps by Evander the Arcadian, in a dark recess
 in the side of the Palatine hill, watered by a perpetual
 fountain, and shaded by a hanging grove.","('Pan', 'PERSON'), ('Evander the Arcadian', 'PERSON'), ('the Palatine hill', 'LOC')"
"The army of Heraclius, and the 
 fleet of Marcellinus, either joined or seconded the Imperial
 lieutenant; and the Vandals who opposed his progress by sea
 or land were successively vanquished.(88) If Basiliscus had 
 seized the moment of consternation, and boldly advanced to
 the capital, Carthage must have surrendered, and the kingdom
 of the Vandals was extinguished.","('Heraclius', 'GPE'), ('Marcellinus', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Basiliscus', 'PERSON'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Vandals', 'PRODUCT')"
"The army of Ricimer was fortified by a numerous reinforcement of Burgundians and Oriental Suevi: he disclaimed all allegiance to the Greek emperor, marched from Milan to the gates of Rome, and, fixing his camp on the banks of the Anio, impatiently expected the arrival of Olybrius, his Imperial candidate.","('Ricimer', 'GPE'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Oriental Suevi', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Anio', 'ORG'), ('Olybrius', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The author of this letter seemed to dissuade the king of the
 Goths from a peace with the Greek emperor: he suggested the
 attack of the Britons on the Loire and he recommended a
 division of Gaul, according to the law of nations, between
 the Visigoths and the Burgundians. (99)","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Britons', 'NORP'), ('Loire', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Visigoths', 'ORG'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('99', 'CARDINAL')"
"The authority of Aegidius ended only with his life,
 and the suspicions of poison and secret violence, which
 derived some countenance from the character of Ricimer, were
 eagerly entertained by the passionate credulity of the
 Gauls.(61)
Naval war of the Vandals, A.D. 361-467.","('Aegidius', 'PERSON'), ('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('61', 'CARDINAL'), ('361-467', 'CARDINAL')"
"The baths, the
 porticoes, the summer and winter apartments, were adapted to
 the purposes of luxury and use; and the adjacent country
 afforded the various prospects of woods, pastures, and
 meadows.(13) In this retreat, where Avitus amused his leisure 
 with books, rural sports, the practice of husbandry, and the
 society of his friends,(14) he received the Imperial diploma, 
 which constituted him master-general of the cavalry and
 infantry of Gaul.","('winter', 'DATE'), ('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('14', 'DATE'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The beneficial though precarious reunion of the greatest
 part of Gaul and Spain was the effect of persuasion as well
 as of force;(47) and the independent Bagaudae, who had 
 escaped or resisted the oppression of former reigns, were
 disposed to confide in the virtues of Majorian.","('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Bagaudae', 'NORP'), ('Majorian', 'PERSON')"
"The bishops of Rome were solicitous to
 abolish a profane custom so repugnant to the spirit of
 Christianity; but their zeal was not supported by the
 authority of the civil magistrate: the inveterate abuse
 subsisted till the end of the fifth century, and pope
 Gelasius, who purified the capital from the last stain of
 idolatry, appeased, by a formal apology, the murmurs of the
 senate and people.(82)
Preparations against the Vandals of Africa, A.D. 468.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('the end of the fifth century', 'DATE'), ('Gelasius', 'PERSON'), ('82', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Vandals of Africa', 'ORG'), ('468', 'CARDINAL')"
"The calends of  January were now approaching, and the venal poet, who had
 loved Avitus and esteemed Majorian, was persuaded by his
 friends to celebrate, in heroic verse, the merit, the
 felicity, the second consulship, and the future triumphs of
 the emperor Anthemius.","('January', 'DATE'), ('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('Majorian', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Anthemius', 'PERSON')"
"The campaign was
 opened by a bold and successful enterprise of the praefect
 Heraclius.(84)","('Heraclius', 'ORG'), ('84', 'CARDINAL')"
"The character and reign of the emperor Maximus, A.D. 455, March 17.","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 455', 'DATE'), ('March 17', 'DATE')"
"The charity of Deogratias, bishop of
 Carthage,(10) was their only consolation and support.","('Deogratias', 'ORG'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('10', 'CARDINAL')"
"The circus and theatres might
 still excite, but they seldom gratified, the desires of the
 people: and the temples which had escaped the zeal of the
 Christians were no longer inhabited either by gods or men;
 the diminished crowds of the Romans were lost in the immense
 space of their baths and porticoes; and the stately
 libraries and halls of justice became useless to an indolent
 generation whose repose was seldom disturbed either by study
 or business.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The citizens of Lyons had
 presumed to shut their gates: they soon implored, and
 experienced, the clemency of Majorian.","('Lyons', 'GPE'), ('Majorian', 'PERSON')"
The clemency of the emperor was extorted from his weakness; and Ricimer suspended his ambitious designs till he had secretly prepared the engines with which he resolved to subvert the throne of Anthemius.,"('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('Anthemius', 'PRODUCT')"
"The dangerous alliance of these
 strangers had oppressed and insulted the last remains of
 Roman freedom and dignity.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The death of Marcian, 
 after a reign of seven years, would have exposed the East to
 the danger of a popular election, if the superior weight of
 a single family had not been able to incline the balance in
 favour of the candidate whose interest they supported.","('Marcian', 'PERSON'), ('seven years', 'DATE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The death of that
 conqueror restored him to his freedom; and Orestes might
 honourably refuse either to follow the sons of Attila into
 the Scythian desert, or to obey the Ostrogoths, who had
 usurped the dominion of Pannonia.","('Orestes', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('the Scythian desert', 'LOC'), ('Ostrogoths', 'PERSON'), ('Pannonia', 'PERSON')"
"The death of the 
 emperor Majorian delivered Theodoric the Second from the
 restraint of fear, and perhaps of honour; he violated his
 recent treaty with the Romans; and the ample territory of
 Narbonne, which he firmly united to his dominions, became
 the immediate reward of his perfidy.","('Majorian', 'PERSON'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Narbonne', 'GPE')"
"The deaths of Aetius and Valentinian had relaxed the ties
 which held the barbarians of Gaul in peace and
 subordination.","('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The delicious shores of the bay of 
 Naples were crowded with villas; and Sylla applauded the
 masterly skill of his rival, who had seated himself on the
 lofty promontory of Misenum, that commands, on every side,
 the sea and land, as far as the boundaries of the horizon.
 (129)","('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Sylla', 'PERSON'), ('Misenum', 'LOC'), ('129', 'CARDINAL')"
"The deputies of the senate were received at Constantinople with some mark of displeasure and indignation: and when they were admitted to the audience of Zeno, he sternly reproached them with their treatment of the two emperors, Anthemius and Nepos, whom the East had successively granted to the prayers of Italy.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Zeno', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('Nepos', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The designs of the Roman government were repeatedly baffled
 by his artful delays, ambiguous promises, and apparent
 concessions; and the interposition of his formidable
 confederate, the king of the Huns, recalled the emperors
 from the conquest of Africa to the care of their domestic
 safety.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"The discovery and
 conquest of the Black nations, that might dwell beneath the
 torrid zone, could not tempt the rational ambition of
 Genseric; but he cast his eyes towards the sea; he resolved
 to create a naval power, and his bold resolution was
 executed with steady and active perseverance.","('Black', 'NORP'), ('Genseric', 'PERSON')"
"The disgrace of the Romans still
 excites our respectful compassion, and we fondly sympathise
 with the imaginary grief and indignation of their degenerate
 posterity.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The distress of Italy was mitigated by 
 the prudence and humanity of Odoacer, who had bound himself,
 as the price of his elevation, to satisfy the demands of a
 licentious and turbulent multitude.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Odoacer', 'PERSON')"
"The distress of the Romans
 was soon aggravated by an unexpected attack; and the
 province, so long cultivated for their use by industrious
 and obedient subjects, was armed against them by an
 ambitious barbarian.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
The edifices of Rome.,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The efforts of Euric were 
 not less vigorous or less successful in Gaul; and throughout
 the country that extends from the Pyrenees to the Rhone and
 the Loire, Berry and Auvergne were the only cities or
 dioceses which refused to acknowledge him as their master.","('Euric', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('Rhone', 'LOC'), ('Loire', 'LOC'), ('Berry', 'LOC'), ('Auvergne', 'LOC')"
"The emperor
 of the West, who was capable of forming great designs and of
 supporting heavy disappointments, consented to a treaty, or
 rather to a suspension of arms, in the full assurance that
 before he could restore his navy he should be supplied with
 provocations to justify a second war.","('West', 'LOC'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"The emperor Majorian has deserved the praises of
 his contemporaries and of posterity; and these praises may
 be strongly expressed in the words of a judicious and
 disinterested historian:  Such a testimony may justify at least the panegyric of Sidonius; and we may acquiesce in the assurance that, although the obsequious orator would have
 flattered with equal zeal the most worthless of princes, the
 extraordinary merit of his object confined him, on this
 occasion, within the bounds of truth.(33) Majorian derived 
 his name from his maternal grandfather, who, in the reign of
 the great Theodosius, had commanded the troops of the
 Illyrian frontier.","('Majorian', 'PERSON'), ('Sidonius', 'PERSON'), ('Majorian', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP')"
"The emperor Maximus
 relieved himself, by a judicious choice, from the weight of
 these distant cares; he silenced the solicitations of his
 friends, listened to the voice of fame, and promoted a
 stranger to the general command of the forces in Gaul.","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The emperor of the West 
 marched from Constantinople, attended by several counts of
 high distinction and a body of guards almost equal to the
 strength and numbers of a regular army: he entered Rome in
 triumph, A.D. 467, April 12.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 467', 'DATE'), ('April 12', 'DATE')"
"The emperor, who, amidst the ruins of the Roman world, revived the ancient language of law and liberty, which Trajan would not have disclaimed, must have derived those generous sentiments from his own heart, since they were not suggested to his imitation by the customs of his age or the example of his predecessors.(39)
His salutary laws, A.D. 457-461.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('457-461', 'CARDINAL')"
"The empress
 Verina, studious to promote the greatness of her own family,
 had married one of her nieces to Julius Nepos, who succeeded
 his uncle Marcellinus in the sovereignty of Dalmatia, a more
 solid possession than the title which he was persuaded to
 accept of Emperor of the West.","('Verina', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julius Nepos', 'PERSON'), ('Marcellinus', 'PERSON'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('Emperor of the West', 'PERSON')"
"The example of these
 warriors was imitated by Orestes,(118) the son of Tatullus, 
 and the father of the last Roman emperor of the West.","('Orestes', 'PERSON'), ('118', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tatullus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"The expense of the naval armament, which Leo sent against
 the Vandals has been distinctly ascertained; and the curious
 and instructive account displays the wealth of the declining
 empire.","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Vandals', 'PRODUCT')"
"The exploits of 
 Theodoric soon convinced the world that he had not
 degenerated from the warlike virtues of his ancestors.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON')"
"The faults of
 Arvandus might deserve compassion; but the impunity of
 Seronatus accused the justice of the republic, till he was
 condemned and executed on the complaint of the people of
 Auvergne.","('Arvandus', 'PERSON'), ('Seronatus', 'PERSON'), ('Auvergne', 'GPE')"
"The fearless spirit of Leo, his 
 authority and eloquence, again mitigated the fierceness of a
 barbarian conqueror: the king of the Vandals promised to
 spare the unresisting multitude, to protect the buildings
 from fire, and to exempt the captives from torture; and
 although such orders were neither seriously given, nor
 strictly obeyed, the mediation of Leo was glorious to
 himself, and in some degree beneficial to his country.","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Leo', 'PERSON')"
"The feeble emperor
 could only procure for their defence the service of twelve
 thousand British auxiliaries.","('twelve\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('British', 'NORP')"
"The formal consent of
 Marcian, emperor of the East, was solicited and obtained;
 but the senate, Rome, and Italy, though humbled by their
 recent calamities, submitted with a secret murmur to the
 presumption of the Gallic usurper.","('Marcian', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Gallic', 'NORP')"
"The formidable navy of
 Basiliscus pursued its prosperous navigation from the
 Thracian Bosphorus to the coast of Africa.","('Basiliscus', 'GPE'), ('the\r\n Thracian Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"The forms
 of the constitution, which alleviated or disguised their
 abject slavery, were abolished by time and violence; the
 Italians alternately lamented the presence or the absence of
 the sovereigns whom they detested or despised; and the
 succession of five centuries inflicted the various evils of
 military licence, capricious despotism, and elaborate
 oppression.","('Italians', 'NORP'), ('five centuries', 'DATE')"
"The friendship of the public enemy might 
 render Olybrius still more unpopular to the Italians; but
 when Ricimer meditated the ruin of the emperor Anthemius, he
 tempted, with the offer of a diadem the candidate who could
 justify his rebellion by an illustrious name and a royal
 alliance.","('Olybrius', 'PERSON'), ('Italians', 'NORP'), ('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('Anthemius', 'PERSON')"
"The grandson of the praefect was raised
 above the condition of a private subject by his marriage
 with Euphemia, the daughter of the emperor Marcian.","('Euphemia', 'PERSON'), ('Marcian', 'PERSON')"
"The hatred of the
 people was suppressed by fear; they respected the spirit and
 splendour of the martial chiefs who were invested with the
 honours of the empire; and the fate of Rome had long
 depended on the sword of those formidable strangers.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The haughty Ricimer, who had long struggled with
 the difficulties of his situation, was at length reduced to
 address the throne of Constantinople in the humble language
 of a subject; and Italy submitted, as the price and security
 of the alliance, to accept a master from the choice of the
 emperor of the East.(63)","('Ricimer', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('63', 'CARDINAL')"
"The holy instruments of the 
 Jewish worship,(8) the gold table, and the gold candlestick 
 with seven branches, originally framed according to the
 particular instructions of God himself, and which were
 placed in the sanctuary of his temple, had been
 ostentatiously displayed to the Roman people in the triumph
 of Titus.","('Jewish', 'NORP'), ('8', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Titus', 'PERSON')"
"The honour of an ambassador should be exempt from suspicion;
 and Edecon had listened to a conspiracy against the life of
 his sovereign.","('Edecon', 'PERSON')"
"The husband of Placidia, who, like most of his
 ancestors, had been invested with the consular dignity,
 might have continued to enjoy a secure and splendid fortune
 in the peaceful residence of Constantinople; nor does he
 appear to have been tormented by such a genius as cannot be
 amused or occupied unless by the administration of an
 empire.","('Placidia', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The imprudent Maximus disregarded these salutary
 considerations: he gratified his resentment and ambition; he
 saw the bleeding corpse of Valentinian at his feet; and he
 heard himself saluted Emperor by the unanimous voice of the
 senate and people.","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"The independent patrician had been persuaded to
 acknowledge the legitimate title of Anthemius whom he
 accompanied in his journey to Rome, the Dalmatian fleet was
 received into the harbours of Italy; the active valour of
 Marcellinus expelled the Vandals from the island of
 Sardinia; and the languid efforts of the West added some
 weight to the immense preparations of the Eastern Romans.","('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Dalmatian', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Marcellinus', 'PERSON'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Sardinia', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('the Eastern Romans', 'NORP')"
"The injury which he
 received from the emperor Valentinian appears to excuse the
 most bloody revenge.","('Valentinian', 'PERSON')"
"The intelligence of this
 loss extorted from Genseric some insidious and in.","('Genseric', 'GPE')"
"The intrepid countenance of Majorian 
 animated his troops with a confidence of victory; and if we
 might credit the historian Procopius, his courage sometimes
 hurried him beyond the bounds of prudence.","('Majorian', 'NORP'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON')"
"The king of Italy was not unworthy of the high station to
 which his valour and fortune had exalted him: his savage
 manners were polished by the habits of conversation; and he
 respected, though a conqueror and a barbarian, the
 institutions, and even the prejudices, of his subjects.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The king of the
 Vandals distrusted the valour of his native subjects, who
 were enervated by the luxury of the South;(51) he suspected 
 the fidelity of the vanquished people, who abhorred him as
 an Arian tyrant; and the desperate measure which he executed
 of reducing Mauritania into a desert(52) could not defeat the 
 operations of the Roman emperor, who was at liberty to land
