Sentence,Entities
(11),"('11', 'CARDINAL')"
(113),"('113', 'CARDINAL')"
(115),"('115', 'CARDINAL')"
"(15)
Situation and extent of Scythia, or Tartary.","('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('Scythia', 'ORG'), ('Tartary', 'ORG')"
(2),"('2', 'CARDINAL')"
(3),"('3', 'CARDINAL')"
(54),"('54', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 Gothic chief was heard to declare, with insolent moderation,
 that, for his own part, he was fatigued with slaughter; but
 that he was astonished how a people who fled before him like
 a flock of sheep could still presume to dispute the
 possession of their treasures and provinces.","('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"A
 Tartar sovereign enjoys the tenth part of the wealth of his
 people; and as his own domestic riches of flocks and herds
 increase in a much larger proportion, he is able plentifully
 to maintain the rustic splendour of his court, to reward the
 most deserving or the most favoured of his followers, and to
 obtain from the gentle influence of corruption the obedience
 which might be sometimes refused to the stern mandates of
 authority.","('Tartar', 'NORP'), ('tenth', 'ORDINAL')"
"A 
 magnificent palace was prepared for his reception; his place
 was assigned above all the princes of the royal family; and
 the patience of the barbarian king was exhausted by the
 ceremonies of a banquet, which consisted of eight courses of
 meat; and of nine solemn pieces of music.","('eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL')"
"A Gothic soldier was slain by the dagger of an
 Arab, and the hairy, naked savage, applying his lips to the
 wound, expressed a horrid delight while he sucked the blood
 of his vanquished enemy. (97)","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Arab', 'NORP')"
"A blow was
 imprudently given; a sword was hastily drawn, and the first
 blood that was spilt in this accidental quarrel became the
 signal of a long and destructive war.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"A circle is drawn, of many miles in circumference,
 to encompass the game of an extensive district; and the
 troops that form the circle regularly advance towards a
 common centre, where the captive animals, surrounded on
 every side, are abandoned to the darts of the hunters.","('many miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"A different mode of vindication or apology was opposed 
 to the complaints of the people, who loudly censured these
 shameful and dangerous concessions. (131)","('131', 'CARDINAL')"
"A fabulous origin was 
 assigned worthy of their form and manners that the witches
 of Scythia, who, for their foul and deadly practices, had
 been driven from society, had copulated in the desert with
 infernal spirits, and that the Huns were the offspring of
 this execrable conjunction. (58)","('Scythia', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('58', 'CARDINAL')"
"A formidable tempest of the barbarians of
 Germany seemed ready to burst over the provinces of Gaul,
 and the mind of Gratian was oppressed and distracted by the
 administration of the Western empire.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"A great number of brave and distinguished officers perished in the battle of Hadrianople, which equalled in the actual loss, and far surpassed in the fatal consequences, the misfortune which Rome had formerly sustained in the fields of Cannae. (93)","('Hadrianople', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Cannae', 'GPE'), ('93', 'CARDINAL')"
"A large fleet of vessels,
 of boats, and of canoes, was provided; many days and nights
 they passed and repassed with indefatigable toil; and the
 most strenuous diligence was exerted by the officers of
 Valens that not a single barbarian, of those who were
 reserved to subvert the foundations of Rome, should be left
 on the opposite shore.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"A numerous colony of the Visigoths was
 seated in Thrace; the remains of the Ostrogoths were planted
 in Phrygia and Lydia; their immediate wants were supplied by
 a distribution of corn and cattle; and their future industry
 was encouraged by an exemption from tribute during a certain
 term of years.","('Visigoths', 'PRODUCT'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Ostrogoths', 'PRODUCT'), ('Phrygia', 'GPE'), ('Lydia', 'GPE'), ('years', 'DATE')"
"A probable testimony has fixed the number of the
 Gothic warriors at two hundred thousand men; and if we can
 venture to add the just proportion of women, of children,
 and of slaves, the whole mass of people which composed this
 formidable emigration must have amounted to near a million
 of persons, of both sexes and of al!","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('two hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('near a million', 'CARDINAL')"
"A select band of the fairest maidens of
 China was annually devoted to the rude embraces of the Huns;
 (36) and the alliance of the haughty Tanjous was secured by 
 their marriage with the genuine, or adopted, daughters of
 the Imperial family, which vainly attempted to escape the
 sacrilegious pollution.","('China', 'GPE'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('36', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tanjous', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"A soldier of the lifeguards of
 Gratian was of the nation of the Alemanni, and of the tribe
 of the Lentienses, who dwelt beyond the lake of Constance.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Lentienses', 'NORP'), ('Constance', 'PERSON')"
"A subject invested with such ample command would
 not long have preserved his fidelity to a distant
 benefactor; and the Imperial council embraced the wise and
 manly resolution of conferring an obligation rather than of
 yielding to an insult.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
A.D. 377,"('A.D. 377', 'DATE')"
A.D. 48.,"('A.D. 48', 'DATE')"
"About the same time, Count
 Richomer returned from the West to announce the defeat and
 submission of the Alemanni; to inform Valens that his nephew
 advanced by rapid marches at the head of the veteran and
 victorious legions of Gaul; and to request, in the name of
 Gratian and of the republic, that every dangerous and
 decisive measure might be suspended till the junction of the
 two emperors should ensure the success of the Gothic war.","('Richomer', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Gothic war', 'EVENT')"
"Above one 
 hundred thousand persons, the poorest, indeed, and the most
 pusillanimous of the people, were contented to remain in
 their native country, to renounce their peculiar name and
 origin, and to mingle with the victorious nation of the
 Sienpi.","('one \r\n hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sienpi', 'NORP')"
"Above two-thirds of the Roman army were destroyed: and the darkness of the night was esteemed a very favourable circumstance, as it served to conceal the flight of the multitude, and to
protect the more orderly retreat of Victor and Richomer, who alone, amidst the general consternation, maintained the advantage of calm courage and regular discipline.(94)
Funeral oration of Valens and his army.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Victor', 'PERSON'), ('Richomer', 'PERSON'), ('94', 'CARDINAL'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"After Valens had terminated the Gothic war with some
 appearance of glory and success, he made a progress through
 his dominions of Asia, and at length fixed his residence in
 the capital of Syria.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('the Gothic war', 'EVENT'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Syria', 'GPE')"
"After the hasty and impolitic
 massacre of three hundred deserters, an act of justice
 extremely useful to the discipline of the Roman armies, the
 Goths indignantly raised the siege of Hadrianople.","('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Hadrianople', 'PRODUCT')"
"After this humiliating submission, the
 Tanjous sometimes departed from their allegiance, and seized
 the favourable moments of war and rapine; but the monarchy
 of the Huns gradually declined, till it was broken, by civil
 dissension, into two hostile and separate kingdoms.","('Tanjous', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"After this signal victory,
 which secured the peace of Gaul and asserted the honour of
 the Roman arms, the emperor Gratian appeared to proceed
 without delay on his Eastern expedition; but, as he
 approached the confines of the Alemanni, he suddenly
 inclined to the left, surprised them by his unexpected
 passage of the Rhine, and boldly advanced into the heart of
 their country.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"Against these enemies, Hermanric prepared to
 exert the united forces of the Gothic state, but he soon
 discovered that his vassal tribes, provoked by oppression,
 were much more inclined to second than to repel the invasion
 of the Huns.","('Hermanric', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"Ammianus Marcellinus, who terminates his
 useful work with the defeat and death of Valens, recommends
 the more glorious subject of the ensuing reign to the
 youthful vigour and eloquence of the rising generation.","('Ammianus Marcellinus', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"An army of forty thousand Goths was maintained for
 the perpetual service of the empire of the East; and those
 haughty troops, who assumed the title of Foederati, or
 allies, were distinguished by their gold collars, liberal
 pay, and licentious privileges.","('forty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Foederati', 'PERSON')"
"An order was immediately promulgated that, on a stated day,
 the Gothic youth should assemble in the capital cities of
 their respective provinces; and, as a report was
 industriously circulated that they were summoned to receive
 a liberal gift of lands and money, the pleasing hope allayed
 the fury of their resentment, and perhaps suspended the
 motions of the conspiracy.","('a stated day', 'DATE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"Another colony advanced, with more intrepid
 courage, towards the shores of the Baltic; associated
 themselves with the northern tribes of Germany; and shared
 the spoil of the Roman provinces of Gaul and Spain.","('Baltic', 'LOC'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE')"
Ant. Christ 51.,"('Christ 51', 'DATE')"
"As each
 moment of delay diminished something of the power and
 resources of the future sovereign of the East, the situation
 of the times would not allow a tedious debate.","('East', 'LOC')"
"As late as
 the thirteenth century their transient residence on the
 eastern banks of the Volga was attested by the name of Great
 Hungary.(49)","('As late as\r\n the thirteenth century', 'DATE'), ('Volga', 'LOC'), ('Great\r\n Hungary', 'GPE'), ('49', 'CARDINAL')"
"As long as the superior genius of Fritigern
 preserved the union and directed the motions of the
 barbarians, their power was not inadequate to the conquest
 of a great empire.","('Fritigern', 'PERSON')"
"As soon
 as the forage of a certain district is consumed, the tribe,
 or rather army, of shepherds makes a regular march to some
 fresh pastures, and thus acquires, in the ordinary
 occupations of the pastoral life, the practical knowledge of
 one of the most important and difficult operations of war.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"As soon as they descried the flaming beacons,(81) 
 they obeyed with incredible speed the signal of their
 leader; the camp was filled with the martial crowd of
 barbarians; their impatient clamours demanded the battle,
 and their tumultuous zeal was approved and animated by the
 spirit of their chiefs.","('81', 'CARDINAL')"
"As they had been deprived by the ministers of the emperor of the common benefits of nature and the fair intercourse of social life, they retaliated the injustice on the subjects of the empire; and the crimes of Lupicinus were expiated by the ruin of the peaceful husbandmen of Thrace, the conflagration of their villages, and the massacre or captivity of their innocent families.","('Lupicinus', 'PERSON'), ('Thrace', 'LOC')"
"As they were conscious how ill they had
 deserved the respect or confidence of the barbarians, they
 diligently collected from every side a military force that
 might urge the tardy and reluctant march of a people who had
 not yet renounced the title or the duties of Roman subjects","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"At the age of
 nineteen the son of Valentinian seemed to possess the
 talents of peace and war; and his personal success against
 the Alemanni was interpreted as a sure presage of his Gothic
 triumphs.(87)
Valens marches against the Goths, A.D. 378.","('the age of\r\n nineteen', 'DATE'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('87', 'CARDINAL'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('378', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the same hour, in all the
 cities of the East, the signal was given of indiscriminate
 slaughter; and the provinces of Asia were delivered, by the
 cruel prudence of Julius, from a domestic enemy, who in a
 few months might have carried fire and sword from the
 Hellespont to the Euphrates.(103)","('the same hour', 'TIME'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Julius', 'PERSON'), ('a\r\n few months', 'DATE'), ('Hellespont', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('103', 'CARDINAL')"
"At these words Fritigern and his companions drew their swords, opened their passage through the unresisting crowd, which filled the palace, the streets, and the gates of Marcianopolis, and, mounting their horses, hastily vanished from the eyes of the astonished Romans.","('Fritigern', 'PERSON'), ('Marcianopolis', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"At this important crisis the military government
 of Thrace was exercised by Lupicinus and Maximus, in whose
 venal minds the slightest hope of private emolument
 outweighed every consideration of public advantage, and
 whose guilt was only alleviated by their incapacity of
 discerning the pernicious effects of their rash and criminal
 administration.","('Thrace', 'GPE'), ('Lupicinus', 'PERSON'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"Athanaric himself, still anxious to avoid the
 guilt of perjury, retired, with a band of faithful
 followers, into the mountainous country of Caucaland, which
 appears to have been guarded and almost concealed by the
 impenetrable forests of Transylvania.(62)","('Athanaric', 'PERSON'), ('Caucaland', 'GPE'), ('Transylvania', 'GPE')"
"Athanaric, who had been a patient spectator
 of these extraordinary events, was at length driven, by the
 chance of arms, from the dark recesses of the woods of
 Caucaland.","('Athanaric', 'PERSON'), ('Caucaland', 'GPE')"
August 9th .,"('August 9th', 'DATE')"
"Battle of Hadrianople, A.D. 378.","('Battle of Hadrianople', 'ORG'), ('378', 'CARDINAL')"
"Before
 he had reposed himself ten days in the capital he was urged
 by the licentious clamours of the Hippodrome to march
 against the barbarians whom he had invited into his
 dominions: and the citizens, who are always brave at a
 distance from any real danger, declared, with confidence,
 that if they were supplied with arms, they alone would
 undertake to deliver the province from the ravages of an
 insulting foe. (88)","('ten days', 'DATE'), ('Hippodrome', 'FAC')"
"Before they passed the Danube they
 were required to deliver their arms, and it was insisted
 that their children should be taken from them and dispersed
 through the provinces of Asia, where they might be civilised
 by the arts of education, and serve as hostages to secure
 the fidelity of their parents.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"But
 the more numerous faction adhered to the fierce and
 faithless Priulf, who inflamed the passions and asserted the
 independence of his warlike followers.","('Priulf', 'PERSON')"
"But age had chilled the daring
 spirit of Athanaric; and instead of leading his people to the field of battle and victory, he wisely listened to the fair proposal of an honourable and advantageous treaty.","('Athanaric', 'PERSON')"
"But as the
 minds of the barbarians were not insensible to the power of
 gratitude, several of the Gothic leaders sincerely devoted
 themselves to the service of the empire, or, at least, of
 the emperor: the whole nation was insensibly divided into
 two opposite factions, and much sophistry was employed in
 conversation and dispute to compare the obligations of their
 first and second engagements.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"But he added, in a whisper of confidential
 friendship, that the exasperated barbarians were averse to
 these reasonable conditions; and that Fritigern was doubtful
 whether he could accomplish the conclusion of the treaty
 unless he found himself supported by the presence and
 terrors of an Imperial army.","('Fritigern', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"But he performed,
 on his knees, the duty of a respectful homage to the emperor
 of China; pronounced, in his own name, and in the name of
 his successors, a perpetual oath of fidelity; and gratefully
 accepted a seal, which was bestowed as the emblem of his
 regal dependence.","('China', 'GPE')"
"But he was soon surrounded by the
 barbarians; and, after a siege of seven days, the monarch,
 hopeless of relief, was reduced to purchase his deliverance
 by an ignominious capitulation.","('seven days', 'DATE')"
"But in the
 winter they return to the South, and shelter their camp,
 behind some convenient eminence, against the winds, which
 are chilled in their passage over the bleak and icy regions
 of Siberia.","('the\r\n winter', 'DATE'), ('South', 'LOC'), ('Siberia', 'LOC')"
"But the
 greatest part of the nation of the Alani embraced the offers
 of an honourable and advantageous union; and the Huns, who
 esteemed the valour of their less fortunate enemies,
 proceeded, with an increase of numbers and confidence, to
 invade the limits of the Gothic empire.","('Alani', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"But the
 person of Witheric, the infant king, was saved by the
 diligence of Alatheus and Saphrax; two warriors of approved
 valour and fidelity, who, by cautious marches, conducted the
 independent remains of the nation of the Ostrogoths towards
 the Danastus, or Dniester, a considerable river, which now
 separates the Turkish dominions from the empire of Russia.","('Witheric', 'PERSON'), ('Alatheus', 'PERSON'), ('Saphrax', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP'), ('Danastus', 'LOC'), ('Dniester', 'LOC'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Russia', 'GPE')"
"But the attention of the emperor
 was most seriously engaged by the important intelligence
 which he received from the civil and military officers who
 were intrusted with the defence of the Danube.","('Danube', 'LOC')"
"But the constant operation of various and
 permanent causes contributed to unite the vagrant Hords into
 national communities, under the command of a supreme head.","('Hords', 'NORP')"
"But the effects which were produced by the battle of
 Hadrianople on the minds of the barbarians and of the
 Romans, extended the victory of the former, and the defeat
 of the latter, far beyond the limits of a single day.","('Hadrianople', 'ORG'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('a single day', 'DATE')"
"But the exploits of the
 hunters of Scythia are not confined to the destruction of
 timid or innocuous beasts: they boldly encounter the angry
 wild boar when he turns against his pursuers, excite the
 sluggish courage of the bear, and provoke the fury of the
 tiger as he slumbers in the thicket.","('Scythia', 'LOC')"
"But the feeble sovereign of the East was actuated only by
 the fatal illusions of pride and jealousy.","('East', 'LOC')"
"But the first magistrate of Hadrianople, incensed by some disorders which had been committed at his country-house, refused this indulgence; and arming against them the inhabitants and manufacturers of a populous city, he urged, with hostile threats, their instant departure.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Hadrianople', 'PERSON')"
"But the flock and herds which accompany the march of the
 Tartars afford a sure and increasing supply of flesh and
 milk; in the far greater part of the uncultivated waste the
 vegetation of the grass is quick and luxuriant; and there
 are few places so extremely barren that the hardy cattle of
 the North cannot find some tolerable pasture.","('Tartars', 'LOC'), ('North', 'LOC')"
"But the generals of Valens, while their attention was solely
 directed to the discontented Visigoths, imprudently disarmed
 the ships and the fortifications which constituted the
 defence of the Danube.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"But the great Theodosius, an epithet which he
 honourably deserved on this momentous occasion, conducted
 himself as the firm and faithful guardian of the republic.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"But the hopes and measures of the 
 Judge of the Visigoths were soon disappointed by the
 trembling impatience of his dismayed countrymen, who were
 persuaded by their fears that the interposition of the
 Danube was the only barrier that could save them from the
 rapid pursuit and invincible valour of the barbarians of
 Scythia.","('Visigoths', 'PERSON'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Scythia', 'ORG')"
"But the most experienced
 statesman of Europe has never been summoned to consider the
 propriety or the danger of admitting or rejecting an
 innumerable multitude of barbarians, who are driven by
 despair and hunger to solicit a settlement on the
 territories of a civilised nation.","('Europe', 'LOC')"
"But the most powerful 
 auxiliaries of the Goths were drawn from the camp of those
 enemies who had expelled them from their native seats.","('Goths', 'NORP')"
"But the most suspicious
 malignity cannot ascribe to Theodosius, in his obscure
 solitude of Caucha, the arts, the desires, or even the hopes
 of an ambitious statesman; and the name of the Exile would
 long since have been forgotten, if his genuine and
 distinguished virtues had not left a deep impression in the
 Imperial court.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Caucha', 'NORP'), ('Exile', 'EVENT'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"But the most warlike and powerful tribes of the Huns
 maintained in their adverse fortune the undaunted spirit of
 their ancestors.","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"But the name of that sea, on whose shores the
 patriot Sovou embraced the life of a shepherd and an exile,
 (31) may be transferred, with much more probability, to the 
 Baikal, a capacious basin, above three hundred miles in
 length, which disdains the modest appellation of a lake,(32) 
 and which actually communicates with the seas of the North,
 by the long course of the Angara, the Tonguska, and the
 Yenesei.","('Sovou', 'PERSON'), ('31', 'CARDINAL'), ('Baikal', 'GPE'), ('three hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('32', 'CARDINAL'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('Angara', 'NORP'), ('Tonguska', 'NORP'), ('Yenesei', 'NORP')"
But the policy of Theodosius derived more solid benefit from the death than he could have expected from the most faithful services of his ally.,"('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"But the progress of the barbarians was
 suddenly stopped by an unexpected obstacle—a triple line
 of vessels, strongly connected with each other, and which
 formed an impenetrable chain of two miles and a half along
 the river.","('two miles and a half', 'QUANTITY')"
"But the stipulation, the most
 offensive to the Goths and the most important to the Romans,
 was shamefully eluded.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"But the tide soon returned with the weight of an immense and irresistible deluge, which was severely felt on the coasts of Sicily, of Dalmatia, of Greece, and of Egypt; large boats were transported and lodged on the roofs of houses, or at the distance of two miles from the shore; the people, with their habitations, were swept away by the waters, and the city of Alexandria annually commemorated the fatal day on which fifty thousand persons had lost their lives in the inundation.","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('two miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"But their pride was humbled, and their progress
 was checked, by the arms and policy of Vouti,(38) the fifth 
 emperor of the powerful dynasty of the Han.","('Vouti', 'PERSON'), ('38', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Han', 'NORP')"
"But they applauded the
 liberality of fortune which had conducted, from the most
 distant countries of the globe, a numerous and invincible
 army of strangers to defend the throne of Valens, who might
 now add to the royal treasures the immense sums of gold
 supplied by the provincials to compensate their annual
 proportion of recruits.","('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"But they respected, in peace, the faith of
 treaties; in war, the dictates of humanity; and their
 memorable victory over Peroses, or Firuz, displayed the
 moderation as well as the valour of the barbarians.","('Peroses', 'NORP'), ('Firuz', 'PERSON')"
"But this extraordinary abstinence,
 which the Stoic would approve and the hermit might envy, is
 commonly succeeded by the most voracious indulgence of
 appetite.","('Stoic', 'NORP')"
"But this humble retreat was instantly surrounded by the enemy; they tried to force the door; they were provoked by a discharge of arrows from the roof; till at length, impatient of delay, they set fire to a
pile of dry faggots, and consumed the cottage with the Roman emperor and his train.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But those inaccessible regions are the ancient
 residence of a powerful and civilised nation, (22) which 
 ascends, by a probable tradition, above forty centuries;(23) 
 and which is able to verify a series of near two thousand
 years by the perpetual testimony of accurate and
 contemporary historians. (24)","('22', 'CARDINAL'), ('forty centuries', 'DATE'), ('23', 'CARDINAL'), ('near two thousand\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('24', 'CARDINAL')"
"But, as it is the indispensable duty of a Tartar sovereign to lead his warlike subjects into the field, the claims of an infant are often disregarded,
 and some royal kinsman, distinguished by his age and valour,
 is intrusted with the sword and sceptre of his predecessor.","('Tartar', 'NORP')"
"By the care of his attendants, Valens was removed from the field of battle to a neighbouring cottage, where they attempted to dress his wound and to provide for his future safety.","('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"By the help of such rafts and vessels as could be hastily
 procured, the leaders of the Ostrogoths transported, without
 opposition, their king and their army, and boldly fixed an
 hostile and independent camp on the territories of the
 empire.(70)
Revolt of the Goths in Maesia, and their first victories.","('Ostrogoths', 'NORP'), ('70', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Maesia', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"By the vigour and conduct of Sebastian,
 a large body of the Goths was surprised in their camp; and
 the immense spoil which was recovered from their hands
 filled the city of Hadrianople and the adjacent plain.","('Sebastian', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Hadrianople', 'GPE')"
Christ. 201.,"('201', 'CARDINAL')"
"Conscious of these disadvantages, which will
 continue to involve a considerable portion of the decline
 and fall of the Roman empire, I shall proceed with doubtful
 and timorous steps.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Death and funeral of Athanaric, A.D. 381, January 25.","('Athanaric', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 381', 'DATE'), ('January 25', 'DATE')"
Death of the emperor Valens.,"('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"During the civil war against Maximus a great
 number of Gothic deserters retired into the morasses of
 Macedonia, wasted the adjacent provinces, and obliged the
 intrepid monarch to expose his person and exert his power to
 suppress the rising flame of rebellion. (134)","('the civil war', 'EVENT'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Macedonia', 'GPE'), ('134', 'CARDINAL')"
"During this suspense of a doubtful and distant negotiation,
 the impatient Goths made some rash attempts to pass the
 Danube without the permission of the government whose
 protection they had implored.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"Every
 forest and every village poured forth a band of hardy
 adventurers; and the great army of the Alemanni, which on
 their approach was estimated at forty thousand men by the
 fears of the people, was afterwards magnified to the number
 of Seventy thousand by the vain and credulous flattery of
 the Imperial court.","('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('forty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Seventy thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"Every youth, on his entrance into the
 world, was united by the ties of honourable friendship and
 brutal love to some warrior of the tribe; nor could he hope
 to be released from this unnatural connection till he had
 approved his manhood by slaying in single combat a huge bear
 or a wild boar of the forest. (84)","('84', 'CARDINAL')"
"Fifty-eight hordes, about two hundred thousand men,
 ambitious of a more honourable servitude, retired towards
 the south, implored the protection of the emperors of China,
 and were permitted to inhabit and to guard the extreme
 frontiers of the province of Chansi and the territory of
 Ortow.","('Fifty-eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('about two hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('Chansi', 'GPE'), ('Ortow', 'GPE')"
"Five months
 after the death of Valens the emperor Gratian produced
 before the assembled troops his colleague and their master,
 who, after a modest, perhaps a sincere resistance, was
 compelled to accept, amidst the general acclamations, the
 diadem, the purple, and the equal title of Augustus.(105)","('Five months', 'DATE'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('105', 'CARDINAL')"
"Fravitta, alarmed and
 exasperated by the insolence of his rival, whose departure
 from the palace might have been the signal of a civil war,
 boldly followed him and, drawing his sword, laid Priulf dead
 at his feet.","('Fravitta', 'PERSON'), ('Priulf', 'PERSON')"
"From the innocent, 
 but humble, labours of his farm, Theodosius was transported,
 in less than four months, to the throne of the Eastern
 empire: and the whole period of the history of the world
 will not perhaps afford a similar example of an elevation at
 the same time so pure and so honourable.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('less than four months', 'DATE'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"From the mouth of the Danube to the
 sea of Japan, the whole longitude of Scythia is about one
 hundred and ten degrees, which, in that parallel, are equal
 to more than five thousand miles.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Japan', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'LOC'), ('one\r\n hundred and ten degrees', 'QUANTITY'), ('more than five thousand miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"From the time of this fatal schism, the Huns of
 the north continued to languish about fifty years, till they
 were oppressed on every side by their foreign and domestic
 enemies.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('about fifty years', 'DATE')"
"Gorgo, which, under the appellation of Carizme, has
 since enjoyed a temporary splendour, was the residence of
 the king, who exercised a legal authority over an obedient
 people.","('Gorgo', 'PERSON'), ('Carizme', 'GPE')"
"Gratian was too late to assist, he was too
 weak to revenge, his unfortunate colleague; and the valiant
 and modest youth felt himself unequal to the support of a
 sinking world.","('Gratian', 'PERSON')"
"He accepted with pleasure the useful reinforcement of hardy workmen who laboured in the goldmines of Thrace (76) for the emolument and under the lash of an unfeeling master: (77) and these new associates conducted the barbarians through the secret paths to the most sequestered places, which had been chosen to secure the inhabitants, the cattle, and the magazines of corn.","('Thrace', 'PERSON'), ('76', 'CARDINAL'), ('77', 'CARDINAL')"
"He cemented a strict and
 useful alliance with the great body of his countrymen who
 obeyed Alatheus and Saphrax as the guardians of their infant
 king: the long animosity of rival tribes was suspended by
 the sense of their common interest; the independent part of
 the nation was associated under one standard; and the chiefs
 of the Ostrogoths appear to have yielded to the superior
 genius of the general of the Visigoths.","('Alatheus', 'PERSON'), ('Saphrax', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP')"
"He declared his intention of marching from
 Antioch to Constantinople, to subdue this dangerous
 rebellion; and, as he was not ignorant of the difficulties
 of the enterprise, he solicited the assistance of his
 nephew, the emperor Gratian, who commanded all the forces of
 the West.","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"He despatched
 messengers of peace, made proposals, required hostages, and
 wasted the hours, till the Romans, exposed without shelter
 to the burning rays of the sun, were exhausted by thirst,
 hunger, and intolerable fatigue.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"He disdained the
 importunate advice; he rejected the humiliating aid; he
 secretly compared the ignominious, at least the inglorious,
 period of his own reign with the fame of a beardless youth;
 and Valens rushed into the field to erect his imaginary
 trophy before the diligence of his colleague could usurp any
 share of the triumphs of the day.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('the day', 'DATE')"
"He fixed his headquarters at Thessalonica, the capital of
 the Macedonian diocese; (117) from whence he could watch the irregular motions of the barbarians, and direct the
 operations of his lieutenants, from the gates of
 Constantinople to the shores of the Hadriatic.","('Thessalonica', 'GPE'), ('Macedonian', 'NORP'), ('117', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Hadriatic', 'NORP')"
"He no longer hesitated to pass the Danube; and a
 very considerable part of the subjects of Fritigern who
 already felt the inconveniences of anarchy, were easily
 persuaded to acknowledge for their king a Gothic Judge,
 whose birth they respected, and whose abilities they had
 frequently experienced.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Fritigern', 'PERSON')"
"He obtained the
 formidable aid of the Taifalae, whose military renown was
 disgraced and polluted by the public infamy of their
 domestic manners.","('Taifalae', 'NORP')"
"He obtained the permission of selecting
 three hundred soldiers from each of the legions, and this
 separate detachment soon acquired the spirit of discipline
 and the exercise of arms, which were almost forgotten under
 the reign of Valens.","('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"He obtained, with
 the title of Tanjou, a convenient territory on the verge of
 the Chinese provinces; and his constant attachment to the
 service of the empire was secured by weakness and the desire
 of revenge.","('Tanjou', 'GPE'), ('Chinese', 'NORP')"
"He restrained the impatient spirit of the
 Visigoths till the injuries and the insults of their tyrants
 should justify their resistance in the opinion of mankind:
 but he was not disposed to sacrifice any solid advantages
 for the empty praise of justice and moderation.","('Visigoths', 'NORP')"
"He was
 informed that the North was agitated by a furious tempest;
 that the irruption of the Huns, an unknown and monstrous
 race of savages, had subverted the power of the Goths; and
 that the suppliant multitudes of that warlike nation, whose
 pride was now humbled in the dust, covered a space many
 miles along the banks of the river.","('North', 'LOC'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('many\r\n miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"He was raised to the throne by the
 acclamations of his equals, and the title of Khan
 expresses in the language of the North of Asia the full
 extent of the regal dignity.","('Khan', 'PERSON'), ('the North of Asia', 'LOC')"
"He was received at Sigan,
 the capital of the monarchy, by the troops, the mandarins,
 and the emperor himself, with all the honours that could
 adorn and disguise the triumph of Chinese vanity. (40)","('Sigan', 'GPE'), ('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('40', 'CARDINAL')"
"He was soon
 persuaded by the successful achievements of his lieutenants
 to despise the power of the Goths, who, by the diligence of
 Fritigern, were now collected in the neighbourhood of
 Hadrianople.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Fritigern', 'ORG'), ('Hadrianople', 'GPE')"
"His
 own merit, and the recommendation of the conqueror of
 Africa, soon raised him to a separate command; and, in the
 station of duke of Mazsia, he vanquished an army of
 Sarmatians; saved the province; deserved the love of the
 soldiers; and provoked the envy of the court.(110)","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Mazsia', 'GPE'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('110', 'CARDINAL')"
"His army was strengthened by a numerous
 reinforcement of veterans; and his march from Constantinople
 to Hadrianople was conducted with so much military skill
 that he prevented the activity of the barbarians, who
 designed to occupy the intermediate defiles, and to
 intercept either the troops themselves or their convoys of
 provisions.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Hadrianople', 'GPE')"
"His death, which has been
 imputed to his own despair, left the reins of government in
 the hands of Withimer, who, with the doubtful aid of some
 Scythian mercenaries, maintained the unequal contest against
 the arms of the Huns and the Alani till he was defeated and
 slain in a decisive battle.","('Withimer', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Alani', 'PERSON')"
"His faithful generals, Trajan and Victor, who perceived his danger, loudly exclaimed that all was lost unless the person of the emperor could be saved.","('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Victor', 'PERSON')"
"His labours were
 interrupted by the alarming intelligence that new swarms of
 barbarians had passed the unguarded Danube, either to
 support the cause or to imitate the example of Fritigern.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Fritigern', 'PERSON')"
"His prudent and successful conduct of the Gothic war, A.D. 379-382.","('the Gothic war', 'EVENT'), ('379-382', 'CARDINAL')"
"His rising 
 fortunes were soon blasted by the disgrace and execution of
 his illustrious father; and Theodosius obtained, as a
 favour, the permission of retiring to a private life in his
 native province of Spain.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Spain', 'GPE')"
"His rival Priarius, king of the
 Alemanni, was guided, or rather impelled, by the same
 headstrong valour; and as their troops were animated by the
 spirit of their leaders, they met, they saw, they
 encountered each other near the town of Argentaria, or
 Colmar,(86) in the plains of Alsace.","('Priarius', 'PERSON'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Argentaria', 'GPE'), ('Colmar', 'GPE'), ('86', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alsace', 'GPE')"
"His time was almost equally divided between
 the town and country; the spirit which had animated his
 public conduct was shown in the active and affectionate
 performance of every social duty; and the diligence of the
 soldier was profitably converted to the improvement of his
 ample patrimony, (111) which lay between Valladolid and 
 Segovia, in the midst of a fruitful district, still famous
 for a most exquisite breed of sheep.(112)","('Valladolid', 'GPE'), ('Segovia', 'GPE'), ('112', 'CARDINAL')"
"Horseflesh, which in
 every age and country has been proscribed by the civilised
 nations of Europe and Asia, they devour with peculiar
 greediness, and this singular taste facilitates the success
 of their military operations.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"IN the second year of the reign of Valentinian and Valens, on the morning of the twenty-first day of July, the greatest part of the Roman world was shaken by a violent and destructive earthquake.","('the second year', 'DATE'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('the twenty-first day of July', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"If Theodosius, hastily collecting his scattered forces, 
 had led them into the field to encounter a victorious enemy,
 his army would have been vanquished by their own fears; and
 his rashness could not have been excused by the chance of
 success.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"If the barbarians were mounted on the horses,
 and equipped with the armour, of their vanquished enemies,
 the numerous studs of Cappadocia and Spain would have
 supplied new squadrons of cavalry; the thirty-four arsenals
 of the empire were plentifully stored with magazines of
 offensive and defensive arms; and the wealth of Asia might
 still have yielded an ample fund for the expenses of the
 war.","('Cappadocia', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('thirty-four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"If, instead of this faint and imperfect outline,
 we could accurately represent the counsels and actions of
 Theodosius in four successive campaigns, there is reason to
 believe that his consummate skill would deserve the applause
 of every military reader.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"In
 this march, which frequently continues many days, the
 cavalry are obliged to climb the hills, to swim the rivers,
 and to wind through the valleys, without interrupting the
 prescribed order of their gradual progress.","('many days', 'DATE')"
"In a council of war, which was influenced by pride
 rather than by reason, it as resolved to seek and to
 encounter the barbarians, who lay encamped in the spacious
 and fertile meadows near the most southern of the mouths of
 the Danube.(79)","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('79', 'CARDINAL')"
"In a season of tranquillity their
 power might have been equal as well as their rank; but, as
 soon as their countrymen were exasperated by hunger and
 oppression, the superior abilities of Fritigern assumed the
 military command, which he was qualified to exercise for the
 public welfare.","('a season', 'DATE'), ('Fritigern', 'PERSON')"
"In every age the Scythians
 and Tartars have been renowned for their invincible courage
 and rapid conquests.","('Scythians', 'NORP'), ('Tartars', 'NORP')"
"In every age the immense plains of
 Scythia or Tartary have been inhabited by vagrant tribes of
 hunters and shepherds, whose indolence refuses to cultivate
 the earth, and whose restless spirit disdains the
 confinement of a sedentary life.","('Scythia', 'LOC'), ('Tartary', 'LOC')"
"In his long
 reign of fifty-four years, the barbarians of the southern
 provinces submitted to the laws and manners of China; and
 the ancient limits of the monarchy were enlarged from the
 great river of Kiang to the port of Canton.","('fifty-four years', 'DATE'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('Kiang', 'GPE'), ('Canton', 'GPE')"
"In that dreary climate, instead
 of the animated picture of a Tartar camp, the smoke which
 issues from the earth, or rather from the snow, betrays the
 subterraneous dwellings of the Tongouses and the Samoiedes:
 the want of horses and oxen is imperfectly supplied by the
 use of reindeer and of large dogs; and the conquerors of the
 earth insensibly degenerate into a race of deformed and
 diminutive savages, who tremble at the sound of arms.(26)
Original seat of the Huns.","('Tartar', 'NORP'), ('Tongouses', 'NORP'), ('Samoiedes', 'NORP'), ('26', 'CARDINAL'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"In the ages of rustic and martial simplicity, a people
 of soldiers and husbandmen are dispersed over the face of an
 extensive and cultivated country; and some time must elapse
 before the warlike youth of Greece or Italy could be
 assembled under the same standard, either to defend their
 own confines, or to invade the territories of the adjacent
 tribes.","('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"In the course of these depredations a great number of the children of the Goths, who had been sold into captivity, were restored to the embraces of their afflicted parents; but these tender interviews, which might have revived and cherished in their minds some sentiments of humanity, tended only to stimulate their native fierceness by the desire of revenge.","('Goths', 'NORP')"
"In the disastrous period of the fall of the Roman empire,
 which may justly be dated from the reign of Valens, the
 happiness and security of each individual were personally
 attacked, and the arts and labours of ages were rudely
 defaced by the barbarians of Scythia and Germany.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Scythia', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"In the eyes 
 of the Greeks and Persians, the real geography of Scythia
 was bounded, on the east, by the mountains of Imaus or Caf;
 and their distant prospect of the extreme and inaccessible
 parts of Asia was clouded by ignorance, or perplexed by
 fiction.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Scythia', 'GPE'), ('Imaus', 'LOC'), ('Caf', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"In the hands of a skilful politician the 
 most different means may be successfully applied to the same
 ends; and the peace of the empire, which had been forwarded
 by the divisions, was accomplished by the reunion of the
 Gothic nation.","('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"In the midst
 of riotous intemperance, the watchful Fritigern observed the
 motions and penetrated the designs of the Romans.","('Fritigern', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"In the midst of noise
 and brutal intemperance Lupicinus was informed by a secret
 messenger that many of his soldiers were slain and despoiled
 of their arms; and as he was already inflamed by wine and
 oppressed by sleep, he issued a rash command, that their
 death should be revenged by the massacre of the guards of
 Fritigern and Alavivus.","('Lupicinus', 'PERSON'), ('Fritigern', 'GPE'), ('Alavivus', 'PERSON')"
"In the midst of tumult, of slaughter, and of dismay, the emperor, deserted by his guards, and wounded, as it was supposed, with an arrow, sought protection among the
Lancearii and the Mattiarii, who still maintained their ground with some appearance of order and firmness.","('Lancearii', 'PERSON'), ('Mattiarii', 'NORP')"
"In the same moment the flying squadrons of
Alatheus and Saphrax, whose return was anxiously expected by the general of the Goths, descended like a whirlwind from the hills, swept across the plain, and added new terrors to the tumultuous but irresistible charge of the barbarian host.","('the same moment', 'TIME'), ('Alatheus', 'NORP'), ('Saphrax', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"In the space of about twelve years their numbers had
 continually increased; and the children who in the first
 emigration were sent over the Hellespont had attained with
 rapid growth the strength and spirit of perfect manhood.(102)","('about twelve years', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Hellespont', 'GPE'), ('102', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the third century
 before the Christian era, a wall of fifteen hundred miles in
 length was constructed, to defend the frontiers of China
 against the inroads of the Huns; (33) but this stupendous 
 work, which holds a conspicuous place in the map of the
 world, has never contributed to the safety of an unwarlike
 people.","('the third century', 'DATE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('fifteen hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('33', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the winter 
 season, the broad and rapid rivers that discharge their
 waters into the Euxine, the Caspian, or the Icy Sea, are
 strongly frozen, the fields are covered with a bed of snow,
 and the fugitive or victorious tribes may securely traverse,
 with their families, their waggons, and their cattle, the
 smooth and hard surface of an immense plain.","('the winter \r\n season', 'DATE'), ('Euxine', 'LOC'), ('Caspian', 'LOC'), ('the Icy Sea', 'LOC')"
"In the winter they descended with their flocks 
 and herds towards the mouth of that mighty river; and their
 summer excursions reached as high as the latitude of
 Saratoff, or perhaps the conflux of the Kama.","('the winter', 'DATE'), ('Saratoff', 'LOC'), ('Kama', 'PERSON')"
"In this important
 crisis the government of the East and the conduct of the
 Gothic war required the undivided attention of a hero and a
 statesman.","('East', 'LOC'), ('the\r\n Gothic war', 'EVENT')"
"In those boundless deserts, where it is
 impossible to form magazines, and difficult to transport a
 sufficient supply of provisions, the armies of Vouti were
 repeatedly exposed to intolerable hardships: and, of one
 hundred and forty thousand soldiers who marched against the
 barbarians, thirty thousand only returned in safety to the
 feet of their master.","('Vouti', 'GPE'), ('one\r\n hundred and forty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Instead of
 confining himself to the timid operations of a defensive
 war, his lieutenants penetrated many hundred miles into the
 country of the Huns.","('many hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"Instead of obeying the orders of their
 sovereign, and satisfying, with decent liberality, the
 demands of the Goths, they levied an ungenerous and
 oppressive tax on the wants of the hungry barbarians.","('Goths', 'NORP')"
"Intimidated by the arms, or allured by the
 promises, of Vouti and his successors, the most considerable
 tribes, both of the East and of the West, disclaimed the
 authority of the Tanjou.","('Vouti', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Tanjou', 'NORP')"
"It is impossible to fill the dark interval of time which
 elapsed after the Huns of the Volga were lost in the eyes of
 the Chinese, and before they showed themselves to those of
 the Romans.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Volga', 'LOC'), ('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"It is well known that the cold of Tartary is
 much more severe than in the midst of the temperate zone
 might reasonably be expected; this uncommon rigour is
 attributed to the height of the plains, which rise,
 especially towards the east, more than half a mile above the
 level of the sea, and to the quantity of saltpetre with
 which the soil is deeply impregnated.","('Tartary', 'LOC'), ('more than half a mile', 'QUANTITY')"
"It was generally
 believed that the Goths had signed the treaty of peace with
 an hostile and insidious spirit; and that their chiefs had
 previously bound themselves by a solemn and secret oath
 never to keep faith with the Romans, to maintain the fairest
 show of loyalty and friendship, and to watch the favourable
 moment of rapine, of conquest, and of revenge.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"It was impossible to conceal from their knowledge the events
 of the Gothic war; and, as those daring youths had not
 studied the language of dissimulation, they betrayed their
 wish, their desire, perhaps their intentions to emulate the
 glorious example of their fathers","('the Gothic war', 'EVENT')"
"It was the wish of Gratian to bestow
 the purple as the reward of virtue; but at the age of
 nineteen it is not easy for a prince, educated in the
 supreme rank, to understand the true characters of his
 ministers and generals.","('Gratian', 'NORP'), ('the age of\r\n nineteen', 'DATE')"
"It was thought expedient that an
 accurate account should be taken of their numbers; but the
 persons who were employed soon desisted, with amazement and
 dismay, from the prosecution of the endless and
 impracticable task;(67) and the principal historian of the 
 age most seriously affirms that the prodigious armies of
 Darius and Xerxes, which had so long been considered as the
 fables of vain and credulous antiquity, were now justified,
 in the eyes of mankind, by the evidence of fact and
 experience.","('Darius', 'PERSON'), ('Xerxes', 'PERSON')"
June 11th.,"('June 11th', 'DATE')"
"Lupicinus had invited the Gothic chiefs to a splendid
 entertainment, and their martial train remained under arms
 at the entrance of the palace.","('Lupicinus', 'ORG'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"Lupicinus left his arms and standards, his tribunes and his bravest soldiers, on the field of battle; and their useless courage served only to protect the ignominious flight of their leader.","('Lupicinus', 'PERSON')"
"Manners of the Pastoral Nations —Progress of the Huns from China to Europe —Flight of the Goths —They  Pass the Danube — Gothic War — Defeat and Death of Valens —Gratian Invests Theodosius with the Eastern Empire —His Character and Success Peace and Settlement of the Goths
Earthquakes, A.D. 365, July 21st.","('the Pastoral Nations', 'ORG'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Flight of the Goths', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Gratian Invests Theodosius with the Eastern Empire —His Character and Success Peace and Settlement of the Goths\r\nEarthquakes', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('A.D. 365', 'DATE'), ('July 21st', 'DATE')"
"Massacre of the Gothic youth in Asia, A.D. 378.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('A.D. 378', 'DATE')"
May 30th—,"('May 30th', 'DATE')"
May.,"('May', 'DATE')"
"Necessity compelled them to exchange the silks of China for
 the furs of Siberia; the imperfect rudiments of civilised
 life were obliterated; and the native fierceness of the Huns
 was exasperated by their intercourse with the savage tribes,
 who were compared, with some propriety, to the wild beasts
 of the desert.","('China', 'GPE'), ('Siberia', 'LOC'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"Notwithstanding these specious arguments and these sanguine
 expectations, it was apparent to every discerning eye that
 the Goths would long remain the enemies, and might soon
 become the conquerors, of the Roman empire.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"On one of the solemn
 festivals, when the chiefs of both parties were invited to
 the Imperial table, they were insensibly heated by wine,
 till they forgot the usual restraints of discretion and
 respect, and betrayed in the presence of Theodosius the
 fatal secret of their domestic disputes.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"On the
 west, near the head of the Irtish, and in the valleys of
 Imaus, they found a more ample space, and more numerous
 enemies.","('Irtish', 'NORP'), ('Imaus', 'LOC')"
"On the appointed day the unarmed
 crowd of the Gothic youth was carefully collected in the
 square or forum; the streets and avenues were occupied by
 the Roman troops, and the roofs of the houses were covered
 with archers and slingers.","('the appointed day', 'DATE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"On the banks of the 
 Tanais the military power of the Huns and the Alani
 encountered each other with equal valour, but with unequal
 success.","('Tanais', 'GPE'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Alani', 'NORP')"
"On the banks of the Dniester the prudent Athanaric, more
 attentive to his own than to the general safety, had fixed
 the camp of the Visigoths; with the firm resolution of
 opposing the victorious barbarians, whom he thought it less
 advisable to provoke.","('Dniester', 'NORP'), ('Athanaric', 'NORP'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP')"
"On the ninth of August, a day which has deserved to be marked
 among the most inauspicious of the Roman calendar,(91) the 
 emperor Valens, leaving, under a strong guard, his baggage
 and military treasure, marched from Hadrianople to attack
 the Goths, who were encamped about twelve miles from the
 city.(92)","('the ninth of August, a day', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('91', 'CARDINAL'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Hadrianople', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('about twelve miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('92', 'CARDINAL')"
"On the side of the north, the ocean 
 was assigned as the limit of the power of the Huns.","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"On the sudden emergency of a hasty march,
 they provide themselves with a sufficient quantity of little
 balls of cheese, or rather of hard curd, which they
 occasionally dissolve in water, and this unsubstantial diet
 will support, for many days, the life, and even the spirits,
 of the patient warrior","('many days', 'DATE')"
"On their arrival in Thrace they were
 joined by Richomer, count of the domestics; and the
 auxiliaries of the West that marched under his banner were
 composed of the Gallic legions, reduced indeed by a spirit
 of desertion to the vain appearances of strength and
 numbers.","('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Richomer', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Gallic', 'NORP')"
"On this occasion, as well
 as on many others, it is a difficult task to reconcile the
 passions and prejudices of the writers of the age of
 Theodosius.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"One of
 the princes of the nation was urged by fear and ambition to
 retire towards the south with eight hordes, which composed
 between forty and fifty thousand families.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('between forty and fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"One of the chiefs of the Roxolani(59) had 
 formerly deserted the standard of Hermanric, and the cruel
 tyrant had condemned the innocent wife of the traitor to be
 torn asunder by wild horses.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roxolani', 'PERSON'), ('59', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hermanric', 'GPE')"
"One of the lieutenants of the Tanjou subdued, in a
 single expedition, twenty-six nations; the Igours, (29) 
 distinguished above the Tartar race by the use of letters,
 were in the number of his vassals; and, by the strange
 connection of human events, the flight of one of those
 vagrant tribes recalled the victorious Parthians from the
 invasion of Syria. (30)","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tanjou', 'NORP'), ('twenty-six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Igours', 'PERSON'), ('29', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tartar', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Parthians', 'NORP'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('30', 'CARDINAL')"
"One of the most dangerous inconveniences of the introduction
 of the barbarians into the army and the palace was sensibly
 felt in their correspondence with their hostile countrymen,
 to whom they imprudently or maliciously revealed the
 weakness of the Roman empire.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"One of the nights without a moon had
 been selected for the execution of their design; and they
 had almost reached the southern bank of the Danube, in the
 firm confidence that they should find an easy landing and an
 unguarded camp.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"Sensible of
 the benefits which would result from the union of the Gothic
 powers under the same standard, he secretly cultivated the
 friendship of the Ostrogoths; and while he professed an
 implicit obedience to the orders of the Roman generals, he
 proceeded by slow marches towards Marcianopolis, the capital
 of the Lower Maesia, about seventy miles from the banks of
 the Danube.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Marcianopolis', 'GPE'), ('the Lower Maesia', 'LOC'), ('about seventy miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"Settlement of the Goths in Thrace and Asia, A.D. 383-395.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('383-395', 'CARDINAL')"
"Several of the hordes
 were allured by the liberal promises of Fritigern; and the
 rapid cavalry of Scythia added weight and energy to the
 steady and strenuous efforts of the Gothic infantry.","('Fritigern', 'NORP'), ('Scythia', 'ORG'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"Some military skill was displayed by Fritigern to
 gain the advantage of a commanding eminence; but the bloody
 conflict, which began and ended with the light, was
 maintained on either side by the personal and obstinate
 efforts of strength, valour, and agility.","('Fritigern', 'PERSON')"
"Some of
 the happy savages who dwell between the tropics are
 plentifully nourished by the liberality of nature, but in
 the climates of the North a nation of shepherds is reduced
 to their flocks and herds.","('North', 'LOC')"
"Some time before the great emigration a numerous body of Goths, under the command of Suerid and Colias, had been received into the protection and service of the empire.(73)","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Suerid', 'PERSON'), ('Colias', 'PERSON')"
"Such are the words of the Gothic historian,(72) who celebrates, with rude eloquence, the glory of his countrymen.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('72', 'DATE')"
"Such at least
 were the recent limits of the black Calmucks, (50) who 
 remained about a century under the protection of Russia, and
 who have since returned to their native seats on the
 frontiers of the Chinese empire.","('Calmucks', 'PERSON'), ('50', 'CARDINAL'), ('about a century', 'DATE'), ('Russia', 'GPE'), ('Chinese', 'NORP')"
"Such was likewise the merit of Theodosius; and the
 infirmities of his body, which most unseasonably languished
 under a long and dangerous disease, could not oppress the
 vigour of his mind, or divert his attention from the public
 service.(118)
Divisions defeat and submission, of the Goths, A.D. 379-382.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('118', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('379-382', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such were the 
 scenes of barbaric rage which disgraced the palace and table
 of the Roman emperor; and, as the impatient Goths could only
 be restrained by the firm and temperate character of
 Theodosius, the public safety seemed to depend on the life
 and abilities of a single man.(136)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('136', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 Northern Sea was fixed as the remote boundary of their
 empire.","('The\r\n Northern Sea', 'LOC')"
"The
 Sarmatians, who could never forgive the successor of
 Valentinian, enjoyed and increased the general confusion;
 and a seasonable irruption of the Alemanni into the
 provinces of Gaul engaged the attention and diverted the
 forces of the emperor of the West.(85)
Victory of Gratian over the Alemani, A.D. 378.","('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('85', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alemani', 'PERSON'), ('378', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 acquisition of Modar, a prince of the royal blood of the
 Amali, gave a bold and faithful champion to the cause of
 Rome.","('Modar', 'ORG'), ('Amali', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The
 advantages of negotiating in the midst of war were perfectly
 understood by the general of the barbarians; and a Christian
 ecclesiastic was despatched, as the holy minister of peace,
 to penetrate and to perplex the councils of the enemy.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The
 barbarians still wore an angry and hostile aspect; but the
 experience of past times might encourage the hope that they
 would acquire the habits of industry and obedience; that
 their manners would be polished by time, education, and the
 influence of Christianity; and that their posterity would
 insensibly blend with the great body of the Roman people.
 (132)","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('132', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 daily subsistence of near a million of extraordinary
 subjects could be supplied only by constant and skilful
 diligence, and might continually be interrupted by mistake
 or accident.","('near a million', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 detachments of these separate garrisons were gradually
 united into small armies; the same cautious measures were
 pursued, according to an extensive and well-concerted plan
 of operations; the events of each day added strength and
 spirit to the Roman arms; and the artful diligence of the
 emperor, who circulated the most favourable reports of the
 success of the war, contributed to subdue the pride of the
 barbarians, and to animate the hopes and courage of his
 subjects.","('each day', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The
 general hunting matches, the pride and delight of the Tartar
 princes, compose an instructive exercise for their numerous
 cavalry.","('Tartar', 'NORP')"
"The
 harsh and obscure appellations of those tribes would offend
 the ear, without informing the understanding, of the reader;
 but I cannot suppress the very natural suspicion that the
 Huns of the North derived a considerable reinforcement from
 the ruin of the dynasty of the South, which, in the course
 of the third century, submitted to the dominion of China;
 that the bravest warriors marched away in search of their
 free and adventurous countrymen; and that, as they had been
 divided by prosperity, they were easily reunited by the
 common hardships of their adverse fortune.(53) The Huns, with 
 their flocks and herds, their wives and children, their
 dependents and allies, were transported to the west of the
 Volga, and they boldly advanced to invade the country of the
 Alani, a pastoral people, who occupied, or wasted, an
 extensive tract of the deserts of Scythia.","('the\r\n Huns of the North', 'ORG'), ('South', 'LOC'), ('the third century', 'DATE'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Volga', 'LOC'), ('Alani', 'NORP'), ('Scythia', 'GPE')"
"The
 loose subordination and extensive possessions of the Huns
 and the Alani delayed the conquests and distracted the
 councils of that victorious people.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Alani', 'PERSON')"
"The
 misfortunes, as well as the provocations, of the Gothic
 nation were forcibly and truly described by their
 ambassador, who protested, in the name of Fritigern, that he
 was still disposed to lay down his arms, or to employ them
 only in the defence of the empire, if he could secure for
 his wandering countrymen a tranquil settlement on the waste
 lands of Thrace, and a sufficient allowance of corn and
 cattle.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Fritigern', 'PERSON'), ('Thrace', 'LOC')"
"The
 sons of the Goths had been judiciously distributed through
 the cities of the East, and the arts of education were
 employed to polish and subdue the native fierceness of their
 temper.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The
 splendid narratives which he general transmitted of his own
 exploits alarmed the Imperial court by the appearance of
 superior merit; and though he cautiously insisted on the
 difficulties of the Gothic war, his valour was praised, his
 advice was rejected; and Valens, who listened with pride and
 pleasure to the flattering suggestions of the eunuchs of the
 palace, was impatient to seize the glory of all easy and
 assured conquest.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('the Gothic war', 'EVENT'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"The 
 desertion of his subjects, and the perplexity of a civil
 war, at length compelled the Tanjou himself to renounce the
 dignity of an independent sovereign, and the freedom of a
 warlike and high-spirited nation.","('Tanjou', 'PERSON')"
"The 
 invasion of the Huns precipitated on the provinces of the
 West the Gothic nation, which advanced, in less than forty
 years, from the Danube to the Atlantic, and opened a way, by
 the success of their arms, to the inroads of so many hostile
 tribes more savage than themselves.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('less than forty\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Atlantic', 'LOC')"
"The 
 provinces of Thrace, Asia, and Egypt, over which Valens had
 reigned, were resigned to the administration of the new
 emperor; but as he was specially intrusted with the conduct
 of the Gothic war, the Illyrian praefecture was dismembered,
 and the two great dioceses of Dacia and Macedonia were added
 to the dominions of the Eastern empire. (106)
Birth and character of Theodosius.","('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('the Gothic war', 'EVENT'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dacia', 'GPE'), ('Macedonia', 'GPE'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('106', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The 
 vicinity of the Huns to the provinces of Persia involved
 them in frequent and bloody contests with the power of that
 monarchy.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"The Chinese
 generals improved the superiority which they derived from
 the temper of their arms, their chariots of war, and the
 service of their Tartar auxiliaries.","('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('Tartar', 'NORP')"
"The Coroultai, (14) or Diet, of the Tartars was 
 regularly held in the spring and autumn in the midst of a
 plain, where the princes of the reigning family and the
 mursas of the respective tribes may conveniently assemble on
 horseback with their martial and numerous trains, and the
 ambitious monarch who reviewed the strength, must consult
 the inclination, of an armed people.","('Coroultai', 'PRODUCT'), ('14', 'CARDINAL'), ('Diet', 'ORG'), ('Tartars', 'LOC')"
"The Gothic cavalry had been detached to
 forage in the adjacent country; and Fritigern still
 continued to practise his customary arts.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Fritigern', 'PERSON')"
"The Gothic king did not long enjoy this splendid and honourable reception; and, as temperance was not the virtue of his nation, it may justly be suspected that his mortal disease was contracted amidst the pleasures of the Imperial banquets.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
The Goths beseige Hadrianople.,"('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Hadrianople', 'PRODUCT')"
"The Goths implore the protection of Valens, A.D. 376.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('376', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Goths who considered
 themselves as the friends of peace, of justice, and of Rome,
 were directed by the authority of Fravitta, a valiant and
 honourable youth, distinguished above the rest of his
 countrymen by the politeness of his manners, the liberality
 of his sentiments, and the mild virtues of social life.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Fravitta', 'PERSON')"
"The Goths, with arms in
 their hands, were permitted to enter the boats; and when
 their strength was collected on the other side of the river,
 the immense camp which was spread over the plains and the
 hills of the Lower Maesia assumed a threatening and even
 hostile aspect.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('the Lower Maesia', 'LOC')"
"The Greeks, who navigated the
 Euxine, and planted their colonies along the seacoast, made
 the gradual and imperfect discovery of Scythia, from the
 Danube and the confines of Thrace, as far as the frozen
 Maeotis, the seat of eternal winter, and Mount Caucasus,
 which, in the language of poetry, was described as the
 utmost boundary of the earth.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Euxine', 'NORP'), ('Scythia', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Maeotis', 'LOC'), ('Mount Caucasus', 'LOC')"
"The Huns and Goths, A.D. 376.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('376', 'CARDINAL')"
The Huns of the Volga.,"('The Huns of the Volga', 'PERSON')"
"The Huns prevailed in the bloody contest; the king
 of the Alani was slain; and the remains of the vanquished
 nation were dispersed by the ordinary alternative of flight
 or submission.(55) A colony of exiles found a secure refuge 
 in the mountains of Caucasus, between the Euxine and the
 Caspian, where they still preserve their name and their
 independence.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Alani', 'PERSON'), ('Caucasus', 'LOC'), ('Euxine', 'LOC'), ('Caspian', 'LOC')"
"The Huns, who under the reign of Valens threatened the
 empire of Rome, had been formidable, in a much earlier
 period, to the empire of China.(27)","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('27', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Imperial
 mandate was at length received for transporting over the
 Danube the whole body of the Gothic nation; (65) but the 
 execution of this order was a task of labour and difficulty.","('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('65', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Ostrogoths impelled several of the German tribes on the
 provinces of Gaul; concluded, and soon violated, a treaty
 with the emperor Gratian; advanced into the unknown
 countries of the North; and, after an interval of more than
 four years, returned with accumulated force to the banks of
 the Lower Danube.","('Ostrogoths', 'PERSON'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('more than\r\n four years', 'DATE'), ('the Lower Danube', 'LOC')"
"The Ostrogoths submitted to
 their fate: and the royal race of the Amali will hereafter
 be found among the subjects of the haughty Attila.","('Ostrogoths', 'NORP'), ('Amali', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The Persian monarchs had extended their 
 western conquests to the banks of the Danube and the limits
 of European Scythia.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('European Scythia', 'ORG')"
"The Romans, who so coolly and so concisely mention the acts
 of justice which were exercised by the legions,(99) reserved their compassion and their eloquence for their own sufferings when the provinces were invaded and desolated by the arms of the successful barbarians.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('99', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Scythians of every age
 have been celebrated as bold and skilful riders, and
 constant practice had seated them so firmly on horseback
 that they were supposed by strangers to perform the ordinary
 duties of civil life, to eat, to drink, and even to sleep,
 without dismounting from their steeds.","('Scythians', 'PERSON')"
"The Sienpi, (42) a tribe of Oriental Tartars, 
 retaliated the injuries which they had formerly sustained;
 and the power of the Tanjous, A.D. 93.after a reign of thirteen
 hundred years, was utterly destroyed before the end of the
 first century of the Christian era.(43)","('Sienpi', 'PERSON'), ('42', 'CARDINAL'), ('Oriental Tartars', 'ORG'), ('Tanjous', 'PRODUCT'), ('A.D. 93', 'DATE'), ('thirteen\r\n hundred years', 'DATE'), ('the end of the\r\n first century', 'DATE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('43', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Tartars are an ugly and even deformed
 race; and while they consider their own women as the
 instruments of domestic labour, their desires, or rather
 their appetites, are directed to the enjoyment of more
 elegant beauty.","('Tartars', 'NORP')"
"The Western world was open to their valour,
 and they resolved, under the conduct of their hereditary
 chieftains, to discover and subdue some remote country which
 was still inaccessible to the arms of the Sienpi and to the
 laws of China. (45)","('Western', 'NORP'), ('Sienpi', 'NORP'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('45', 'CARDINAL')"
The White Huns of the Sogdiana.,"('The White Huns', 'PERSON')"
"The absolute refusal of Valens
 suspended their progress, and discovered the repentance, the
 suspicions, and the fears of the Imperial council.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The active cavalry of Scythia
 is always followed, in their most distant and rapid
 incursions, by an adequate number of spare horses, who may
 be occasionally used either to redouble the speed or to
 satisfy the hunger of the barbarians.","('Scythia', 'GPE')"
"The advocates of
 Theodosius could affirm, with some appearance of truth and
 reason, that it was impossible to extirpate so many warlike
 tribes, who were rendered desperate by the loss of their
 native country; and that the exhausted provinces would be
 revived by a fresh supply of soldiers and husbandmen.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The aged king of the Goths languished some time after the
 dangerous wound which he received from their daggers; but
 the conduct of the war was retarded by his infirmities; and
 the public councils of the nation were distracted by a
 spirit of jealousy and discord.","('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The annals of China (25) 
 illustrate the state and revolutions of the pastoral tribes,
 which may still be distinguished by the vague appellation of
 Scythians or Tartars—the vassals, the enemies, and
 sometimes the conquerors of a great empire, whose policy has
 uniformly opposed the blind and impetuous valour of the
 barbarians of the North.","('China', 'GPE'), ('25', 'CARDINAL'), ('Scythians', 'NORP'), ('Tartars', 'NORP'), ('North', 'LOC')"
"The army of the Goths, laden 
 with the spoils of the wealthy suburbs and the adjacent
 territory, slowly moved from the Bosphorus to the mountains
 which form the western boundary of Thrace.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Thrace', 'LOC')"
The barbarians expected his approach about nine miles from Marcianopolis; and on this occasion the talents of the general were found to be of more prevailing efficacy than the weapons and discipline of the troops.,"('about nine miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Marcianopolis', 'GPE')"
"The barbarians opposed to his progress the
 obstacles of nature and of courage; and still continued to
 retreat from one hill to another till they were satisfied,
 by repeated trials, of the power and perseverance of their
 enemies.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The barbarians stood silent and amazed, till they were exasperated by the insulting clamours and missile weapons of the populace: but when patience or contempt was fatigued, they crushed the undisciplined multitude, inflicted many a shameful wound on the backs of their flying enemies, and despoiled them of the splendid armour(74) which they were unworthy to bear.","('74', 'CARDINAL')"
"The barbarians were surprised
 with the splendid appearance of the capital of the East, the
 height and extent of the walls, the myriads of wealthy and
 affrighted citizens who crowded the ramparts, and the
 various prospect of the sea and land.","('East', 'LOC')"
"The barbarians would have deserved to feel
 the cruel and perfidious policy of the Imperial court if
 they had suffered themselves to be dispersed through the
 provinces.","('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"The barbarians, who considered their
 arms as the ensigns of honour and the pledges of safety,
 were disposed to offer a price which the lust or avarice of
 the Imperial officers was easily tempted to accept.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The bravest of the Ostrogoths led the 
 van; the main body consisted of the remainder of their
 subjects and soldiers; and the women and children securely
 followed in the rear.","('Ostrogoths', 'PERSON')"
"The calamities of 
 the War were painted in the most lively colours; and the
 first symptoms of the return of order, of plenty, and
 security were diligently exaggerated.","('the War', 'EVENT'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The camp of Valens, which he pitched under the
 walls of Hadrianople, was fortified, according to the
 practice of the Romans, with a ditch and rampart; and a most
 important council was summoned to decide the fate of the
 emperor and of the empire.","('Valens', 'GPE'), ('Hadrianople', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The camp of the Tanjou
 was surprised in the midst of sleep and intemperance; and,
 though the monarch of the Huns bravely cut his way through
 the ranks of the enemy, he left above fifteen thousand of
 his subjects on the field of battle.","('Tanjou', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('fifteen thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The camp, and not the soil, is the
 native country of the genuine Tartar.","('Tartar', 'NORP')"
"The cavalry of Scythia was forced to
 yield to the admirable swiftness and spirit of the Arabian
 horses; their riders were skilled in the evolutions of
 irregular war; and the Northern barbarians were astonished
 and dismayed by the inhuman ferocity of the barbarians of
 the South.","('Scythia', 'GPE'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('Northern barbarians', 'NORP'), ('South', 'LOC')"
"The cavalry of the Tanjou frequently consisted of
 two or three hundred thousand men, formidable by the
 matchless dexterity with which they managed their bows and
 their horses; by their hardy patience in supporting the
 inclemency of the weather; and by the incredible speed of
 their march, which was seldom checked by torrents or
 precipices, by the deepest rivers, or by the most lofty
 mountains.","('Tanjou', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('three hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The children of
 the Goths, those at least of a distinguished rank, were
 separated from the multitude.","('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The choice of
 Gratian was soon declared in favour of an exile, whose
 father, only three years before, had suffered, under the
 sanction of his authority, an unjust and ignominious death.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('three years before', 'DATE')"
"The choice of stations is regulated by the difference of the
 seasons; in the summer the Tartars advance towards the
 North, and pitch their tents on the banks of a river, or, at
 least, in the neighbourhood of a running stream.","('the summer', 'DATE'), ('Tartars', 'NORP'), ('North', 'LOC')"
"The clamorous shouts and dying
 groans apprised Fritigern of his extreme danger; and, as he
 possessed the calm and intrepid spirit of a hero, he saw
 that he was lost if he allowed a moment of deliberation to
 the man who had so deeply injured him.","('Fritigern', 'PERSON')"
"The clamours of a
 multitude, untaught to disguise their sentiments, announced
 the first symptoms of resistance, and alarmed the timid and
 guilty minds of Lupicinus and Maximus.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Lupicinus', 'PERSON'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"The conquest of China has been twice achieved by the
 pastoral tribes of the North: the forces of the Huns were
 not inferior to those of the Moguls, or of the Mantcheoux;
 and their ambition might entertain the most sanguine hopes
 of success.","('China', 'GPE'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Moguls', 'NORP'), ('Mantcheoux', 'NORP')"
"The course of their emigration soon 
 carried them beyond the mountains of Imaus and the limits of
 the Chinese geography; but we are able to distinguish the
 two great divisions of these formidable exiles, which
 directed their march towards the Oxus and towards the Volga.","('Imaus', 'LOC'), ('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Oxus', 'ORG'), ('Volga', 'LOC')"
"The danger of the times
 seemed to justify the jealous suspicions of the provincials;
 and these suspicions were admitted as unquestionable
 evidence that the Goths of Asia had formed a secret and
 dangerous conspiracy against the public safety.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The death of
 Valens had left the East without a sovereign; and Julius,
 who filled the important station of master-general of the
 troops, with a high reputation of diligence and ability,
 thought it his duty to consult the senate of Constantinople,
 which he considered, during the vacancy of the throne, as
 the representative council of the nation.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Julius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The death of that hero, the predecessor
 and master of the renowned Alaric, relieved an impatient
 multitude from the intolerable yoke of discipline and
 discretion.","('Alaric', 'PERSON')"
The defeat of the Romans.,"('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The deliverance and peace of the Roman provinces(119) was the work of prudence, rather than of valour: the prudence of
 Theodosius was seconded by fortune; and the emperor never
 failed to seize, and to improve, every favourable
 circumstance.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('119', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The design was prosecuted with some
 conduct and success; the barbarians had almost exhausted
 their own magazines and the harvests of the country; and the
 diligence of Saturninus, the master-general of the cavalry,
 was employed to improve the strength and to contract the
 extent of the Roman fortifications.","('Saturninus', 'ORG'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The dexterity of the
 spies whom he sent into the Gothic camp allured the
 barbarians into a fatal snare.","('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"The different characters that mark the civilised nations of
 the globe may be ascribed to the use and the abuse of
 reason, which so variously shapes and so artificially
 composes the manners and opinions of an European or a
 Chinese.","('European', 'NORP'), ('Chinese', 'NORP')"
"The eastern provinces of their empire
 were exposed to the Scythians of Asia, the wild inhabitants
 of the plains beyond the Oxus and the Jaxartes, two mighty
 rivers, which direct their course towards the Caspian Sea.","('Scythians', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Oxus', 'LOC'), ('Jaxartes', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Caspian Sea', 'LOC')"
"The emperor Gratian invests Theodosius with the empire of the East, A.D. 379, January 19.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('379', 'CARDINAL'), ('January 19', 'DATE')"
"The emperor Gratian was far advanced on his march towards
 the plains of Hadrianople when he was informed, at first by
 the confused voice of fame, and afterwards by the more
 accurate reports of Victor and Richomer, that his impatient
 colleague had been slain in battle, and that two-thirds of
 the Roman army were exterminated by the sword of the
 victorious Goths.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Hadrianople', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Victor', 'PERSON'), ('Richomer', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The emperor Kaoti, (34) a soldier of fortune, whose 
 personal merit had raised him to the throne, marched against
 the Huns with those veteran troops which had been trained in
 the civil wars of China.","('Kaoti', 'PERSON'), ('34', 'CARDINAL'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('China', 'GPE')"
"The emperor of the East was no longer guided by
 the wisdom and authority of his elder brother, A.D. 375, Nov 17.","('East', 'LOC'), ('A.D. 375', 'PERSON'), ('Nov 17', 'DATE')"
"The emperor was persuaded
 to send an ambassador to the Gothic camp; the zeal of
 Richomer, who alone had courage to accept the dangerous
 commission, was applauded; and the count of the domestics,
 adorned with the splendid ensigns of his dignity, had
 proceeded some way in the space between the two armies when
 he was suddenly recalled by the alarm of battle.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Richomer', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The enterprise of some light
 detachments, who in the month of February passed the Rhine
 upon the ice, was the prelude of a more important war.","('the month of February', 'DATE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"The evening was already far
 advanced; and the two armies prepared themselves for the
 approaching combat, which was deferred only till the dawn of
 day.","('The evening', 'TIME'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('the dawn of\r\n day', 'DATE')"
"The event of the battle of Hadrianople, so fatal to Valens and to the empire, may be described in a few words: the Roman cavalry fled; the infantry was abandoned, surrounded, and cut in pieces.","('Hadrianople', 'GPE'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The exploits of 
 Sebastian,(90) who was recently engaged in the service of 
 Valens, and promoted to the rank of master-general of the
 infantry, were still more honourable to himself, and useful
 to the republic.","('Sebastian', 'PERSON'), ('90', 'DATE'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"The fabric of a mighty state, which has been reared
 by the labours of successive ages, could not be overturned
 by the misfortune of a single day, if the fatal power of the
 imagination did not exaggerate the real measure of the
 calamity.","('a single day', 'DATE')"
"The fatal oversight, as observed and
 improved by Alatheus and Saphrax, who anxiously watched the
 favourable moment of escaping from the pursuit of the Huns.","('Alatheus', 'PERSON'), ('Saphrax', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"The fate of the vanquished Huns was diversified by the
 various influence of character and situation.(44)","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"The first of these colonies established their dominion in
 the fruitful and extensive plains of the Sogdiana, on the
 eastern side of the Caspian, where they preserved the name
 of Huns, with the epithet of Euthalites or Nepthalites.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Sogdiana', 'LOC'), ('Caspian', 'LOC'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Euthalites', 'NORP'), ('Nepthalites', 'NORP')"
"The five years(63) which he spent at 
 Antioch were employed to watch, from a secure distance, the
 hostile designs of the Persian monarch; to check the
 depredations of the Saracens and Isaurians;(64) to enforce, 
 by arguments more prevalent than those of reason and
 eloquence, the belief of the Arian theology, and to satisfy
 his anxious suspicions by the promiscuous execution of the
 innocent and the guilty.","('five years(63', 'DATE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Isaurians', 'NORP'), ('64', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arian', 'NORP')"
"The flattering poet, who 
 celebrated in the court of Honorius the glory of the father
 and of the son, ascribes the victory to the personal prowess
 of Theodosius; and almost insinuates that the king of the
 Ostrogoths was slain by the hand of the emperor.(127)","('Honorius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Ostrogoths', 'PERSON'), ('127', 'CARDINAL')"
"The flocks and herds, after grazing all day in
 the adjacent pastures, retire, on the approach of night,
 within the protection of the camp.","('all day', 'DATE'), ('night', 'TIME')"
"The funeral of Athanaric was performed with solemn rites in the capital of the East; a stately monument was erected to his memory; and his whole army, won by the liberal courtesy and decent grief of Theodosius, enlisted under the standard of the Roman
 empire. (122)","('Athanaric', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('122', 'CARDINAL')"
"The general who commanded the military and 
 naval powers of the Thracian frontier soon perceived that
 his superiority would be disadvantageous to the public
 service; and that the barbarians, awed by the presence of
 his fleet and legions, would probably defer the passage of
 the river till the approaching winter.","('Thracian', 'NORP')"
"The general, or rather the final, capitulation of the Goths, may be dated four years, one month, and twenty-five days A.D. 382, October 3., after the defeat and death of the emperor Valens. (123)
Invasion and defeat of the Gruthungi, or Ostrogoths, A.D. 386, October.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('four years', 'DATE'), ('one month', 'DATE'), ('twenty-five days', 'DATE'), ('A.D. 382', 'DATE'), ('October 3', 'DATE'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('123', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gruthungi', 'ORG'), ('Ostrogoths', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 386', 'DATE'), ('October', 'DATE')"
"The generals of the Goths were saluted by the fierce and joyful acclamations of the camp; war was instantly resolved, and the resolution was executed without delay: the banners of the nation were displayed according to the custom of their ancestors; and the air resounded with the harsh and mournful music of the barbarian trumpet.","('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The glory of the day was 
 justly ascribed to the missile weapons and well-practised
 evolutions of the Roman soldiers: the Alemanni, who long
 maintained their ground, were slaughtered with unrelenting
 fury: five thousand only of the barbarians escaped to the
 woods and mountains; and the glorious death of their king on
 the field of battle saved him from the reproaches of the
 people, who are always disposed to accuse the justice or
 policy of an unsuccessful war.","('the day', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('five thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The great Hermanric, whose dominions extended from the
 Baltic to the Euxine, enjoyed, in the full maturity of age
 and reputation, the fruit of his victories, when he was
 alarmed by the formidable approach of an host of unknown
 enemies,(56) on whom his barbarous subjects might, without 
 injustice, bestow the epithet of barbarians.","('Hermanric', 'PERSON'), ('Baltic', 'LOC'), ('Euxine', 'NORP'), ('56', 'CARDINAL')"
"The great Theodosius, a name celebrated in history and dear
 to the Catholic church, (104) was summoned to the Imperial 
 court, which had gradually retreated from the confines of
 Thrace to the more secure station of Sirmium.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('104', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Sirmium', 'ORG')"
"The hardships of the
 savage life, which destroy in their infancy the children who
 are born with a less healthy and robust constitution,
 the two sexes.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The hasty
 and imprudent attack was made by Bacurius the Iberian, who
 commanded a body of archers and targeteers: and, as they
 advanced with rashness, they retreated with loss and
 disgrace.","('Bacurius the Iberian', 'PERSON')"
"The hereditary chiefs of the tribes and families were still
 permitted to command their followers in peace and war: but
 the royal dignity was abolished; and the generals of the
 Goths were appointed and removed at the pleasure of the
 emperor.","('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The houses of the
 Tartars are no more than small tents, of an oval form which
 afford a cold and dirty habitation for the promiscuous youth
 of both sexes.","('Tartars', 'LOC')"
"The illustrious deserter soon obtained the rank of
 master-general, with an important command; surprised an army
 of his countrymen, who were immersed in wine and sleep; and,
 after a cruel slaughter of the astonished Goths, returned
 with an immense spoil, and four thousand waggons, to the
 Imperial camp.(120)","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('120', 'CARDINAL')"
"The immediate
 jurisdiction of the Khan is confined within the limits of
 his own tribe, and the exercise of his royal prerogative has
 been moderated by the ancient institution of a national
 council.","('Khan', 'PERSON')"
"The important
 pass of Succi was betrayed by the fear or the misconduct of
 Maurus; and the barbarians, who no longer had any resistance
 to apprehend from the scattered and vanquished troops of the
 East, spread themselves over the face of a fertile and
 cultivated country, as far as the confines of Italy and the
 Hadriatic Sea.(98)","('Succi', 'PERSON'), ('Maurus', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('the\r\n Hadriatic Sea', 'LOC'), ('98', 'CARDINAL')"
"The impression was communicated to the waters; the shores of the Mediterranean were left dry by the sudden retreat of the sea; great quantities of fish were caught with the hand; large vessels were stranded on the mud; and a curious spectator (1) amused his eye, or rather his fancy, by contemplating the various appearance of valleys and mountains which had never, since the formation of the globe, been exposed to the sun.","('Mediterranean', 'LOC'), ('1', 'CARDINAL')"
"The imprudence of Valens and his ministers had introduced
 into the heart of the empire a nation of enemies; but the
 Visigoths might even yet have been reconciled by the manly
 confession of past errors and the sincere performance of
 former engagements.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP')"
"The insolence or the indignation of the Goths,
 if they conceived themselves to be the objects either of
 fear or of contempt, might urge them to the most desperate
 extremities, and the fortune of the state seemed to depend
 on the prudence, as well as the integrity, of the generals
 of Valens.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"The intelligence that Gratian was preparing
 to lead the military force of Gaul and of the West to the
 assistance of his uncle Valens, pointed out to the restless
 spirit of the Alemanni the moment and the mode of a
 successful invasion.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Alemanni', 'NORP')"
"The just apprehension that he himself might be surrounded
 and overwhelmed by the arms of hostile and unknown nations,
 compelled Saturninus to relinquish the siege of the Gothic
 camp; and the indignant Visigoths, breaking from their
 confinement, satiated their hunger and revenge by the
 repeated devastation of the fruitful country which extends
 above three hundred miles from the banks of the Danube to
 the straits of the Hellespont. (83)","('Saturninus', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('three hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Hellespont', 'LOC'), ('83', 'CARDINAL')"
"The latitude of these
 extensive deserts cannot be so easily or so accurately
 measured; but, from the fortieth degree, which touches the
 wall of China, we may securely advance above a thousand
 miles to the northward, till our progress is stopped by the
 excessive cold of Siberia.","('China', 'GPE'), ('a thousand\r\n miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Siberia', 'LOC')"
"The leaders of the Ostrogoths, Alatheus and
 Saphrax, the guardians of their infant king, appeared soon
 afterwards on the northern banks of the Danube, and
 immediately despatched their ambassadors to the court of
 Antioch to solicit, with the same professions of allegiance
 and gratitude, the same favour which had been granted to the
 suppliant Visigoths.","('Ostrogoths', 'NORP'), ('Alatheus', 'PERSON'), ('Saphrax', 'PERSON'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP')"
"The legions of
 Armenia supported their fame in arms, but they were
 oppressed by the irresistible weight of the hostile
 multitude: the left wing of he Romans was thrown into
 disorder, and the field was strewed with their mangled
 carcasses.","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The legions which had been ordered to
 march into Pannonia were immediately recalled or detained
 for the defence of Gaul; the military command was divided
 between Nanienus and Mellobaudes; and the youthful emperor,
 though he respected the long experience and sober wisdom of
 the former, was much more inclined to admire and to follow
 the martial ardour of his colleague, who was allowed to
 unite the incompatible characters of count of the domestics
 and of king of the Franks.","('Pannonia', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Nanienus', 'NORP'), ('Mellobaudes', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"The liberality of
 the emperor was accompanied, however, with two harsh and
 rigorous conditions, which prudence might justify on the
 side of the Romans, but which distress alone could extort
 from the indignant Goths.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The long and memorable quarrel of Iran and Touran is still
 the theme of history or romance: the famous, perhaps the
 fabulous, valour of the Persian heroes, Rustan and
 Asfendiar, was signalised, in the defence of their country,
 against the Afrasiabs of the North;(20) and the invincible 
 spirit of the same barbarians resisted, on the same ground,
 the victorious arms of Cyrus and Alexander.(21)","('Iran', 'GPE'), ('Touran', 'GPE'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Rustan', 'PERSON'), ('Asfendiar', 'PERSON'), ('Afrasiabs', 'NORP'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('20', 'CARDINAL'), ('Cyrus', 'PERSON'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('21', 'CARDINAL')"
"The loss of forty thousand Romans, who fell in the
 plains of Hadrianople, might have been soon recruited in the
 populous provinces of the East, which contained so many
 millions of inhabitants.","('forty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Hadrianople', 'LOC'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('so many\r\n millions', 'CARDINAL')"
"The manners of his subjects, accustomed, like
 himself, to blood and rapine, might excuse in their eyes
 such partial acts of tyranny as would excite the horror of a
 civilised people, but the power of a despot has never been
 acknowledged in the deserts of Scythia.","('Scythia', 'GPE')"
"The march and the return of
