Sentence,Entities
"""Bareheaded, their hands crossed on their breast, they stood
 with downcast looks in the presence of the tribune; and they  trembled, good God, how they trembled!"" (41)","('41', 'CARDINAL')"
"""If the one advances,"" says a servant of Gregory,  ""the other retreats; the one appears an animal fearful of the land, the other a
 creature apprehensive of the water.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON')"
"""If you are spared,"" said the tribune,  ""by the
 mercy of the Romans, will you not promise to support the good estate with your lives and fortunes?""","('Romans', 'NORP')"
(44),"('44', 'CARDINAL')"
(45),"('45', 'CARDINAL')"
(55),"('55', 'CARDINAL')"
(April 9.),"('April 9', 'DATE')"
"(Sept. 21.) and proceeded to a new election of Robert of Geneva, Clement the Seventh, whom they announced to the nations as the true and rightful vicar of Christ.","('Sept. 21', 'DATE'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Geneva', 'GPE'), ('Clement', 'PERSON'), ('the Seventh', 'DATE'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"A Christian, a philosopher, (93) and a patriot, will be equally scandalized by the temporal kingdom of the clergy; and the local majesty of Rome, the remembrance of her consuls and triumphs, may seem to embitter the sense, and aggravate the shame, of her slavery.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('93', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"A banquet, such as the Caesars had given, was prepared for the Romans.","('Caesars', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"A citizen has remarked, with pride and pleasure, that the king of the Romans, after passing with a slight salute the cardinals and prelates who met him at the gate, distinguished the dress and person of the senator of Rome; and in this last farewell, the pageants of the empire and the republic were clasped in a friendly embrace.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"A civil war exhausted his treasures, and the patience of the city: the Colonna maintained their hostile station at Palestrina; and his mercenaries soon despised a leader whose ignorance and
 fear were envious of all subordinate merit.","('Colonna', 'PERSON'), ('Palestrina', 'GPE')"
"A false application of
 the name and maxims of antiquity was the source of the hopes
 and disappointments of Petrarch; yet he could not overlook
 the difference of times and characters; the immeasurable
 distance between the first Caesars and a Bohemian prince,
 who by the favour of the clergy had been elected the titular
 head of the German aristocracy.","('Petrarch', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Caesars', 'PERSON'), ('Bohemian', 'NORP'), ('German', 'NORP')"
"A free and vigorous opposition
 was formed in the city; and when the tribune proposed in the
 public council (47) to impose a new tax, and to regulate the
 government of Perugia, thirty-nine members voted against his
 measures; repelled the injurious charge of treachery and
 corruption; and urged him to prove, by their forcible
 exclusion, that if the populace adhered to his cause, it was
 already disclaimed by the most respectable citizens.","('47', 'CARDINAL'), ('Perugia', 'GPE'), ('thirty-nine', 'CARDINAL')"
"A general and peremptory order was
 issued from the Capitol to all the nobles, that they should
 peaceably retire to their estates: they obeyed; and their
 departure secured the tranquillity of the free and obedient
 citizens of Rome.","('Capitol', 'ORG'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"A king of France, who has deserved the epithet of wise, was unwilling to release them from a local dependence: the cardinals, for the most part his subjects, were attached to the language, manners, and climate of Avignon; to their stately palaces; above all, to the wines of Burgundy.","('France', 'GPE'), ('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('Burgundy', 'GPE')"
A liberal salary of three thousand florins was assigned for his expense and reward; and his public appearance represented the majesty of the republic.,"('three thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"A mule, with a jar of oil,
 had been stolen near Capranica; and the lord of the Ursini
 family was condemned to restore the damage, and to discharge
 a fine of four hundred florins for his negligence in
 guarding the highways.","('Capranica', 'PRODUCT'), ('Ursini', 'PERSON'), ('four hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"A prisoner at Avignon, (A.D. 1351.)","('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1351', 'DATE')"
"A privilege of rapine and oppression was
 long maintained by the barons of Rome; their houses were a
 fortress and a sanctuary: and the ferocious train of
 banditti and criminals whom they protected from the law
 repaid the hospitality with the service of their swords and
 daggers.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"A prophecy, or rather a summons, affixed on the church door
 of St. George, was the first public evidence of his designs;
 a nocturnal assembly of a hundred citizens on Mount
 Aventine, the first step to their execution.","('St. George', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mount\r\n Aventine', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"A short delay would have saved the Colonna, the delay of a
 single month, which elapsed between the triumph and the
 exile of Rienzi.","('Colonna', 'PRODUCT'), ('a\r\n single month', 'DATE'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"A simple citizen describes with pity, or perhaps with pleasure, the humiliation of the barons of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"A sonnet in praise of Rome was
 accepted as the effusion of genius and gratitude; and after
 the whole procession had visited the Vatican, the profane
 wreath was suspended before the shrine of St. Peter.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('St. Peter', 'FAC')"
"A subsequent day was appointed for the coronation of Rienzi; (40) seven crowns of different leaves or metals were successively placed on his head by the most eminent of the
 Roman clergy; they represented the seven gifts of the Holy Ghost; and he still professed to imitate the example of the ancient tribunes.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('40', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Holy Ghost', 'PERSON')"
A sudden alarm from the bell of the Capitol could still summon to the standard above twenty thousand volunteers: the support of the tribune and the laws required a more regular and permanent force.,"('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"A whole hour, without voice or motion, he stood amidst the multitude half naked and half dead: their rage was hushed into curiosity and wonder: the last feelings of reverence and compassion yet struggled in his favour; and they might have prevailed, if a bold assassin had not plunged a dagger in his breast.","('A whole hour', 'TIME'), ('half', 'CARDINAL'), ('half', 'CARDINAL')"
"A.D. 1355, January-May.","('A.D. 1355', 'DATE'), ('January-May', 'DATE')"
"According to the laws of Rome, (82) her first magistrate was required to be a doctor of laws, an alien, of a place at least forty miles from the city; with whose inhabitants he must not be connected in the third canonical degree of blood or alliance.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('82', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('at least forty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('third', 'ORDINAL')"
"After a solemn profession of fidelity, the Roman
 tribune was sent into Italy, with the title of senator; but
 the death of Baroncelli appeared to supersede the use of his
 mission; and the legate, Cardinal Albornoz, (53) a consummate
 statesman, allowed him with reluctance, and without aid, to
 undertake the perilous experiment.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Baroncelli', 'PERSON'), ('Cardinal Albornoz', 'PERSON'), ('53', 'DATE')"
"After an exile of seven years, the first deliverer was again
 restored to his country.","('seven years', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"After discoursing on a text of Virgil, and
 thrice repeating his vows for the prosperity of Rome, he
 knelt before the throne, and received from the senator a
 laurel crown, with a more precious declaration, ""This is the
 reward of merit.""","('Virgil', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"After drawing his military force to the metropolis, and imposing the best security of oaths (80) and treaties, Nicholas received with a smiling countenance the faithful advocate and vassal of the church.","('80', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nicholas', 'PERSON')"
"After securing a faithful band to protect his first
 declaration, he proclaimed through the city, by sound of
 trumpet, that on the evening of the following day, all
 persons should assemble without arms before the church of
 St. Angelo, to provide for the reestablishment of the good
 estate.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the evening of the following day', 'TIME'), ('St. Angelo', 'GPE')"
"After such an example, none who were conscious of
 guilt could hope for impunity, and the flight of the wicked,
 the licentious, and the idle, soon purified the city and
 territory of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"After such manifest and repeated guilt, even the mercy of
 Nicholas was silent.","('Nicholas', 'PERSON')"
"After the loss of liberty and empire, his third and more
 humble wish was to reconcile the shepherd with his flock; to
 recall the Roman bishop to his ancient and peculiar diocese.","('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"After this severe lesson, the popes contracted their ambition, which was almost satisfied, resumed the character of a common parent, and abstained from all offensive hostilities, except in a hasty quarrel, when the vicar of Christ and the Turkish sultan were armed at the same time against the kingdom of Naples. (91)","('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('91', 'CARDINAL')"
"After thus eradicating the remains of the schism, the synod of Constance proceeded with slow and cautious steps to elect the sovereign of Rome and the head of the church.","('Constance', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"After thus restoring the forces and finances of the republic, the tribune recalled the nobles from their solitary independence; required their personal appearance in the Capitol; and imposed an oath of allegiance to the new government, and of submission to the laws of the good
 estate.","('Capitol', 'ORG')"
"Amidst her domestic factions, she
 was doubtless superior to France both in art and science, in
 wealth and politeness; but the difference could scarcely
 support the epithet of barbarous, which he promiscuously
 bestows on the countries beyond the Alps.","('France', 'GPE'), ('Alps', 'LOC')"
"Amidst the indulgence of enthusiasm and
 eloquence, (15)","('15', 'CARDINAL')"
"Amidst the public misfortunes, the
 faults of Rienzi were forgotten; and the Romans sighed for
 the peace and prosperity of their good estate. (50)
 Adventures of Rienzi.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('50', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"And thus, for a short remnant of life and power, will these aged priests endanger the peace and salvation of the Christian world."" (74)
Council of Pisa, A.D. 1409.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('74', 'CARDINAL'), ('Council of Pisa', 'ORG'), ('1409', 'CARDINAL')"
"Apprehensive for their safety, but still more
 apprehensive of the danger of a refusal, the princes and
 barons returned to their houses at Rome in the garb of
 simple and peaceful citizens: the Colonna and Ursini, the
 Savelli and Frangipani, were confounded before the tribunal
 of a plebeian, of the vile buffoon whom they had so often
 derided, and their disgrace was aggravated by the
 indignation which they vainly struggled to disguise.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Colonna', 'NORP'), ('Ursini', 'NORP'), ('Savelli', 'NORP'), ('Frangipani', 'NORP')"
"As long as the yoke of Rienzi was that of justice and their country, their
 conscience forced them to esteem the man, whom pride and interest provoked them to hate: his extravagant conduct soon fortified their hatred by contempt; and they conceived the hope of subverting a power which was no longer so deeply
 rooted in the public confidence.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"At his own choice, the Roman people would have
 displayed their attachment and authority, by lavishing on
 his head the names of senator or consul, of king or emperor:
 he preferred the ancient and modest appellation of tribune;
 the protection of the commons was the essence of that sacred office; and they were ignorant, that it had never
 been invested with any share in the legislative or executive
 powers of the republic.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"At length a
 vigorous resolution was embraced; and a solemn embassy, of
 the titular patriarch of Alexandria, two archbishops, five
 bishops, five abbots, three knights, and twenty doctors, was
 sent to the courts of Avignon and Rome, to require, in the
 name of the church and king, the abdication of the two
 pretenders, of Peter de Luna, who styled himself Benedict
 the Thirteenth, and of Angelo Corrario, who assumed the name
 of Gregory the Twelfth.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Peter de Luna', 'PERSON'), ('Benedict', 'PERSON'), ('Thirteenth', 'DATE'), ('Angelo Corrario', 'PERSON'), ('Gregory the Twelfth', 'PERSON')"
"At the head of one
 hundred and fifty soldiers, the count of Minorbino
 introduced himself into Rome; barricaded the quarter of the
 Colonna: and found the enterprise as easy as it had seemed
 impossible.","('one\r\n hundred and fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Minorbino', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Colonna', 'PERSON')"
"At the hour of worship, he showed himself to the
 returning crowds in a majestic attitude, with a robe of
 purple, his sword, and gilt spurs; but the holy rites were
 soon interrupted by his levity and insolence.","('the hour', 'TIME')"
"At the sound of the great bell the
 people assembled; they were arraigned for a conspiracy
 against the tribune's life; and though some might sympathize
 in their distress, not a hand, nor a voice, was raised to
 rescue the first of the nobility from their impending doom.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Avignon, the
 mystic Babylon, the sink of vice and corruption, was the
 object of his hatred and contempt; but he forgets that her
 scandalous vices were not the growth of the soil, and that
 in every residence they would adhere to the power and luxury
 of the papal court.","('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('Babylon', 'GPE')"
"Besieging Rome by land and water, he thrice entered the gates as a Barbarian conqueror; profaned the altars, violated the virgins, pillaged the merchants, performed his devotions at St. Peter's, and left a garrison in the castle of St. Angelo.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP'), (""St. Peter's"", 'FAC'), ('St. Angelo', 'GPE')"
"Beyond the Alps, more especially at Avignon, the revolution
 was the theme of curiosity, wonder, and applause.","('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Avignon', 'GPE')"
"But
 the propitious season had elapsed; and if Venice, Florence,
 Sienna, Perugia, and many inferior cities offered their
 lives and fortunes to the good estate, the tyrants of
 Lombardy and Tuscany must despise, or hate, the plebeian
 author of a free constitution.","('the propitious season', 'DATE'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('Florence', 'GPE'), ('Sienna', 'GPE'), ('Perugia', 'GPE'), ('Lombardy', 'GPE'), ('Tuscany', 'GPE')"
"But Porcaro had learned from the
 younger Brutus, that with tyrants no faith or gratitude
 should be observed: the exile declaimed against the
 arbitrary sentence; a party and a conspiracy were gradually
 formed: his nephew, a daring youth, assembled a band of
 volunteers; and on the appointed evening a feast was
 prepared at his house for the friends of the republic.","('Porcaro', 'PERSON'), ('Brutus', 'PERSON')"
"But after their return from Avignon, the keys of St. Peter were guarded by the sword of St. Paul.","('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('St. Paul', 'GPE')"
"But as soon as the monarchs of France, Germany and Spain, contended with gigantic arms for the dominion of Italy, they supplied with art the deficiency of strength; and concealed, in a labyrinth of wars and treaties, their aspiring views, and the immortal hope of chasing the Barbarians beyond the Alps.","('France', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Alps', 'LOC')"
"But as soon as they were united at Anagni and Fundi, in a place of security, they cast aside the mask, accused their own falsehood and hypocrisy, excommunicated the apostate and antichrist of Rome, Election of Clement VII.","('Anagni', 'GPE'), ('Fundi', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But he still possessed in the castle of St. Angelo a faithful garrison and a train of artillery: their batteries incessantly thundered on the city, and a bullet more dexterously pointed broke down the barricade of the bridge, and scattered with a single shot the heroes of the republic.","('St. Angelo', 'GPE')"
"But his justice was sullied with cruelty, his activity was prompted by the ambition of conquest: after his decease the abuses revived; the treasure was dissipated; he entailed on posterity thirty-five new taxes and the venality of offices; and, after his death, his statue was demolished by an ungrateful, or an injured, people. (97)","('thirty-five', 'CARDINAL')"
"But his trial and condemnation would have involved some questions, which it was more prudent to leave under the veil of mystery: the temporal supremacy of the popes; the duty of residence; the civil and ecclesiastical privileges of the clergy and people of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But in the disorders of the schism, an aspiring neighbour, Ladislaus king of Naples, alternately supported and betrayed the pope and the people; by the former he was
 declared gonfalonier, or general, of the church, while the latter submitted to his choice the nomination of their magistrates.","('Ladislaus', 'PERSON'), ('Naples', 'GPE')"
"But in the eyes of Petrarch, and
 those of his graver contemporaries, his love was a sin, and
 Italian verse a frivolous amusement.","('Petrarch', 'PERSON'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
"But in the year one thousand five hundred and eighty the ancient statutes were collected, methodized in
 three books, and adapted to present use, under the
 pontificate, and with the approbation, of Gregory the
 Thirteenth: (83) this civil and criminal code is the modern
 law of the city; and, if the popular assemblies have been
 abolished, a foreign senator, with the three conservators,
 still resides in the palace of the Capitol. (84)","('the year one thousand five hundred and eighty', 'DATE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gregory the\r\n Thirteenth', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('83', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Capitol', 'FAC')"
"But in this decisive moment, Rienzi
 was not less anxious or apprehensive than his captives: he
 dreaded the splendour of their names, their surviving
 kinsmen, the inconstancy of the people the reproaches of the
 world, and, after rashly offering a mortal injury, he vainly
 presumed that, if he could forgive, he might himself be
 forgiven.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"But instead of
 extinguishing the schism, the rashness of the French and Italians had given a third pretender to the chair of St. Peter.","('French', 'NORP'), ('Italians', 'NORP'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE')"
"But such voluntary obedience evaporates with the first
 transports of zeal; and Rienzi felt the importance of
 justifying his usurpation by a regular form and a legal
 title.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"But the cloud which hung over the seven hills would be dispelled by the presence of their lawful sovereign: eternal fame, the prosperity of Rome, and the peace of Italy, would be the recompense of the pope who should dare to embrace this generous resolution.","('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
But the joy of Petrarch and the Italians was soon turned into grief and indignation.,"('Petrarch', 'PERSON'), ('Italians', 'NORP')"
"But the popes no
 longer trembled in the Vatican: they had strength to
 command, if they had resolution to claim, the obedience of
 their subjects; and the strangers, who observed these
 partial disorders, admired the easy taxes and wise
 administration of the ecclesiastical state. (87)","('Vatican', 'FAC')"
"But the senator was confined to the administration of justice: the Capitol, the treasury, and the government of
 the city and its territory, were entrusted to the three conservators, who were changed four times in each year: the militia of the thirteen regions assembled under the banners of their respective chiefs, or caporioni; and the first of these was distinguished by the name and dignity of the
 prior.","('Capitol', 'ORG'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('each year', 'DATE'), ('thirteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But this momentary sunshine was soon
 clouded by his own vices and those of the people: in the
 Capitol, he might often regret the prison of Avignon; and
 after a second administration of four months, Rienzi was
 massacred in a tumult which had been fomented by the Roman
 barons.","('Capitol', 'ORG'), ('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('four months', 'DATE'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But when
 their pride and avarice had exhausted the patience of the
 Romans, a confraternity of the Virgin Mary protected or
 avenged the republic: the bell of the Capitol was again
 tolled, the nobles in arms trembled in the presence of an
 unarmed multitude; and of the two senators, Colonna escaped
 from the window of the palace, and Ursini was stoned at the
 foot of the altar.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('the Virgin Mary', 'PERSON'), ('Capitol', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Colonna', 'PERSON'), ('Ursini', 'PERSON')"
"By the avocations of the schism, by foreign arms, and popular tumults, Urban the Sixth and his three successors were often compelled to interrupt their residence in the Vatican.","('Sixth', 'ORDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Vatican', 'FAC')"
"By the first he fulfils the wish of honesty and inexperience, that no civil suit should be protracted beyond the term of fifteen days.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('fifteen days', 'DATE')"
Character and Coronation of Petrarch.,"('Coronation of Petrarch', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Conspiracy of Porcaro, A.D. 1453, January 9.","('Porcaro', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1453', 'DATE'), ('January 9', 'DATE')"
"Could passion have listened to reason; could
 private interest have yielded to the public welfare; the
 supreme tribunal and confederate union of the Italian
 republic might have healed their intestine discord, and
 closed the Alps against the Barbarians of the North.","('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('North', 'LOC')"
"Council of Constance, (A.D. 1414-1418.)","('Council of Constance', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 1414-1418', 'DATE')"
"Council of Pisa, A.D. 1409.","('Council of Pisa', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 1409', 'DATE')"
"Defeat and death of the Colonna,(Nov. 20.)","('Colonna', 'PERSON'), ('Nov. 20', 'DATE')"
"Destitute of aid or hope, he was besieged till the evening: the doors of the Capitol were destroyed with axes and fire; and while the senator attempted to escape in a plebeian habit, he was discovered and dragged to the platform of the palace, the fatal scene of his judgments and executions.","('the evening', 'TIME'), ('Capitol', 'FAC')"
"Devoid of eloquence or genius, Baroncelli was
 distinguished by a resolute spirit: he spoke the language of
 a patriot, and trod in the footsteps of tyrants; his
 suspicion was a sentence of death, and his own death was the
 reward of his cruelties.","('Baroncelli', 'PERSON')"
"During fifteen years,
 the pacific designs of the university were eluded by the
 arts of the rival pontiffs, the scruples or passions of
 their adherents, and the vicissitudes of French factions,
 that ruled the insanity of Charles the Sixth.","('fifteen years', 'DATE'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Charles the Sixth', 'PERSON')"
"During several weeks, the cardinals attended their new master with the fairest professions of attachment and loyalty; till the summer heats permitted a decent escape from the city.","('several weeks', 'DATE')"
"During some weeks they were checked by the memory of their
 danger, rather than of their deliverance, till the most
 powerful of the Ursini, escaping with the Colonna from the
 city, erected at Marino the standard of rebellion.","('some weeks', 'DATE'), ('Ursini', 'NORP'), ('Colonna', 'NORP'), ('Marino', 'PERSON')"
"Eugenius the Fourth was the last pope expelled by the tumults of the Roman people, (78) Nicholas V. (A.D. 1447.) and Nicholas the Fifth, the last who was importuned by the  presence of a Roman emperor. (79)","('Eugenius', 'PERSON'), ('Fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Nicholas V.', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 1447', 'DATE'), ('Nicholas the Fifth', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('79', 'CARDINAL')"
"Even his justice was tainted
 with the guilt or reproach of selfish cruelty: the most
 virtuous citizen of Rome was sacrificed to his jealousy; and in the execution of a public robber, from whose purse he had been assisted, the magistrate too much forgot, or too much remembered, the obligations of the debtor. (54)","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Fall and flight of the tribune Rienzi, A.D. 1347, Dec. 15.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 1347', 'DATE'), ('Dec. 15', 'DATE')"
Fear and hatred of the nobles of Rome.,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
"For myself, it is my wish to depart in charity with all mankind, nor am I willing, in these last moments, to offend even the pope and clergy of Rome. (98)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('98', 'CARDINAL')"
"For the ancient honour of Rome, and
 the success of their commission, the ambassadors solicited a
 conference with the magistrates of the city, whom they
 gratified by a positive declaration, that the most Christian
 king did not entertain a wish of transporting the holy see
 from the Vatican, which he considered as the genuine and
 proper seat of the successor of St. Peter.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE')"
"For the maintenance of the public defence, for the establishment of granaries, for the relief of widows, orphans, and indigent convents, Rienzi applied, without fear of sacrilege, the revenues of the apostolic chamber: the three branches of hearth-money, the salt-duty,
 and the customs, were each of the annual produce of one hundred thousand florins; (26) and scandalous were the
 abuses, if in four or five months the amount of the salt-duty could be trebled by his judicious economy.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('26', 'CARDINAL'), ('four or five months', 'DATE')"
"For these reasons, and the hope of repassing the Alps, they rashly violated the peace and unity of the church; and the merits of their double choice are yet agitated in the Catholic schools. (67)","('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"From his earliest
 youth, Petrarch aspired to the poetic crown.","('Petrarch', 'PERSON')"
"From nature he had received the gift of a handsome person, (35) till it was swelled and disfigured by intemperance: and his propensity to laughter was corrected in the magistrate by the affectation of gravity and sternness.","('35', 'DATE')"
"From such parents Nicholas Rienzi Gabrini could inherit
 neither dignity nor fortune; and the gift of a liberal
 education, which they painfully bestowed, was the cause of
 his glory and untimely end.","('Nicholas Rienzi Gabrini', 'PERSON')"
"From the
 hands of a venerable knight he received the order of the
 Holy Ghost; the purification of the bath was a previous
 ceremony; but in no step of his life did Rienzi excite such
 scandal and censure as by the profane use of the porphyry
 vase, in which Constantine (a foolish legend) had been
 healed of his leprosy by Pope Sylvester. (37)","('the\r\n Holy Ghost', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Pope Sylvester', 'PERSON'), ('37', 'DATE')"
"From the banks of the Tyber and the Rhone, the hostile
 pontiffs encountered each other with the pen and the sword:
 the civil and ecclesiastical order of society was disturbed;
 and the Romans had their full share of the mischiefs of
 which they may be arraigned as the primary authors. (70)","('Tyber', 'LOC'), ('Rhone', 'LOC'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('70', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the first alarm, the bell of the Capitol
 incessantly tolled; but, instead of repairing to the
 well-known sound, the people were silent and inactive; and
 the pusillanimous Rienzi, deploring their ingratitude with
 sighs and tears, abdicated the government and palace of the
 republic.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"From the pages of Livy he had not imbibed the
 art, or even the courage, of a general: an army of twenty
 thousand Romans returned without honour or effect from the
 attack of Marino; and his vengeance was amused by painting
 his enemies, their heads downwards, and drowning two dogs
 (at least they should have been bears) as the
 representatives of the Ursini.","('Livy', 'PERSON'), ('twenty\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Marino', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ursini', 'PERSON')"
"From them, however, and from
 every part of Italy, the tribune received the most friendly
 and respectful answers: they were followed by the
 ambassadors of the princes and republics; and in this
 foreign conflux, on all the occasions of pleasure or
 business, the low born notary could assume the familiar or
 majestic courtesy of a sovereign. (29)","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"From this misery
 he was relieved by the sense of merit or the smile of favour;
 and the employment of apostolic notary afforded him a daily
 stipend of five gold florins, a more honourable and extensive
 connection, and the right of contrasting, both in words and
 actions, his own integrity with the vices of the state.","('five', 'CARDINAL')"
"Great Schism of the West. 
Re-union of the Latin Church.","('the Latin Church', 'ORG')"
"Great schism of the West, A.D. 1378-1418.","('1378-1418', 'DATE')"
"Gregory the Eleventh did not survive above fourteen months his return to the Vatican; and his decease was followed by the great schism of the West, which distracted the Latin church above forty years.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Eleventh', 'DATE'), ('fourteen months', 'DATE'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('forty years', 'DATE')"
"Gregory the Twelfth, whose obedience was reduced to the narrow precincts of Rimini, descended with more honour from the throne; and his ambassador convened the session, in which he renounced the title and authority of lawful pope.","('Gregory the Twelfth', 'PERSON'), ('Rimini', 'GPE')"
"He confesses that the successor of St.
 Peter is the bishop of the universal church; yet it was not
 on the banks of the Rhone, but of the Tyber, that the
 apostle had fixed his everlasting throne; and while every
 city in the Christian world was blessed with a bishop, the
 metropolis alone was desolate and forlorn.","('St.\r\n Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Rhone', 'LOC'), ('Tyber', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"He fell senseless with the first stroke: the impotent revenge of his enemies inflicted a thousand wounds: and the senator's body was abandoned to the dogs, to the Jews, and to the flames.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jews', 'NORP')"
"He might have learned, that the ancient tribunes, so strong and sacred in the public opinion, were not distinguished in style, habit, or
 appearance, from an ordinary plebeian; (33) and that as often as they visited the city on foot, a single viator, or beadle, attended the exercise of their office.","('33', 'CARDINAL')"
He solicits the popes of Avignon to fix their residence at Rome.,"('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"His Latin works of
 philosophy, poetry, and eloquence, established his serious
 reputation, which was soon diffused from Avignon over France
 and Italy: his friends and disciples were multiplied in
 every city; and if the ponderous volume of his writings (6)
 be now abandoned to a long repose, our gratitude must
 applaud the man, who by precept and example revived the
 spirit and study of the Augustan age.","('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Augustan', 'NORP')"
"His Virtues and Vices, His  Expulsion and  Death.","('Virtues and Vices', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"His arms were sometimes unfortunate, and to a delay of three days he was indebted
 for his life and crown: but Ladislaus triumphed in his turn; and it was only his premature death that could save the metropolis and the ecclesiastical state from the ambitious conqueror, who had assumed the title, or at least the
 powers, of king of Rome. (71)","('three days', 'DATE'), ('Ladislaus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('71', 'CARDINAL')"
"His base and implacable revenge denied the honours of burial; and the bodies of the Colonna, which he threatened to expose with those of the vilest malefactors, were secretly interred by the holy virgins of their name and family.","('Colonna', 'PRODUCT')"
"His death, (A.D. 1354, September 8.)","('A.D. 1354', 'DATE'), ('September 8', 'DATE')"
"His death, A.D. 1378, March 27.","('A.D. 1378', 'DATE'), ('March 27', 'DATE')"
"His elaborate oration was that of a Christian and
 a suppliant; and, as the humble minister of the commons, he
 entreated his masters to pardon these noble criminals, for
 whose repentance and future service he pledged his faith and
 authority.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"His first reception was
 equal to his wishes: the day of his entrance was a public
 festival; and his eloquence and authority revived the laws
 of the good estate.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"His first trial of the popular
 feelings was at the funeral of Eugenius the Fourth: in an
 elaborate speech he called the Romans to liberty and arms;
 and they listened with apparent pleasure, till Porcaro was
 interrupted and answered by a grave advocate, who pleaded
 for the church and state.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Eugenius the Fourth', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Porcaro', 'PERSON')"
"His inflexible zeal, which loudly censured their luxury and vice, would have attached them to the stations and duties of their parishes at Rome; and had he not fatally delayed a new promotion, the French cardinals would have been reduced to a helpless minority in the sacred college.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('French', 'NORP')"
"His name,
 the purple of two cardinals, his uncles, a recent marriage,
 and a mortal disease were disregarded by the inflexible
 tribune, who had chosen his victim.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"His oath in the Capitol proclaims his right and duty to observe and assert the laws, to control the proud, to protect the poor, and to exercise justice and mercy within the extent of his jurisdiction.","('Capitol', 'ORG')"
"His person was invisible, his name
 was yet formidable; and the anxiety of the court of Avignon
 supposes, and even magnifies, his personal merit.","('Avignon', 'GPE')"
"His poetic coronation at Rome, A.D. 1341,April 8.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1341', 'DATE'), ('April 8', 'DATE')"
"His robes were of gold brocade or crimson velvet, or in the summer season of a lighter silk: he bore in his hand an ivory sceptre; the sound of trumpets announced his approach; and his solemn steps were preceded at least by four lictors or attendants, whose red wands were enveloped with bands or streamers of the golden colour or livery of the city.","('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"His wife, his son, his uncle, (a barber in name and
 profession,) exposed the contrast of vulgar manners and princely expense; and without acquiring the majesty, Rienzi degenerated into the vices, of a king.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"I have not undertaken the ecclesiastical history of the schism; but Rome, the object of these last chapters, is deeply interested in the disputed succession of her sovereigns.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"I. The conflict of Eugenius with the fathers of Basil, and the weight or apprehension of a new excise, emboldened and provoked the Romans to usurp the temporal government of the city.","('Eugenius', 'PERSON'), ('Basil', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"In Rome the voice of freedom and discord is no longer heard; and, instead of the foaming torrent, a smooth and stagnant lake reflects the image of idleness and servitude.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In a quarter of the city which was inhabited only by
 mechanics and Jews, the marriage of an innkeeper and a
 washer woman produced the future deliverer of Rome. (20)","('quarter', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('20', 'CARDINAL')"
"In a reign of five years, he exterminated the outlaws and banditti, abolished the profane sanctuaries of Rome, (96) formed a naval and military force, restored and emulated the monuments of antiquity, and after a liberal use and large increase of the revenue, left five millions of crowns in the castle of St. Angelo.","('five years', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('96', 'CARDINAL'), ('five millions', 'CARDINAL'), ('St. Angelo', 'GPE')"
"In a studied
 oration, he expiated on the motives and the means of their
 enterprise; the name and liberties of Rome; the sloth and
 pride of their ecclesiastical tyrants; the active or passive
 consent of their fellow-citizens; three hundred soldiers,
 and four hundred exiles, long exercised in arms or in
 wrongs; the license of revenge to edge their swords, and a
 million of ducats to reward their victory.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('four hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('a\r\n million', 'CARDINAL')"
"In each harbour of the coast a vessel was stationed for the assurance of commerce; a standing militia of three hundred and sixty horse and thirteen hundred foot was levied, clothed, and paid in the thirteen quarters of the city: and the spirit of a commonwealth may be traced in the grateful allowance of one hundred florins, or pounds, to the heirs of every soldier who lost his life in the service of his country.","('three hundred and sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirteen hundred foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('the thirteen quarters', 'DATE'), ('one hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"In his civil and
 religious processions through the city, he rode on a white steed, the symbol of royalty: the great banner of the republic, a sun with a circle of stars, a dove with an olive branch, was displayed over his head; a shower of gold and silver was scattered among the populace, fifty guards with halberds encompassed his person; a troop of horse preceded his march; and their tymbals and trumpets were of massy silver.","('fifty', 'CARDINAL')"
"In his passage through Milan he received the visit,
 and repaid the flattery, of the poet-laureate; accepted a
 medal of Augustus; and promised, without a smile, to imitate
 the founder of the Roman monarchy.","('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the
 act or diploma (14) which was presented to Petrarch, the title and prerogatives of poet-laureate are revived in the Capitol, after the lapse of thirteen hundred years; and he
 receives the perpetual privilege of wearing, at his choice,
 a crown of laurel, ivy, or myrtle, of assuming the poetic
 habit, and of teaching, disputing, interpreting, and
 composing, in all places whatsoever, and on all subjects of
 literature.","('14', 'CARDINAL'), ('Petrarch', 'PERSON'), ('Capitol', 'ORG'), ('thirteen hundred years', 'DATE')"
"In the
 morning they understood their sentence from the visit of a
 confessor and the tolling of the bell.","('the\r\n morning', 'TIME')"
"In the
 thirty-sixth year of his age, he was solicited to accept the
 object of his wishes; and on the same day, in the solitude
 of Vaucluse, he received a similar and solemn invitation
 from the senate of Rome and the university of Paris.","('the\r\n thirty-sixth year', 'DATE'), ('Vaucluse', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Paris', 'GPE')"
"In the apprehension of modern times, Petrarch (1) is the Italian songster of Laura and love.","('Petrarch', 'PERSON'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Laura', 'PERSON')"
"In the camp, Rienzi appeared to less advantage than
 in the rostrum; and he neglected the progress of the rebel
 barons till their numbers were strong, and their castles
 impregnable.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"In the common council all male citizens had a right to vote; and the value of their privilege was enhanced by the care with
 which any foreigners were prevented from usurping the title and character of Romans.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"In the death, as in the life, of Rienzi, the hero and the coward were strangely mingled.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"In the disguise of a monk or a
 pilgrim, he escaped from the castle of St. Angelo, implored
 the friendship of the king of Hungary at Naples, tempted the
 ambition of every bold adventurer, mingled at Rome with the
 pilgrims of the jubilee, lay concealed among the hermits of
 the Apennine, and wandered through the cities of Italy,
 Germany, and Bohemia.","('St. Angelo', 'GPE'), ('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Apennine', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Bohemia', 'GPE')"
"In the evening,
 which they had reached the church and palace of Constantine,
 he thanked and dismissed the numerous assembly, with an
 invitation to the festival of the ensuing day.","('the evening', 'TIME'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"In the familiar society
 of Cicero and Livy, he had imbibed the ideas of an ancient
 patriot; and his ardent fancy kindled every idea to a
 sentiment, and every sentiment to a passion.","('Cicero', 'PERSON'), ('Livy', 'PERSON')"
"In the fervour of youth, with the authority of age, Petrarch
 addressed his exhortations to five successive popes, and his
 eloquence was always inspired by the enthusiasm of sentiment
 and the freedom of language. (57)","('Petrarch', 'PERSON'), ('five', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the first period of their conquests, till the expedition of Charles the Eighth, the popes might successfully wrestle with the adjacent princes and states, whose military force was equal, or inferior, to their own.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Charles the Eighth', 'PERSON')"
"In the first, the banner of
 liberty, Rome was seated on two lions, with a palm in one
 hand and a globe in the other; St. Paul, with a drawn sword,
 was delineated in the banner of justice; and in the third,
 St. Peter held the keys of concord and peace.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('St. Paul', 'LOC'), ('the third', 'DATE'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE')"
"In the harmony of his Tuscan rhymes, Italy applauds, or rather adores, the father of her lyric poetry; and his verse, or at least his name, is
 repeated by the enthusiasm, or affectation, of amorous
 sensibility.","('Tuscan', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"In the midst of these laudable occupations, the pope was alarmed by the approach of Frederic the Third of Austria; though his fears could not be justified by the character or the power of the Imperial candidate.","('Frederic the Third of Austria', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"In the musical games of antiquity,
 a prize was bestowed on the victor: (9) the belief that
 Virgil and Horace had been crowned in the Capitol inflamed
 the emulation of a Latin bard; (10) and the laurel (11) was
 endeared to the lover by a verbal resemblance with the name
 of his mistress.","('9', 'CARDINAL'), ('Virgil', 'PERSON'), ('Horace', 'PERSON'), ('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('11', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the name of
 the senate and people, an eloquent Roman asserted their
 desire to cooperate in the union of the church, deplored the
 temporal and spiritual calamities of the long schism, and
 requested the protection of France against the arms of the
 king of Naples.","('Roman', 'PERSON'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Naples', 'GPE')"
"In the office of nuncio, or the rank of cardinal, he may acquire some knowledge of the world, but the primitive stain will adhere to his mind and manners: from study and experience he may suspect the mystery of his profession; but the sacerdotal artist will imbibe some portion of the bigotry which he inculcates.","('nuncio', 'ORG')"
"In the society of the Germans and Bohemians, he is
 said to have contracted the habits of intemperance and
 cruelty: adversity had chilled his enthusiasm, without
 fortifying his reason or virtue; and that youthful hope,
 that lively assurance, which is the pledge of success, was
 now succeeded by the cold impotence of distrust and despair.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Bohemians', 'NORP')"
"In the trammels of servile faith, he has learned to believe because it is absurd, to revere all that is contemptible, and to despise whatever might deserve the esteem of a rational being; to punish error as a crime, to reward mortification and celibacy as the first of virtues; to place the saints of the calendar (94) above the heroes of Rome and the sages of Athens; and to consider the missal, or the crucifix, as more useful instruments than the plough or the loom.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('94', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Athens', 'GPE')"
"In the various, and often inconsistent, narratives, (66) the shades of popular violence are more darkly or faintly colored: but the licentiousness of the seditious Romans was inflamed by a sense of their privileges, and the danger of a second emigration.","('66', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"In their eyes, Italy was foreign or hostile; and they reluctantly embarked at Marseilles, as if they had been sold or banished into the land of the Saracens.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Marseilles', 'GPE'), ('Saracens', 'NORP')"
"In these useful functions he was assisted by three learned strangers; the two collaterals, and the judge of criminal appeals: their frequent trials of robberies, rapes, and murders, are attested by the laws; and
 the weakness of these laws connives at the licentiousness of private feuds and armed associations for mutual defence.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In this character, and with the consent of the Roman, the tribune enacted the most salutary laws for the restoration and maintenance of the good estate.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Instead of maintaining a crowd of tenants and followers, the produce of their estates was consumed in the private expenses which multiply the pleasures, and diminish the power, of the lord. (92)","('92', 'CARDINAL')"
"Instead of restoring to
 Rome her glory and her provinces, he had bound himself by a
 secret treaty with the pope, to evacuate the city on the day
 of his coronation; and his shameful retreat was pursued by
 the reproaches of the patriot bard. (56)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('the day', 'DATE')"
"It is an obvious truth, that the times must be suited to
 extraordinary characters, and that the genius of Cromwell or
 Retz might now expire in obscurity.","('Cromwell', 'PERSON'), ('Retz', 'PERSON')"
"It was formally provided, that none, except the supreme magistrate, should possess or command the gates, bridges, or towers of the state; that no private garrisons should be introduced into the towns or castles of the Roman territory; that none should bear arms, or presume to fortify their houses in the city or country; that the barons should be responsible for the safety of the highways, and the free passage of provisions; and that the protection of malefactors and robbers should be expiated by a fine of a thousand marks of silver.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('a thousand marks', 'MONEY')"
"It was the boast of Rienzi, that he
 had delivered the throne and patrimony of St. Peter from a
 rebellious aristocracy; and Clement the Sixth, who rejoiced
 in its fall, affected to believe the professions, to applaud
 the merits, and to confirm the title, of his trusty servant.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('St. Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Clement', 'PERSON'), ('Sixth', 'ORDINAL')"
"It would be easy,
 (he said,) on the next day, the festival of the Epiphany, to
 seize the pope and his cardinals, before the doors, or at
 the altar, of St. Peter's; to lead them in chains under the
 walls of St. Angelo; to extort by the threat of their
 instant death a surrender of the castle; to ascend the
 vacant Capitol; to ring the alarm bell; and to restore in a
 popular assembly the ancient republic of Rome.","('the next day', 'DATE'), ('Epiphany', 'EVENT'), (""St. Peter's"", 'FAC'), ('St. Angelo', 'GPE'), ('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"John Pepin, count of
 Minorbino, (49) in the kingdom of Naples, had been condemned
 for his crimes, or his riches, to perpetual imprisonment;
 and Petrarch, by soliciting his release, indirectly
 contributed to the ruin of his friend.","('John Pepin', 'PERSON'), ('Minorbino', 'PERSON'), ('49', 'DATE'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Petrarch', 'PERSON')"
Last disorders of the nobles of Rome.,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
"More eloquent than judicious, more enterprising than resolute, the faculties of Rienzi were not balanced by cool and commanding reason: he magnified in a tenfold proportion the
 objects of hope and fear; and prudence, which could not have erected, did not presume to fortify, his throne.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"Negotiations for peace and union, A.D. 1392-1407.","('A.D. 1392-1407', 'DATE')"
"Never perhaps has the energy and effect of a single mind
 been more remarkably felt than in the sudden, though
 transient, reformation of Rome by the tribune Rienzi.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"Of his two immediate successors, Eugenius IV. (A.D. 1431.)","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Eugenius IV.', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 1431', 'DATE')"
"Of the five whom Petrarch exhorted, the three first, John the Twenty-second, Benedict the Twelfth, and Clement the Sixth, were importuned or amused by the boldness of the orator; but the memorable change which had been attempted by Urban the Fifth was finally accomplished by Gregory the Eleventh.","('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Petrarch', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Twenty-second', 'DATE'), ('Benedict the Twelfth', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Clement', 'PERSON'), ('Sixth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Urban', 'PERSON'), ('Fifth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gregory the Eleventh', 'PERSON')"
"Of the three popes, John the Twenty-third was the first victim: he fled and was brought back a prisoner: the most scandalous charges were suppressed; the vicar of Christ was only accused of piracy, murder, rape, sodomy, and incest; and after subscribing his own condemnation, he expiated in prison the imprudence of trusting his person to a free city beyond the Alps.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Twenty-third', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC')"
"On
 the first rumour, he returned to his palace, affected to
 despise this plebeian tumult, and declared to the messenger
 of Rienzi, that at his leisure he would cast the madman from
 the windows of the Capitol.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('Capitol', 'FAC')"
"On the same day, under various pretences, he invited to the Capitol
 his principal enemies, among whom were five members of the
 Ursini and three of the Colonna name.","('the same day', 'DATE'), ('Capitol', 'ORG'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ursini', 'ORG'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Colonna', 'ORG')"
"On this momentous occasion, the college of twenty-three cardinals was fortified with thirty deputies; six of whom were chosen in each of the five great nations of Christendom,  the Italian, the German, the French, the Spanish, and the English: (75) the interference of strangers was softened by
 their generous preference of an Italian and a Roman; Election of Martin V.  and the hereditary, as well as personal, merit of Otho Colonna recommended him to the conclave.","('twenty-three', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirty', 'CARDINAL'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christendom', 'NORP'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Spanish', 'LANGUAGE'), ('English', 'LANGUAGE'), ('75', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Otho Colonna', 'PERSON')"
"Peter Agapet
 Colonna, who had himself been senator of Rome, was arrested
 in the street for injury or debt; and justice was appeased
 by the tardy execution of Martin Ursini, who, among his
 various acts of violence and rapine, had pillaged a
 shipwrecked vessel at the mouth of the Tyber. (28)","('Peter Agapet\r\n Colonna', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Martin Ursini', 'PERSON'), ('Tyber', 'PRODUCT')"
"Petrarch had been the private friend, perhaps the secret counsellor, of Rienzi: his writings breathe the most ardent
 spirit of patriotism and joy; and all respect for the pope, all gratitude for the Colonna, was lost in the superior duties of a Roman citizen.","('Petrarch', 'PERSON'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('Colonna', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
Petrarch invites and upbraids the emperor Charles IV.,"('Charles IV', 'PERSON')"
"Petrarch, A.D. 1304, June 19- 1374,July 19.","('A.D. 1304', 'DATE'), ('June 19- 1374', 'DATE'), ('July 19', 'DATE')"
"Petrarch, Italy, and Europe, were astonished
 by a revolution which realized for a moment his most
 splendid visions.","('Petrarch', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('a moment', 'TIME')"
"Porcaro, and nine of his accomplices,
 were hanged without the benefit of the sacraments; and,
 amidst the fears and invectives of the papal court, the
 Romans pitied, and almost applauded, these martyrs of their
 country. (85)","('Porcaro', 'PERSON'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('85', 'CARDINAL')"
"Posterity will compare the virtues and failings of this extraordinary man; but in a long period of anarchy and servitude, the name of Rienzi has often been celebrated as the deliverer of his country, and the last of the Roman patriots.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Prudently waiving all invidious inquiry into the origin and merits of the dispute, they proposed, as a healing measure, that the two pretenders of Rome and Avignon should abdicate at the same time, after
 qualifying the cardinals of the adverse factions to join in
 a legitimate election; and that the nations should subtract
 (73) their obedience, if either of the competitor preferred
 his own interest to that of the public.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('73', 'CARDINAL')"
Restoration of the Freedom and Government of Rome by the Tribune Rienzi.,"('the Freedom and Government of Rome', 'ORG'), ('the Tribune Rienzi', 'ORG')"
"Return of Urban V. (A.D. 1367, October 16-1370, April 17.)","('A.D. 1367', 'DATE'), ('October 16-1370', 'DATE'), ('April 17', 'DATE')"
Return of the Popes from Avignon.,"('Popes', 'PERSON'), ('Avignon', 'GPE')"
"Revolutions of Rome, A.D. 1347-1354.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('1347-1354', 'CARDINAL')"
"Rienzi led the
 procession from the Capitol to the Lateran; the tediousness
 of the way was relieved with decorations and games; the
 ecclesiastical, civil, and military orders marched under
 their various banners; the Roman ladies attended his wife;
 and the ambassadors of Italy might loudly applaud or
 secretly deride the novelty of the pomp.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('Lateran', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Rienzi was
 encouraged by the presence and applause of an innumerable
 crowd, who understood little, and hoped much; and the
 procession slowly rolled forwards from the castle of St.
 Angelo to the Capitol.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('St.\r\n Angelo', 'GPE'), ('Capitol', 'FAC')"
"Rienzi was indulged with an easy confinement and the use of books; and in the assiduous study of Livy and the Bible, he sought the cause and the consolation of his misfortunes.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('Livy', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Bible', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Rienzi was transported slowly, but in safe custody, from Prague to Avignon: his entrance into the city was that of a malefactor; in his prison he was chained by the leg; and four cardinals were named to inquire into the crimes of heresy and rebellion.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('Prague', 'GPE'), ('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"Rienzi, senator of Rome, A.D. 1354.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1354', 'DATE')"
"Rome accepted with joy and obedience the noblest of her sons; the ecclesiastical statewas defended by his powerful family; and the elevation of Martin the Fifth is the aera of the restoration and establishment of the popes in the Vatican. (76)
Martin V. A.D. 1417.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Martin', 'PERSON'), ('Fifth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Martin V. A.D. 1417', 'PERSON')"
"Rome and the principal states of Italy, Germany, Portugal, England, (69) the Low Countries,
 and the kingdoms of the North, adhered to the prior election
 of Urban the Sixth, who was succeeded by Boniface the Ninth,
 Innocent the Seventh, and Gregory the Twelfth.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Portugal', 'GPE'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('69', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Low Countries', 'GPE'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('Urban the Sixth', 'DATE'), ('Boniface the Ninth', 'PERSON'), ('the Seventh', 'DATE'), ('Gregory the Twelfth', 'PERSON')"
"Rome was again agitated by the bloody
 feuds of the barons, who detested each other, and despised
 the commons: their hostile fortresses, both in town and
 country, again rose, and were again demolished: and the
 peaceful citizens, a flock of sheep, were devoured, says the
 Florentine historian, by these rapacious wolves.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Florentine', 'NORP')"
"Rome was commanded by an impregnable citadel: the use of cannon is a powerful engine against popular seditions: a regular force of cavalry and infantry was enlisted under the banners of the pope: his ample revenues supplied the resources of war: and, from the extent of his domain, he could bring down on a rebellious city an army of hostile neighbours and loyal subjects. (88)","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Rome was restored, adorned, and enlightened, by the peaceful reign of Nicholas the Fifth.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Nicholas the Fifth', 'PERSON')"
"Rome was still the
 metropolis of the Christian world; and the fame and fortunes
 of the tribune were diffused in every country by the
 strangers who had enjoyed the blessings of his government.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"Rome was still the lawful
 mistress of the world: the pope and the emperor, the bishop
 and general, had abdicated their station by an inglorious
 retreat to the Rhone and the Danube; but if she could resume
 her virtue, the republic might again vindicate her liberty
 and dominion.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Rhone', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"Since the invasion of Robert the Norman, the Romans had pursued their domestic quarrels without the dangerous interposition of a stranger.","('Robert the Norman', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Since the removal of the Holy See, the sacred buildings of the Lateran and the Vatican, their altars and their saints, were left in a state of poverty and decay; and Rome was often painted
 under the image of a disconsolate matron, as if the wandering husband could be reclaimed by the homely portrait of the age and infirmities of his weeping spouse. (58)","('the Holy See', 'ORG'), ('Lateran', 'NORP'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Since the union of the duchies of Ferrara and Urbino, the ecclesiastical state extends from the Mediterranean to the Adriatic, and from the confines of Naples to the banks of the Po; and as early as the sixteenth century, the greater part of that spacious and fruitful country acknowledged the lawful claims and temporal sovereignty of the Roman pontiffs.","('Ferrara', 'GPE'), ('Urbino', 'GPE'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Po', 'LOC'), ('as early as the sixteenth century', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
Sixtus V. (A.D. 1585-1590.),"('Sixtus V. (A.D. 1585-1590', 'DATE')"
"So tame were the times, so feeble was the Austrian, that the pomp of his coronation was accomplished with order and harmony: but the superfluous honour was so disgraceful to an independent nation, that his successors have excused themselves from the toilsome pilgrimage to the Vatican; and rest their Imperial title on the choice of the electors of Germany.","('Austrian', 'NORP'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"Some reasons of public or private moment, his own impatience or the prayers of the cardinals, recalled Urban to France; and the approaching election was saved from the tyrannic patriotism of the Romans.","('Urban', 'NORP'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
Statutes of Rome.,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Stephen Colonna the younger, the noble spirit to whom Petrarch ascribed the restoration of Italy, was preceded or accompanied in death by his son John, a gallant youth, by his brother Peter, who might regret the ease and honours of the church, by a nephew of legitimate birth, and by two bastards of the Colonna race; and the number of seven, the seven crowns, as Rienzi styled them, of the Holy Ghost, was completed by the agony of the deplorable parent, and the veteran chief, who had survived the hope and fortune of his house.","('Stephen Colonna', 'PERSON'), ('Petrarch', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Peter', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Colonna', 'NORP'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('the Holy Ghost', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Such new claims of the synod and conclave were disputed; three kings, of Germany, Hungary, and Naples, adhered to the cause of Gregory the Twelfth; and Benedict the Thirteenth, himself a Spaniard, was acknowledged by the devotion and patriotism of that powerful nation.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Gregory the Twelfth', 'PERSON'), ('Benedict', 'PERSON'), ('Thirteenth', 'DATE'), ('Spaniard', 'NORP')"
"The
 eloquence of Rienzi was prompt and persuasive: the multitude
 is always prone to envy and censure: he was stimulated by
 the loss of a brother and the impunity of the assassins; nor
 was it possible to excuse or exaggerate the public
 calamities.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"The
 emperor Charles the Fourth gave audience to a stranger, who
 frankly revealed himself as the tribune of the republic; and
 astonished an assembly of ambassadors and princes, by the
 eloquence of a patriot and the visions of a prophet, the
 downfall of tyranny and the kingdom of the Holy Ghost. (51)","('Charles the Fourth', 'PERSON'), ('the Holy Ghost', 'GPE'), ('51', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 fortifications of the castle were instantly restored; the
 vassals attended their lord; the outlaws armed against the
 magistrate; the flocks and herds, the harvests and
 vineyards, from Marino to the gates of Rome, were swept away
 or destroyed; and the people arraigned Rienzi as the author
 of the calamities which his government had taught them to
 forget.","('Marino', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"The
 orator had the honour of haranguing Pope Clement the Sixth,
 and the satisfaction of conversing with Petrarch, a
 congenial mind: but his aspiring hopes were chilled by
 disgrace and poverty and the patriot was reduced to a single
 garment and the charity of the hospital.","('Pope Clement the Sixth', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Petrarch', 'PERSON')"
"The
 pope and the sacred college had never been dazzled by his
 specious professions; they were justly offended by the
 insolence of his conduct; a cardinal legate was sent to
 Italy, and after some fruitless treaty, and two personal
 interviews, he fulminated a bull of excommunication, in
 which the tribune is degraded from his office, and branded
 with the guilt of rebellion, sacrilege, and heresy. (48)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 privileged houses, the private sanctuaries in Rome, on which
 no officer of justice would presume to trespass, were
 abolished; and he applied the timber and iron of their
 barricades in the fortifications of the Capitol.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Capitol', 'FAC')"
"The
 surviving barons of Rome were now humbled to a sense of
 allegiance; their interest and revenge engaged them in the
 service of the church; but as the fate of the Colonna was
 before their eyes, they abandoned to a private adventurer
 the peril and glory of the revolution.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Colonna', 'PERSON')"
"The
 venerable father of the Colonna was exposed in his own
 palace to the double shame of being desirous, and of being
 unable, to protect a criminal.","('Colonna', 'PERSON')"
"The Capitol was yet
 stained with the blood of Rienzi, when Charles the Fourth
 descended from the Alps to obtain the Italian and Imperial
 crowns.","('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('Charles the Fourth', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The Christian world was at length provoked by their
 obstinacy and fraud: they were deserted by their cardinals,
 who embraced each other as friends and colleagues; and their
 revolt was supported by a numerous assembly of prelates and
 ambassadors.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The Colonna and Ursini still exercised their deadly feuds: the bannerets of Rome asserted and abused the privileges of a republic: the vicars of Christ, who had levied a military force, chastised their
 rebellion with the gibbet, the sword, and the dagger; and, in a friendly conference, eleven deputies of the people were perfidiously murdered and cast into the street.","('Colonna', 'PERSON'), ('Ursini', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('eleven', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Colonna and Ursini vied with each other in the decoration of their palaces and chapels; and their antique
 splendour was rivalled or surpassed by the sudden opulence of the papal families.","('Colonna', 'PERSON'), ('Ursini', 'PERSON')"
"The French and Germans at length withdrew from the field of battle: Milan, Naples, Sicily, Sardinia, and the sea-coast of Tuscany, were
 firmly possessed by the Spaniards; and it became their interest to maintain the peace and dependence of Italy, which continued almost without disturbance from the middle of the sixteenth to the opening of the eighteenth century.","('French', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Sardinia', 'GPE'), ('Tuscany', 'GPE'), ('Spaniards', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('the middle of the sixteenth to the opening of the eighteenth century', 'DATE')"
"The Gracchi would have frowned or smiled, could they have read the sonorous titles and epithets of their successor,""NICHOLAS, SEVERE AND MERCIFUL; DELIVERER OF ROME; DEFENDER OF ITALY; (34) FRIEND OF MANKIND, AND OF LIBERTY, PEACE, AND JUSTICE; TRIBUNE AUGUST:""his theatrical pageants had prepared the revolution; but Rienzi abused, in luxury and pride, the political maxim of speaking to the eyes, as well as the
 understanding, of the multitude.","('Gracchi', 'PERSON'), ('34', 'CARDINAL'), ('TRIBUNE', 'ORG'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"The Vatican was swayed and protected by the religious policy of the Catholic king: his prejudice and interest disposed him in every dispute to support the prince against the people; and instead of the encouragement, the aid, and the
 asylum, which they obtained from the adjacent states, the friends of liberty, or the enemies of law, were enclosed on all sides within the iron circle of despotism.","('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"The abbot of Mount Cassin had been
 consulted, whether he would accept the triple crown (62) from the clergy and people:","('Mount Cassin', 'PERSON'), ('62', 'CARDINAL')"
"The abbot of Mount Cassin had been
 consulted, whether he would accept the triple crown (62) from the clergy and people: 
 ""I am a citizen of Rome,"" (63) replied that venerable ecclesiastic,  ""and my first law is, the voice of my country."" (64)","('Mount Cassin', 'PERSON'), ('62', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('63', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('64', 'CARDINAL')"
"The academical
 honours of the three faculties had introduced a royal degree
 of master or doctor in the art of poetry; (7) and the title
 of poet- laureate, which custom, rather than vanity,
 perpetuates in the English court, (8) was first invented by
 the Caesars of Germany.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('7', 'CARDINAL'), ('English', 'NORP'), ('8', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesars', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"The acts of the tribune were abolished, his head was
 proscribed; yet such was the terror of his name, that the
 barons hesitated three days before they would trust
 themselves in the city, and Rienzi was left above a month in
 the castle of St. Angelo, from whence he peaceably withdrew,
 after laboring, without effect, to revive the affection and
 courage of the Romans.","('three days', 'DATE'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('a month', 'DATE'), ('St. Angelo', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The ambition of the honours of chivalry (36) betrayed the
 meanness of his birth, and degraded the importance of his
 office; and the equestrian tribune was not less odious to
 the nobles, whom he adopted, than to the plebeians, whom he
 deserted.","('36', 'CARDINAL')"
"The answers of Benedict and Gregory were
 alike edifying and alike deceitful; and, in evading the
 demand of their abdication, the two rivals were animated by
 a common spirit.","('Benedict', 'PERSON'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The apartments, porticos, and courts of the Lateran were spread with innumerable tables for either sex, and every condition; a stream of wine flowed from the nostrils of Constantine's brazen horse; no complaint, except of the scarcity of water, could be heard; and the licentiousness of the multitude was curbed by discipline and fear.","('Lateran', 'LOC'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The aspect of
 the seven hills and their majestic ruins confirmed these
 lively impressions; and he loved a country by whose liberal
 spirit he had been crowned and adopted.","('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"The belief of his incapacity
 encouraged their operations: they were invited by their
 secret adherents; and the barons attempted, with four
 thousand foot, and sixteen hundred horse, to enter Rome by
 force or surprise.","('four\r\n thousand foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('sixteen hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The birth of Stephen Porcaro was noble, his
 reputation spotless: his tongue was armed with eloquence,
 his mind was enlightened with learning; and he aspired,
 beyond the aim of vulgar ambition, to free his country and
 immortalize his name.","('Stephen Porcaro', 'PERSON')"
"The blessings of peace and justice, for which
 civil society has been instituted, were banished from Rome:
 the jealous citizens, who might have endured every personal
 or pecuniary injury, were most deeply wounded in the
 dishonour of their wives and daughters: (22) they were equally
 oppressed by the arrogance of the nobles and the corruption
 of the magistrates; and the abuse of arms or of laws was the only circumstance that distinguished the lions from the
 dogs and serpents of the Capitol.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('22', 'CARDINAL'), ('Capitol', 'ORG')"
"The ceremony of his coronation (13) was performed in the
 Capitol, by his friend and patron the supreme magistrate of
 the republic.","('13', 'DATE'), ('Capitol', 'FAC')"
"The conclave was intimidated by the shouts, and encompassed by the arms, of thirty thousand rebels; the bells of the Capitol and St. Peter's rang an alarm: ""Death, or an Italian pope!""  was the universal cry; the same threat was repeated by the twelve bannerets or chiefs of the quarters, in the form of charitable advice; some preparations were made for burning the obstinate cardinals; and had they chosen a Transalpine subject, it is probable that they would never have departed alive from the Vatican.","('thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Capitol', 'ORG'), (""St. Peter's"", 'GPE'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('Transalpine', 'NORP'), ('Vatican', 'FAC')"
"The conqueror ascended the Capitol; deposited his crown and sceptre on the altar; and boasted, with some truth, that he had cut off an ear, which neither pope nor emperor had been able to amputate.","('Capitol', 'FAC')"
"The dangerous office of tribune was
 successively occupied by two plebeians, Cerroni and
 Baroncelli.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Cerroni', 'PERSON'), ('Baroncelli', 'PERSON')"
"The decree of the senate, which granted the most
 ample prerogatives to the emperor Vespasian, had been
 inscribed on a copper plate still extant in the choir of the
 church of St. John Lateran. (23)","('Vespasian', 'PERSON'), ('St. John Lateran', 'ORG'), ('23', 'CARDINAL')"
"The deliverance of his country inspired Rienzi with a vast,
 and perhaps visionary, idea of uniting Italy in a great
 federative republic, of which Rome should be the ancient and
 lawful head, and the free cities and princes the members and
 associates.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The dominion of priests is most
 odious to a liberal spirit: every scruple was removed by the
 recent knowledge of the fable and forgery of Constantine's
 donation; Petrarch was now the oracle of the Italians; and
 as often as Porcaro revolved the ode which describes the
 patriot and hero of Rome, he applied to himself the visions
 of the prophetic bard.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Petrarch', 'PERSON'), ('Italians', 'NORP'), ('Porcaro', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The election was annual: a severe scrutiny was instituted into the conduct of the departing senator; nor
 could he be recalled to the same office till after the expiration of two years.","('annual', 'DATE'), ('two years', 'DATE')"
"The epistle of the sacred college affirms his free, and regular, election; which had been inspired, as usual, by the Holy Ghost; he was adored, invested, and crowned, with the customary rites; his temporal authority was obeyed at Rome and Avignon, and his ecclesiastical supremacy was acknowledged in the Latin world.","('the Holy Ghost', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"The first and most generous wish of Petrarch was the
 restoration of a free republic; but after the exile and
 death of his plebeian hero, he turned his eyes from the
 tribune, to the king, of the Romans.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Petrarch', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The first counsels for the peace and union of Christendom arose from the university of Paris, from the faculty of the
Sorbonne, whose doctors were esteemed, at least in the Gallican church, as the most consummate masters of theological science. (72)","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christendom', 'GPE'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Sorbonne', 'ORG'), ('Gallican', 'NORP'), ('72', 'CARDINAL')"
"The former was composed of the magistrates and their immediate predecessors, with some fiscal and legal officers, and three classes of thirteen, twenty-six, and forty, counsellors: amounting in the whole to about one hundred and twenty persons.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty-six', 'CARDINAL'), ('forty', 'CARDINAL'), ('about one hundred and twenty', 'CARDINAL')"
The genius of Sixtus the Fifth (95) burst from the gloom of a Franciscan cloister.,"('Sixtus the Fifth', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('95', 'CARDINAL'), ('Franciscan', 'NORP')"
"The grant was ratified by the authority of the
 senate and people; and the character of citizen was the
 recompense of his affection for the Roman name.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The great bell instantly rang
 an alarm, and so rapid was the tide, so urgent was the
 danger, that Colonna escaped with precipitation to the
 suburb of St. Laurence: from thence, after a moment's
 refreshment, he continued the same speedy career till he
 reached in safety his castle of Palestrina; lamenting his
 own imprudence, which had not trampled the spark of this
 mighty conflagration.","('Colonna', 'PERSON'), ('St. Laurence', 'GPE'), ('Palestrina', 'PERSON')"
"The great hall of
 the Capitol had been decorated for the bloody scene with red
 and white hangings: the countenance of the tribune was dark
 and severe; the swords of the executioners were unsheathed;
 and the barons were interrupted in their dying speeches by
 the sound of trumpets.","('Capitol', 'FAC')"
"The inflexible Roman returned from Anagni with an
 increase of reputation and zeal; and, on the first
 opportunity, the games of the place Navona, he tried to
 inflame the casual dispute of some boys and mechanics into a
 general rising of the people.","('Roman', 'PERSON'), ('Anagni', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Navona', 'PERSON')"
"The kings of Castile, Arragon, Navarre, and Scotland, obtained an equal and honourable treaty; with the concurrence of the Spaniards, Benedict was deposed by the council; but the harmless old man was left in a solitary castle to excommunicate twice each day the rebel kingdoms which had deserted his cause.","('Castile', 'GPE'), ('Arragon', 'GPE'), ('Navarre', 'GPE'), ('Scotland', 'GPE'), ('Spaniards', 'NORP'), ('Benedict', 'PERSON')"
"The last coronation of a German emperor, Frederic III. (A.D. 1452, March 18.)","('German', 'NORP'), ('Frederic III.', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 1452', 'DATE'), ('March 18', 'DATE')"
"The last revolt of Rome, (A.D. 1434, May 29-October 26.)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1434', 'DATE'), ('May 29-October 26', 'DATE')"
"The legate Albornoz, who seemed desirous of his ruin,
 inflexibly refused all supplies of men and money; a faithful
 subject could no longer presume to touch the revenues of the
 apostolical chamber; and the first idea of a tax was the
 signal of clamour and sedition.","('Albornoz', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The long habits of obedience and education subdued the turbulent
 spirit of the nobles and commons of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The merits of the lover
 I am still less qualified to appreciate: nor am I deeply
 interested in a metaphysical passion for a nymph so shadowy,
 that her existence has been questioned; (2) for a matron so
 prolific, (3) that she was delivered of eleven legitimate
 children, (4) while her amorous swain sighed and sung at the
 fountain of Vaucluse. (5)","('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('eleven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Vaucluse', 'PRODUCT')"
"The mildness of Cerroni was unequal to the
 times; and after a faint struggle, he retired with a fair
 reputation and a decent fortune to the comforts of rural
 life.","('Cerroni', 'PERSON')"
"The most glorious
 circumstance of his reign was an appeal to his justice from
 Lewis, king of Hungary, who complained, that his brother and
 her husband had been perfidiously strangled by Jane, queen
 of Naples: (30) her guilt or innocence was pleaded in a
 solemn trial at Rome; but after hearing the advocates, (31)
 the tribune adjourned this weighty and invidious cause,
 which was soon determined by the sword of the Hungarian.","('Lewis', 'PERSON'), ('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('Jane', 'PERSON'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('30', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('31', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hungarian', 'NORP')"
"The nice balance of the Vatican was often subverted by the soldiers of the North and West, who were united under the standard of Charles the Fifth: the feeble and fluctuating policy of Clement the Seventh exposed his person and dominions to the conqueror; and Rome was abandoned seven months to a lawless army, more cruel and rapacious than the Goths and Vandals. (90)","('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Charles the Fifth', 'PERSON'), ('Clement', 'PERSON'), ('Seventh', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('seven months', 'DATE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('90', 'CARDINAL')"
"The nobles, as if destitute of arms and counsels,
 beheld in silent consternation this strange revolution; and
 the moment had been prudently chosen, when the most
 formidable, Stephen Colonna, was absent from the city.","('Stephen Colonna', 'PERSON')"
"The old animosity of the Colonna and Ursini was suspended for a moment by their common disgrace: they associated their wishes, and perhaps their designs; an assassin was seized and tortured; he
 accused the nobles; and as soon as Rienzi deserved the fate, he adopted the suspicions and maxims, of a tyrant.","('Colonna', 'PERSON'), ('Ursini', 'PERSON'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"The people shouted, ""Long life to the
 Capitol and the poet!""","('Capitol', 'ORG')"
"The people sympathized in their grief, repented of their own fury, and detested the indecent joy of Rienzi, who visited the spot where these illustrious victims had fallen.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"The poet-laureate of the Capitol maintains the act, applauds the hero, and mingles with some apprehension and advice, the most lofty hopes of the permanent and rising greatness of the republic. (32)","('Capitol', 'ORG'), ('32', 'CARDINAL')"
"The policy
 of the Caesars has been repeated by the popes; and the
 bishop of Rome affected to maintain the form of a republic,
 while he reigned with the absolute powers of a temporal, as
 well as a spiritual, monarch.","('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The political
 enthusiasm of Rienzi had exalted him to a throne; the same
 enthusiasm, in the next century, conducted his imitator to
 the gallows.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('the next century', 'DATE')"
"The pomp of his knighthood, A.D. 1347,August 1.","('A.D. 1347', 'DATE'), ('August 1', 'DATE')"
"The pope's vicar,
 the simple bishop of Orvieto, who had been persuaded to
 sustain a part in this singular ceremony, marched on his
 right hand; and three great standards were borne aloft as
 the emblems of their design.","('Orvieto', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"The pope's vicar, the bishop of Orvieto, attempted to check this career of folly; but his feeble protest was silenced by martial music; and instead of withdrawing from the assembly, he
 consented to dine with his brother tribune, at a table which had hitherto been reserved for the supreme pontiff.","('Orvieto', 'GPE')"
"The popes acquire absolute dominion of Rome, A.D. 1500 etc.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 1500', 'DATE')"
The popular legislature consisted of the secret and the common councils of the Romans.,"('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The poverty and
 debasement of Rome excited the indignation and pity of her
 grateful son; he dissembled the faults of his
 fellow-citizens; applauded with partial fondness the last of
 their heroes and matrons; and in the remembrance of the
 past, in the hopes of the future, was pleased to forget the
 miseries of the present time.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The powers of heaven were interested in their cause: Bridget of Sweden, a saint and pilgrim, disapproved the return, and foretold the death, of Urban the Fifth: Final return of Gregory XI. (A.D. 1377, January 17.) the migration of Gregory the Eleventh was encouraged by St. Catherine of Sienna, the spouse of Christ and ambassadress of the Florentines; and the popes themselves, the great masters of human credulity, appear to have listened to these visionary females. (59)","('Bridget', 'PERSON'), ('Sweden', 'GPE'), ('Urban', 'PERSON'), ('Fifth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gregory XI', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 1377', 'DATE'), ('January 17', 'DATE'), ('Gregory the Eleventh', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('St. Catherine of Sienna', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Florentines', 'NORP'), ('59', 'CARDINAL')"
"The privileges of Rome, her eternal
 sovereignty over her princes and provinces, was the theme of
 his public and private discourse; and a monument of
 servitude became in his hands a title and incentive of
 liberty.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The public officers
 dragged him from his palace and nuptial bed: his trial was
 short and satisfactory: the bell of the Capitol convened the
 people: stripped of his mantle, on his knees, with his hands
 bound behind his back, he heard the sentence of death; and
 after a brief confession, Ursini was led away to the
 gallows.","('Capitol', 'ORG'), ('Ursini', 'PERSON')"
The rash proceedings of Pisa were corrected by the council of Constance; the emperor Sigismond acted a conspicuous part as the advocate or protector of the Catholic church; and the number and weight of civil and ecclesiastical members might seem to constitute the states-general of Europe.,"('Pisa', 'GPE'), ('Constance', 'PERSON'), ('Sigismond', 'PERSON'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
The reigning pontiff well deserved the appellation of Clement: the strange vicissitudes and magnanimous spirit of the captive excited his pity and esteem; and Petrarch believes that he respected in the hero the name and sacred character of a poet. (52),"('Clement', 'PERSON'), ('Petrarch', 'PERSON')"
"The residents of Avignon had been invaded by hostile violence: at the head of thirty thousand robbers,
 a hero had extorted ransom and absolution from the vicar of Christ and the sacred college; and the maxim of the French warriors, to spare the people and plunder the church, was a new heresy of the most dangerous import. (60)","('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('60', 'CARDINAL')"
"The rise and fall of the tribune Rienzi
 will occupy the following pages: (16) the subject is
 interesting, the materials are rich, and the glance of a
 patriot bard (17) will sometimes vivify the copious, but
 simple, narrative of the Florentine, (18) and more especially
 of the Roman, historian. (19)
 Birth, character, and patriotic designs of Rienzi.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('16', 'CARDINAL'), ('17', 'CARDINAL'), ('Florentine', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('19', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"The royal prerogative of coining money, which had been exercised near three hundred years by the senate, was first resumed by Martin the Fifth, (77) and his image and superscription introduce the series of the papal medals.","('three hundred years', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Martin', 'PERSON'), ('Fifth', 'ORDINAL'), ('77', 'DATE')"
"The sacred college was then composed of twenty-two cardinals: six of these had remained at Avignon; eleven Frenchmen, one Spaniard, and four Italians, entered the conclave in the usual form.","('twenty-two', 'CARDINAL'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('eleven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Frenchmen', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Spaniard', 'NORP'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italians', 'NORP')"
"The same constraint imposed the necessity of dissembling in the eyes of Rome and of the world; the pride and cruelty of Urban presented a more inevitable danger; and they soon discovered the features of the tyrant, who could walk in his garden and recite his breviary, while he heard from an adjacent chamber six cardinals groaning on the rack.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Urban', 'PERSON'), ('six', 'CARDINAL')"
"The senate and people acknowledged him as their lawful sovereign, and laid at his feet the keys of the gates, the bridges, and the fortresses; of the quarter at least beyond the Tyber. (61)","('the quarter', 'DATE'), ('Tyber', 'PERSON')"
"The senator, with a
 strong guard, invested the house: the nephew of Porcaro cut
 his way through the crowd; but the unfortunate Stephen was
 drawn from a chest, lamenting that his enemies had
 anticipated by three hours the execution of his design.","('Porcaro', 'PERSON'), ('Stephen', 'PERSON'), ('three hours', 'TIME')"
"The son of a citizen of
 Florence invariably preferred the country of his birth to
 that of his education; and Italy, in his eyes, was the queen
 and garden of the world.","('Florence', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The speech, perhaps the mind, of the tribune, was inspired
 with a lively regard for the purity of the faith: he
 insinuated his claim to a supernatural mission from the Holy
 Ghost; enforced by a heavy forfeiture the annual duty of
 confession and communion; and strictly guarded the spiritual
 as well as temporal welfare of his faithful people. (27)
 Freedom and prosperity of the Roman republic.","('the Holy\r\n Ghost', 'PERSON'), ('27', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The spiritual thunders of the Vatican depend on the force of
 opinion; and if that opinion be supplanted by reason or
 passion, the sound may idly waste itself in the air; and the
 helpless priest is exposed to the brutal violence of a noble or a plebeian adversary.","('Vatican', 'FAC')"
"The states of Savoy, Sicily, Cyprus, Arragon, Castille, Navarre, and Scotland were inclined by their example and authority to the obedience of Clement the Seventh, and after his decease, of Benedict the Thirteenth.","('Savoy', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Cyprus', 'GPE'), ('Arragon', 'GPE'), ('Castille', 'GPE'), ('Navarre', 'GPE'), ('Scotland', 'GPE'), ('Clement', 'PERSON'), ('the Seventh', 'DATE'), ('Benedict', 'PERSON'), ('Thirteenth', 'DATE')"
The statutes and government of Rome.,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The study of history and
 eloquence, the writings of Cicero, Seneca, Livy, Caesar, and
 Valerius Maximus, elevated above his equals and
 contemporaries the genius of the young plebeian: he perused
 with indefatigable diligence the manuscripts and marbles of
 antiquity; loved to dispense his knowledge in familiar
 language; and was often provoked to exclaim,  When the republic addressed to the throne of Avignon an embassy of the three orders, the spirit and eloquence of Rienzi recommended him
 to a place among the thirteen deputies of the commons.","('Cicero', 'PERSON'), ('Seneca', 'PERSON'), ('Livy', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Valerius Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Avignon', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('thirteen', 'CARDINAL')"
"The succeeding pontificate of Innocent the Sixth opened a
 new prospect of his deliverance and restoration; and the
 court of Avignon was persuaded, that the successful rebel
 could alone appease and reform the anarchy of the
 metropolis.","('Innocent the Sixth', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Avignon', 'GPE')"
"The supine ignorance of the nobles was incapable
 of discerning the serious tendency of such representations:
 they might sometimes chastise with words and blows the
 plebeian reformer; but he was often suffered in the Colonna
 palace to amuse the company with his threats and
 predictions; and the modern Brutus (25) was concealed under
 the mask of folly and the character of a buffoon.","('Colonna', 'NORP'), ('Brutus', 'PERSON'), ('25', 'CARDINAL')"
"The synods of Ferrara and Florence, the fear or resentment of Eugenius, prolonged his absence: he was received by a submissive people; but the pontiff understood from the acclamations of his triumphal entry, that to secure their loyalty and his own repose, he must grant without delay the abolition of the odious excise.","('Ferrara', 'PERSON'), ('Florence', 'GPE'), ('Eugenius', 'PERSON')"
"The tribune had reigned with absolute dominion, by the
 choice, and in the hearts, of the Romans: the senator was
 the servile minister of a foreign court; and while he was
 suspected by the people, he was abandoned by the prince.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The tribune is respected in Italy, etc.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The troops of St. Peter again occupied the Capitol; the magistrates departed to their homes; the most guilty were executed or exiled; and the legate, at the head of two thousand foot and four thousand horse, was saluted as the father of the city.","('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('two thousand foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('four thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The tumult of a democracy was checked by wise and jealous precautions: except the magistrates, none could propose a question; none were permitted to speak, except from an open pulpit or tribunal; all disorderly acclamations were suppressed; the sense of the majority was decided by a secret ballot; and their
 decrees were promulgated in the venerable name of the Roman senate and people.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The twelve French cardinals, above two thirds of the votes, were masters of the election; and whatever might be their provincial jealousies, it cannot fairly be presumed that they would have sacrificed their right and interest to a foreign candidate, who would never restore them to their native country.","('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('two thirds', 'CARDINAL')"
"The two first divisions
 had passed along the walls, but the prospect of a free entrance tempted the headstrong valour of the nobles in the rear; and after a successful skirmish, they were overthrown and massacred without quarter by the crowds of the Roman people.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The value of either object was enhanced by
 the difficulties of the pursuit; and if the virtue or
 prudence of Laura was inexorable, (12) he enjoyed, and might
 boast of enjoying, the nymph of poetry.","('Laura', 'PERSON'), ('12', 'DATE')"
"The vanity, rather than the interest, of the nation determined the court and clergy of France. (68)","('France', 'GPE')"
"The vision and prophecies of St. Martin and Pope Boniface had been used by the tribune to animate his troops: (43) he displayed, at least in the pursuit, the spirit of a hero; but he forgot the maxims of the ancient Romans, who abhorred the triumphs of civil war.","('St. Martin', 'PERSON'), ('Pope Boniface', 'PERSON'), ('43', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The vision of freedom and empire had
 vanished: their fallen spirit would have acquiesced in
 servitude, had it been smoothed by tranquillity and order;
 and it was scarcely observed, that the new senators derived
 their authority from the Apostolic See; that four cardinals
 were appointed to reform, with dictatorial power, the state
 of the republic.","('the Apostolic See', 'ORG'), ('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"The whole night was employed in the celebration of
 thirty masses of the Holy Ghost; and in the morning, Rienzi,
 bareheaded, but in complete armour, issued from the church,
 encompassed by the hundred conspirators.","('thirty', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Holy Ghost', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Rienzi', 'PERSON'), ('hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The wild and original character of Sixtus the Fifth stands alone in the series of the pontiffs; the maxims and effects of their temporal government may be collected from the positive and comparative view of the arts and philosophy, the agriculture and trade, the wealth and population, of the ecclesiastical state.","('Sixtus the Fifth', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"The zeal of Petrarch, which had been
 cooled by the unworthy conduct, was rekindled by the
 sufferings and the presence, of his friend; and he boldly
 complains of the times, in which the saviour of Rome was
 delivered by her emperor into the hands of her bishop.","('Petrarch', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Their apparent boldness was prompted by despair; they passed
 in separate chambers a sleepless and painful night; and the
 venerable hero, Stephen Colonna, striking against the door
 of his prison, repeatedly urged his guards to deliver him by
 a speedy death from such ignominious servitude.","('Stephen Colonna', 'PERSON')"
"Their choice was not yet limited to the purple; and their unanimous votes acquiesced in the archbishop of Bari, a subject of Naples, conspicuous for his zeal and learning, who ascended the throne of St. Peter under the name of Urban the Sixth.","('Bari', 'PERSON'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('St. Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Urban the Sixth', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Their claims were readily deduced from the genuine, or fabulous, donations of the darker ages: the successive steps of their final settlement would engage us too far in the transactions of Italy, and even of Europe; the crimes of Alexander the Sixth, the martial operations of Julius the Second, and the liberal policy of Leo the Tenth, a theme which has been adorned by the pens of the noblest historians of the times. (89)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Sixth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Julius', 'PERSON'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Leo the Tenth', 'PERSON'), ('89', 'CARDINAL')"
Their constancy was exhausted by a rebellion of five months.,"('five months', 'DATE')"
"Their first choice, an involuntary and illegal act, was annulled by fear of death and the menaces of the Romans; and their complaint is justified by the strong evidence of probability and fact.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Their leader, who had escaped from Bologna, appeared among
 them in a robe of purple and gold: his voice, his
 countenance, his gestures, bespoke the man who had devoted
 his life or death to the glorious cause.","('Bologna', 'GPE')"
"These allegorical emblems
 were variously repeated in the pictures which Rienzi
 exhibited in the streets and churches; and while the
 spectators gazed with curious wonder, the bold and ready
 orator unfolded the meaning, applied the satire, inflamed
 their passions, and announced a distant hope of comfort and
 deliverance.","('Rienzi', 'PERSON')"
"They
 had vainly flattered themselves with the hope of restoring
 the seat of the ecclesiastical monarchy, and of relieving
 their poverty with the tributes and offerings of the nations; Calamities of Rome.","('Calamities', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
They oppose Reinzi in arms.,"('Reinzi', 'PERSON')"
"They rose in arms, elected seven governors of the republic, and a constable of the Capitol; imprisoned the pope's nephew; besieged his person in the palace; and shot volleys of arrows into his bark as he escaped down the Tyber in the habit of a monk.","('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('Tyber', 'PRODUCT')"
"They swore to live and die with the republic and the church,
 whose interest was artfully united by the nominal
 association of the bishop of Orvieto, the pope's vicar, to
 the office of tribune.","('Orvieto', 'GPE')"
"To vanquish the obstinacy of Benedict the Thirteenth or his adherents, the emperor in person undertook a journey from Constance to Perpignan.","('Benedict', 'PERSON'), ('Thirteenth', 'DATE'), ('Constance', 'PERSON'), ('Perpignan', 'GPE')"
"Twelve patrician youths were arrayed in
 scarlet; six representatives of the most illustrious
 families, in green robes, with garlands of flowers,
 accompanied the procession; in the midst of the princes and
 nobles, the senator, count of Anguillara, a kinsman of the
 Colonna, assumed his throne; and at the voice of a herald
 Petrarch arose.","('Twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Anguillara', 'PERSON'), ('Colonna', 'PERSON'), ('Petrarch', 'PERSON')"
"Under the reign of Sixtus the Fourth, Rome was distracted by
 the battles and sieges of the rival houses: after the
 conflagration of his palace, the prothonotary Colonna was
 tortured and beheaded; and Savelli, his captive friend, was
 murdered on the spot, for refusing to join in the
 acclamations of the victorious Ursini. (86)","('the reign of Sixtus the Fourth', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Colonna', 'PERSON'), ('Savelli', 'PERSON'), ('Ursini', 'PERSON'), ('86', 'CARDINAL')"
"Under the tyranny of the Ghibeline nobles, the wisest patriots regretted the dominion of the church; and their repentance was unanimous and effectual.","('Ghibeline', 'NORP')"
