Sentence,Entities
"(1) After a preamble filled with passion and  reproach, Constantine absolutely prohibits the assemblies of the heretics, and confiscates their public property to the use either of the revenue or of the Catholic church.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
(172),"('172', 'CARDINAL')"
(3),"('3', 'CARDINAL')"
(45),"('45', 'CARDINAL')"
"(5)
African Controversy, A.D. 312.","('312', 'CARDINAL')"
"1/.
 If they were asked whether the Son was like unto the Father,
 the question was resolutely answered in the negative by the
 heretics who adhered to the principles of Arius, or indeed
 to those of philosophy, which seem to establish an infinite
 difference between the Creator and the most excellent of his
 creatures.","('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Son', 'PERSON'), ('Arius', 'PERSON')"
2/.,"('2', 'CARDINAL')"
"3/. The sect
 which asserted the doctrine of a similar substance was the
 most numerous, at least in the provinces of Asia; and when
 the leaders of both parties were assembled in the council of
 Seleucia, (70) their opinion would have prevailed by a majority of one hundred and five to forty-three bishops.","('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Seleucia', 'ORG'), ('70', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred and five', 'CARDINAL'), ('forty-three', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 fourth part of the Donatist bishops followed the independent
 standard of the Maximianists.","('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Donatist', 'ORG'), ('Maximianists', 'NORP')"
"A formulary of consent was transmitted by
 the messengers of state to the absent bishops: and all those
 who refused to submit their private opinion to the public
 and inspired wisdom of the councils of Arles and Milan were
 immediately banished by the emperor, who affected to execute
 the decrees of the catholic church.","('Arles', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"A large majority
 of the bishops of Asia appeared to support or favour his
 cause; and their measures were conducted by Eusebius of
 Caesarea, the most learned of the Christian prelates; and by
 Eusebius of Nicomedia, who had acquired the reputation of a
 statesman without forfeiting that of a saint.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesarea', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('Nicomedia', 'PERSON')"
"A letter was publicly read and ignominiously
 torn, in which their patron, Eusebius of Nicomedia,
 ingenuously confessed that the admission of the HOMOOUSION, or Consubstantial, a word already familiar to the Platonists, was incompatible with the principles of their
 theological system.","('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('Nicomedia', 'PERSON'), ('Consubstantial', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Platonists', 'NORP')"
"A metaphysical argument
 became the cause or pretence of political contests; the
 subtleties of the Platonic school were used as the badges of
 popular factions, and the distance which separated their
 respective tenets was enlarged or magnified by the acrimony
 of dispute.","('Platonic', 'NORP')"
"A modern writer, who, with a just confidence, has prefixed
 to his own history the honourable epithets of political and
 philosophical, (163) accuses the timid prudence of 
 Montesquieu, for neglecting to enumerate, among the causes
 of the decline of the empire, a law of Constantine, by which
 the exercise of the Pagan worship was absolutely suppressed,
 and a considerable part of his subjects was left destitute
 of priests, temples, and of any public religion.","('Montesquieu', 'GPE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Pagan', 'NORP')"
"A numerous colony of Jews had been invited, by the favour 
 of the Ptolemies, to settle in their new capital.(14) While 
 the bulk of the nation practised the legal ceremonies, and
 pursued the lucrative occupations of commerce, a few Hebrews
 of a more liberal spirit devoted their lives to religious
 and philosophical contemplation.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Ptolemies', 'NORP'), ('14', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hebrews', 'NORP')"
"A prophet, or apostle, inspired by
 the Deity, can alone exercise a lawful dominion over the
 faith of mankind: and the theology of Plato might have been
 for ever confounded with the philosophical visions of the
 Academy, the Porch, and the Lyccum, if the name and divine
 attributes of the Logos had not been confirmed by the
 celestial pen of the last and most sublime of the
 Evangelists. (20)","('Deity', 'PERSON'), ('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n Academy, the Porch', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Lyccum', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Logos', 'ORG'), ('Evangelists', 'NORP'), ('20', 'CARDINAL')"
"A report
 that the ceremonies of Paganism were suppressed is formally
 contradicted by the emperor himself, who wisely assigns, as
 the principle of his moderation, the invincible force of
 habit, of prejudice, and of superstition.","('Paganism', 'NORP')"
"A secret chain of swift and trusty messengers
 informed him of the vicissitudes of the battle; and while
 the courtiers stood trembling round their affrighted master,
 Valens assured him that the Gallic legions gave way; and
 insinuated, with some presence of mind, that the glorious
 event had been revealed to him by an angel.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP')"
"A severe
 inquisition, which was taken by the praetorian vicar and the
 proconsul of Africa, the report of two episcopal visitors
 who had been sent to Carthage, the decrees of the councils
 of Rome and of Arles, and the supreme judgment of
 Constantine himself in his sacred consistories were all
 favourable to the cause of Caecilian; and he was unanimously
 acknowledged by the civil and ecclesiastical powers as the
 true and lawful primate of Africa.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Arles', 'GPE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Caecilian', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"A similar union of the Mosaic faith 
 and the Grecian philosophy distinguishes the works of Philo,
 which were composed, for the most part, under the reign of
 Augustus.(17)","('Mosaic', 'NORP'), ('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('Philo', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('17', 'CARDINAL')"
"A vessel, which
 lay ready at the garden stairs, immediately hoisted sail,
 and, while the people were still ignorant of the meditated
 sacrilege, their bishop was already embarked on his voyage
 to Thessalonica.","('Thessalonica', 'GPE')"
A.D. 325,"('A.D. 325', 'DATE')"
"About fifty years
 afterwards, the Ebionites, whose errors are mentioned by
 Justin Martyr, with less severity than they seem to deserve,
 (25) formed a very inconsiderable portion of the Christian 
 name.","('About fifty years\r\n afterwards', 'DATE'), ('Ebionites', 'PERSON'), ('Justin Martyr', 'PERSON'), ('25', 'DATE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"About four years after the supposed date of his bloody edict, Constantius visited the temples of Rome; and the decency of his behaviour is recommended by a Pagan orator as an example worthy of the imitation of succeeding princes.","('About four years', 'DATE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Pagan', 'NORP')"
"After every satisfaction and security had been given which
 justice or even delicacy could require, the primate
 proceeded, by slow journeys, through the provinces of
 Thrace, Asia, and Syria; and his progress was marked by the
 abject homage of the Oriental bishops, who excited his
 contempt without deceiving his penetration.(118) At Antioch 
 he saw the emperor Constantius; sustained, with modest
 firmness, the embraces and protestations of his master; and
 eluded the proposal of allowing the Arians a single church
 at Alexandria by claiming, in the other cities of the
 empire, a similar toleration for his own party; a reply
 which might have appeared just and moderate in the mouth of
 an independent prince.","('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Arians', 'NORP'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"After some ineffectual resistance, his rival was expelled from the city by the permission of the emperor and the power of the opposite faction; the adherents of Felix were inhumanly murdered in the streets, in the public places, in the baths, and even in the churches; and the face of Rome, upon the return of a Christian bishop, renewed the horrid image of the massacres of Marius and the proscriptions of Sylla.(149)
Constantinople
II.","('Felix', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Marius', 'PERSON'), ('Sylla', 'PERSON'), ('149', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the 
 edict of toleration had restored peace and leisure to the
 Christians, the Trinitarian controversy was revived in the
 ancient seat of Platonism, the learned, the opulent, the
 tumultuous city of Alexandria; and the flame of religious
 discord was rapidly communicated from the schools to the
 clergy, the people, the provinces, and the East.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Trinitarian', 'NORP'), ('Platonism', 'NORP'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"After the death of Alexander the episcopal
 throne was disputed by Paul and Macedonius.","('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Macedonius', 'PERSON')"
"After the return of the 
 deputies from Alexandria, the majority of the council
 pronounced the final sentence of degradation and exile
 against the primate of Egypt.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"Alternate responses
 and a more regular paslmody (146) were introduced into the 
 public service by Flavianus and Diodorus, two devout and
 active laymen, who were attached to the Nicene faith.","('146', 'CARDINAL'), ('Flavianus', 'PERSON'), ('Diodorus', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nicene', 'NORP')"
"Amidst the storms of persecution, the archbishop of
 Alexandria was patient of labour, jealous of fame, careless
 of safety; and although his mind was tainted by the
 contagion of fanaticism, Athanasius displayed a superiority
 of character and abilities which would have qualified him,
 far better than the degenerate sons of Constantine, for the
 government of a great monarchy.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Among those prelates who
 led the honourable band of confessors and exiles, Liberius
 of Rome, Osius of Cordova, Paulinus of Treves, Dionysius of
 Milan, Eusebius of Vercellae, Lucifer of Cagliari, and
 Hilary of Poitiers, may deserve to be particularly
 distinguished.","('Liberius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Osius', 'PERSON'), ('Cordova', 'GPE'), ('Paulinus', 'PERSON'), ('Treves', 'GPE'), ('Dionysius', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('Vercellae', 'GPE'), ('Lucifer', 'PERSON'), ('Cagliari', 'GPE'), ('Hilary', 'PERSON'), ('Poitiers', 'GPE')"
"An ignominious silence was imposed on the
 oracles, which had been publicly convicted of fraud and
 falsehood; the effeminate priests of the Nile were
 abolished; and Constantine discharged the duties of a Roman
 censor, when he gave orders for the demolition of several
 temples of Phoenicia, in which every mode of prostitution
 was devoutly practised in the face of day, and to the honour
 of Venus.(166)","('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Phoenicia', 'GPE'), ('Venus', 'LOC'), ('166', 'CARDINAL')"
Arian Sects,"('Arian Sects', 'PERSON')"
"Arius himself was
 treated by the whole court with the respect which would have
 been due to an innocent and oppressed man.","('Arius', 'PERSON')"
"As
 soon as they were informed of his banishment into Thrace, a
 general assembly was convened, and the clergy of Rome bound
 themselves, by a public and solemn oath, never to desert
 their bishop, never to acknowledge the usurper Felix, who,
 by the influence of the eunuchs, had been irregularly chosen
 and consecrated within the walls of a profane palace.","('Thrace', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Felix', 'PERSON')"
"As he was
 yet ignorant of the difficulty of appeasing the quarrels of
 theologians, he addressed to the contending parties, to
 Alexander and to Arius, a moderating epistle;(77) which may 
 be ascribed with far greater reason to the untutored sense
 of a soldier and statesman than to the dictates of any of
 his episcopal counsellors.","('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Arius', 'PERSON'), ('77', 'CARDINAL')"
"As it
 frequently happens that the sounds and characters which
 approach the nearest to each other accidentally represent
 the most opposite ideas, the observation would be itself
 ridiculous, if it were possible to mark any real and
 sensible distinction between the doctrine of the
 Semi-Arians, as they were improperly styled, and that of the
 Catholics themselves.","('Semi-Arians', 'NORP'), ('Catholics', 'NORP')"
"As long as the danger
 continued, she regularly supplied him with books and
 provisions, washed his feet, managed his correspondence, and
 dexterously concealed from the eye of suspicion this
 familiar and solitary intercourse between a saint whose
 character required the most unblemished chastity, and a
 female whose charms might excite the most dangerous
 emotions.(142)","('142', 'CARDINAL')"
"As long as the dark heresies of Praxeas and
 Sabellius laboured to confound the Father with the Son, (41) 
 the orthodox party might be excused if they adhered more
 strictly and more earnestly to the distinction than to the
 equality of the divine persons.","('Praxeas', 'PERSON'), ('Sabellius', 'PERSON'), ('the Father with the Son', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('41', 'CARDINAL')"
"As soon as the emperor was relieved from the terrors of  the civil war, he devoted the leisure of his winter quarters at Arles, Milan, Sirmium, and Constantinople, to the amusement or toils of controversy: the sword of the magistrate, and even of the tyrant, was unsheathed, to enforce the reasons of the theologian; and as he opposed the orthodox faith of Nice, it is readily confessed that his incapacity and ignorance were equal to his presumption.(93)","('the civil war', 'EVENT'), ('Arles', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Sirmium', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Nice', 'PERSON')"
"As the chapel in which the body of the great
 Constantine had been deposited was in a ruinous condition,
 the bishop transported those venerable remains into the
 church of St. Acacius.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('St. Acacius', 'GPE')"
"As the justice of the sentence
 was publicly avowed by the whole party, the only motive
 which could restrain Constantius from giving his messengers
 the sanction of a written mandate must be imputed to his
 doubt of the event; and to a sense of the danger to which he
 might expose the second city and the most fertile province
 of the empire, if the people should persist in the
 resolution of defending, by force of arms, the innocence of
 their spiritual father.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"As these difficulties arise from
 the nature of the subject, they oppress, with the same
 insuperable weight, the philosophic and the theological
 disputant; but we may observe two essential and peculiar
 circumstances which discriminated the doctrines of the
 catholic church from the opinions of the Platonic school.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Platonic', 'NORP')"
"At first their depredations were coloured by the plea of necessity, but they soon exceeded the measure of subsistence, indulged without control their intemperance and
 avarice, burnt the villages which they had pillaged, and reigned the licentious tyrants of the open country.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"At the
 end of two years their pious obstinacy subsisted entire and
 unshaken; and when Constantius visited Rome, he was assailed
 by the importunate solicitations of a people who had
 preserved, as the last remnant of their ancient freedom, the
 right of treating their sovereign with familiar insolence.","('the\r\n end of two years', 'DATE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"At the end of three
 years the primate was summoned to the court of Milan by the
 emperor Constans, who, in the indulgence of unlawful
 pleasures, still professed a lively regard for the orthodox
 faith.","('the end of three\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Constans', 'PERSON')"
"At the hour of
 midnight, twenty-three days after the signature of the
 treaty, Syrianus, duke of Egypt, at the head of five
 thousand soldiers, armed and prepared for an assault,
 unexpectedly invested the church of St. Theonas, where the
 archbishop, with a part of his clergy and people, performed
 their nocturnal devotions.","('the hour of\r\n midnight', 'TIME'), ('twenty-three days', 'DATE'), ('Syrianus', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('five\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('St. Theonas', 'GPE')"
"At the hour of midnight, as she related her story
 many years afterwards, she was surprised by the appearance
 of the archbishop in a loose undress, who, advancing with
 hasty steps, conjured her to afford him the protection which
 he had been directed by a celestial vision to seek under her
 hospitable roof.","('the hour of midnight', 'TIME')"
"Athanasius had openly disapproved 
 that ignominious peace, and the emperor was disposed to
 believe that he had abused his ecclesiastical and civil
 power to persecute those odious sectaries; that he had
 sacrilegiously broken a chalice in one of their churches of
 Maraeotis; that he had whipped or imprisoned six of their
 bishops; and that Arsenius, a seventh bishop of the same
 party, had been murdered, or at least mutilated, by the
 cruel hand of the primate.(103)","('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maraeotis', 'PERSON'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arsenius', 'PERSON'), ('seventh', 'ORDINAL'), ('103', 'CARDINAL')"
"Athanasius still rejected 
 the pious importunity of the monks and presbyters who were
 attached to his person; and nobly refused to desert his
 episcopal station till he had dismissed in safety the last
 of the congregation.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"Athanasius waited with decent pride
 till he had received three successive epistles full of the
 strongest assurances of the protection, the favour, and the
 esteem of his sovereign; who invited him to resume his
 episcopal seat, and who added the humiliating precaution of
 engaging his principal ministers to attest the sincerity of
 his intentions.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"Before 
 Athanasius, at the head of fifty Egyptian prelates, sailed
 from Alexandria, he had wisely secured the alliance of the
 Meletians; and Arsenius himself, his imaginary victim, and
 his secret friend, was privately concealed in his train.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Meletians', 'NORP'), ('Arsenius', 'PERSON')"
Before Christ 300.,"('300', 'CARDINAL')"
Before Christ 360.,"('Christ 360', 'PERSON')"
"Before he condemned the Manichaeans and their kindred sects, he resolved to make an accurate inquiry into the nature of their religious principles.","('Manichaeans', 'NORP')"
"Besides the general design of
 fixing on a perpetual basis the divine honours of Christ,
 the most ancient and respectable of the ecclesiastical
 writers have ascribed to the evangelic theologian a
 particular intention to confute two opposite heresies, which
 disturbed the peace of the primitive church.(21)
The Ebionites and Docetes
I.","('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('The Ebionites and Docetes\r\nI', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Bishops, virgins, and even spotless
 infants, were subjected to the disgrace of a public penance
 before they could be admitted to the communion of the
 Donatists.","('Donatists', 'ORG')"
"But
 these depredations were confined to a small part of the
 Roman world; and the provinces had been long since
 accustomed to endure the same sacrilegious rapine, from the
 tyranny of princes and proconsuls who could not be suspected
 of any design to subvert the established religion.(167)
and his sons.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But as Athanasius was continually engaged with the
 prejudices and passions of every order of men, from the monk
 to the emperor, the knowledge of human nature was his first
 and most important science.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But as soon as the heat of
 controversy had subsided and the progress of the Sabellians
 was no longer an object of terror to the churches of Rome,
 of Africa, or of Egypt, the tide of theological opinion
 began to flow with a gentle but steady motion toward the
 contrary extreme; and the most orthodox doctors allowed
 themselves the use of the terms and definitions which had
 been censured in the mouth of the sectaries.(42)","('Sabellians', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('42', 'CARDINAL')"
"But as the degrees
 of theological hatred depend on the spirit of the war rather
 than on the importance of the controversy, the heretics who
 degraded were treated with more severity than those who
 annihilated the person of the Son.","('Son', 'PERSON')"
"But as the sectaries might still exist under the cloud of royal disgrace, the conquest of the East was immediately followed by an edict which announced their total destruction.","('East', 'LOC')"
"But as the western provincials had the good fortune of
 deriving their religion from an orthodox source, they
 preserved with steadiness the doctrine which they had
 accepted with docility; and when the Arian pestilence
 approached their frontiers, they were supplied with the
 seasonable preservative of the Homoousion by the paternal
 care of the Roman pontiff.","('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Homoousion', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But as those princes presumed to extend
 their despotism over the faith, as well as over the lives
 and fortunes of their subjects, the weight of their suffrage
 sometimes inclined the ecclesiastical balance: and the
 prerogatives of the King of Heaven were settled, or changed,
 or modified, in the cabinet of an earthly monarch.","('the King of Heaven', 'PERSON')"
"But he
 solemnly declares his unalterable resolution to pursue with
 fire and sword the seditious adherents of the wicked
 Athanasius, who, by flying from justice, has confessed his
 guilt, and escaped the ignominious death which he had so
 often deserved.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"But the
 ideas of toleration were so repugnant to the practice, and
 even to the sentiments, of those times, that, when the answer of Constantius was publicly read in the Circus of Rome, so reasonable a project of accommodation was rejected with contempt and ridicule.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('the Circus of Rome', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"But the
 memory of the firm and effectual support which the primate
 of Egypt had derived from the attachment of the Western
 church engaged Constantius to suspend the execution of the
 sentence till he had obtained the concurrence of the Latin
 bishops.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"But the Christians formed a numerous and disciplined
 society; and the jurisdiction of their laws and magistrates
 was strictly exercised over the minds of the faithful.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"But the bishops of the Latin provinces had no sooner reached
 their respective dioceses than they discovered their
 mistake, and repented of their weakness.","('Latin', 'NORP')"
"But the credit of his favourite Osius,
 who appears to have presided in the council of Nice, might
 dispose the emperor in favour of the orthodox party; and a
 well-timed insinuation, that the same Eusebius of Nicomedia,
 who now protected the heretic, had lately assisted the
 tyrant,(79) might exasperate him against their adversaries.","('Osius', 'PERSON'), ('Nice', 'GPE'), ('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('Nicomedia', 'PERSON'), ('79', 'DATE')"
"But the credulous
 monarch, unskilled in the stratagems of theological warfare,
 might be deceived by the modest and specious professions of
 the heretics, whose sentiments he never perfectly
 understood; and while he protected Arius, and persecuted
 Athanasius, he still considered the council of Nice as the
 bulwark of the Christian faith, and the peculiar glory of
 his own reign.(84)
Constantius favours the Arians, A.D. 337-361.","('Arius', 'PERSON'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Nice', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Arians', 'PERSON'), ('337-361', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the deserts of 
 Thebais were now peopled by a race of wild, yet submissive
 fanatics, who preferred the commands of their abbot to the
 laws of their sovereign.","('Thebais', 'GPE')"
"But the injustice of these ecclesiastical judges had not
 been countenanced by the submission, or even by the
 presence, of Athanasius.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"But the more fashionable
 saints of the Arian times, the intrepid Athanasius, the
 learned Gregory Nazianzen, and the other pillars of the
 church, who supported with ability and success the Nicene
 doctrine, appeared to consider the expression of substance
 as if it had been synonymous with that of nature; and they
 ventured to illustrate their meaning by affirming that three
 men, as they belong to the same common species, are
 consubstantial or homoousian to each other.(58)","('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Gregory Nazianzen', 'PERSON'), ('Nicene', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the most sagacious
 of the Christian theologians, the great Athanasius himself,
 has candidly confessed (32) that, whenever he forced his 
 understanding to meditate on the divinity of the Logos, his
 toilsome and unavailing efforts recoiled on themselves; that
 the more he thought, the less he comprehended; and the more
 he wrote, the less capable was he of expressing his
 thoughts.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('32', 'DATE'), ('Logos', 'ORG')"
"But the pride of
 Arius was supported by the applause of a numerous party.","('Arius', 'PERSON')"
"But the repeated attempts of the emperor to seduce
 or to intimidate the bishops of Rome and Cordova were for
 some time ineffectual.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Cordova', 'GPE')"
"But the subject who has reduced his prince to the necessity
 of dissembling can never expect a sincere and lasting
 forgiveness; and the tragic fate of Constans soon deprived
 Athanasius of a powerful and generous protector.","('Constans', 'PERSON'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"But the triumph of 
 Arianism had been preceded by the removal of the orthodox
 clergy, whom it was impossible either to intimidate or to
 corrupt; and the reign of Constantius was disgraced by the
 unjust and ineffectual persecution of the great Athanasius.","('Arianism', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"But the voice of reason (if reason was indeed on the side of
 Athanasius) was silenced by the clamours of a factious or
 venal majority; and the councils of Arles and Milan were not
 dissolved till the archbishop of Alexandria had been
 solemnly condemned and deposed by the judgment of the
 Western, as well as of the Eastern, church.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Arles', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"But their national pride would have
 been mortified by a fair confession of their former poverty:
 and they boldly marked, as the sacred inheritance of their
 ancestors, the gold and jewels which they had so lately
 stolen from their Egyptian masters.","('Egyptian', 'NORP')"
"But this 
 religious war, so horrible to nature, was prevented by the
 timely compliance of Constantius; and the emperor of the
 East condescended to solicit a reconciliation with a subject
 whom he had injured.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"But this incident, so inconsiderable that it scarcely
 deserves a place in history, was productive of a memorable
 schism, which afflicted the provinces of Africa above three
 hundred years, and was extinguished only with Christianity
 itself.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('three\r\n hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Christianity', 'NORP')"
But this inestimable privilege was soon violated: with the knowledge of truth the emperor imbibed the maxims of persecution; and the sects which dissented from the Catholic church were afflicted and oppressed by the triumph of Christianity.,"('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Christianity', 'NORP')"
"But this inferiority was compensated by the
 advantages of skill, of experience, and of discipline; and
 the minority was conducted by Valens and Ursacius, two
 bishops of Illyricum, who had spent their lives in the
 intrigues of courts and councils, and who had been trained
 under the Eusebian banner in the religious wars of the East.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Ursacius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Illyricum', 'ORG'), ('Eusebian', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"But when the primate of Egypt, deserted and
 proscribed by the Latin church, was left destitute of any
 foreign support, Constantius despatched two of his
 secretaries with a verbal commission to announce and execute
 the order of his banishment.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"But, as if the conduct of the emperor had been guided by
 passion instead of principle, three years from the council
 of Nice were scarcely elapsed before he discovered some
 symptoms of mercy, and even of indulgence, towards the
 proscribed sect, which was secretly protected by his
 favourite sister.","('three years', 'DATE'), ('Nice', 'GPE')"
"By a particular edict he exempted them from the general penalties of the law; (4) allowed them to build a  church at Constantinople; respected the miracles of their saints; invited their bishop, Acesius, to the council of Nice; and gently ridiculed the narrow tenets of his sect by a familiar jest, which from the mouth of a sovereign must have been received with applause and gratitude.","('4', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Acesius', 'PERSON'), ('Nice', 'GPE')"
"By a public and
 passionate epistle, the emperor congratulates the
 deliverance of Alexandria from a popular tyrant, who deluded
 his blind votaries by the magic of his eloquence; expatiates
 on the virtues and piety of the most reverend George, the
 elected bishop; and aspires, as the patron and benefactor of
 the city, to surpass the fame of Alexander himself.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('George', 'PERSON'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON')"
"By an edict of Constantius
 against the catholics, which has not been judged worthy of a
 place in the Theodosian code, those who refused to
 communicate with the Arian bishops, and particularly with
 Macedonius, were deprived of the immunities of ecclesiastics
 and of the rights of Christians; they were compelled to
 relinquish the possession of the churches, and were strictly
 prohibited from holding their assemblies within the walls of
 the city.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosian', 'NORP'), ('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Macedonius', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"By the assiduous study of the 
 Latin language he soon qualified himself to negotiate with
 the western clergy; his decent flattery swayed and directed
 the haughty Julius: the Roman pontiff was persuaded to
 consider his appeal as the peculiar interest of the
 Apostolic see; and his innocence was unanimously declared in
 a council of fifty bishops of Italy.","('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Julius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Apostolic', 'NORP'), ('fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"By their arguments and negotiations they embarrassed, they
 confounded, they at last deceived the honest simplicity of
 the Latin bishops, who suffered the palladium of the faith
 to be extorted from their hands by fraud and importunity,
 rather than by open violence.","('Latin', 'NORP')"
"By their zeal
 and abilities they both deserved the eminent station to
 which they aspired; and if the moral character of Macedonius
 was less exceptionable, his competitor had the advantage of
 a prior election and a more orthodox doctrine.","('Macedonius', 'PERSON')"
"By this
 seeming moderation the catholics were deceived into a false
 and fatal security; while the legions of the Upper Egypt,
 and of Libya, advanced, by secret orders and hasty marches,
 to besiege, or rather to surprise, a capital habituated to
 sedition, and inflamed by religious zeal.(134)","('the Upper Egypt', 'LOC'), ('Libya', 'GPE'), ('134', 'CARDINAL')"
Character and adventures of Athanasius,"('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"Conduct of the emperors in the Arian controvesy 
 Such was the rise and progress, and such were the natural
 revolutions, of those theological disputes which disturbed
 the peace of Christianity under the reigns of Constantine
 and of his sons.","('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Constantine 
 listened to the complaints of Athanasius with impartial and
 even gracious attention; the members of the synod of Tyre
 were summoned to justify their proceedings and the arts of
 the Eusebian faction would have been confounded if they had
 not aggravated the guilt of the primate by the dexterous
 supposition of an unpardonable offence — a criminal design
 to intercept and detain the corn-fleet of Alexandria, which
 supplied the subsistence of the new capital.(108)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Tyre', 'PERSON'), ('Eusebian', 'NORP'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('108', 'CARDINAL')"
"Constantine easily believed that the heretics, who presumed to dispute his opinions or to oppose his commands, were guilty of the most absurd and criminal obstinacy; and that a seasonable application of moderate severities might save those unhappy men from the danger of an everlasting condemnation.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Constantine gave them security, wealth, honours, and revenge; and the support of the orthodox faith  was considered as the most sacred and important duty of the civil magistrate.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Constantinople alone enjoyed the
 advantage of being born and educated in the bosom of the
 faith.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Corruption, the most
 infallible symptom of constitutional liberty, was
 successfully practised; honours, gifts, and immunities were
 offered and accepted as the price of an episcopal vote;(124) 
 and the condemnation of the Alexandrian primate was artfully
 represented as the only measure which could restore the
 peace and union of the Catholic church.","('124', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alexandrian', 'NORP'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"Council of Rimi, A.D. 360","('Council of Rimi', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 360', 'DATE')"
"Councils of Arles and Milan, A.D. 353-355","('Arles', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 353-355', 'DATE')"
"Counts,
 praefects, tribunes, whole armies, were successively
 employed to pursue a bishop and a fugitive; the vigilance of
 the civil and military powers was excited by the Imperial
 edicts; liberal rewards were promised to the man who should
 produce Athanasius, either alive or dead; and the most
 severe penalties were denounced against those who should
 dare to protect the public enemy. (138)","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('138', 'CARDINAL')"
"Driven from their native villages, the Donatist peasants assembled in formidable gangs on the edge of the Gaetulian desert, and readily exchanged the habits of labor for a life of idleness and rapine, which was consecrated by the name of religion, and faintly condemned by the doctors of the sect.","('Donatist', 'NORP'), ('the Gaetulian desert', 'LOC')"
"During the six years of persecution and exile, 
 Athanasius repeated his visits to his fair and faithful
 companion; and the formal declaration, that he saw the
 councils of Rimini and Seleucia, (143) forces us to believe 
 that he was secretly present at the time and place of their
 convocation.","('the six years', 'DATE'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Rimini', 'GPE'), ('Seleucia', 'PERSON'), ('143', 'CARDINAL')"
"Educated in the family of Alexander, he had
 vigorously opposed the early progress of the Arian heresy:
 he exercised the important functions of secretary under the
 aged prelate; and the fathers of the Nicene council beheld
 with surprise and respect the rising virtues of the young
 deacon.","('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Nicene', 'NORP')"
"Educated in the school of Plato, accustomed to the
 sublime idea of the Logos, they readily conceived that the
 brightest Aeon, or Emanation of the Deity, might assume the
 outward shape and visible appearances of a mortal;(26) but 
 they vainly pretended that the imperfections of matter are
 incompatible with the purity of a celestial substance.","('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('Logos', 'ORG'), ('Aeon', 'ORG')"
"Encouraged by success, Constantius ventured to
 approve the conduct of his ministers.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"Eusebius of Casarea yielded a reluctant and
 ambiguous consent to the homoousion; (80) and the wavering 
 conduct of the Nicomedian Eusebius served only to delay
 about three months his disgrace and exile.(81)He persecutes the Arian","('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('Casarea', 'PERSON'), ('80', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Nicomedian Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('about three months', 'DATE'), ('Arian', 'NORP')"
"Every motive of authority and fashion, of interest and reason, now militated on the side of Christianity; but two or three generations elapsed before their victorious influence was universally felt.","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"Excluded from the civil and religious communion
 of mankind, they boldly excommunicated the rest of mankind
 who had embraced the impious party of Caecilian, and of the
 Traditors, from whom he derived his pretended ordination.","('Caecilian', 'PERSON'), ('Traditors', 'NORP')"
Faith of the Western or Latin church,"('Western', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"Five times was Athanasius expelled from
 his throne; twenty years he passed as an exile or a
 fugitive; and almost every province of the Roman empire was
 successively witness to his merit, and his sufferings in the
 cause of the Homoousion, which he considered as the sole
 pleasure and business, as the duty and as the glory of his
 life.","('Five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('twenty years', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Homoousion', 'EVENT')"
"Four-score years after the death of Christ, the
 Christians of Bithynia declared before the tribunal of Pliny
 that they invoked him as a god: and his divine honours have
 been perpetuated in every age and country, by the various
 sects who assume the name of his disciples.(38) Their tender 
 reverence for the memory of Christ, and their horror for the
 profane worship of any created being, would have engaged
 them to assert the equal and absolute divinity of the logos,
 if their rapid ascent towards the throne of heaven had not
 been imperceptibly checked by the apprehension of violating
 the unity and sole supremacy of the great Father of Christ,
 and of the Universe.","('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Bithynia', 'PERSON'), ('Pliny', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Universe', 'ORG')"
"From that moment the
 primate of Egypt disappeared from the eyes of his enemies,
 and remained above six years concealed in impenetrable
 obscurity.(137)","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('six years', 'DATE'), ('137', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the age
 of Constantine to that of Clovis and Theodoric, the temporal
 interests both of the Romans and barbarians were deeply
 involved in the theological disputes of Arianism.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Arianism', 'NORP')"
"From the depth of his inaccessible retreat
 the intrepid primate waged an incessant and offensive war
 against the protector of the Arians; and his seasonable
 writings, which were diligently circulated and eagerly
 perused, contributed to unite and animate the orthodox
 party.","('Arians', 'NORP')"
"From the first debates
 it appeared that only four score prelates adhered to the
 party, though they affected to anathematise the name and
 memory of Arius.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arius', 'PERSON')"
"From their mutual reproaches, as
 well as from the story of this dark transaction, it may
 justly be inferred that the late persecution had embittered
 the zeal, without reforming the manners, of the African
 Christians.","('the African\r\n Christians', 'NORP')"
"General character of the Christian sects, A.D. 312-361.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 312-361', 'DATE')"
"Gratitude and humanity would have 
 disposed the primate of Egypt to deplore the untimely fate
 of Constans, and to abhor the guilt of Magnentius; but as he
 clearly understood that the apprehensions of Constantius
 were his only safeguard, the fervour of his prayers for the
 success of the righteous cause might perhaps be somewhat
 abated.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Constans', 'NORP'), ('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"He
 prudently declined the tribunal of his enemies, despised the
 summons of the synod of Caesarea; and, after a long and
 artful delay, submitted to the peremptory commands of the
 emperor, who threatened to punish his criminal disobedience
 if he refused to appear in the council of Tyre.(104)","('Caesarea', 'GPE'), ('Tyre', 'ORG'), ('104', 'CARDINAL')"
"He
 reckoned among his immediate followers two bishops of Egypt,
 seven presbyters, twelve deacons, and (what may appear
 almost incredible) seven hundred virgins.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"He
 was successively a slave, or at least a husbandman, a
 travelling tinker, a goldsmith, a physician, a schoolmaster,
 a theologian, and at last the apostle of a new church, which
 was propagated by the abilities of his disciple Eunomius.(68)   Armed with texts of Scripture, and with captious syllogisms
 from the logic of Aristotle, the subtle Aetius had acquired
 the fame of an invincible disputant, whom it was impossible
 either to silence or to convince.","('Eunomius', 'PERSON'), ('Scripture', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Aristotle', 'PERSON'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON')"
"He filled that
 eminent station above forty-six years, and his long
 administration was spent in a perpetual combat against the
 powers of Arianism.","('forty-six years', 'DATE'), ('Arianism', 'ORG')"
"He gave audience to the ambassadors of
 the tyrant, with whom he was afterwards accused of holding a
 secret correspondence; (120) and the emperor Constantius 
 repeatedly assured his dearest father, the most reverend
 Athanasius, that, notwithstanding the malicious rumours
 which were circulated by their common enemies, he had
 inherited the sentiments, as well as the throne, of his
 deceased brother.(121)","('120', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('121', 'CARDINAL')"
"He has
 always been revered in the orthodox school as one of the
 most accurate masters of the Christian theology; and he was
 supposed to possess two profane sciences, less adapted to
 the episcopal character — the knowledge of jurisprudence,(97) 
 and that of divination. (98)","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('97', 'CARDINAL')"
"He invites and exhorts, in the most pressing
 terms, the subjects of the Roman empire to imitate the
 exampleby Constantine, of their master; but he declares that those who still refuse to open their eyes to the celestial light may free enjoy their temples and their fancied gods.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"He laments that the Christian people, who had
 the same God, the same religion, and the same worship,
 should be divided by such inconsiderable distinctions; and
 he seriously recommends to the clergy of Alexandria the
 example of the Greek philosophers, who could maintain their
 arguments without losing their temper and assert their
 freedom without violating their friendship.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"He learned with surprise that
 the provinces of that great country, from the confines of
 Cyrene to the Columns of Hercules, were distracted with
 religious discord.(6) The source of the division was derived 
 from a double election in the church of Carthage, the second
 in rank and opulence of the ecclesiastical thrones of the
 West Caecilian and Majourinus were the two rival primates of
 Africa; and the death of the latter soon made room for
 Donatus, who, by his superior abilities and apparent
 virtues, was the firmest support of his party.","('Cyrene', 'GPE'), ('the Columns of Hercules', 'ORG'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('the\r\n West Caecilian', 'LOC'), ('Majourinus', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Donatus', 'PERSON')"
"He resolved either to
 convert or to extirpate them, and, as he distrusted on this
 occasion the efficacy of an ecclesiastical mission, he
 commanded a body of four thousand legionaries to march
 against the rebels, and to reduce the territory of Mantinium
 (155) under his spiritual dominion.","('four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mantinium', 'GPE'), ('155', 'CARDINAL')"
"He resolved to make a bold; and
 dangerous experiment, whether the throne was inaccessible to
 the voice of truth; and before the final sentence could be
 pronounced at Tyre, the intrepid primate threw himself into
 a bark which was ready to hoist sale for the Imperial city.","('Tyre', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"He was
 once secreted in a dry cistern, which he had scarcely left
 before he was betrayed by the treachery of a female slave;
 (141) and he was once concealed in a still more extraordinary 
 asylum, the house of a virgin, only twenty years of age, and
 who was celebrated in the whole city for her exquisite
 beauty.","('twenty years of age', 'DATE')"
"He was provoked by the insults which had
 been offered to his statues; he was alarmed by the real as
 well as the imaginary magnitude of the spreading mischief;
 and he extinguished the hope of peace and toleration, from
 the moment that he assembled three hundred bishops within
 the walls of the same palace.","('three hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"His
 prayers and threats, the authority of the sovereign, the
 sophistry of Valens and Ursacius, the distress of cold and
 hunger, and the tedious melancholy of a hopeless exile, at
 length extorted the reluctant consent of the bishops of
 Rimini.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Ursacius', 'PERSON'), ('Rimini', 'GPE')"
"His
 spiritual comforter, Valens, the Arian bishop of the
 diocese, employed the most artful precautions to obtain such
 early intelligence as might secure either his favour or his
 escape.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Arian', 'NORP')"
"His behaviour 
 Athanasius had indeed escaped from the most imminent
 dangers; and the adventures of that extraordinary man
 deserve and fix our attention.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
His competitor  Alexander assumed the office of his judge.,"('Alexander', 'PERSON')"
"His faith was
 approved by the synod of Jerusalem; and the emperor seemed
 impatient to repair his injustice, by issuing an absolute
 command that he should be solemnly admitted to the communion
 in the cathedral of Constantinople.","('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"His firm
 attachment to the Nicene creed, which has given Paul a place
 in the calendar among saints and martyrs, exposed him to the
 resentment of the Arians.","('Nicene', 'NORP'), ('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Arians', 'NORP')"
"His first exile, A.D. 336","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('A.D. 336', 'DATE')"
"His learning was much less
 profound and extensive than that of Eusebius of Caesarea,
 and his rude eloquence could not be compared with the
 polished oratory of Gregory or Basil; but whenever the
 primate of Egypt was called upon to justify his sentiments
 or his conduct, his unpremeditated style, either of speaking
 or writing, was clear, forcible, and persuasive.","('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesarea', 'GPE'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Basil', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"His poetical imagination
 sometimes fixed and animated these metaphysical
 abstractions; the three archical or original principles
 were represented in the Platonic system as three Gods,
 united with each other by a mysterious and ineffable
 generation; and the Logos was particularly considered under
 the more accessible character of the Son of an Eternal
 Father, and the Creator and Governor of he world.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Platonic', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Logos', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('the Son of an Eternal\r\n Father', 'PERSON')"
"His retreat, A.D. 356-362","('A.D. 356-362', 'DATE')"
"His second exile, A.D. 341","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('A.D. 341', 'DATE')"
"I. A chosen society of philosophers, men of a liberal
 education and curious disposition, might silently meditate,
 and temperately discuss in the gardens of Athens or the
 library of Alexandria, the abstruse questions of
 metaphysical science.","('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"I. According to the first hypothesis, which was maintained by Arius and his disciples, the logos
 was a dependent and spontaneous production, created from
 nothing by the will of the Father.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Arius', 'PERSON')"
"If the bishops of the council of Nice(55) had been permitted 
 to follow the unbiassed dictates of their conscience, Arius
 and his associates could scarcely have flattered themselves
 with the hopes of obtaining a majority of votes in favour of
 an hypothesis so directly adverse to the two most popular
 opinions of the catholic world.","('Nice', 'ORG'), ('55', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"If they obtained possession of a church which had
 been used by their Catholic adversaries, they purified the
 unhallowed building with the same jealous care which a
 temple of idols might have required.","('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"In
 his distress he always derived support, or at least
 consolation, from the faithful attachment of his parochial
 clergy; and the hundred bishops of Egypt adhered, with
 unshaken zeal, to the cause of Athanasius.","('hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"In
 the remote province of Gaul, but in the hospitable court of
 Treves, Athanasius passed about twenty-eight months.","('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Treves', 'GPE'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('about twenty-eight months', 'DATE')"
"In a time of public danger the dull claims of age
 and of rank are sometimes superseded; and within five months
 after his return from Nice the deacon Athanasius was seated
 on the archiepiscopal throne of Egypt.","('five months', 'DATE'), ('Nice', 'GPE'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"In his public apologies, which he addressed to the
 emperor himself, he sometimes affected the praise of
 moderation; whilst at the same time, in secret and vehement
 invectives, he exposed Constantius as a weak and wicked
 prince, the executioner of his family, the tyrant of the
 republic, and the Anti-christ of the church.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Anti-christ', 'NORP')"
"In his youth the primate of Egypt resisted the great
 Constantine, who had repeatedly signified his will that
 Arius should be restored to the catholic communion.(101)","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Arius', 'PERSON'), ('101', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the East as well as in the West, in cities as well as in the country, a great number of temples were respected, or at least were spared; and the devout multitude still enjoyed the luxury of sacrifices, of festivals, and of processions, by the permission, or by the connivance, of the civil government.","('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"In the actions of these desperate
 enthusiasts, who were admired by one party as the martyrs of
 God, and abhorred by the other as the victims of Satan, an
 impartial philosopher may discover the influence and the
 last abuse of that inflexible spirit which was originally
 derived from the character and principals of the Jewish
 nation.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Satan', 'PERSON'), ('Jewish', 'NORP')"
"In the beginning of the present century the
 example of the Circumcellions has been renewed in the
 persecution, the boldness, the crimes and the enthusiasm of
 the Camisards; and if the fanatics of Languedoc surpassed
 those of Numidia by their military achievements, the
 Africans maintained their fierce independence with more
 resolution and perseverance.(159)","('the beginning of the present century', 'DATE'), ('Circumcellions', 'PERSON'), ('Camisards', 'NORP'), ('Languedoc', 'GPE'), ('Numidia', 'NORP'), ('Africans', 'NORP'), ('159', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the height
 of his prosperity, the victorious monarch, who had chastised
 the rashness of Gallus, and suppressed the revolt of
 Sylvanus, who had taken the diadem from the head of
 Vetranio, and vanquished in the field the legions of
 Magnentius, received from an invisible hand a wound which he
 could neither heal nor revenge; and the son of Constantine
 was the first of the Christian princes who experienced the
 strength of those principles which, in the cause of
 religion, could resist the most violent exertions of the
 civil power.(144)
Arian Bishops","('Gallus', 'PERSON'), ('Sylvanus', 'PERSON'), ('Vetranio', 'PERSON'), ('Magnentius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Arian Bishops', 'PERSON')"
"In the modest
 equipage which pride and policy would affect, he frequently
 performed the episcopal visitation of his provinces, from
 the mouth of the Nile to the confines of Ethiopia;
 familiarly conversing with the meanest of the populace, and
 humbly saluting the saints and hermits of the desert.(100)","('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Ethiopia', 'GPE'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the most
 gentle and honourable terms he required the attendance of
 Paul in the baths of Zeuxippus, which had a private
 communication with the palace and the sea.","('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Zeuxippus', 'PRODUCT')"
"In the second hypothesis, the logos
 possessed all the inherent, incommunicable perfections which
 religion and philosophy appropriate to the Supreme God.","('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"In the space of fourteen years he
 was five times driven from his throne, to which he was more
 frequently restored by the violence of the people than by
 the permission of the prince, and the power of Macedonius
 could be secured only by the death of his rival.","('the space of fourteen years', 'DATE'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Macedonius', 'NORP')"
"In the use, as well as in the acquisition,
 of power, the tyrant George disregarded the laws of
 religion, of justice, and of humanity; and the same scenes
 of violence and scandal which had been exhibited in the
 capital were repeated in more than ninety episcopal cities
 of Egypt.","('George', 'PERSON'), ('more than ninety', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"In these familiar conferences with
 the sovereign of the West, Athanasius might lament the error
 of Constantius, but he boldly arraigned the guilt of his
 eunuchs and his Arian prelates; deplored the distress and
 danger of the Catholic church; and excited Constans to
 emulate the zeal and glory of his father.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Constans', 'PERSON')"
"Indifference of Constantine, A.D. 324","('Constantine', 'GPE'), ('324', 'CARDINAL')"
"Instead of alleging this imaginary law, which would have
 blazed in the front of the Imperial codes, we may safely
 appeal to the original epistle which Constantine addressed
 to the followers of the ancient religion, at a time when he
 no long disguised his conversion, nor dreaded the rivals of
 his throne.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"It was decided, with some 
 appearance of equity, that a bishop, deprived by a synod,
 should not resume his episcopal functions till he had been
 absolved by the judgment of an equal synod; the law was
 immediately applied to the case of Athanasius; the council
 of Antioch pronounced, or rather confirmed, his degradation:
 a stranger, named Gregory, was seated on his throne; and
 Philagrius,(111) the praefect of Egypt, was instructed to 
 support the new primate with the civil and military powers
 of the province.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Philagrius', 'PERSON'), ('111', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"It was on this occasion that, according
 to Jerom, the world was surprised to find itself Arian.(75)","('Jerom', 'PERSON'), ('Arian', 'NORP'), ('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"Like him, they presumed to pronounce their judgment on
 mysteries into which they had never been regularly
 initiated:(85) and the fate of the Trinitarian controversy 
 depended, in a great measure, on the sentiments of
 Constantius, who inherited the provinces of the East, and
 acquired the possession of the whole empire.","('85', 'CARDINAL'), ('Trinitarian', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"Macedonius
 was informed that a large district of Paphlagonia was almost
 entirely inhabited by those sectaries.","('Macedonius', 'PERSON'), ('Paphlagonia', 'GPE')"
"Macedonius, who was supported by a regular
 force, obtained a decisive victory, but his reign was
 disturbed by clamour and sedition, and the causes which
 appeared the least connected with the subject of dispute
 were sufficient to nourish and to kindle the flame of civil
 discord.","('Macedonius', 'PERSON')"
"Many of these fanatics were possessed with the horror of life, and the desire of martyrdom; and they deemed it of
 little moment by what means, or by what hands, they
 perished, if their conduct was sanctified by the intention
 of devoting themselves to the glory of the true faith, and
 the hope of eternal happiness. (160)","('160', 'CARDINAL')"
"Ninety bishops of that sect or faction assembled
 at Antioch under the specious pretence of dedicating the
 cathedral.","('Ninety', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"Ninety-four bishops
 of the West, seventy-six bishops of the East, encountered
 each other at Sardica, on the verge of the two empires, but
 in the dominions of the protector of Athanasius.","('Ninety-four', 'CARDINAL'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('seventy-six', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Sardica', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"Nor was it only in ecclesiastical assemblies, among men
 whose education and manners were similar to his own, that
 Athanasius displayed the ascendancy of his genius.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"Notwithstanding the applause which has been
 bestowed on the eloquence and sagacity of Constantine,(78) a 
 Roman general, whose religion might be still a subject of
 doubt, and whose mind had not been enlightened either by
 study or by inspiration, was indifferently qualified to
 discuss, in the Greek language, a metaphysical question, or
 an article of faith.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('78', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'LANGUAGE')"
"Notwithstanding the rapid increase of Christians under
 the reign of the Flavian family, Rome, Alexandria, and the
 other great cities of the empire, still contained a strong
 and powerful faction of Infidels, who envied the prosperity,
 and who ridiculed, even in their theatres, the theological
 disputes of the church.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Flavian', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Infidels', 'NORP')"
"On the memorable night when
 the church of St. Theonas was invested by the troops of
 Syrianus, the archbishop, seated on his throne, expected,
 with calm and intrepid dignity, the approach of death.","('the memorable night', 'TIME'), ('St. Theonas', 'GPE'), ('Syrianus', 'PERSON')"
"On the same day which
 had been fixed for the triumph of Arius, he expired; and the
 strange and horrid circumstances of his death might excite a
 suspicion that the orthodox saints had contributed more
 efficaciously than by their prayers to deliver the church
 from the most formidable of her enemies.","('the same day', 'DATE'), ('Arius', 'PERSON')"
"One
 question, which gradually arose from the Arian controversy,
 may, however, be noticed, as it served to produce and
 discriminate the three sects who were united only by their
 common aversion to the Homoousion of the Nicene synod.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arian', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Homoousion', 'NORP'), ('Nicene', 'NORP')"
"One hundred years before
 the birth of Christ, a philosophical treatise, which
 manifestly betrays the style and sentiments of the school of
 Plato, was produced by the Alexandrian Jews, and unanimously
 received as a genuine and valuable relic of the inspired
 Wisdom of Solomon. (16)","('One hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandrian Jews', 'NORP'), ('Wisdom of Solomon', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('16', 'CARDINAL')"
"Oppressed by the conspiracy of the Asiatic
 prelates, Athanasius withdrew from Alexandria and passed
 three years(112) as an exile and a suppliant on the holy 
 threshold of the Vatican.(113)","('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('three years', 'DATE'), ('112', 'CARDINAL'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('113', 'CARDINAL')"
"Our more intimate knowledge of the ecclesiastical transactions of the reign of Constantius would furnish an ample commentary on this remarkable
 passage; which justifies the rational apprehensions of Athanasius, that the restless activity of the clergy, who wandered round the empire in search of the true faith, would excite the contempt and laughter of the unbelieving world. (92)","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('92', 'CARDINAL')"
"Perhaps their complaint was not without foundation, that the
 credulity of the emperor had been abused by the insidious
 arts of his favourite Osius.","('Osius', 'PERSON')"
"Persecution against Athanasius, A.D. 330","('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('330', 'CARDINAL')"
"Persecution of heresy — The Schism of the Donatists — The Arian Controversy — Athanasius — Distracted state of the Church and the Empire under Constantine and his sons — Toleration of Paganism 
THE grateful applause of the clergy has consecrated the memory of a prince, who indulged their passions and promoted their interest.","('The Arian Controversy — Athanasius — Distracted state of the Church and the Empire', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Toleration of Paganism', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Persuasion and violence were employed
 to extort the reluctant signature of the decrepit bishop of
 Cordova, whose strength was broken, and whose faculties were
 perhaps impaired, by the weight of an hundred years; and the
 insolent triumph of the Arians provoked some of the orthodox
 party to treat with inhuman severity the character, or
 rather the memory, of an unfortunate old man, to whose
 former services Christianity itself was so deeply indebted.
 (129)
Exiles","('Cordova', 'PERSON'), ('an hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Arians', 'NORP'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('129', 'CARDINAL')"
"Proscribed by the civil and ecclesiastical powers of the
 empire, the Donatists still maintained in some provinces,
 particularly in Numidia, their superior numbers; and four
 hundred bishops acknowledged the jurisdiction of their
 primate.","('Donatists', 'NORP'), ('Numidia', 'GPE'), ('four\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"Prudence would 
 undoubtedly suggest the mild and respectful tone that became
 a subject and a bishop.","('Prudence', 'PERSON')"
"Rome
I.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Schism of the Donatists, A.D. 315.","('Donatists', 'ORG'), ('315', 'CARDINAL')"
"So
 strange an apparition excited his surprise and indignation;
 and the guards were ordered to remove the importunate
 suitor; but his resentment was subdued by involuntary
 respect; and the haughty spirit of the emperor was awed by
 the courage and eloquence of a bishop who implored his
 justice and awakened his conscience. (107)","('107', 'CARDINAL')"
"Some fortunate conjectures of 
 future events, which impartial reasoners might ascribe to
 the experience and judgment of Athanasius, were attributed
 by his friends to heavenly inspiration, and imputed by his
 enemies to infernal magic.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"Some of the penal regulations were copied from the edicts of Diocletian; and this method of conversion was applauded by the same bishops who had felt the hand of oppression, and had pleaded for the rights of humanity.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Some of them might confess that he was born of a virgin; 
 but they obstinately rejected the preceding existence and
 divine perfections of the logos, or Son of God, which are so
 clearly defined in the Gospel of St. John.","('the Gospel of St. John', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Sometimes they rudely 
 disturbed the festivals, and profaned the temples of
 Paganism, with the design of exciting the most zealous of
 the idolaters to revenge the insulted honour of their gods.","('Paganism', 'NORP')"
"Such
 appear to have been the secret doctrines which were
 cautiously whispered in the gardens of the Academy; and
 which, according to the more recent disciples of Plato,
 could not be perfectly understood till after an assiduous
 study of thirty years.(12)
taught in the scool of Alexandria.","('Academy', 'ORG'), ('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('thirty years', 'DATE'), ('12', 'DATE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"Such extreme caution afforded
 Athanasius a specious pretence respectfully to dispute the
 truth of an order which he could not reconcile either with
 the equity or with the former declarations of his gracious
 master.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"Such talents engaged the
 friendship of the Arian bishops, till they were forced to
 renounce and even to persecute a dangerous ally, who, by the
 accuracy of his reasoning, had prejudiced their cause in the
 popular opinion, and offended the piety of their most
 devoted followers.","('Arian', 'NORP')"
"Such was the nice and capricious taste of the emperor
 Constantius, and so easily was he offended by the slightest
 deviation from his imaginary standard of Christian truth,
 that he persecuted, with equal zeal, those who defended the
 consubstantiality, those who asserted the similar substance,
 and those who denied the likeness, of the Son of God.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('the Son of God', 'PERSON')"
"Synods in
 Palestine and Bithynia were opposed to the synods of Egypt.","('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('Bithynia', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"Taurus, the Praetorian praefect, was instructed not to
 dismiss the prelates till they should all be united in the
 same opinion; and his efforts were supported by a power of
 banishing fifteen of the most refractory, and a promise of
 the consulship if he achieved so difficult an adventure.","('Taurus', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('fifteen', 'CARDINAL')"
"That divided church was incapable of affording
 an impartial judicature; the controversy was solemnly tried
 in five successive tribunals, which were appointed by the
 emperor; and the whole proceeding, from the first appeal to
 the final sentence, lasted above three years.","('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('three years', 'DATE')"
"The
 Christians, who abhorred the gross and impure generation of
 the Greek mythology, (35) were tempted to argue from the 
 familiar analogy of the filial and paternal relations.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('35', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 Greek word which was chosen to express this mysterious
 resemblance bears so close an affinity to the orthodox
 symbol, that the profane of every age have derided the
 furious contests which the difference of a single diphthong
 excited between the Homoousians and the Homoiousians.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Homoousians', 'NORP'), ('Homoiousians', 'NORP')"
"The
 abstruse question of the eternity of the logos was agitated
 in ecclesiastic conferences and popular sermons; and the  Arius  heterodox opinions of Arius (43) were soon made public by his  own zeal and by that of his adversaries.","('Arius', 'PERSON'), ('Arius', 'PERSON'), ('43', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 authority of these bishops, who, to the number of seventy,
 condemned Caecilian, and consecrated Majorinus, is again
 weakened by the infamy of some of their personal characters;
 and by the female intrigues, sacrilegious bargains, and
 tumultuous proceedings, which are imputed to this Numidian
 council. (7)","('seventy', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caecilian', 'PERSON'), ('Majorinus', 'PERSON'), ('Numidian', 'NORP'), ('7', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 caution, the delay, the difficulty with which he proceeded
 in the condemnation and punishment of a popular bishop,
 discovered to the world that the privileges of the church
 had already revived a sense of order and freedom in the
 Roman government.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The
 character of Son seemed to imply a perpetual subordination
 to the voluntary author of his existence;(36) but as the act 
 of generation, in the most spiritual and abstracted sense,
 must be supposed to transmit the properties of a common
 nature,(37) they durst not presume to circumscribe the powers 
 or the duration of the Son of an eternal and omnipotent
 Father.","('Son', 'PERSON'), ('36', 'CARDINAL'), ('37', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 council of the West was protracted till the seventh month.","('West', 'LOC'), ('the seventh month', 'DATE')"
"The
 death of the emperor changed the face of public affairs;
 and, amidst the general indulgence of a young reign, the
 primate was restored to his country by an honourable edict
 of the younger Constantine, who expressed a deep sense of
 the innocence and merit of his venerable guest.(109)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('109', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 doors were at length burst open: a cloud of arrows was
 discharged among the people; the soldiers, with drawn
 swords, rushed forwards into the sanctuary; and the dreadful
 gleam of their armour was reflected by the holy luminaries
 which burnt round the altar.(136)","('136', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 doxology, or sacred hymn, which celebrates the glory of the
 Trinity, is susceptible of very nice, but material,
 inflections; and the substance of an orthodox or an
 heretical creed may be expressed by the difference of a
 disjunctive or a copulative particle.","('Trinity', 'LOC')"
"The
 ecclesiastical government of Constantine cannot be justified
 from the reproach of levity and weakness.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The
 election of Athanasius has not escaped the reproach of
 irregularity and precipitation; (99) but the propriety of his 
 behaviour conciliated the affections both of the clergy and
 of the people.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('99', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 historian may therefore be permitted respectfully to
 withdraw the veil of the sanctuary, and to deduce the
 progress of reason and faith, of error and passion, from the
 school of Plato to the decline and fall of the empire.","('Plato', 'PERSON')"
"The
 incarnation of the logos is reduced to a mere inspiration of
 the Divine Wisdom, which filled the soul and directed all
 the actions of the man Jesus.","('the Divine Wisdom', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Jesus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 interest of the common cause inclined them to join their
 numbers and to conceal their differences; their animosity
 was softened by the healing counsels of toleration, and
 their disputes were suspended by the use of the mysterious
 Homoousion, which either party was free to interpret
 according to their peculiar tenets.","('Homoousion', 'PRODUCT')"
"The
 ordinary punishments of death, exile, and confiscation were
 inflicted with partial rigour, and the Greeks still revere
 the holy memory of two clerks, a reader and a subdeacon, who
 were accused of the murder of Hermogenes, and beheaded at
 the gates of Constantinople.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hermogenes', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The
 pretences of rapine and oppression were insensibly multiplied (168); every indulgence was shown to the illegal behaviour of the Christians; every doubt was explained to the disadvantage of Paganism, and the demolition of the temples was celebrated as one of the auspicious events of the reign of Constans and Constantius. (169)","('168', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Paganism', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constans', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('169', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 sacraments of the church were administered to the reluctant
 victims, who denied the vocation and abhorred the principles
 of Macedonius.","('Macedonius', 'PERSON')"
"The
 successor of Constantius has expressed, in a concise but
 lively manner, some of the theological calamities which
 afflicted the empire, and more especially the East, in the
 reign of a prince who was the slave of his own passions, and
 of those of his eunuchs.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The
 synod of Tyre was conducted by Eusebius of Caesarea, with
 more passion, and with less art, than his learning and
 experience might promise; his numerous faction repeated the
 names of homicide and tyrant; and their clamours were
 encouraged by the seeming patience of Athanasius, who
 expected the decisive moment to produce Arsenius alive and
 unhurt in the midst of the assembly.","('Tyre', 'PERSON'), ('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesarea', 'GPE'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Arsenius', 'PERSON')"
"The
 unfortunate Paul was dragged in chains from the sandy
 deserts of Mesopotamia to the most desolate places of Mount
 Taurus,(150) confined in a dark and narrow dungeon, left six 
 days without food, and at length strangled, by the order of
 Philip, one of the principal ministers of the emperor
 Constantius.(151)","('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Mesopotamia', 'LOC'), ('Mount\r\n Taurus', 'LOC'), ('150', 'CARDINAL'), ('six \r\n days', 'DATE'), ('Philip', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('151', 'CARDINAL')"
"The 
 emperor respected, and might forgive, this inflexible
 resolution; and the faction who considered Athanasius as
 their most formidable enemy were constrained to dissemble
 their hatred, and silently to prepare an indirect and
 distant assault.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"The Alexandrians were impatient to rise in
 arms for the defence of an eloquent and liberal pastor.","('Alexandrians', 'NORP')"
"The Arian
 presbyter or bishop, who had secreted for his use the
 testament of the deceased emperor, improved the fortunate
 occasion which had introduced him to the familiarity of a
 prince whose public counsels were always swayed by his
 domestic favourites.","('Arian', 'NORP')"
"The Arians soon perceived
 the danger of their situation, and prudently assumed those
 modest virtues which, in the fury of civil and religious
 dissensions, are seldom practised, or even praised, except
 by the weaker party.","('Arians', 'PERSON')"
"The Arians still thought it
 prudent to disguise, in ambiguous language, their real
 sentiments and designs; but the orthodox bishops, armed with
 the favour of the people and the decrees of a general
 council, insisted on every occasion, and particularly at
 Milan, that their adversaries should purge themselves from
 the suspicion of heresy, before they presumed to arraign the
 conduct of the great Athanasius.(127)
Condemnation of Athanasius, A.D. 355.","('Arians', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('127', 'CARDINAL'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('355', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Arians, who 
 considered as their own the victory of Constantius,
 preferred his glory to that of his father.(88) Cyril, bishop 
 of Jerusalem, immediately composed the description of a
 celestial cross, encircled with a splendid rainbow, which,
 during the festival of Pentecost, about the third hour of
 the day, had appeared over the Mount of Olives, to the
 edification of the devout pilgrims and the people of the
 holy city. (89)","('Arians', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Cyril', 'PERSON'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Pentecost', 'EVENT'), ('about the third hour of\r\n the day', 'TIME'), ('the Mount of Olives', 'LOC'), ('89', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Arians, who had secretly determined the guilt and
 condemnation of their enemy, attempted, however, to disguise
 their injustice by the imitation of judicial forms; the
 synod appointed an episcopal commission of six delegates to
 collect evidence on the spot; and this measure, which was
 vigorously opposed by the Egyptian bishops, opened new
 scenes of violence and perjury.(105)","('Arians', 'PERSON'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP'), ('105', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Christian Revelation, which was 
 consummated under the reign of Nerva, disclosed to the world
 the amazing secret, that the LOGOS, who was with God from
 the beginning, and was God, who had made all things, and for
 whom all things had been made, was incarnate in the person
 of Jesus of Nazareth; who had been born of a virgin, and
 suffered death on the cross.","('The Christian Revelation', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Nerva', 'PERSON'), ('Jesus of Nazareth', 'PERSON')"
"The Consubstantialists, who by
 their success have deserved and obtained the title of
 Catholics, gloried in the simplicity and steadiness of their
 own creed, and insulted the repeated variations of their
 adversaries, who were destitute of any certain rule of
 faith.","('Consubstantialists', 'NORP'), ('Catholics', 'NORP')"
"The Donatists who were taken in arms
 received, and they soon deserved, the same treatment which
 might have been shown to the wild beasts of the desert.","('Donatists', 'NORP')"
"The Eastern
 council, after consuming four days in fierce and unavailing
 debate, separated without any definite conclusion.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('four days', 'DATE')"
"The Gnostics, who were distinguished by the
 epithet of Docetes, deviated into the contrary extreme, and
 betrayed the human, while they asserted the divine nature of
 Christ.","('Gnostics', 'NORP'), ('Docetes', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"The Imperial city of Constantinople was, in 
 some measure, raised at the expense, and was adorned with
 the spoils, of the opulent temples of Greece and Asia; the
 sacred property; was confiscated; the statues of gods and
 heroes were transported, with rude familiarity, among a
 people who considered them as objects, not of adoration, but
 of curiosity; the gold and silver were restored to
 circulation; and the magistrates, the bishops, and the
 eunuchs, improved the fortunate occasion of gratifying, at
 once, their zeal, their avarice, and their resentment.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The Latins had received the 
 rays of divine knowledge through the dark and doubtful
 medium of a translation.","('Latins', 'NORP')"
"The Nicene creed was ratified by Constantine; and his firm
 declaration, that those who resisted the divine judgment of
 the synod must prepare themselves for an immediate exile,
 annihilated the murmurs of a feeble opposition; which, from
 seventeen, was almost instantly reduced to two, protesting
 bishops.","('Nicene', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('seventeen', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Novatian peasants, 
 animated by despair and religious fury, boldly encountered
 the invaders of their country, and, though many of the
 Paphlagonians were slain, the Roman legions were vanquished
 by an irregular multitude, armed only with scythes and axes,
 and, except a few who escaped by an ignominious flight, four
 thousand soldiers were left dead on the field of battle.","('Novatian', 'NORP'), ('Paphlagonians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('four\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Novatians of Constantinople and the adjacent country, by
 their firm attachment to the Homoousian standard, deserved
 to be confounded with the catholics themselves.","('Novatians', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Homoousian', 'NORP')"
"The Pagans of Alexandria, who still formed a
 numerous and discontented party, were easily persuaded to
 desert a bishop whom they feared and esteemed.","('Pagans', 'NORP'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"The Roman pontiff purchased his return by some
 criminal compliances; and afterwards expiated his guilt by a
 seasonable repentance.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Roman pontiff, as long as he maintained his station
 and his principles, was guarded by the warm attachment of a
 great people, and could reject with scorn the prayers, the
 menaces, and the oblations of an heretical prince.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Roman, in
 the presence of his sovereign, asserted the innocence of
 Athanasius, and his own freedom.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"The Sabellian sense,
 which, about fifty years before, had obliged the council of
 Antioch(57) to prohibit this celebrated term, had endeared it 
 to those theologians who entertained a secret but partial
 affection for a nominal Trinity.","('Sabellian', 'NORP'), ('about fifty years before', 'DATE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('57', 'CARDINAL'), ('Trinity', 'ORG')"
"The Son, by whom all
 things were made, (48) had been begotten before all worlds, 
 and the longest of the astronomical periods could be
 compared only as a fleeting moment to the extent of his
 duration; yet this duration was not infinite,(49) and there 
 had been a time which preceded the ineffable generation of
 the logos.","('Son', 'PERSON'), ('48', 'DATE'), ('49', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Spaniard declared himself ready
 to suffer under Constantius, as he had suffered three-score
 years before under his grandfather Maximian.","('Spaniard', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"The abuse of
 Christianity introduced into the Roman government new causes
 of tyranny and sedition; the bands of civil society were
 torn asunder by the fury of religious factions; and the
 obscure citizen, who might calmly have surveyed the
 elevation and fall of successive emperors, imagined and
 experienced that his own life and fortune were connected
 with the interests of a popular ecclesiastic.","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The advantage
 which Cacilian might claim from the priority of his
 ordination was destroyed by the illegal, or at least
 indecent, haste with which it had been performed, without
 expecting the arrival of the bishops of Numidia.","('Cacilian', 'PERSON'), ('Numidia', 'GPE')"
"The advantage of personally negotiating with
 his friends, and of observing and improving the divisions of
 his enemies, might justify, in a prudent statesman, so bold
 and dangerous an enterprise: and Alexandria was connected by
 trade and navigation with every seaport of the
 Mediterranean.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC')"
"The advocates of a system which seemed to 
 establish three independent Deities attempted to preserve
 the unity of the First Cause, so conspicuous in the design
 and order of the world, by the perpetual concord of their
 administration and the essential agreement of their will.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Deities', 'ORG')"
"The archbishop of 
 Alexandria, for whose safety they eagerly devoted their
 lives, was lost among a uniform and well-disciplined
 multitude; and on the nearer approach of danger, he was
 swiftly removed, by their officious hands, from one place of
 concealment to another, till he reached the formidable
 deserts, which the gloomy and credulous temper of
 superstition had peopled with daemons and savage monsters.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The archbishop of Alexandria was capable of
 distinguishing how far he might boldly command, and where he
 must dexterously insinuate; how long he might contend with
 power, and when he must withdraw from persecution; and while
 he directed the thunders of the church against heresy and
 rebellion, he could assume, in the bosom of his own party,
 the flexible and indulgent temper of a prudent leader.","('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"The arms of the Macedonians diffused over Asia and Egypt the
 language and learning of Greece; and the theological system
 of Plato was taught, with less reserve, and perhaps with
 some improvements, in the celebrated school of Alexandria.
 (13)","('Macedonians', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('13', 'CARDINAL')"
"The attention of the prince and people was attracted by this
 theological dispute; and the decision, at the end of six
 years,(46) was referred to the supreme authority of the  general council of Nice.","('the end of six\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('46', 'DATE'), ('the  general council of Nice', 'ORG')"
"The authority of a general council, to which the Arians
 themselves had been compelled to submit, inscribed on the
 banners of the orthodox party the mysterious characters of
 the word Homoousion, which essentially contributed,
 notwithstanding some obscure disputes, some nocturnal
 combats, to maintain and perpetuate the uniformity of faith,
 or at least of language.","('Arians', 'NORP')"
"The bishop
 of the diocese usually assisted at these interviews; the
 master of the offices stood before the veil or curtain of
 the sacred apartment; and the uniform moderation of the
 primate might be attested by these respectable witnesses, to
 whose evidence he solemnly appeals. (116)","('116', 'CARDINAL')"
"The bishop of Poitiers, who in his
 Phrygian exile very wisely aimed at a coalition of parties,
 endeavours to prove that, by a pious and faithful
 interpretation,(71) the Homoiousion may be reduced to a consubstantial sense.","('Poitiers', 'GPE'), ('Phrygian', 'GPE'), ('71', 'CARDINAL')"
"The bishops of the East were directed to meet at
 Seleucia, in Isauria; while those of the West held their
 deliberations at Rimini, on the coast of the Hadriatic, and
 instead of two or three deputies from each province, the
 whole episcopal body was ordered to march.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Seleucia', 'GPE'), ('Isauria', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Rimini', 'GPE'), ('Hadriatic', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"The bishops of the contending factions 
 maintained, with equal ardour and obstinacy, that their
 adversaries were degraded, or at least dishonoured, by the
 odious crime of delivering the Holy Scriptures to the
 officers of Diocletian.","('the Holy Scriptures', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The capital of the East had never been polluted by
 the worship of idols, and the whole body of the people had
 deeply imbibed the opinions, the virtues, and the passions
 which distinguished the Christians of that age from the rest
 of mankind.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"The catholics
 rose in the defence of their bishop; the palace of
 Hermogenes was consumed; the first military officer of the
 empire was dragged by the heels through the streets of
 Constantinople, and, after he expired, his lifeless corpse
 was exposed to their wanton insults. (152)","('Hermogenes', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('152', 'CARDINAL')"
"The cause of truth and justice was promoted by the
 influence of gold,(114) and the ministers of Constans advised 
 their sovereign to require the convocation of an
 ecclesiastical assembly, which might act as the
 representatives of the Catholic church.","('Constans', 'NORP'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"The civil
 war between the assassin and the only surviving brother of
 Constans, which afflicted the empire above three years,
 secured an interval of repose to the Catholic church; and
 the two contending parties were desirous to conciliate the
 friendship of a bishop who, by the weight of his personal
 authority, might determine the fluctuating resolutions of an
 important province.","('Constans', 'PERSON'), ('three years', 'DATE'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The civil powers of Egypt found themselves
 inadequate to the task of persuading or compelling the
 primate to abdicate his episcopal throne; and they were
 obliged to conclude a treaty with the popular leaders of
 Alexandria, by which it was stipulated that all proceedings
 and all hostilities should be suspended till the emperor's
 pleasure had been more distinctly ascertained.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"The commission of
 enforcing a sentence of banishment against Paul had been
 intrusted to Hermogenes, the master-general of the cavalry,
 but the execution of it was fatal to himself.","('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Hermogenes', 'PERSON')"
"The complaints and mutual accusations which assailed the
 throne of Constantine, as soon as the death of Maxentius had
 submitted Africa to his victorious arms, were ill adapted to
 edify an imperfect proselyte.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"The consubstantiality of the Father and the Son was established
 by the council of Nice, and has been unanimously received as
 a fundamental article of the Christian faith by the consent
 of the Greek, the Latin, the Oriental, and the Protestant
 churches.","('the Father and the Son', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Nice', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('Protestant', 'NORP')"
"The council of Rimini was not
 allowed to separate till the members had imprudently
 subscribed a captious creed, in which some expressions,
 susceptible of an heretical sense, were inserted in the room
 of the Homoousion.","('Rimini', 'GPE'), ('Homoousion', 'PRODUCT')"
"The council of Sardica reveals the first symptoms 
 of discord and schism between the Greek and Latin churches,
 which were separated by the accidental difference of faith
 and the permanent distinction of language.","('Sardica', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"The cruel and arbitrary disposition of Constantius, which
 did not always require the provocations of guilt and
 resistance, was justly exasperated by the tumults of his
 capital and the criminal behaviour of a faction which
 opposed the authority and religion of their sovereign","('Constantius', 'GPE')"
"The darkness and tumult of the night
 favoured the retreat of the archbishop; and though he was
 oppressed by the waves of an agitated multitude, though he
 was thrown to the ground, and left without sense or motion,
 he still recovered his undaunted courage, and eluded the
 eager search of the soldiers, who were instructed by their
 Arian guides that the head of Athanasius would be the most
 acceptable present to the emperor.","('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON')"
"The death of that prince exposed Athanasius to a second
 persecution; and the feeble Constantius, the sovereign of
 the East, soon became the secret accomplice of the
 Eusebians.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Eusebians', 'NORP')"
"The decree, expressed in the
 fiercest language of malice and revenge, was communicated to
 the emperor and the Catholic church; and the bishops
 immediately resumed a mild and devout aspect, such as became
 their holy pilgrimage to the Sepulchre of Christ.(106)","('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('106', 'CARDINAL')"
"The deputies of the East and of the West attended
 the emperor in the palace of Constantinople, and he enjoyed
 the satisfaction of imposing on the world a profession of
 faith which established the likeness, without expressing the
 consubstantiality, of the Son of God.(95)","('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('the Son of God', 'PERSON'), ('95', 'CARDINAL')"
"The design of establishing an uniformity of
 doctrine, which had engaged him to convene so many synods in
 Gaul, Italy, Illyricum, and Asia, was repeatedly baffled by
 his own levity, by the divisions of the Arians, and by the
 resistance of the catholics; and he resolved, as the last
 and decisive effort, imperiously to dictate the decrees of a
 general council.","('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Illyricum', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Arians', 'NORP')"
"The despotic power of his implacable enemy filled the whole
 extent of the Roman world and the exasperated monarch had
 endeavoured, by a very pressing epistle to the Christian
 princes of Ethiopia, to exclude Athanasius from the most
 remote and sequestered regions of the earth.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Ethiopia', 'GPE'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('earth', 'LOC')"
"The destructive earthquake of Nicomedia,
 the difficulty of finding a convenient place, and perhaps
 some secret motives of policy, produced an alteration in the
 summons.","('Nicomedia', 'GPE')"
"The devotion of individuals was the first circumstance
 which distinguished the Christians from the Platonists: the
 second was the authority of the church.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Platonists', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"The disgrace and exile of the orthodox bishops of the West
 were designed as so many preparatory steps to the ruin of
 Athanasius himself.(133) Six-and-twenty months had elapsed, 
 during which the Imperial court secretly laboured, by the
 most insidious arts, to remove him from Alexandria, and to
 withdraw the allowance which supplied his popular
 liberality.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('133', 'CARDINAL'), ('Six-and-twenty months', 'DATE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"The divine sanction which the Apostle had bestowed on the
 fundamental principle of the theology of Plato encouraged
 the learned proselytes of the second and third centuries to
 admire and study the writings of the Athenian sage, who had
 thus marvellously anticipated one of the most surprising
 discoveries of the Christian revelation.","('Apostle', 'PERSON'), ('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Athenian', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
The divisions of Christianity suspended the ruin of Paganism; (173) and the holy war against the infidels was less vigorously prosecuted by princes and bishops who were more immediately alarmed by the guilt and danger of domestic rebellion.,"('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Paganism', 'NORP'), ('173', 'CARDINAL')"
"The doors of the sacred edifice
 yielded to the impetuosity of the attack, which was
 accompanied with every horrid circumstance of tumult and
 bloodshed; but, as the bodies of the slain, and the
 fragments of military weapons, remained the next day an
 unexceptionable evidence in the possession of the catholics,
 the enterprise of Syrianus may be considered as a successful
 irruption rather than as an absolute conquest.","('the next day', 'DATE'), ('Syrianus', 'GPE')"
"The eager vehemence which animated the spectators on the decisive moment of a horserace was now directed towards a different object, and the Circus resounded with the shout of thousands, who repeatedly exclaimed ""One God, One Christ, One Bishop!""","('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('One', 'CARDINAL')"
"The edict of Milan, the great charter of toleration, had confirmed to each individual of the Roman world the privilege of choosing and professing his own religion.","('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The eloquence of Plato, the name of Solomon, the authority
 of the school of Alexandria, and the consent of the Jews and
 Greeks, were insufficient to establish the truth of a
 mysterious doctrine, which might please, but could not
 satisfy, a rational mind.","('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('Solomon', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"The eminent station of Liberius, who governed
 the capital of the empire; the personal merit and long
 experience of the venerable Osius, who was revered as the
 favourite of the great Constantine, and the father of the
 Nicene faith, placed those prelates at the head of the Latin
 church: and their example, either of submission or
 resistance, would probably be imitated by the episcopal
 crowds.","('Liberius', 'GPE'), ('Osius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Nicene', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"The emperor
 declared his resolution of employing the troops and
 treasures of Europe in the orthodox cause; and signified, by
 a concise and peremptory epistle to his brother Constantius,
 that, unless he consented to the immediate restoration of
 Athanasius, he himself, with a fleet and army, would seat
 the archbishop on the throne of Alexandria.(117)","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('117', 'CARDINAL')"
"The emperor 
 was satisfied that the peace of Egypt would be secured by
 the absence of a popular leader but he refused to fill the
 vacancy of the archiepiscopal throne; and the sentence
 which, after long hesitation, he pronounced, was that of a
 jealous ostracism rather than of an ignominious exile.","('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"The emperor had now imbibed the spirit of
 controversy, and the angry sarcastic style of his edicts was
 designed to inspire his subjects with the hatred which he
 had conceived against the enemies of Christ.(82)
and the orthodox party, A.D. 328-337","('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 328-337', 'DATE')"
"The emperor received with politeness these
 female deputies, whose wealth and dignity were displayed in
 the magnificence of their dress and ornaments; he admired
 their inflexible resolution of following their beloved
 pastor to the most distant regions of the earth, and
 consented that the two bishops, Liberius and Felix, should
 govern in peace their respective congregations.","('earth', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Liberius', 'PERSON'), ('Felix', 'PERSON')"
"The emperor was soon convinced that he had too hastily proscribed the orthodox faith and the exemplary morals of the Novatians, who had dissented from the church in some articles of discipline which were not perhaps essential to salvation.","('Novatians', 'NORP')"
"The entrance of the archbishop into
 his capital was a triumphal procession; absence and
 persecution had endeared him to the Alexandrians; his
 authority, which he exercised with rigour, was more firmly
 established; and his fame was diffused from Ethiopia to
 Britain, over the whole extent of the Christian world(119)
Resentment of Constantius, A.D. 351","('Alexandrians', 'NORP'), ('Ethiopia', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('119', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'GPE'), ('351', 'CARDINAL')"
"The eunuchs, the women, and the bishops, who governed the
