Sentence,Entities
"""Remember that Maurice is still alive,""  resounded from the opposite side; and the indiscreet clamour of the blues admonished and stimulated the cruelty of the tyrant.","('Maurice', 'PERSON')"
"""Wilt thou govern better?"" were the last words of the
 despair of Phocas.","('Wilt', 'PERSON'), ('Phocas', 'PERSON')"
(54),"('54', 'CARDINAL')"
(55),"('55', 'CARDINAL')"
(75),"('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 general pardon might have diffused comfort and tranquillity
 through a country which had been shaken by the late
 revolutions; yet, before the sanguinary temper of Chosroes
 is blamed, we should learn whether the Persians had not been
 accustomed either to dread the rigour, or to despise the
 weakness, of their sovereign.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"A Scythian chief, who commanded their right
 wing, suddenly turned the flank of the enemy, attacked their
 rear-guard in the presence of Chosroes, penetrated to the
 midst of the camp, pillaged the royal tent, profaned the
 eternal fire, loaded a train of camels with the spoils of
 Asia, cut his way through the Persian host, and returned
 with songs of victory to his friends, who had consumed the
 day in single combats, or ineffectual skirmishes.","('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Chosroes', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('the\r\n day', 'DATE')"
"A band of a thousand Romans, who continued to
 guard the person of Chosroes, proclaimed his confidence in
 the fidelity of the strangers; his growing strength enabled
 him to dismiss this unpopular aid, but he steadily professed
 the same gratitude and reverence to his adopted father; and
 till the death of Maurice, the peace and alliance of the two
 empires were faithfully maintained.","('a thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"A daughter of Phocas, his only child, was given in marriage
 to the patrician Crispus, (52) and the royal images of the bride and bridegroom were indiscreetly placed in the circus,
 by the side of the emperor.","('Phocas', 'PERSON'), ('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('52', 'DATE')"
"A faint rumour of their
 undertaking was conveyed to the ears of Phocas, and the wife
 and mother of the younger Heraclius were secured as the
 hostages of his faith: but the treacherous heart of Crispus
 extenuated the distant peril, the means of defence were
 neglected or delayed, and the tyrant supinely slept till the
 African navy cast anchor in the Hellespont.","('Phocas', 'PERSON'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('African', 'NORP'), ('Hellespont', 'PRODUCT')"
"A fanatic monk ran
 through the streets with a drawn sword, denouncing against
 him the wrath and the sentence of God; and a vile plebeian,
 who represented his countenance and apparel, was seated on
 an ass, and pursued by the imprecations of the multitude.
 (43)","('43', 'CARDINAL')"
"A matron who commanded the respect and pity
 of mankind, the daughter, wife, and mother of emperors, was
 tortured like the vilest malefactor, to force a confession
 of her designs and associates; and the empress Constantina,
 with her three innocent daughters, was beheaded at
 Chalcedon, on the same ground which had been stained with
 the blood of her husband and five sons.","('Constantina', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('five', 'CARDINAL')"
"A messenger was
 intercepted with a real or fictitious mandate to the
 cadarigan, or second in command, directing him to send,
 without delay, to the throne, the head of a guilty or
 unfortunate general.","('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"A modest wish of
 resigning the purple to the rank and merit of Germanus was
 opposed by his resolution, more obstinate and equally
 sincere; the senate and clergy obeyed his summons; and, as
 soon as the patriarch was assured of his orthodox belief, he
 consecrated the successful usurper in the church of St. John
 the Baptist.","('Germanus', 'PERSON'), ('St. John\r\n the Baptist', 'PERSON')"
"A pious hope was indulged,
 that the church as well as the state might triumph in this
 revolution: but if Chosroes had sincerely listened to the
 Christian bishops, the impression was erased by the zeal and
 eloquence of the Magi: if he was armed with philosophic
 indifference, he accommodated his belief, or rather his
 professions, to the various circumstances of an exile and a
 sovereign.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Magi', 'PERSON')"
"A prince of a
 less malignant temper could not easily have forgiven his
 benefactor; and the secret hatred of Hormouz was envenomed
 by a malicious report, that Bahram had privately retained
 the most precious fruits of his Turkish victory.","('Hormouz', 'PERSON'), ('Bahram', 'PERSON'), ('Turkish', 'NORP')"
"A prince who could promote and
 support this unworthy favorite must derive no glory from the
 accidental merit of his colleague Priscus. (38)","('Priscus', 'PERSON')"
"A purer spirit of religion was shown in the
 relief and deliverance of fifty thousand captives.","('fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"A second
 messenger, who had been commanded to bring the rebel in
 chains, was trampled under the feet of an elephant, and
 manifestos were diligently circulated, His rebellion.","('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"About the third watch of the night, the Roman
 praefect was informed of his approach, and he introduced the
 royal stranger to the fortress at the dawn of day.","('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('the night', 'TIME'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"According to the faith and mercy of his Christian enemies,
 he sunk without hope into a still deeper abyss; (107) and it
 will not be denied, that tyrants of every age and sect are
 the best entitled to such infernal abodes.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('107', 'CARDINAL')"
"According to the friendly and
 equal forms of the Byzantine and Persian courts, he
 announced his exaltation to the throne; and his ambassador
 Lilius, who had presented him with the heads of Maurice and
 his sons, was the best qualified to describe the
 circumstances of the tragic scene.","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Lilius', 'PERSON'), ('Maurice', 'PERSON')"
"After a bloody
 conflict, which continued till the evening, the Romans
 prevailed in the assault; and a Persian of gigantic size was
 slain and thrown into the Sarus by the hand of the emperor
 himself.","('the evening', 'TIME'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Sarus', 'NORP')"
"After a long and pernicious
indulgence, the cure of this inveterate evil was undertaken by Maurice; but the rash attempt, which
drew destruction on his own head, tended only to aggravate the disease.","('Maurice', 'PERSON')"
"After a long impatience,
 the senate, the clergy, and the people, went forth to meet
 their hero, with tears and acclamations, with olive branches
 and innumerable lamps; he entered the capital in a chariot
 drawn by four elephants; and as soon as the emperor could
 disengage himself from the tumult of public joy, he tasted
 more genuine satisfaction in the embraces of his mother and
 his son. (110)","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('110', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a long series of legal succession, the military disorders of the third century were again revived; yet such was the novelty of the enterprise, that the insurgents were awed by their own
rashness.","('the third century', 'DATE')"
"After a sumptuous
 banquet, he presented Ziebel with the plate and ornaments,
 the gold, the gems, and the silk, which had been used at the
 Imperial table, and, with his own hand, distributed rich
 jewels and ear-rings to his new allies.","('Ziebel', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"After his revolt, Varanes or Bahram is stigmatized by the
 son of Hormouz as an ungrateful slave; the proud and
 ambiguous reproach of despotism, since he was truly
 descended from the ancient princes of Rei, (10) one of the
 seven families whose splendid, as well as substantial,
 prerogatives exalted them above the heads of the Persian
 nobility.","('Varanes', 'PERSON'), ('Bahram', 'PERSON'), ('Hormouz', 'PERSON'), ('Rei', 'PERSON'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"After the abdication of Maurice, the two factions
 disputed the choice of an emperor; but the favourite of the
 blues was rejected by the jealousy of their antagonists, and
 Germanus himself was hurried along by the crowds who rushed
 to the palace of Hebdomon, seven miles from the city, to
 adore the majesty of Phocas the centurion.","('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germanus', 'PERSON'), ('Hebdomon', 'GPE'), ('seven miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Phocas', 'GPE')"
"After the defeat of Abrahah under the walls of Mecca, the discord of his sons and brothers gave an easy entrance to the Persians: they chased the strangers of Abyssinia beyond the Red Sea; and a native prince of the ancient
 Homerites was restored to the throne as the vassal or viceroy of the great Nushirvan. (4)","('Abrahah', 'PERSON'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Abyssinia', 'GPE'), ('the Red Sea', 'LOC'), ('Homerites', 'NORP'), ('Nushirvan', 'NORP'), ('4', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the division of his army, Heraclius prudently retired
 to the banks of the Phasis, from whence he maintained a
 defensive war against the fifty thousand gold spears of
 Persia.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Phasis', 'PRODUCT'), ('fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"After the junction of the Imperial troops, which
 Bahram vainly struggled to prevent, the contest was decided
 by two battles on the banks of the Zab, and the confines of
 Media. and final victory.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Bahram', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Zab', 'ORG')"
"After the loss of Egypt,
 the capital was afflicted by famine and pestilence; and the
 emperor, incapable of resistance, and hopeless of relief,
 had resolved to transfer his person and government to the
 more secure residence of Carthage.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"After the reduction of Galilee, and
 the region beyond the Jordan, whose resistance appears to
 have delayed the fate of the capital, Jerusalem itself was
 taken by assault.","('Galilee', 'GPE'), ('Jordan', 'GPE'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE')"
"After this
 unsuccessful campaign, the want of magazines, and perhaps
 some inroad of the Turks, obliged him to disband or divide
 his forces; the Romans were left masters of the field, and
 their general Justinian, advancing to the relief of the
 Persarmenian rebels, erected his standard on the banks of
 the Araxes.","('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Persarmenian', 'NORP'), ('Araxes', 'ORG')"
"After this barbarous imprecation, he calmly inquired, what oath was
 most sacred and venerable among the Christians, what guilt
 or perjury it was most dangerous to incur.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Alarmed by the
 hasty intrusion and bold reproaches of the captive, Hormouz
 looked round, but in vain, for advice or assistance;
 discovered that his strength consisted in the obedience of
 others; and patiently yielded to the single arm of Bindoes,
 who dragged him from the throne to the same dungeon in which
 he himself had been so lately confined.","('Hormouz', 'PERSON'), ('Bindoes', 'PERSON')"
"Alarmed by the danger of
 his kingdom, the powers of Chosroes were already recalled
 from the Nile and the Bosphorus, and three formidable armies
 surrounded, in a distant and hostile land, the camp of the
 emperor.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"Alexandria might have been relieved by a naval
 force, but the archbishop and the praefect embarked for
 Cyprus; and Chosroes entered the second city of the empire,
 which still preserved a wealthy remnant of industry and
 commerce.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Cyprus', 'GPE'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
Alliances and conquests of Heraclius.,"('Heraclius', 'GPE')"
"Amidst the glories of the succeeding campaign, Heraclius is
 almost lost to our eyes, and to those of the Byzantine
 historians. (91)","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('91', 'CARDINAL')"
"Among the victims of
 his cruelty, Bindoes, a Sassanian prince, had been cast into
 a dungeon; his fetters were broken by the zeal and courage
 of a brother; and he stood before the king at the head of
 those trusty guards, who had been chosen as the ministers of
 his confinement, and perhaps of his death.","('Bindoes', 'PERSON'), ('Sassanian', 'NORP')"
"An experience of
 seven hundred years might convince the rival nations of the
 impossibility of maintaining their conquests beyond the
 fatal limits of the Tigris and Euphrates.","('seven hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"Anchialus was the last term of
 his progress by sea and land; he solicited, without success,
 a miraculous answer to his nocturnal prayers; his mind was
 confounded by the death of a favorite horse, the encounter
 of a wild boar, a storm of wind and rain, and the birth of a
 monstrous child; and he forgot that the best of omens is to
 unsheathe our sword in the defence of our country.","('Anchialus', 'PERSON')"
"As
 soon as Modain was freed from the presence of the usurper,
 the loyal inhabitants obeyed the first summons of Mebodes at
 the head of only two thousand horse, and Chosroes accepted
 the sacred and precious ornaments of the palace as the
 pledge of their truth and the presage of his approaching
 success.","('Modain', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Mebodes', 'PERSON'), ('only two thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Chosroes', 'NORP')"
"As a subject and a Christian, it was the duty of Gregory to
 acquiesce in the established government; but the joyful
 applause with which he salutes the fortune of the assassin,
 has sullied, with indelible disgrace, the character of the
 saint.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON')"
"As imprudent would it have been to advance into the
 provinces of Asia, leaving their innumerable cavalry to
 intercept his convoys, and continually to hang on the
 lassitude and disorder of his rear.","('Asia', 'LOC')"
"As soon as the mountains became passable, the emperor
 received the welcome news of the success of the conspiracy,
 the death of Chosroes, and the elevation of his eldest son
 to the throne of Persia.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"As the excuse of
 his cruelty, he sometimes condescended to observe, that the
 fears of the Persians would be productive of hatred, and
 that their hatred must terminate in rebellion but he forgot
 that his own guilt and folly had inspired the sentiments
 which he deplored, and prepared the event which he so justly
 apprehended.","('Persians', 'NORP')"
"As the passes were faithfully guarded, Hormouz could only
 compute the number of his enemies by the testimony of a
 guilty conscience, and the daily defection of those who, in
 the hour of his distress, avenged their wrongs, or forgot
 their obligations.","('Hormouz', 'PERSON'), ('the hour', 'TIME')"
"As the successor of the
 Lombards, the chagan asserted his claim to the important
 city of Sirmium, the ancient bulwark of the Illyrian
 provinces. (27)","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Sirmium', 'GPE'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP'), ('27', 'CARDINAL')"
"At his
 command, one of the largest elephants of the Imperial
 stables was equipped with stately caparisons, and conducted
 by a numerous train to the royal village in the plains of
 Hungary.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'FAC'), ('Hungary', 'GPE')"
"At his command, the army of Dastagerd
 retreated to a new camp: the front was covered by the Arba,
 and a line of two hundred elephants; the troops of the more
 distant provinces successively arrived, and the vilest
 domestics of the king and satraps were enrolled for the last
 defence of the throne.","('Dastagerd', 'GPE'), ('Arba', 'PRODUCT'), ('two hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"At his liberal invitation,
 the horde of Chozars (98) transported their tents from the
 plains of the Volga to the mountains of Georgia; Heraclius
 received them in the neighbourhood of Teflis, and the khan
 with his nobles dismounted from their horses, if we may
 credit the Greeks, and fell prostrate on the ground, to
 adore the purple of the Caesars.","('Chozars', 'PERSON'), ('98', 'DATE'), ('Volga', 'LOC'), ('Georgia', 'GPE'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Teflis', 'LOC'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Caesars', 'ORG')"
At the age of fourscore the sovereign of the East would perhaps have chosen the peaceful enjoyment of his glory and greatness;,"('East', 'LOC')"
"At the dead of night, she escaped to the
 sanctuary of St. Sophia; but her tears, and the gold of her
 associate Germanus, were insufficient to provoke an
 insurrection.","('St. Sophia', 'GPE'), ('Germanus', 'PERSON')"
"At the first
 tumult, Chosroes, the eldest of the sons of Hormouz, escaped
 from the city; he was persuaded to return by the pressing
 and friendly invitation of Bindoes, who promised to seat him
 on his father's throne, and who expected to reign under the
 name of an inexperienced youth.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Hormouz', 'PERSON'), ('Bindoes', 'PERSON')"
"At the head of
 forty thousand men, Chosroes himself had returned from some
 distant expedition to oppose the progress of the Roman arms;
 but he retreated on the approach of Heraclius, declining the
 generous alternative of peace or of battle.","('forty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON')"
"At the same time, the eastern provinces of Persia were
 invaded by the great khan, who passed the Oxus at the head
 of three or four hundred thousand Turks.","('Persia', 'LOC'), ('Oxus', 'PERSON'), ('three or four hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Turks', 'NORP')"
"At the siege of Dara, the valour of Bahram was
 signalized under the eyes of Nushirvan, and both the father
 and son successively promoted him to the command of armies,
 the government of Media, and the superintendence of the
 palace.","('Dara', 'PERSON'), ('Bahram', 'GPE'), ('Nushirvan', 'PERSON'), ('the government of Media', 'ORG')"
"At the time when this prediction is said to have been
 delivered, no prophecy could be more distant from its
 accomplishment, since the first twelve years of Heraclius
 announced the approaching dissolution of the empire.","('the first twelve years', 'DATE'), ('Heraclius', 'ORG')"
"At this distance we can
 only conjecture, that he was endowed with more personal
 courage than political resolution; that he was detained by
 the charms, and perhaps the arts, of his niece Martina, with
 whom, after the death of Eudocia, he contracted an
 incestuous marriage; (73) and that he yielded to the base
 advice of the counsellors, who urged, as a fundamental law,
 that the life of the emperor should never be exposed in the
 field.","('Martina', 'PERSON'), ('Eudocia', 'PERSON'), ('73', 'DATE')"
"Attended only by his concubines, and a
 troop of thirty guards, he secretly departed from the
 capital, followed the banks of the Euphrates, traversed the
 desert, and halted at the distance of ten miles from
 Circesium.","('thirty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('ten miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Circesium', 'GPE')"
"Before the emperor presumed to
 tread the consecrated ground, he was instructed to strip
 himself of the diadem and purple, the pomp and vanity of the
 world: but in the judgment of his clergy, the persecution of
 the Jews was more easily reconciled with the precepts of the
 gospel.","('Jews', 'NORP')"
"Both his friends and enemies were persuaded, that it was the
 intention of Chosroes to bury himself under the ruins of the
 city and palace: and as both might have been equally adverse
 to his flight, the monarch of Asia, with Sira,  and three
 concubines, escaped through a hole in the wall nine days
 before the arrival of the Romans.","('Chosroes', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Sira', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('nine days', 'DATE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"But
 these operations are neglected by the Byzantine historians,
 and, like the authors of epic poetry and romance, they
 ascribe the victory, not to the military conduct, but to the
 personal valour, of their favorite hero.","('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"But Egypt itself, the only
 province which had been exempt, since the time of
 Diocletian, from foreign and domestic war, was again subdued
 by the successors of Cyrus.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Cyrus', 'PERSON')"
"But as the strong
 garrison of Singidunum, which commanded the conflux of the
 two rivers, might have stopped their passage and baffled his
 designs, he dispelled their apprehensions by a solemn oath
 that his views were not hostile to the empire.","('Singidunum', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"But his
 sacred ambassadors enjoyed and abused an unbounded license
 in the midst of Constantinople: they urged, with importunate
 clamors, the increase of tribute, or the restitution of
 captives and deserters: and the majesty of the empire was
 almost equally degraded by a base compliance, or by the
 false and fearful excuses with which they eluded such
 insolent demands.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"But in the first attempts they were rudely framed, and awkwardly managed; and the resistance of Diocletianopolis and Beraea, of Philippopolis and Adrianople, soon exhausted the skill and patience of the besiegers.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Diocletianopolis', 'NORP'), ('Beraea', 'PERSON'), ('Philippopolis', 'GPE'), ('Adrianople', 'GPE')"
"But in the space of twenty-four
 years, he was deterred by superstition or resentment from
 approaching the gates of Ctesiphon: and his favorite
 residence of Artemita, or Dastagerd, was situate beyond the
 Tigris, about sixty miles to the north of the capital.","('twenty-four\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Ctesiphon', 'PERSON'), ('Artemita', 'GPE'), ('Dastagerd', 'GPE'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('about sixty miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"But it has always been the pride and policy of Oriental
 princes to display the titles and attributes of their
 omnipotence; to upbraid a nation of slaves with their true
 name and abject condition, and to enforce, by cruel and
 insolent threats, the rigour of their absolute commands.","('Oriental', 'NORP')"
"But the
 approach of a Roman army on the side of the Araxes compelled
 the implacable tyrant to smile and to applaud; and the toils
 of Bahram were rewarded with the permission of encountering
 a new enemy, by their skill and discipline more formidable
 than a Scythian multitude.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Araxes', 'NORP'), ('Bahram', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'NORP')"
"But the
 long experience of war had hardened the minds and bodies of
 that effeminate people; their zeal and bravery were approved
 in the service of a declining empire; they abhorred and
 feared the usurpation of the house of Sassan, and the memory
 of persecution envenomed their pious hatred of the enemies
 of Christ.","('Sassan', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"But the Greeks were
 still masters of the sea; a fleet of galleys, transports,
 and store-ships, was assembled in the harbour; the Barbarians
 consented to embark; a steady wind carried them through the
 Hellespont the western and southern coast of Asia Minor lay
 on their left hand; the spirit of their chief was first
 displayed in a storm, and even the eunuchs of his train were
 excited to suffer and to work by the example of their
 master.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Hellespont', 'GPE'), ('Asia Minor', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But the glory of Maurice was conspicuous in the long and fortunate reign of his son and
 his ally.","('Maurice', 'PERSON')"
"But the languid mists of the morning and evening are
 separated by the brightness of the meridian sun; the
 Arcadius of the palace arose the Caesar of the camp; and the
 honour of Rome and Heraclius was gloriously retrieved by the
 exploits and trophies of six adventurous campaigns.","('evening', 'TIME'), ('Arcadius', 'LOC'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('six', 'CARDINAL')"
But the lieutenant of Chosroes had fatally mistaken the intentions of his master.,"('Chosroes', 'PERSON')"
"But the loss
 of his subjects, and the danger of his kingdom, were
 overbalanced in the mind of Hormouz by the disgrace of his
 personal enemy; and no sooner had Bahram collected and
 reviewed his forces, than he received from a royal messenger
 the insulting gift of a distaff, a spinning-wheel, and a
 complete suit of female apparel.","('Hormouz', 'PERSON'), ('Bahram', 'PERSON')"
"But the nephew of Justinian declared his resolution to avenge the injuries of his Christian ally the prince of Abyssinia, as they suggested a decent pretence to discontinue the annual tribute, which was poorly disguised by the name of pension.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Abyssinia', 'GPE'), ('annual', 'DATE')"
"But the new monarch was saluted with unanimous acclamations;
 the flight of Chosroes (yet where could he have fled?) was
 rudely arrested, eighteen sons were massacred  before his
 face, and he was thrown into a dungeon, where he expired on
 the fifth day.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('eighteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('the fifth day', 'DATE')"
"But the pride of the Persian had not yet
 sunk to the level of his fortune; he derived a momentary
 confidence from the retreat of the emperor; he wept with
 impotent rage over the ruins of his Assyrian palaces, and
 disregarded too long the rising murmurs of the nation, who
 complained that their lives and fortunes were sacrificed to
 the obstinacy of an old man.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Assyrian', 'NORP')"
"But the provinces, which had been
 fashioned by the habits of six hundred years to the virtues
 and vices of the Roman government, supported with reluctance
 the yoke of the Barbarians.","('six hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"But the revenge and ambition
 of Chosroes exhausted his kingdom; and the new levies of
 subjects, strangers, and slaves, were divided into three
 formidable bodies.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the revenue no
 longer flowed in the usual channels; the credit of an
 arbitrary prince is annihilated by his power; and the
 courage of Heraclius was first displayed in daring to borrow
 the consecrated wealth of churches, under the solemn vow of
 restoring, with usury, whatever he had been compelled to
 employ in the service of religion and the empire.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But the review of his loss, and the consciousness
 of his danger, determined Chosroes to a speedy retreat: he
 burnt, in his passage, the vacant town of Melitene; and,
 without consulting the safety of his troops, boldly swam the
 Euphrates on the back of an elephant.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Melitene', 'GPE'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"But the senate and
 people were animated by the spirit of Heraclius, who had
 detached to their relief a body of twelve thousand
 cuirassiers; the powers of fire and mechanics were used with
 superior art and success in the defence of Constantinople;
 and the galleys, with two and three ranks of oars, commanded
 the Bosphorus, and rendered the Persians the idle spectators
 of the defeat of their allies.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('twelve thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"But the spirit of the empress Constantina, still mindful of
 her father, her husband, and her sons, aspired to freedom
 and revenge.","('Constantina', 'PERSON')"
"But the will of Chosroes was no longer
 revered, and Siroes,  who gloried in the rank and merit of
 his mother Sira, had conspired with the malecontents to
 assert and anticipate the rights of primogeniture. (106)","('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Siroes', 'PERSON'), ('Sira', 'PERSON'), ('106', 'CARDINAL')"
"But their new subjects were soon disgusted
 with the vices or virtues which they had imbibed in a
 foreign land; the instability of their dominion gave birth
 to a vulgar observation, that the choice of Rome was
 solicited and rejected with equal ardor by the capricious
 levity of Oriental slaves. (18)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('18', 'CARDINAL')"
"But these losses, which astonished the provinces and the court, produced a salutary effect in the repentance and abdication of the emperor Justin: a new spirit arose in the Byzantine councils; and a truce of three years was obtained by the prudence of Tiberius.","('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('three years', 'DATE'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON')"
"By
 these implacable enemies, Heraclius, on either side, was
 insulted and besieged: and the Roman empire was reduced to
 the walls of Constantinople, with the remnant of Greece,
 Italy, and Africa, and some maritime cities, from Tyre to
 Trebizond, of the Asiatic coast.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Tyre', 'GPE'), ('Trebizond', 'GPE'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP')"
"By a false motion, which
 seemed to threaten Armenia, he drew them, against their
 wishes, to a general action.","('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"By a just gradation of magnificent scenes, they
 penetrated to the royal seat of Dastagerd,  and, though
 much of the treasure had been removed, and much had been
 expended, the remaining wealth appears to have exceeded
 their hopes, and even to have satiated their avarice.","('Dastagerd', 'GPE')"
"By the departure of the Lombards, and the ruin of the
 Gepidae, the balance of power was destroyed on the Danube;
 and the Avars spread their permanent dominion from the foot
 of the Alps to the sea-coast of the Euxine.","('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('Gepidae', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Avars', 'NORP'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Euxine', 'PRODUCT')"
"By the fatal vicissitude of human affairs, the
 same scenes were renewed at Ctesiphon, which had been
 exhibited at Rome after the death of Marcus Antoninus.","('Ctesiphon', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Marcus Antoninus', 'PERSON')"
"By the oppressive laws
 of Justinian, the adversaries of the church were made the
 enemies of the state; the alliance of the Jews, Nestorians,
 and Jacobites, had contributed to the success of Chosroes,
 and his partial favour to the sectaries provoked the hatred
 and fears of the Catholic clergy.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Nestorians', 'NORP'), ('Jacobites', 'NORP'), ('Chosroes', 'NORP'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"By the secret
 emissaries of Crispus and the senate, the independent exarch
 was solicited to save and to govern his country; but his
 ambition was chilled by age, and he resigned the dangerous
 enterprise to his son Heraclius, and to Nicetas, the son of
 Gregory, his friend and lieutenant.","('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Nicetas', 'PERSON'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON')"
Chosroes flies to the Romans.,"('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Chosroes had ascended the throne without guilt, and
 his piety strove to alleviate the misery of the abdicated
 monarch; from the dungeon he removed Hormouz to an apartment
 of the palace, supplied with liberality the consolations of
 sensual enjoyment, and patiently endured the furious sallies
 of his resentment and despair.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Hormouz', 'PERSON')"
"Chosroes invades the Roman empire, A.D. 603, etc.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 603', 'DATE')"
"Chosroes led
 into the field the slaves of the palace and the populace of
 the capital: they beheld with terror the banners of a
 veteran army; they were encompassed and surprised by the
 evolutions of the general; and the satraps who had deposed
 Hormouz, received the punishment of their revolt, or
 expiated their first treason by a second and more criminal
 act of disloyalty.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Hormouz', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"Cilicia was
 soon encompassed with the Persian arms; but their cavalry
 hesitated to enter the defiles of Mount Taurus, till they
 were circumvented by the evolutions of Heraclius, who
 insensibly gained their rear, whilst he appeared to present
 his front in order of battle.","('Cilicia', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Mount Taurus', 'LOC'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON')"
"Conquest of Yemen by Nushirvan, A.D. 570, etc","('Yemen', 'GPE'), ('Nushirvan', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 570', 'DATE')"
"Conscious of their fear
 and hatred, the Persian conqueror governed his new subjects
 with an iron sceptre; and, as if he suspected the stability
 of his dominion, he exhausted their wealth by exorbitant
 tributes and licentious rapine despoiled or demolished the
 temples of the East; and transported to his hereditary
 realms the gold, the silver, the precious marbles, the arts,
 and the artists of the Asiatic cities.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP')"
Contest of Rome and Persia,"('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"Deaf to their advice and
 entreaty, the emperor boldly advanced (34) seven miles from
 the capital; the sacred ensign of the cross was displayed in
 the front; and Maurice reviewed, with conscious pride, the
 arms and numbers of the veterans who had fought and
 conquered beyond the Tigris.","('34', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
Death of Bahram.,"('Bahram', 'PERSON')"
"Death of Maurice and his children, A.D. 602, Nov. 27.","('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 602', 'DATE'), ('Nov. 27', 'DATE')"
"Deprived of
 the only chief whom they could fear or esteem, the bands
 which he had led to victory were twice broken by the
 cavalry, trampled by the elephants, and pierced by the
 arrows of the Barbarians; and a great number of the captives
 were beheaded on the field of battle by the sentence of the
 victor, who might justly condemn these seditious mercenaries
 as the authors or accomplices of the death of Maurice.","('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Maurice', 'PERSON')"
"Deprived of his firmest support, and doubtful of the
 fidelity of his subjects, the greatness of Chosroes was
 still conspicuous in its ruins.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON')"
"During
 the vigour of the Roman power, several princes were seated on
 the throne of Persia by the arms and the authority of the
 first Caesars.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Caesars', 'ORG')"
"During ten successive days, the capital was
 assaulted by the Avars, who had made some progress in the
 science of attack; they advanced to sap or batter the wall,
 under the cover of the impenetrable tortoise; their engines
 discharged a perpetual volley of stones and darts; and
 twelve lofty towers of wood exalted the combatants to the
 height of the neighbouring ramparts.","('ten successive days', 'DATE'), ('Avars', 'NORP'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL')"
"Eastward of the Tigris, at the
 end of the bridge of Mosul, the great Nineveh had formerly
 been erected: (101) the city, and even the ruins of the city,
 had long since disappeared; (102) the vacant space afforded a
 spacious field for the operations of the two armies.","('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Mosul', 'GPE'), ('Nineveh', 'GPE'), ('101', 'CARDINAL'), ('102', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Elated by his recent success, he
 despatched a herald with a bold defiance to the camp of the
 Romans, requesting them to fix a day of battle, and to
 choose whether they would pass the river themselves, or
 allow a free passage to the arms of the great king.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('a day', 'DATE')"
"Election of Phocas, A.D. 602, October.","('Election of Phocas', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 602', 'DATE'), ('October', 'DATE')"
"Elevation of Heraclius — The Persian War — Chosroes Subdues Syria, Egypt, and Asia Minor — Siege of Constantinople by the Persians and Avars — Persian Expeditions.","('The Persian War — Chosroes Subdues Syria', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Asia Minor — Siege of Constantinople by the Persians and Avars — Persian Expeditions', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Even after his death the republic was afflicted by the
 crimes of Phocas, which armed with a pious cause the most
 formidable of her enemies.","('Phocas', 'PERSON')"
"Every
 province, and each city of Persia, was the scene of
 independence, of discord, and of blood; and the state of
 anarchy prevailed about eight years longer, ! till the
 factions were silenced and united under the common yoke of
 the Arabian caliphs. (108)","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('about eight years', 'DATE'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('108', 'CARDINAL')"
"Exasperated by long and hopeless oppression,
 the provinces of Babylon, Susa, and Carmania, erected the
 standard of revolt; and the princes of Arabia, India, and
 Scythia, refused the customary tribute to the unworthy
 successor of Nushirvan.","('Babylon', 'GPE'), ('Susa', 'GPE'), ('Carmania', 'GPE'), ('Arabia', 'GPE'), ('India', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'PERSON'), ('Nushirvan', 'PERSON')"
"Exploits of Bahram, A.D. 590.","('Bahram', 'GPE'), ('590', 'CARDINAL')"
"First expedition of Heraclius against the Persians, A.D. 622.","('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('622', 'CARDINAL')"
"For himself, he refused
 to fly: his body was tortured with sciatic pains, (45) his
 mind was enfeebled by superstition; he patiently awaited the
 event of the revolution, and addressed a fervent and public
 prayer to the Almighty, that the punishment of his sins
 might be inflicted in this world rather than in a future
 life.","('45', 'CARDINAL')"
"For the crime of an ambitious centurion, the
 nation which he oppressed was chastised with the calamities
 of war; and the same calamities, at the end of twenty years,
 were retaliated and redoubled on the heads of the Persians.
 (57)","('the end of twenty years', 'DATE'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"Fourscore thousand (95) of his native subjects,
 and of the vassal tribes of Gepidae, Russians, Bulgarians,
 and Sclavonians, advanced under the standard of the chagan;
 a month was spent in marches and negotiations, but the whole
 city was invested on the thirty-first of July, from the
 suburbs of Pera and Galata to the Blachernae and seven
 towers; and the inhabitants descried with terror the flaming
 signals of the European and Asiatic shores.","('Gepidae', 'NORP'), ('Russians', 'NORP'), ('Bulgarians', 'NORP'), ('Sclavonians', 'NORP'), ('a month', 'DATE'), ('thirty-first of July', 'DATE'), ('Pera', 'GPE'), ('Galata', 'GPE'), ('Blachernae', 'GPE'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP')"
"From
 thence the king of Persia was conducted to the more
 honourable residence of Hierapolis; and Maurice dissembled
 his pride, and displayed his benevolence, at the reception
 of the letters and ambassadors of the grandson of Nushirvan.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Hierapolis', 'PERSON'), ('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('Nushirvan', 'PERSON')"
"From Belgrade to the
 walls of Constantinople a line may be measured of six
 hundred miles: that line was marked with flames and with
 blood; the horses of the Avars were alternately bathed in
 the Euxine and the Adriatic; and the Roman pontiff, alarmed
 by the approach of a more savage enemy, (29) was reduced to cherish the Lombards, as the protectors of Italy.","('Belgrade', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('six\r\n hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Avars', 'NORP'), ('Euxine', 'NORP'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('29', 'CARDINAL'), ('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"From all sides, the
 scattered garrisons of the maritime cities and the mountains
 might repair with speed and safety to his Imperial standard.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"From the commanding heights, a band of resolute men might
 overwhelm with stones and darts the myriads of the Turkish
 host: their emperor and his son were transpierced with
 arrows; and the fugitives were left, without counsel or
 provisions, to the revenge of an injured people.","('Turkish', 'NORP')"
"From the long-disputed banks of the Tigris and Euphrates,
 the reign of the grandson of Nushirvan was suddenly extended
 to the Hellespont and the Nile, the ancient limits of the
 Persian monarchy.","('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Nushirvan', 'PERSON'), ('Hellespont', 'LOC'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"From the palace of Dastagerd, he
 pursued his march within a few miles of Modain or Ctesiphon,
 till he was stopped, on the banks of the Arba, by the
 difficulty of the passage, the rigour of the season, and
 perhaps the fame of an impregnable capital.","('Dastagerd', 'GPE'), ('a few miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Modain', 'GPE'), ('Ctesiphon', 'GPE'), ('Arba', 'LOC'), ('season', 'DATE')"
"From the spacious and fruitful plains of
 Albania, the emperor appears to follow the chain of
 Hyrcanian Mountains, to descend into the province of Media
 or Irak, and to carry his victorious arms as far as the
 royal cities of Casbin and Ispahan, which had never been
 approached by a Roman conqueror.","('Albania', 'GPE'), ('Hyrcanian Mountains', 'LOC'), ('Irak', 'GPE'), ('Casbin', 'LOC'), ('Ispahan', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"He again ascended his throne to receive the
 congratulations of the ambassadors of France and India: and
 the fame of Moses, Alexander, and Hercules, (112) was
 eclipsed in the popular estimation, by the superior merit
 and glory of the great Heraclius.","('France', 'GPE'), ('India', 'GPE'), ('Moses', 'PERSON'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Hercules', 'PERSON'), ('112', 'CARDINAL'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON')"
"He commands Chosroes, the son of Hormouz, to shun the example and fate of his father, to confine the
 traitors who had been released from their chains, to deposit
 in some holy place the diadem which he had usurped, and to
 accept from his gracious benefactor the pardon of his faults
 and the government of a province.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Hormouz', 'PERSON')"
"He defined the duties
 of a king, and the Persian nobles listened with a smile of
 contempt; they were fired with indignation when he dared to
 vilify the character of Chosroes; and by the indiscreet
 offer of resigning the sceptre to the second of his sons, he
 subscribed his own condemnation, and sacrificed the life of
 his own innocent favorite.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"He is deposed, A.D. 628, February 25.","('A.D. 628', 'DATE'), ('February 25', 'DATE')"
"He landed his troops on the confines of Syria and
 Cilicia, in the Gulf of Scanderoon, where the coast suddenly
 turns to the south; (79) and his discernment was expressed in
 the choice of this important post. (80)","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Cilicia', 'GPE'), ('the Gulf of Scanderoon', 'LOC'), ('79', 'CARDINAL'), ('80', 'CARDINAL')"
"He might despise the
 resentment of a blind and unpopular tyrant, but the tiara
 was trembling on his head, till he could subvert the power,
 or acquire the friendship, of the great Bahram, who sternly
 denied the justice of a revolution, in which himself and his
 soldiers, the true representatives of Persia, had never been
 consulted.","('Bahram', 'NORP'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"He permitted the Persians
 to oppress for a while the provinces, and to insult with
 impunity the capital of the East; while the Roman emperor
 explored his perilous way through the Black Sea, (84) and the
 mountains of Armenia, penetrated into the heart of Persia,
 (85) and recalled the armies of the great king to the defence
 of their bleeding country.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('the Black Sea', 'LOC'), ('84', 'CARDINAL'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('85', 'CARDINAL')"
"He proudly displayed the ensigns of
 royalty; but the city and palace of Modain had already
 escaped from the hand of the tyrant.","('Modain', 'GPE')"
"He repelled the threefold attack of the Persians, improved the divisions of their chiefs, and, by a well-concerted train of marches, retreats, and successful actions, finally chased them from the field into the fortified cities of Media and Assyria.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Media', 'GPE'), ('Assyria', 'GPE')"
"He surveyed the enormous beast with surprise, with
 disgust, and possibly with terror; and smiled at the vain
 industry of the Romans, who, in search of such useless
 rarities, could explore the limits of the land and sea.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"He swore by
 his sword, the symbol of the god of war, that he did not, as
 the enemy of Rome, construct a bridge upon the Save.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"He would have been content with the neutrality of the
 Avars; and his friendly entreaty, that the chagan would act,
 not as the enemy, but as the guardian, of the empire, was
 accompanied with a more persuasive donative of two hundred
 thousand pieces of gold.","('Avars', 'PERSON'), ('two hundred\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Her life was forfeited to revenge, and even
 to justice: but the patriarch obtained and pledged an oath
 for her safety: a monastery was allotted for her prison, and
 the widow of Maurice accepted and abused the lenity of his
 assassin.","('Maurice', 'PERSON')"
"Heraclius
 himself, with the skill and patience of a centurion,
 inculcated the lessons of the school of tactics, and the
 soldiers were assiduously trained in the use of their
 weapons, and the exercises and evolutions of the field.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON')"
"Heraclius
 was rewarded by their tears and grateful acclamations; but
 this wise measure, which spread the fame of his benevolence,
 diffused the murmurs of the Persians against the pride and
 obstinacy of their own sovereign.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"Heraclius performed in person the
 pilgrimage of Jerusalem, the identity of the relic was
 verified by the discreet patriarch, (111) and this august
 ceremony has been commemorated by the annual festival of the
 exaltation of the cross.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('111', 'CARDINAL')"
"Heraclius subscribed these
 ignominious terms; but the time and space which he obtained
 to collect such treasures from the poverty of the East, was
 industriously employed in the preparations of a bold and
 desperate attack.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"His
 zeal was rewarded by the gratitude and docility of Hormouz,
 who acknowledged himself more indebted to his preceptor than
 to his parent: but when age and labor had impaired the
 strength, and perhaps the faculties, of this prudent
 counsellor, he retired from court, and abandoned the
 youthful monarch to his own passions and those of his
 favorites.","('Hormouz', 'PERSON')"
"His anxiety was relieved by the deliverance of
 Constantinople; his hopes were confirmed by a victory of his
 brother Theodorus; and to the hostile league of Chosroes
 with the Avars, the Roman emperor opposed the useful and
 honourable alliance of the Turks.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Theodorus', 'PERSON'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Avars', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Turks', 'NORP')"
"His armour of
 pure and massy gold, the shield of one hundred and twenty
 plates, the sword and belt, the saddle and cuirass, adorned
 the triumph of Heraclius; and if he had not been faithful to
 Christ and his mother, the champion of Rome might have
 offered the fourth opime spoils to the Jupiter of the
 Capitol. (103)","('one hundred and twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Jupiter', 'LOC'), ('103', 'CARDINAL')"
"His avarice defrauded the troops; his jealous
 caprice degraded the satraps; the palace, the tribunals, the
 waters of the Tigris, were stained with the blood of the
 innocent, and the tyrant exulted in the sufferings and
 execution of thirteen thousand victims.","('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('thirteen thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"His character,  and Phocas does not appear less hateful in the exercise than in the acquisition of power.","('Phocas', 'PERSON')"
"His coronation was accompanied by that of his wife Eudoxia; and their posterity, till the fourth
 generation, continued to reign over the empire of the East.","('Eudoxia', 'PERSON'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"His death, A.D. 579.","('A.D. 579', 'DATE')"
"His empire extended over Hungary,
 Poland, and Prussia, from the mouth of the Danube to that of
 the Oder; (31) and his new subjects were divided and
 transplanted by the jealous policy of the conqueror. (32)","('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('Poland', 'GPE'), ('Prussia', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Oder', 'PERSON'), ('31', 'CARDINAL'), ('32', 'CARDINAL')"
"His fall and death, A.D. 610, October 4.","('A.D. 610', 'DATE'), ('October 4', 'DATE')"
"His fate alone was remembered; and at the end of twenty years, in the recital of the history of Theophylact, the mournful tale was interrupted by the tears of the audience. (47)","('the end of twenty years', 'DATE'), ('Theophylact', 'EVENT'), ('47', 'CARDINAL')"
"His last war with the Romans, A.D. 72,etc  but as soon as war became inevitable, he took the field with the alacrity of youth, whilst the aggressor trembled in the palace of Constantinople.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 72', 'DATE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"His preparations for war, A.D. 621.","('621', 'CARDINAL')"
"His second expedition, A.D. 623,624,625.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('623,624,625', 'CARDINAL')"
"His ships were already
 laden with the treasures of the palace; but his flight was
 arrested by the patriarch, who armed the powers of religion
 in the defence of his country; led Heraclius to the altar of
 St. Sophia, and extorted a solemn oath, that he would live
 and die with the people whom God had intrusted to his care.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('St. Sophia', 'GPE')"
"His soul was
 superior to the vanity of entertaining Constantinople with
 an imperfect triumph; but the presence of the emperor was
 indispensably required to soothe the restless and rapacious
 spirit of the Avars.","('Constantinople', 'PERSON'), ('Avars', 'NORP')"
"His superstition was subdued by fear: on the
 third day, he entered with joy the fortifications of
 Ctesiphon; yet he still doubted of his safety till he had
 opposed the River Tigris to the pursuit of the Romans.","('the\r\n third day', 'DATE'), ('Ctesiphon', 'PERSON'), ('the River Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"His third expedition, A.D. 627.","('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('627', 'CARDINAL')"
"His western trophy was erected, not on the walls
 of Carthage, (62) but in the neighbourhood of Tripoli; the
 Greek colonies of Cyrene were finally extirpated; and the
 conqueror, treading in the footsteps of Alexander, returned
 in triumph through the sands of the Libyan desert. of Asia Minor, A.D. 616 etc.","('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Tripoli', 'GPE'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Cyrene', 'GPE'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Libyan', 'NORP'), ('Asia Minor', 'LOC'), ('616', 'CARDINAL')"
Hormouz is deposed and imprisoned.,"('Hormouz', 'PERSON')"
"However it might be
 varnished by fiction or sophistry, Chosroes turned with
 horror from the assassin, imprisoned the pretended envoy,
 disclaimed the usurper, and declared himself the avenger of
 his father and benefactor.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON')"
"I have already traced the steps
 of a revolution so pleasing, in Gregory's opinion, both to
 heaven and earth;","('Gregory', 'PERSON')"
"If he marched against the
 enemy, the pleasant valleys of Mount Haemus opposed an
 insuperable barrier; but in his retreat, he explored, with
 fearless curiosity, the most difficult and obsolete paths,
 which had almost escaped the memory of the oldest native.","('Mount Haemus', 'LOC')"
"If the
 motives of Chosroes had been pure and honourable, he must
 have ended the quarrel with the death of Phocas, and he
 would have embraced, as his best ally, the fortunate African
 who had so generously avenged the injuries of his benefactor
 Maurice.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Phocas', 'PERSON'), ('African', 'NORP'), ('Maurice', 'PERSON')"
"In
 the course of this successful inroad, he signalized the zeal
 and revenge of a Christian emperor: at his command, the
 soldiers extinguished the fire, and destroyed the temples,
 of the Magi; the statues of Chosroes, who aspired to divine
 honours, were abandoned to the flames; and the ruins of
 Thebarma or Ormia, (90) which had given birth to Zoroaster
 himself, made some atonement for the injuries of the holy
 sepulchre.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Magi', 'PERSON'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Thebarma', 'NORP'), ('Ormia', 'PERSON'), ('90', 'CARDINAL'), ('Zoroaster', 'PERSON')"
"In
 the heat of the action, three valiant chiefs were
 successively slain by the sword and lance of the emperor:
 among these was Rhazates himself; he fell like a soldier,
 but the sight of his head scattered grief and despair
 through the fainting ranks of the Persians.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rhazates', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"In
 the massacre of the Imperial family, (50) the mercy, or
 rather the discretion, of Phocas had spared these unhappy
 females, and they were decently confined to a private house.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('50', 'CARDINAL'), ('Phocas', 'PERSON')"
"In
 the recovery of the standards and prisoners which had fallen
 into the hands of the Persians, the emperor imitated the
 example of Augustus: their care of the national dignity was
 celebrated by the poets of the times, but the decay of
 genius may be measured by the distance between Horace and
 George of Pisidia: the subjects and brethren of Heraclius
 were redeemed from persecution, slavery, and exile; but,
 instead of the Roman eagles, the true wood of the holy cross
 was restored to the importunate demands of the successor of
 Constantine.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Horace', 'PERSON'), ('George of Pisidia', 'PERSON'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"In a dispute of precedency between the two factions, his partial judgment inclined in favour of the greens.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In a dispute with
 the Greek and Indian philosophers, Buzurg (8) had once
 maintained, that the most grievous misfortune of life is old
 age without the remembrance of virtue; and our candor will
 presume that the same principle compelled him, during three
 years, to direct the councils of the Persian empire.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Indian', 'NORP'), ('Buzurg', 'PERSON'), ('8', 'CARDINAL'), ('three\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"In a secret
 interview, he produced the portrait of his daughter Eudocia,
 (99) condescended to flatter the Barbarian with the promise
 of a fair and august bride; obtained an immediate succour of
 forty thousand horse, and negotiated a strong diversion of
 the Turkish arms on the side of the Oxus. (100)","('Eudocia', 'PERSON'), ('99', 'DATE'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('forty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Oxus', 'PRODUCT'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"In a small
 bark, the unfortunate Maurice, with his wife and nine
 children, escaped to the Asiatic shore; but the violence of
 the wind compelled him to land at the church of St.
 Autonomus, (44) near Chalcedon, from whence he despatched
 Theodosius, he eldest son, to implore the gratitude and
 friendship of the Persian monarch.","('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('St.\r\n Autonomus', 'FAC'), ('44', 'CARDINAL'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"In a strain of artful adulation, which assumed the
 language of freedom, they presumed to censure the excess of
 his gratitude and friendship for the Greeks; a nation with
 whom it was dangerous to conclude either peace or alliance;
 whose superstition was devoid of truth and justice, and who
 must be incapable of any virtue, since they could perpetrate
 the most atrocious of crimes, the impious murder of their
 sovereign. (56)","('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"In every word, and in every
 action, the son of Nushirvan degenerated from the virtues of
 his father.","('Nushirvan', 'PERSON')"
"In five
 successive battles, which seem to have been conducted with
 skill and resolution, seventeen thousand two hundred
 Barbarians were made prisoners: near sixty thousand, with
 four sons of the chagan, were slain: the Roman general
 surprised a peaceful district of the Gepidae, who slept
 under the protection of the Avars; and his last trophies
 were erected on the banks of the Danube and the Teyss.","('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('seventeen thousand two hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('near sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Gepidae', 'NORP'), ('Avars', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Teyss', 'PRODUCT')"
"In that grave, the faults and errors of Maurice were kindly interred.","('Maurice', 'PERSON')"
"In the
 disposition both of his troops and provinces the chagan
 exposed the vassals, whose lives he disregarded, (33) to the
 first assault; and the swords of the enemy were blunted
 before they encountered the native valour of the Avars.","('33', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Avars', 'NORP')"
"In the
 first and last years of a long reign, the emperor appears to
 be the slave of sloth, of pleasure, or of superstition, the
 careless and impotent spectator of the public calamities.","('the\r\n first and last years', 'DATE')"
"In the
 same campaign, another army advanced from the Euphrates to
 the Thracian Bosphorus; Chalcedon surrendered after a long
 siege, and a Persian camp was maintained above ten years in
 the presence of Constantinople.","('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('the Thracian Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('ten years', 'DATE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"In the battle of Nineveh, his courage might have
 taught the Persians to vanquish, or he might have fallen
 with honour by the lance of a Roman emperor.","('Nineveh', 'GPE'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the battle of Nineveh, which was fiercely
 fought from daybreak to the eleventh hour, twenty-eight
 standards, besides those which might be broken or torn, were
 taken from the Persians; the greatest part of their army was
 cut in pieces, and the victors, concealing their own loss,
 passed the night on the field.","('Nineveh', 'GPE'), ('daybreak', 'TIME'), ('the eleventh hour', 'TIME'), ('twenty-eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"In the camp of Issus, the Roman general
 reformed the sloth and disorder of the veterans, and
 educated the new recruits in the knowledge and practice of
 military virtue.","('Issus', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the construction and use of ships, engines, and fortifications, the
Barbarians admired the superior ingenuity of a people whom they had so often vanquished in the
field.","('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"In the games of
 the Circus, which he repeated with unusual pomp, Maurice
 disguised, with smiles of confidence, the anxiety of his
 heart, condescended to solicit the applause of the factions,
 and flattered their pride by accepting from their respective
 tribunes a list of nine hundred blues and fifteen hundred
 greens, whom he affected to esteem as the solid pillars of
 his throne Their treacherous or languid support betrayed his
 weakness and hastened his fall: the green faction were the
 secret accomplices of the rebels, and the blues recommended
 lenity and moderation in a contest with their Roman brethren","('Circus', 'EVENT'), ('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('nine hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifteen hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the just assurance, that
 his accomplices could neither forgive nor hope to be
 forgiven, and that every Persian might be trusted as the
 judge and enemy of the tyrant, he instituted a public trial
 without a precedent and without a copy in the annals of the
 East.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"In the just fervour of indignation, an order was signified to the army of the Danube, that they
 should spare the magazines of the province, and establish
 their winter quarters in the hostile country of the Avars.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Avars', 'NORP')"
"In the language of a Barbarian, without
 guile, the prince of the Avars affected to complain of the
 insincerity of the Greeks; (26) yet he was not inferior to
 the most civilized nations in the refinement of
 dissimulation and perfidy.","('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('Avars', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('26', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the language of the usurpers of every
 age, he imputes his own crimes to the Deity, and, without
 degrading his equal majesty, he offers to reconcile the long
 discord of the two nations, by a treaty of peace and
 alliance more durable than brass or iron.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the mean
 while, the magistrates of Constantinople repeatedly strove
 to purchase the retreat of the chagan; but their deputies
 were rejected and insulted; and he suffered the patricians
 to stand before his throne, while the Persian envoys, in
 silk robes, were seated by his side.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"In the mean while his general Adarman advanced from Babylon, traversed the desert, passed the Euphrates, insulted the suburbs of Antioch, reduced to ashes the city of Apamea, and laid the spoils of Syria at the feet of his master, whose perseverance in the midst of winter at length subverted the bulwark of the East.","('Adarman', 'PERSON'), ('Babylon', 'GPE'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Apamea', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"In the name of his
 generous benefactor, a rich diadem was presented to the
 fugitive prince, with an inestimable gift of jewels and
 gold; a powerful army was assembled on the frontiers of
 Syria and Armenia, under the command of the valiant and
 faithful Narses, (17) and this general, of his own nation,
 and his own choice, was directed to pass the Tigris, and
 never to sheathe his sword till he had restored Chosroes to
 the throne of his ancestors.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('17', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON')"
"In the obscure
 picture of the calamities of the empire, (64) it is not easy
 to discern the figure of Chosroes himself, to separate his
 actions from those of his lieutenants, or to ascertain his
 personal merit in the general blaze of glory and
 magnificence.","('64', 'DATE'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON')"
"In the presence of the senate, the son-in-law of
 Phocas was condemned to embrace the monastic life; and the
 sentence was justified by the weighty observation of
 Heraclius, that the man who had betrayed his father could
 never be faithful to his friend.","('Phocas', 'PERSON'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON')"
"In the severity of the winter season, Sarbaraza
 deemed himself secure in the walls of Salban: he was surprised by the activity of Heraclius, who divided his troops, and performed a laborious march in the silence of the night.","('the winter season', 'DATE'), ('Sarbaraza', 'PERSON'), ('Salban', 'PERSON'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('the silence of the night', 'TIME')"
"In the space of two
 centuries, none of the successors of Theodosius had appeared
 in the field: their lives were supinely spent in the palace
 of Constantinople; and the Greeks could no longer
 understand, that the name of emperor, in its primitive
 sense, denoted the chief of the armies of the republic.","('the space of two\r\n centuries', 'DATE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"In the useless altercations, that precede and justify the quarrels of princes, the Greeks and the Barbarians accused each other of violating the peace which had been concluded between the two empires about four years before the death of
 Justinian.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('about four years', 'DATE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Instead of half
 a million of inhabitants, which have been ascribed to Tauris
 under the reign of the Sophys, the city contained no more
 than three thousand houses; but the value of the royal
 treasures was enhanced by a tradition, that they were the
 spoils of Croesus, which had been transported by Cyrus from
 the citadel of Sardes.","('half\r\n a million', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tauris', 'PERSON'), ('Sophys', 'NORP'), ('more\r\n than three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Croesus', 'PRODUCT'), ('Cyrus', 'PERSON'), ('Sardes', 'GPE')"
"Instead of skirmishing on the frontier, the two monarchs who
 disputed the empire of the East aimed their desperate
 strokes at the heart of their rival.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"It is not improbable,
 that a native subject of Persia should encourage his master
 and his friend to deliver and possess the provinces of Asia.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"It is still more probable, that Chosroes should animate his
 troops by the assurance that the sword which they dreaded
 the most would remain in its scabbard, or be drawn in their
 favour.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON')"
"It was
 the duty of the Byzantine historians to have revealed the
 causes of his slumber and vigilance.","('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"It was determined
 by the conspirators, that Siroes, with the ensigns of
 royalty, should appear in the camp; and if the enterprise
 should fail, his escape was contrived to the Imperial court.","('Siroes', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"It was more difficult to trust the fidelity of
 Crispus, whose recent services were recompensed by the
 command of the Cappadocian army.","('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('Cappadocian', 'NORP')"
"It was still in the power of
 Chosroes to obtain a reasonable peace; and he was repeatedly
 pressed by the messengers of Heraclius to spare the blood of
 his subjects, and to relieve a humane conqueror from the
 painful duty of carrying fire and sword through the fairest
 countries of Asia.","('Chosroes', 'NORP'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"Lamenting the barren superfluity of materials, I have
 studied to compress the narrative of these uninteresting
 transactions: but the just Nushirvan is still applauded as
 the model of Oriental kings, and the ambition of his
 grandson Chosroes prepared the revolution of the East, which
 was speedily accomplished by the arms and the religion of
 the successors of Mahomet.","('Nushirvan', 'PERSON'), ('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"Narses was removed from his military
 command; he reared an independent standard at Hierapolis, in
 Syria: he was betrayed by fallacious promises, and burnt
 alive in the market-place of Constantinople.","('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Hierapolis', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Nine hundred and sixty
 elephants were maintained for the use or splendour of the
 great king: his tents and baggage were carried into the
 field by twelve thousand great camels and eight thousand of
 a smaller size; (66) and the royal stables were filled with
 six thousand mules and horses, among whom the names of
 Shebdiz and Barid are renowned for their speed or beauty.","('Nine hundred and sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('twelve thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('eight thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('66', 'CARDINAL'), ('six thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Shebdiz', 'PERSON'), ('Barid', 'PERSON')"
"No sooner did the
 grandson of Nushirvan display his own and the Roman banners
 beyond the Tigris, than he was joined, each day, by the
 increasing multitudes of the nobility and people; and as he
 advanced, he received from every side the grateful offerings
 of the keys of his cities and the heads of his enemies.","('Nushirvan', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"Nushirvan, or Chosroes, conducted in person the siege of Dara; and although that important fortress had been left destitute of troops and magazines, the valour of the inhabitants resisted above five months the archers, the elephants, and the military engines of the Great King.","('Nushirvan', 'GPE'), ('Chosroes', 'NORP'), ('Dara', 'PERSON'), ('five months', 'DATE'), ('the Great King', 'GPE')"
"Of the Persian spoils, the
 most valuable portion had been expended in the war,
 distributed to the soldiers, or buried, by an unlucky
 tempest, in the waves of the Euxine.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Euxine', 'PRODUCT')"
"Of the characters conspicuous in history, that of Heraclius
 is one of the most extraordinary and inconsistent.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON')"
"Of the soldiers who had conspired with Phocas,
 only two were found to have survived the stroke of time and
 of the Barbarians; (77) the loss, even of these seditious
 veterans, was imperfectly supplied by the new levies of
 Heraclius, and the gold of the sanctuary united, in the same
 camp, the names, and arms, and languages of the East and
 West.","('Phocas', 'PERSON'), ('only two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('77', 'CARDINAL'), ('Heraclius', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"On a sudden the
 hippodrome was encompassed by the Scythian cavalry, who had
 pressed their secret and nocturnal march: the tremendous
 sound of the chagan's whip gave the signal of the assault,
 and Heraclius, wrapping his diadem round his arm, was saved
 with extreme hazard, by the fleetness of his horse.","('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON')"
"On the
 twenty-ninth of June, thirty thousand Barbarians, the
 vanguard of the Avars, forced the long wall, and drove into
 the capital a promiscuous crowd of peasants, citizens, and
 soldiers.","('the\r\n twenty-ninth of June', 'DATE'), ('thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Avars', 'NORP')"
"On the return of spring, Justinian descended into the fertile plains of Assyria; the flames of war approached the residence of Nushirvan;","('Justinian', 'NORP'), ('Assyria', 'GPE'), ('Nushirvan', 'GPE')"
"On the return of spring, the emperor traversed in seven days the mountains of Curdistan, and passed without resistance the
 rapid stream of the Tigris.","('spring', 'DATE'), ('seven days', 'DATE'), ('Curdistan', 'GPE'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"On the shore of Chalcedon, the emperor
 held a safer conference with a more honourable foe, who,
 before Heraclius descended from his galley, saluted with
 reverence and pity the majesty of the purple.","('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON')"
"On the third day, amidst the acclamations of a
 thoughtless people, Phocas made his public entry in a
 chariot drawn by four white horses: the revolt of the troops
 was rewarded by a lavish donative; and the new sovereign,
 after visiting the palace, beheld from his throne the games of the hippodrome.","('the third day', 'DATE'), ('Phocas', 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"On this memorable
 day, Heraclius, on his horse Phallas, surpassed the bravest
 of his warriors: his lip was pierced with a spear; the steed
 was wounded in the thigh; but he carried his master safe and
 victorious through the triple phalanx of the Barbarians.","('this memorable\r\n day', 'DATE'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Phallas', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"Oppressed by the weight of
 their spoils and captives, the Roman army halted under the
 walls of Amida; and Heraclius informed the senate of
 Constantinople of his safety and success, which they had
 already felt by the retreat of the besiegers.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Amida', 'GPE'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Pelusium, the key of that
 impervious country, was surprised by the cavalry of the
 Persians: they passed, with impunity, the innumerable
 channels of the Delta, and explored the long valley of the
 Nile, from the pyramids of Memphis to the confines of
 Aethiopia.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Delta', 'LOC'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Memphis', 'GPE'), ('Aethiopia', 'GPE')"
"Perhaps he was awakened by the last insolent
 demand of the Persian conqueror; but at the moment when
 Heraclius assumed the spirit of a hero, the only hopes of
 the Romans were drawn from the vicissitudes of fortune,
 which might threaten the proud prosperity of Chosroes, and
 must be favourable to those who had attained the lowest
 period of depression.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Chosroes', 'NORP')"
"Persia had
 already repented of her fatal rashness, which betrayed the
 heir of the house of Sassan to the ambition of a rebellious
 subject: and the bold refusal of the Magi to consecrate his
 usurpation, compelled Bahram to assume the sceptre,
 regardless of the laws and prejudices of the nation.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Sassan', 'PERSON'), ('Magi', 'PERSON'), ('Bahram', 'PERSON')"
Persia had been lost by a king; it was saved by a hero.,"('Persia', 'GPE')"
"Phocas emperor, A.D. 602, Nov. 23 - A.D. 610, October 4..","('A.D. 602', 'DATE'), ('Nov. 23 - A.D. 610', 'DATE'), ('October 4', 'DATE')"
"Placed on the verge of the two great empires of the East, Mahomet observed with secret joy the progress of their mutual destruction; and in the midst of the Persian triumphs, he ventured to foretell, that before many years should elapse, victory should again return to the banners of the Romans. (69)
Distress of Heraclius, A.D. 610-622.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('many years', 'DATE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('69', 'CARDINAL')"
"Pride, polciy, and power of the chagan of the Avars, A.D. 570-600,etc.","('Avars', 'PRODUCT'), ('570-600', 'CARDINAL')"
"Reign of Heraclius, A.D. 610, October 5 - A.D. 642, February 11.","('Heraclius', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 610', 'DATE'), ('October 5 - A.D. 642', 'DATE'), ('February 11', 'DATE')"
"Restoration and policy of Chosroes, A.D. 591-603.","('Chosroes', 'ORG'), ('591-603', 'CARDINAL')"
Revolt of Constantinople.,"('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Revolutions of Persia after the Death of Chosroes or Nushirvan — His Son Hormouz, a Tyrant, Is Deposed — Usurpation of Bahram —  Flight and Restoration of Chosroes II —  His Gratitude to the Romans — The Chagan of the Avars —  Revolt of the Army against Maurice —  His Death.","('Persia', 'LOC'), ('the Death of Chosroes', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Son Hormouz', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Usurpation of Bahram —  Flight and Restoration of Chosroes II —  His Gratitude to the Romans — The Chagan of the Avars —  Revolt of the Army against Maurice —  His Death', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Sain was flayed alive, according to the inhuman practice of his country; and the separate and rigorous confinement of the ambassadors violated the law of nations, and the faith of an express stipulation.","('Sain', 'PERSON')"
"Sarbar still maintained the important station of
 Chalcedon; but the jealousy of Chosroes, or the artifice of
 Heraclius, soon alienated the mind of that powerful satrap
 from the service of his king and country.","('Sarbar', 'PERSON'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('Chosroes', 'NORP'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON')"
"Sarbar, the general of the third army,
 penetrated through the provinces of Asia to the well-known
 camp of Chalcedon, and amused himself with the destruction
 of the sacred and profane buildings of the Asiatic suburbs,
 while he impatiently waited the arrival of his Scythian
 friends on the opposite side of the Bosphorus.","('Sarbar', 'PERSON'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Bosphorus', 'LOC')"
"Since the days of Scipio and Hannibal, no bolder enterprise
 has been attempted than that which Heraclius achieved for
 the deliverance of the empire (83)","('the days', 'DATE'), ('Scipio', 'PERSON'), ('Hannibal', 'PERSON'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('83', 'CARDINAL')"
"Since the death of Trajan the arms of the empire had not
 penetrated so deeply into the old Dacia: yet the success of
 Priscus was transient and barren; and he was soon recalled
 by the apprehension that Baian, with dauntless spirit and
 recruited forces, was preparing to avenge his defeat under
 the walls of Constantinople. (39)","('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Dacia', 'PERSON'), ('Priscus', 'PERSON'), ('Baian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('39', 'CARDINAL')"
"Singidunum, at the distance of fifty
 miles, experienced a more cruel fate: the buildings were
 razed, and the vanquished people was condemned to servitude
 and exile.","('Singidunum', 'GPE'), ('fifty\r\n miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"Six thousand guards successively mounted before the palace
 gate; the service of the interior apartments was performed
 by twelve thousand slaves, and in the number of three
 thousand virgins, the fairest of Asia, some happy concubine
 might console her master for the age or the indifference of
 Sira.","('Six thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('twelve thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('three\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Sira', 'PERSON')"
"So
 rapid was the pursuit, that the Avars almost entered the
 golden gate of Constantinople with the flying crowds: (71)
 but the plunder of the suburbs rewarded their treason, and
 they transported beyond the Danube two hundred and seventy
 thousand captives.","('Avars', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('71', 'CARDINAL'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('two hundred and seventy\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"So obscure had been the former condition of
Phocas, that the emperor was ignorant of the name and character of his rival; but as soon as he
learned, that the centurion, though bold in sedition, was timid in the face of danger, ""Alas!"" cried
the desponding prince, ""if he is a coward, he will surely be a murderer.""","('Phocas', 'PERSON'), ('Alas', 'PERSON')"
State of the Roman armies.,"('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Stripped of the diadem and purple, clothed in a
 vile habit, and loaded with chains, he was transported in a
 small boat to the Imperial galley of Heraclius, who
 reproached him with the crimes of his abominable reign.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Heraclius', 'PRODUCT')"
"Strong in victory and fame, Heraclius boldly
 ascended the heights of Mount Taurus, directed his march
 through the plains of Cappadocia, and established his
 troops, for the winter season, in safe and plentiful
 quarters on the banks of the River Halys. (82)","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Mount Taurus', 'LOC'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE'), ('winter', 'DATE'), ('the River Halys', 'LOC'), ('82', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such tears must have flowed in secret, and such compassion
 would have been criminal, under the reign of Phocas, who was
 peaceably acknowledged in the provinces of the East and
 West.","('Phocas', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"Such voluntary homage and
 important aid were entitled to the warmest acknowledgments;
 and the emperor, taking off his own diadem, placed it on the
 head of the Turkish prince, whom he saluted with a tender
 embrace and the appellation of son.","('Turkish', 'NORP')"
"Syria, Egypt, and the provinces of Asia, were subdued by the
 Persian arms, while Europe, from the confines of Istria to
 the long wall of Thrace, was oppressed by the Avars,
 unsatiated with the blood and rapine of the Italian war.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Istria', 'LOC'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Avars', 'NORP'), ('the Italian war', 'EVENT')"
"That
 river, an impetuous torrent, was about three hundred feet
 broad; the bridge was fortified with strong turrets; and the
 banks were lined with Barbarian archers.","('about three hundred feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
"That city, if we may credit the
 resemblance of name and character, was the famous
 Azimuntium, (36) which had alone repelled the tempest of
 Attila.","('Azimuntium', 'NORP'), ('36', 'DATE'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"That seasonable interval was employed in the preparations of war; and the voice of rumour proclaimed to the world, that from the distant countries of the Alps and the Rhine, from Scythia, Maesia, Pannonia, Illyricum, and Isauria, the strength of the Imperial cavalry was reenforced with one hundred and fifty thousand soldiers.","('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Scythia', 'LOC'), ('Maesia', 'LOC'), ('Pannonia', 'LOC'), ('Illyricum', 'NORP'), ('Isauria', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('one hundred and fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"That unhappy old man was
 himself tortured with the sharpest pains both of mind and
 body; and, in the consciousness of his approaching end, he
 resolved to fix the tiara on the head of Merdaza, the most
 favoured of his sons.","('Merdaza', 'PERSON')"
"The
 Christians of the East were scandalized by the worship of
 fire, and the impious doctrine of the two principles: the
 Magi were not less intolerant than the bishops; and the
 martyrdom of some native Persians, who had deserted the
 religion of Zoroaster, (63) was conceived to be the prelude
 of a fierce and general persecution.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Magi', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Zoroaster', 'PERSON'), ('63', 'DATE')"
"The
 blind partiality of fraternal love might excuse the
 promotion of his brother Peter, who fled with equal disgrace
 from the Barbarians, from his own soldiers and from the
 inhabitants of a Roman city.","('Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The
 cavalry and infantry in light or heavy armour were divided
 into two parties; the trumpets were fixed in the centre, and
 their signals directed the march, the charge, the retreat or
 pursuit; the direct or oblique order, the deep or extended
 phalanx; to represent in fictitious combat the operations of
 genuine war.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 clergy themselves appear to have sympathized with the public
 distress; and the discreet patriarch of Alexandria, without
 admitting the precedent of sacrilege, assisted his sovereign
 by the miraculous or seasonable revelation of a secret
 treasure. (76)","('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
"The
 darkness of the night, and the separation of the Romans,
 afforded the Persian monarch an opportunity of revenge; and
 one of their camps was swept away by a rapid and impetuous
 assault.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 discovery of his flight agitated with terror and tumult the
 palace, the city, and the camp of Dastagerd: the satraps
 hesitated whether they had most to fear from their sovereign
 or the enemy; and the females of the harem were astonished
 and pleased by the sight of mankind, till the jealous
 husband of three thousand wives again confined them to a
 more distant castle.","('Dastagerd', 'GPE'), ('three thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 eastern regions of Germany, which had been left vacant by
 the emigration of the Vandals, were replenished with
 Sclavonian colonists; the same tribes are discovered in the
 neighbourhood of the Adriatic and of the Baltic, and with the
 name of Baian himself, the Illyrian cities of Neyss and
 Lissa are again found in the heart of Silesia.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Sclavonian', 'NORP'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC'), ('Baltic', 'LOC'), ('Baian', 'PERSON'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP'), ('Neyss', 'GPE'), ('Lissa', 'GPE'), ('Silesia', 'GPE')"
"The
 lieutenant of the emperor Maurice preferred the safer
 alternative; and this local circumstance, which would have
 enhanced the victory of the Persians, rendered their defeat
 more bloody and their escape more difficult.","('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"The
 martial ardor of Maurice was opposed by the grave flattery
 of the senate, the timid superstition of the patriarch, and
 the tears of the empress Constantina; and they all conjured
 him to devolve on some meaner general the fatigues and
 perils of a Scythian campaign.","('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('Constantina', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'PERSON')"
"The
 ministers of flattery and corruption, who had been banished
 by his father, were recalled and cherished by the son; the
 disgrace and exile of the friends of Nushirvan established
 their tyranny; and virtue was driven by degrees from the
 mind of Hormouz, from his palace, and from the government of
 the state.","('Nushirvan', 'PERSON'), ('Hormouz', 'PERSON')"
"The
 patriotism of the Persian general was stimulated by his
 affection for the city of his forefathers: in the hour of
 victory, every peasant became a soldier, and every soldier a
 hero; and their ardor was kindled by the gorgeous spectacle
 of beds, and thrones, and tables of massy gold, the spoils
 of Asia, and the luxury of the hostile camp.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('the hour', 'TIME'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The
 pleasant vale of Damascus has been adorned in every age with
 a royal city: her obscure felicity has hitherto escaped the
 historian of the Roman empire: but Chosroes reposed his
 troops in the paradise of Damascus before he ascended the
 hills of Libanus, or invaded the cities of the Phoenician
 coast.","('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Libanus', 'LOC'), ('Phoenician', 'NORP')"
"The Avars were repulsed; a
 fleet of Sclavonian canoes was destroyed in the harbour; the
 vassals of the chagan threatened to desert, his provisions
 were exhausted, and after burning his engines, he gave the
 signal of a slow and formidable retreat.","('Avars', 'PRODUCT'), ('Sclavonian', 'NORP')"
"The Colchian allies prepared to desert his
 standard; and the fears of the bravest veterans were
 expressed, rather than concealed, by their desponding
 silence.","('Colchian', 'NORP')"
"The Greeks and modern Persians minutely
 describe how Chosroes was insulted, and famished, and
 tortured, by the command of an inhuman son, who so far
 surpassed the example of his father: but at the time of his
 death, what tongue would relate the story of the parricide?","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON')"
"The Persian alliance restored the troops of the East to the
 defence of Europe: and Maurice, who had supported ten years
 the insolence of the chagan, declared his resolution to
 march in person against the Barbarians.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('ten years', 'DATE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"The Persians unanimously declared, that
 Chosroes had forfeited the sceptre; a separate treaty was
 concluded with the government of Constantinople; and if some
 considerations of honour or policy restrained Sarbar from
 joining the standard of Heraclius, the emperor was assured
 that he might prosecute, without interruption, his designs
 of victory and peace.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Sarbar', 'PERSON'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON')"
"The Persians were equally successful,
 and more fortunate, in the sack of Caesarea, the capital of
 Cappadocia; and as they advanced beyond the ramparts of the
 frontier, the boundary of ancient war, they found a less
 obstinate resistance and a more plentiful harvest.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Caesarea', 'GPE'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE')"
"The Persians,
 in their turn, retreated with precipitation; in the camp of
 Edessa, Heraclius reviewed an army of seventy thousand
 Romans and strangers; and some months were successfully
 employed in the recovery of the cities of Syria, Mesopotamia
 and Armenia, whose fortifications had been imperfectly
 restored.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Edessa', 'GPE'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('seventy thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('some months', 'DATE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Mesopotamia', 'GPE'), ('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"The Romans, with the faithful subjects of Persia,
 amounted to sixty thousand, while the whole force of the
 usurper did not exceed forty thousand men: the two generals
 signalized their valour and ability; but the victory was
 finally determined by the prevalence of numbers and
 discipline.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('forty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The amorous matron who
 opened the gates of Friuli passed a short night in the arms
 of her royal lover; the next evening, Romilda was condemned
 to the embraces of twelve Avars, and the third day the
 Lombard princess was impaled in the sight of the camp, while
 the chagan observed with a cruel smile, that such a husband
 was the fit recompense of her lewdness and perfidy. (70)","('Friuli', 'GPE'), ('Romilda', 'PERSON'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('Avars', 'NORP'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Lombard', 'PERSON')"
"The angle which the emperor occupied was
 deeply indented into a vast semicircle of the Asiatic,
 Armenian, and Syrian provinces; and to whatsoever point of
 the circumference he should direct his attack, it was easy
 for him to dissemble his own motions, and to prevent those
 of the enemy.","('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Armenian', 'NORP'), ('Syrian', 'NORP')"
"The anxiety
 of Chosroes was soon relieved by the assurance, that the
 emperor had espoused the cause of justice and royalty; but
 Maurice prudently declined the expense and delay of his
 useless visit to Constantinople.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The arms of the Romans, in slow
 sieges and frequent inroads, afflicted the frontiers of
 Mesopotamia and Assyria: one of their generals professed
 himself the disciple of Scipio; and the soldiers were
 animated by a miraculous image of Christ, whose mild aspect
 should never have been displayed in the front of battle.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Mesopotamia', 'LOC'), ('Assyria', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Scipio', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"The arts of
 negotiation, unknown to the simple greatness of the senate
 and the Caesars, were assiduously cultivated by the
 Byzantine princes; and the memorials of their perpetual
 embassies (2) repeat, with the same uniform prolixity, the language of falsehood and declamation, the insolence of the Barbarians, and the servile temper of the tributary Greeks.","('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"The authors of the revolution,
 eager to display their merits in the court or camp of
 Tauris, preceded the ambassadors of Siroes, who delivered
 the letters of their master to his brother the emperor of
 the Romans. (109)","('Tauris', 'PERSON'), ('Siroes', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('109', 'CARDINAL')"
"The beauty of Sira, or Schirin, (21) her
 wit, her musical talents, are still famous in the history,
 or rather in the romances, of the East: her own name is
 expressive, in the Persian tongue, of sweetness and grace;
 and the epithet of Parviz alludes to the charms of her royal
 lover.","('Sira', 'PERSON'), ('Schirin', 'PERSON'), ('21', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Parviz', 'PERSON')"
"The bishop of
 Singidunum presented the gospel, which the chagan received
 with devout reverence.","('Singidunum', 'GPE')"
"The bodies of the father and his five sons were cast into the sea; their heads were exposed at Constantinople to the insults or pity of the multitude; and it was not till some signs of putrefaction had appeared, that Phocas connived at the private burial of these venerable remains.","('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Phocas', 'PERSON')"
"The bridges
 of the Euphrates were destroyed by the Persians; but as soon
 as the emperor had discovered a ford, they hastily retired
 to defend the banks of the Sarus, (92) in Cilicia.","('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Sarus', 'ORG'), ('92', 'CARDINAL'), ('Cilicia', 'GPE')"
"The brother of Maurice attempted to violate this
 privilege, and to mingle a patriot band with the mercenaries
 of his camp; they retired to the church, he was not awed by
 the sanctity of the place; the people rose in their cause,
 the gates were shut, the ramparts were manned; and the
 cowardice of Peter was found equal to his arrogance and
 injustice.","('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('Peter', 'PERSON')"
"The camps both of Asia and Europe
 were agitated with frequent and furious seditions; (41) the
enraged soldiers of Edessa pursued with reproaches, with threats, with wounds, their trembling
generals; they overturned the statues of the emperor, cast stones against the miraculous image of
Christ, and either rejected the yoke of all civil and military laws, or instituted a dangerous model of
voluntary subordination.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('41', 'CARDINAL'), ('Edessa', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"The chagan was encamped in the plains of Thrace; but he
 dissembled his perfidious designs, and solicited an
 interview with the emperor near the town of Heraclea.","('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Heraclea', 'GPE')"
"The churches of Persarmenia were oppressed by the intolerant spirit of the Magi;  they secretly invoked the protector of the Christians, and, after the pious murder of their satraps, the rebels were avowed and supported as the brethren and subjects of the Roman emperor.","('Persarmenia', 'GPE'), ('Magi', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The complaints of Nushirvan were disregarded by the Byzantine court; Justin yielded to the importunities of the Turks, who offered an alliance against the common enemy; and the Persian monarchy was threatened at the same instant by the united forces of Europe, of Aethiopia, and of Scythia.","('Nushirvan', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Aethiopia', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'ORG')"
"The conflict of Rome and Persia was prolonged from the death
 of Craesus to the reign of Heraclius.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Craesus', 'PERSON'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON')"
"The conquest of Jerusalem, (60) which had been
 meditated by Nushirvan, was achieved by the zeal and avarice
 of his grandson; the ruin of the proudest monument of
 Christianity was vehemently urged by the intolerant spirit
 of the Magi; and he could enlist for this holy warfare with
 an army of six-and- twenty thousand Jews, whose furious
 bigotry might compensate, in some degree, for the want of
 valour and discipline.","('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('60', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nushirvan', 'PERSON'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Magi', 'PERSON'), ('six-and- twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jews', 'NORP')"
"The conscience of the
 emperor was oppressed by the obligation of restoring the
 wealth of the clergy, which he had borrowed for their own
 defence: a perpetual fund was required to satisfy these
 inexorable creditors; the provinces, already wasted by the
 arms and avarice of the Persians, were compelled to a second
 payment of the same taxes; and the arrears of a simple
 citizen, the treasurer of Damascus, were commuted to a fine
 of one hundred thousand pieces of gold.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('one hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The defection was rapid and universal;
 his loyal slaves were sacrificed to the public fury; the
 troops deserted to the standard of Bahram; and the provinces
 again saluted the deliverer of his country.","('Bahram', 'GPE')"
"The despair of a captive, whom his country refused to ransom, disclosed to the Avars the invention and practice of
 military engines. (30)","('Avars', 'PRODUCT'), ('30', 'CARDINAL')"
"The despatches were transmitted to
 Sarbar himself; and as soon as he read the sentence of his
 own death, he dexterously inserted the names of four hundred
 officers, assembled a military council, and asked the
 Cadarigan whether he was prepared to execute the commands of
 their tyrant.","('Sarbar', 'PERSON'), ('four hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Cadarigan', 'PERSON')"
"The devotion of
 the Romans ascribed this signal deliverance to the Virgin
 Mary; but the mother of Christ would surely have condemned
 their inhuman murder of the Persian envoys, who were
 entitled to the rights of humanity, if they were not
 protected by the laws of nations. (97)","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('the Virgin\r\n Mary', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The diligence of Heraclius was not less
 admirable in the use of victory; by a march of forty-eight
 miles in four-and-twenty hours, his vanguard occupied the
 bridges of the great and the lesser Zab; and the cities and
 palaces of Assyria were open for the first time to the
 Romans.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('forty-eight\r\n miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('four-and-twenty hours', 'TIME'), ('Zab', 'PERSON'), ('Assyria', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The discovery or the suspicion of a second
 conspiracy, dissolved the engagements, and rekindled the
 fury, of Phocas. and tyranny.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Phocas', 'NORP')"
"The emperor suspected the popularity of Germanus with
 the soldiers and citizens: he feared, he threatened, but he
 delayed to strike; the patrician fled to the sanctuary of
 the church; the people rose in his defence, the walls were
 deserted by the guards, and the lawless city was abandoned
 to the flames and rapine of a nocturnal tumult.","('Germanus', 'PERSON')"
"The enemies were dispersed and dismayed; Heraclius
 pursued his march to Sebaste in Cappadocia; and at the
 expiration of three years, the same coast of the Euxine
 applauded his return from a long and victorious expedition.
 (93)
Deliverance of Constantinople from the Persians and Avars, A.D. 626.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Sebaste', 'GPE'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE'), ('three years', 'DATE'), ('Euxine', 'PERSON'), ('93', 'CARDINAL'), ('Deliverance of Constantinople', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('626', 'CARDINAL')"
"The example of her warlike youth was propagated to
 succeeding generations; and they obtained, from the first or
 the second Justin, an honourable privilege, that their valour
 should be always reserved for the defence of their native
 country.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Justin', 'PERSON')"
"The father must desire that his
 posterity should inherit the fruit of his crimes, but the
 monarch was offended by this premature and popular
 association: the tribunes of the green faction, who accused
 the officious error of their sculptors, were condemned to
 instant death: their lives were granted to the prayers of
 the people; but Crispus might reasonably doubt, whether a
 jealous usurper could forget and pardon his involuntary
 competition.","('Crispus', 'PERSON')"
"The first army of fifty thousand men,
 illustrious by the ornament and title of the golden spears,
 was destined to march against Heraclius; the second was
 stationed to prevent his junction with the troops of his
