Sentence,Entities
"""Spare the king of Italy,""  cried a loyal voice, and Asbad struck his lance through the body of Totila.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Asbad', 'PERSON'), ('Totila', 'PERSON')"
"""The eighth
 day,"" replied Totila; but early the next morning he attempted to surprise a foe, suspicious of deceit, and prepared for battle.","('The eighth\r\n day', 'DATE'), ('Totila', 'PERSON'), ('the next morning', 'TIME')"
(33),"('33', 'CARDINAL')"
(43),"('43', 'CARDINAL')"
(44),"('44', 'CARDINAL')"
"(5)
Revolt of the Goths, A.D. 540.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('540', 'CARDINAL')"
(54),"('54', 'CARDINAL')"
(75),"('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 bold assassin executed their sentence by striking off the
 head of Hildibald in the midst of a banquet; the Rugians, a
 foreign tribe, assumed the privilege of election: and
 Totila,  the nephew of the late king, was tempted, by
 revenge, to deliver himself and the garrison of Trevigo into
 the hands of the Romans.","('Hildibald', 'PERSON'), ('Rugians', 'NORP'), ('Totila', 'PERSON'), ('Trevigo', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"A Moorish tribe encamped under the
 walls of Leptis, to renew their alliance, and receive from
 the governor the customary gifts.","('Moorish', 'NORP'), ('Leptis', 'GPE')"
"A feeble youth, the grandson of
 Clovis, reigned over the Austrasians or oriental Franks.","('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Austrasians', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"A fleet and army sailed for the relief of
 Sicily, under the conduct of Liberius; but his youth  and want of experience were afterwards discovered, and before he
 touched the shores of the island he was overtaken by his
 successor.","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Liberius', 'PERSON')"
"A generous emulation inspired the
 Romans and their Barbarian allies; and Narses, who calmly
 viewed and directed their efforts, doubted to whom he should
 adjudge the prize of superior bravery.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"A hero on the banks of the
 Euphrates, a slave in the palace of Constantinople, he
 accepted with reluctance the painful task of supporting his
 own reputation, and retrieving the faults of his successors.","('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"A menace of killing their prisoners
 quickened the payment of heavy ransoms; and the departure of
 Zabergan was hastened by the report, that double-prowed
 vessels were built on the Danube to intercept his passage.","('Zabergan', 'PERSON'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"A personal injury, the unjust
 execution or murder of his brother, rendered Antalas the
 enemy of the Romans.","('Antalas', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"A rapacious minister of the finances closely pursued the footsteps of Belisarius; and as the old registers of tribute had been burnt by the Vandals, he indulged his fancy in a
 liberal calculation and arbitrary assessment of the wealth
 of Africa. (1)","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('1', 'CARDINAL')"
"A soldier trained in the school
 of Belisarius, Paul of Cilicia, retired with four hundred
 men to the mole of Hadrian.","('Belisarius', 'GPE'), ('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Cilicia', 'GPE'), ('four hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hadrian', 'PERSON')"
"A splendid
 allowance was assigned by the emperor: the general
 contribute his private fortune: his two sons were popular
 and active and he surpassed, in the promptitude and success
 of his levies the expectation of mankind.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"A stranger to the schools and the camp, he
 studied in the palace to dissemble, to flatter, and to
 persuade; and as soon as he approached the person of the
 emperor, Justinian listened with surprise and pleasure to
 the manly counsels of his chamberlain and private treasurer.
 (30)","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('30', 'CARDINAL')"
"A.D. 526, May 20.","('A.D. 526', 'DATE'), ('May 20', 'DATE')"
"A.D. 551, July 9.","('A.D. 551', 'DATE'), ('July 9', 'DATE')"
"A.D. 565, March 13.","('A.D. 565', 'DATE'), ('March 13', 'DATE')"
"About two years after the last victory of Belisarius, the
 emperor returned from a Thracian journey of health, or
 business, or devotion.","('About two years', 'DATE'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Thracian', 'NORP')"
"Absolute in the exercise of his authority, more absolute in
 the affection of his troops, Narses led a numerous and
 gallant army from Philippopolis to Salona, from whence he
 coasted the eastern side of the Adriatic as far as the
 confines of Italy.","('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Philippopolis', 'GPE'), ('Salona', 'GPE'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Aethiopia and Egypt have been stigmatized, in every
 age, as the original source and seminary of the plague. (87)","('Aethiopia', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('87', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a
 long silence, Belisarius was commanded to leave a sufficient
 garrison at Rome, and to transport himself into the province
 of Lucania, whose inhabitants, inflamed by Catholic zeal,
 had cast away the yoke of their Arian conquerors.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Lucania', 'GPE'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Arian', 'NORP')"
"After a combat of many hours, his left arm was
 fatigued by the weight of twelve javelins which hung from
 his shield.","('many hours', 'TIME'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a period of thirteen centuries, the
 institution of Romulus expired; and if the nobles of Rome
 still assumed the title of senators, few subsequent traces
 can be discovered of a public council, or constitutional
 order.","('thirteen centuries', 'DATE'), ('Romulus', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"After a reign of sixty years, the throne of the Gothic kings
 was filled by the exarchs of Ravenna, the representatives in
 peace and war of the emperor of the Romans.","('sixty years', 'DATE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"After a reign of thirty
 days, Gontharis himself was stabbed at a banquet by the hand
 of Artaban;  and it is singular enough, that an Armenian  prince, of the royal family of Arsaces, should reestablish
 at Carthage the authority of the Roman empire.","('thirty\r\n days', 'DATE'), ('Gontharis', 'PERSON'), ('Artaban', 'PERSON'), ('Armenian', 'NORP'), ('Arsaces', 'PERSON'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"After his patience had been exhausted by delay and disappointment, the Roman general repassed the Adriatic, and expected at Dyrrachium the arrival of the troops, which were slowly assembled among the subjects and allies of the empire.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC'), ('Dyrrachium', 'ORG')"
"After reducing, by force, or treaty, the towns of inferior
 note in the midland provinces of Italy, Totila proceeded,
 not to assault, but to encompass and starve, the ancient
 capital.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Totila', 'GPE')"
"After the
 battle of Casilinum, Narses entered the capital; the arms
 and treasures of the Goths, the Franks, and the Alamanni,
 were displayed; his soldiers, with garlands in their hands,
 chanted the praises of the conqueror; and Rome, for the last
 time, beheld the semblance of a triumph.","('Casilinum', 'GPE'), ('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Alamanni', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"After the death of
 Caesar, a long-haired star was conspicuous to Rome and to
 the nations, during the games which were exhibited by young
 Octavian in honor of Venus and his uncle.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Octavian', 'PERSON'), ('Venus', 'PERSON')"
"After the death of Teias, the Roman general
 separated his troops to reduce the cities of Italy; Lucca
 sustained a long and vigorous siege: and such was the
 humanity or the prudence of Narses, that the repeated
 perfidy of the inhabitants could not provoke him to exact
 the forfeit lives of their hostages.","('Teias', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Lucca', 'GPE'), ('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"After the departure
 of Totila, the Roman general sallied from the port at the
 head of a thousand horse, cut in pieces the enemy who
 opposed his progress, and visited with pity and reverence
 the vacant space of the eternal city.","('Totila', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('a thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the loss of Germanus, the nations were provoked to
 smile, by the strange intelligence, that the command of the
 Roman armies was given to a eunuch.","('Germanus', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"After the reduction of Naples and Cumae, the
 provinces of Lucania, Apulia, and Calabria, submitted to the
 king of the Goths.","('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Cumae', 'GPE'), ('Lucania', 'GPE'), ('Apulia', 'GPE'), ('Calabria', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"Against
 the city which had so long delayed the course of his
 victories, he appeared inexorable: one third of the walls,
 in different parts, were demolished by his command; fire and
 engines prepared to consume or subvert the most stately
 works of antiquity; and the world was astonished by the
 fatal decree, that Rome should be changed into a pasture for
 cattle.","('one third', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"An impulsive or vibratory motion was
 felt: enormous chasms were opened, huge and heavy bodies
 were discharged into the air, the sea alternately advanced
 and retreated beyond its ordinary bounds, and a mountain was
 torn from Libanus, (84) and cast into the waves, where it
 protected, as a mole, the new harbor of Botrys (85) in Phoenicia.","('Libanus', 'GPE'), ('84', 'CARDINAL'), ('Botrys', 'PRODUCT'), ('85', 'CARDINAL'), ('Phoenicia', 'GPE')"
"An officer in whom Belisarius confided was sent from Ravenna to hasten and conduct the succours; but the message was neglected, and the messenger was detained at Constantinople by an advantageous marriage.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"And this appearance
 explains the tradition which Varro has preserved, that under
 his reign the planet Venus changed her color, size, figure,
 and course; a prodigy without example either in past or
 succeeding ages. (78)","('Varro', 'PERSON'), ('Venus', 'LOC')"
"As
 early as the fourth campaign, under the discipline of
 Belisarius himself, fifty thousand laborers died of hunger
 (58) in the narrow region of Picenum; (59) and a strict
 interpretation of the evidence of Procopius would swell the
 loss of Italy above the total sum of her present
 inhabitants. (60)
Invasion of the Bulgarians, A.D. 559.","('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('58', 'CARDINAL'), ('Picenum', 'GPE'), ('59', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('60', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bulgarians', 'NORP'), ('559', 'CARDINAL')"
"As he marched without
 order or precaution along the Aemilian way, an ambuscade of
 Franks suddenly rose from the amphitheatre of Parma; his
 troops were surprised and routed; but their leader refused
 to fly; declaring to the last moment, that death was less
 terrible than the angry countenance of Narses.","('Aemilian', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Parma', 'GPE'), ('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as Narses had paid his devotions to the Author of
 victory, and the blessed Virgin, his peculiar patroness, (38)
 he praised, rewarded, and dismissed the Lombards.","('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Virgin', 'PERSON'), ('38', 'DATE'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as daylight had displayed
 the entire victory of the Goths, their monarch devoutly
 visited the tomb of the prince of the apostles; but while he
 prayed at the altar, twenty-five soldiers, and sixty
 citizens, were put to the sword in the vestibule of the
 temple.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('twenty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('sixty', 'CARDINAL')"
"As soon as they
 touched the principal barrier, the fire- ship was instantly
 grappled to the bridge; one of the towers, with two hundred
 Goths, was consumed by the flames; the assailants shouted
 victory; and Rome was saved, if the wisdom of Belisarius had
 not been defeated by the misconduct of his officers.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('two hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"As their own, by the double right of conquest and
 inheritance, they claimed the estates which Genseric had
 assigned to his victorious troops.","('Genseric', 'PERSON')"
"Ascend six hundred years, and contemplate the kings
 of the earth soliciting an audience, as the slaves or
 freedmen of the Roman senate! (41)
Defeat and death of Teias, the last king of the Goths, A.D. 553, March.","('six hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('41', 'CARDINAL'), ('Teias', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 553', 'DATE'), ('March', 'DATE')"
"At his humble prayer, the lives of the Romans were spared; and the chastity of the maids and matrons was preserved inviolate from the passions of the hungry soldiers.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"At length a fleet and army were assembled for the relief of
 Ruscianum, or Rossano, (18) a fortress sixty furlongs from
 the ruins of Sybaris, where the nobles of Lucania had taken
 refuge.","('Ruscianum', 'GPE'), ('Rossano', 'GPE'), ('18', 'CARDINAL'), ('sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sybaris', 'GPE'), ('Lucania', 'GPE')"
"At length his innocence was acknowledged; his
 freedom and honor were restored; and death, which might be
 hastened by resentment and grief, removed him from the world
 in about eight months after his deliverance.","('about eight months', 'DATE')"
"At the command, or at least in
 the name, of a Catholic emperor, the pope, (7) their
 spiritual father, had been torn from the Roman church, and
 either starved or murdered on a desolate island. (8)","('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('7', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"At the distance of sixty furlongs the Roman generals halted
 to regulate the division of the spoil.","('sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"At the distance only of two bow-shots, the armies spent the morning in dreadful suspense, and the Romans tasted some necessary food, without unloosing the cuirass from their breast, or the bridle from their horses.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('the morning', 'TIME'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"At the eighth period, in the year two thousand three hundred and fifty-five, their calculations may perhaps be verified by the astronomers of some future capital in the Siberian or American wilderness.","('eighth', 'ORDINAL'), ('the year two thousand three hundred and fifty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Siberian', 'NORP'), ('American', 'NORP')"
"At the entrance of the spring, the Imperial troops, who had
 guarded the cities, assembled, to the number of eighteen
 thousand men, in the neighborhood of Rome.","('the spring', 'DATE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('eighteen\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"At the expiration of twenty-five days, Totila
 returned by hasty marches from Apulia to avenge the injury
 and disgrace.","('twenty-five days', 'DATE'), ('Totila', 'PERSON'), ('Apulia', 'GPE')"
Attempt of Belisarius.,"('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Before Lucca had surrendered, Italy was overwhelmed by a new
 deluge of Barbarians.","('Lucca', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"Before the departure of Belisarius, Perusia was besieged,
 and few cities were impregnable to the Gothic arms.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Perusia', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"Before the third hour of the day, the bakers'
 shops were plundered of their bread, the houses were shut,
 and every citizen, with hope or terror, prepared for the
 impending tumult.","('the third hour of the day', 'TIME')"
"Belisarius appeared before
 the council with less fear than indignation: after forty
 years' service, the emperor had prejudged his guilt; and
 injustice was sanctified by the presence and authority of
 the patriarch.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), (""forty\r\n years'"", 'DATE')"
Belisarius expected his approach.,"('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Belisarius himself
 had always understood, that riches, in a corrupt age, are
 the support and ornament of personal merit.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Belisarius reposed from his toils,
 in the high station of general of the East and count of the
 domestics; and the older consuls and patricians respectfully
 yielded the precedency of rank to the peerless merit of the
 first of the Romans. (20)","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('20', 'CARDINAL')"
"Belisarius reposed in the shade
 of his laurels, but the command of the principal army was
 reserved for Germanus, (26) the emperor's nephew, whose rank and merit had been long depressed by the jealousy of the court.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Germanus', 'PERSON'), ('26', 'CARDINAL')"
"Belisarius soon discovered, that he was sent to remain the idle and impotent spectator of the glory of a young Barbarian; and his own epistle exhibits a genuine and lively picture of the distress of a noble mind.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
"Bessas replied, with
 unfeeling tranquillity, that it was impossible to feed,
 unsafe to dismiss, and unlawful to kill, the subjects of the
 emperor.","('Bessas', 'PERSON')"
"Buccelin was
 actuated by ambition, and Lothaire by avarice.","('Lothaire', 'PERSON')"
"Buccelin, and the greatest part of
 his army, perished on the field of battle, in the waters of
 the Vulturnus, or by the hands of the enraged peasants: but
 it may seem incredible, that a victory, (52) which no more
 than five of the Alamanni survived, could be purchased with
 the loss of fourscore Romans.","('Buccelin', 'PERSON'), ('Vulturnus', 'NORP'), ('52', 'CARDINAL'), ('no more\r\n than five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alamanni', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"But
 his friends were numerous in the councils of the emperor,
 and Belisarius obeyed with reluctance the commands of envy
 and Justinian, which forbade him to achieve the deliverance
 of his country.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"But
 the Goths soon embraced a more generous resolution: to
 descend the hill, to dismiss their horses, and to die in
 arms, and in the possession of freedom.","('Goths', 'NORP')"
"But
 the officer who succeeded to the command (his name was
 Diogenes) deserved their esteem and confidence; and the
 Goths, instead of finding an easy conquest, encountered a
 vigorous resistance from the soldiers and people, who
 patiently endured the loss of the port and of all maritime
 supplies.","('Diogenes', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"But a generous band of four
 hundred obliged the mariners, when they were in sight of the
 Isle of Lesbos, to alter their course: they touched on
 Peloponnesus, ran ashore on a desert coast of Africa, and
 boldly erected, on Mount Aurasius, the standard of
 independence and revolt.","('four\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('the\r\n Isle of Lesbos', 'GPE'), ('Peloponnesus', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Mount Aurasius', 'LOC')"
"But avarice rendered Bessas immovable; while
 the youthful ardor of Isaac delivered him into the hands of
 a superior enemy.","('Bessas', 'PERSON'), ('Isaac', 'PERSON')"
"But he was conscious that the
 clergy and people of Italy aspired to a second revolution:
 he felt or suspected the rapid progress of treason; and he
 resolved to risk the Gothic kingdom on the chance of a day,
 in which the valiant would be animated by instant danger and
 the disaffected might be awed by mutual ignorance.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('a day', 'DATE')"
"But if they continued hard and dry, a mortification
 quickly ensued, and the fifth day was commonly the term of
 his life.","('the fifth day', 'DATE')"
"But the Barbarians
 were exasperated by the report, that she had prompted the people to overthrow the statues of the great Theodoric; and the life of that venerable matron would have been sacrificed to his memory, if Totila had not respected her birth, her virtues, and even the pious motive of her revenge.","('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Totila', 'PERSON')"
"But the churches which their piety had
 spared, were stripped by the sacrilegious hands of the
 Alamanni, who sacrificed horses' heads to their native
 deities of the woods and rivers; (49) they melted or profaned
 the consecrated vessels, and the ruins of shrines and altars
 were stained with the blood of the faithful.","('Alamanni', 'NORP'), ('49', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the dagger of conspiracy (19) awaited his
 return.","('19', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the deliverance of Rome
 was the last calamity of the Roman people.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But the emperor, alarmed by the distress and
 danger of his Italian conquests, despatched to the relief of
 Naples a fleet of galleys and a body of Thracian and
 Armenian soldiers.","('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Thracian', 'NORP'), ('Armenian', 'NORP')"
"But the enterprise of forcing these barriers, and relieving
 the capital, displays a shining example of the boldness and
 conduct of Belisarius.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"But the eunuch Narses
 (29) is ranked among the few who have rescued that unhappy
 name from the contempt and hatred of mankind.","('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('29', 'DATE')"
"But the eyes of the prince and people were directed to a
 feeble veteran, who was compelled by the public danger to
 resume the armor in which he had entered Carthage and
 defended Rome.","('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But the fatal security, like the
 predestination of the Turks, must have aided the progress of
 the contagion; and those salutary precautions to which
 Europe is indebted for her safety, were unknown to the
 government of Justinian.","('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Justinian', 'ORG')"
"But the gallant and accomplished
 youth was easily persuaded to prefer the Gothic throne
 before the service of Justinian; and as soon as the palace
 of Pavia had been purified from the Rugian usurper, he
 reviewed the national force of five thousand soldiers, and
 generously undertook the restoration of the kingdom of
 Italy.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Pavia', 'GPE'), ('Rugian', 'NORP'), ('five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"But the indiscretion of an accomplice saved
 the poor remnant of the days of Justinian.","('the days of Justinian', 'DATE')"
"But the name of the
 emperor is eclipsed by the names of his victorious generals;
 and Belisarius still lives, to upbraid the envy and
 ingratitude of his sovereign.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"But the places of the brave
 Armenians were insensibly supplied by lazy citizens, who
 purchased an exemption from the duties of civil life,
 without being exposed to the dangers of military service.","('Armenians', 'NORP')"
"But the power of Theodora expired, the parents of
 Joannina returned, and her honor, perhaps her happiness,
 were sacrificed to the revenge of an unfeeling mother, who
 dissolved the imperfect nuptials before they had been
 ratified by the ceremonies of the church. (22)","('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('Joannina', 'PERSON'), ('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the power of kings is most
 effectual to destroy; and the twenty years of the Gothic war
 had consummated the distress and depopulation of Italy.","('the twenty years', 'DATE'), ('the Gothic war', 'EVENT'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"But the spirit of a martial people outstripped
 the timid counsels of the court: two brothers, Lothaire and
 Buccelin, (48) the dukes of the Alemanni, stood forth as the
 leaders of the Italian war; and seventy-five thousand
 Germans descended in the autumn from the Rhaetian Alps into
 the plain of Milan.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Lothaire', 'PERSON'), ('Buccelin', 'PERSON'), ('48', 'DATE'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('the Italian war', 'EVENT'), ('seventy-five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('the Rhaetian Alps', 'LOC'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"But the vices of the Byzantine
 court were felt in that distant province; the troops
 complained that they were neither paid nor relieved, and as
 soon as the public disorders were sufficiently mature, Stoza
 was again alive, in arms, and at the gates of Carthage.","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Stoza', 'PERSON'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"But the victories and the losses of Justinian were alike pernicious to mankind; and such was the
 desolation of Africa, that in many parts a stranger might wander whole days without meeting the face either of a friend or an enemy.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('whole days', 'DATE')"
"But the wars, the conquests, and the triumphs of Justinian, are the feeble and pernicious efforts of old age, which exhaust the remains of strength, and accelerate the decay of the powers of life.","('Justinian', 'NORP')"
"But the works of man are impotent against
 the assaults of nature: a recent earthquake had shaken the
 foundations of the wall; and the forces of the empire were
 employed on the distant frontiers of Italy, Africa, and
 Persia.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"But their spirit
 insensibly stooped to the offers of capitulation; they
 retrieved their arrears of pay, and preserved their arms and
 horses, by enlisting in the service of Totila; their chiefs,
 who pleaded a laudable attachment to their wives and
 children in the East, were dismissed with honor; and above
 four hundred enemies, who had taken refuge in the
 sanctuaries, were saved by the clemency of the victor.","('Totila', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('four hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"But they heard the shouts of
 multitudes, they beheld the arms and discipline of the
 front; they were assaulted on the flanks by two ambuscades
 which rose from the woods; their foremost warriors fell by
 the hand of the aged hero and his gnards; and the swiftness
 of their evolutions was rendered useless by the close attack
 and rapid pursuit of the Romans.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"By his command the vessels of gold
 and silver were removed from the churches in the
 neighborhood, and even the suburbs, of Constantinople; the
 ramparts were lined with trembling spectators; the golden
 gate was crowded with useless generals and tribunes, and the
 senate shared the fatigues and the apprehensions of the
 populace.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"By the command, and
 after the example, of Narses, they repeated each day their
 military exercise on foot and on horseback, accustomed their
 ear to obey the sound of the trumpet, and practised the
 steps and evolutions of the Pyrrhic dance.","('Narses', 'NORP'), ('Pyrrhic', 'NORP')"
"Capricious pardon and
 arbitrary punishment imbittered the irksomeness and
 discontent of a long reign: a conspiracy was formed in the
 palace; and, unless we are deceived by the names of
 Marcellus and Sergius, the most virtuous and the most
 profligate of the courtiers were associated in the same
 designs.","('Marcellus', 'PERSON'), ('Sergius', 'PERSON')"
"Character and expedition of the eunuch Narses, A.D. 552.","('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('552', 'CARDINAL')"
"Comets, A.D. 531, 539.","('531', 'CARDINAL'), ('539', 'CARDINAL')"
"Compassion afforded him the shelter of an obscure tomb; but the Romans were not satisfied of their victory, till they beheld the corpse of the Gothic king.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"Dagistheus
 was released from prison to command the Huns; and Kobad, the
 grandson and nephew of the great king, was conspicuous by
 the regal tiara at the head of his faithful Persians, who
 had devoted themselves to the fortunes of their prince. (32)","('Dagistheus', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'PERSON'), ('Kobad', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"Death and Character of Justinian—  Comets, Earthquakes, and Plague","('Death and Character of Justinian', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Defeat and death of Totila, A.D. 552, July.","('Totila', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 552', 'DATE'), ('July', 'DATE')"
"Defeat of the Franks and Alamanni by Narses, A.D. 554.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Alamanni', 'PERSON'), ('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('554', 'CARDINAL')"
"Delay afforded time for rash communications and honest
 confessions: Artaban and his accomplices were condemned by
 the senate, but the extreme clemency of Justinian detained
 them in the gentle confinement of the palace, till he
 pardoned their flagitious attempt against his throne and
 life.","('Artaban', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"During his sickness,
 the public consternation was expressed in the habits of the
 citizens; and their idleness and despondence occasioned a
 general scarcity in the capital of the East.","('East', 'LOC')"
"Each of the wings was composed of eight thousand Romans; the right was guarded by the cavalry of the Huns, the left was covered by fifteen hundred chosen horse, destined, according to the emergencies of action, to sustain the retreat of their friends, or to encompass the flank of the enemy.","('eight thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('fifteen hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"Each year is marked by the repetition of earthquakes, of
 such duration, that Constantinople has been shaken above
 forty days; of such extent, that the shock has been
 communicated to the whole surface of the globe, or at least
 of the Roman empire.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('forty days', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Eight years afterwards, while
 the sun was in Capricorn, another comet appeared to follow
 in the Sagittary; the size was gradually increasing; the
 head was in the east, the tail in the west, and it remained
 visible above forty days.","('Eight years afterwards', 'DATE'), ('Capricorn', 'LOC'), ('Sagittary', 'LOC'), ('forty days', 'DATE')"
"Extent and duration, A.D. 542-594.","('A.D. 542-594', 'DATE')"
"Famine had relaxed the strength and discipline of the
 garrison of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Fear or remorse restrained the daggers of the assassins, but
 the patience of Solomon emboldened their discontent; and, at
 the end of ten days, a furious sedition was kindled in the
 Circus, which desolated Africa above ten years.","('Solomon', 'PERSON'), ('the end of ten days', 'DATE'), ('Circus', 'FAC'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('ten years', 'DATE')"
"Final recall of Belisarius, A.D. 548, September.","('Belisarius', 'PRODUCT'), ('A.D. 548', 'DATE'), ('September', 'DATE')"
"Forgetful of the past, and regardless of the
 future, they abused the present hour of prosperity and
 peace.","('the present hour', 'TIME')"
"Four
 Isaurian sentinels, while their companions slept, and their
 officers were absent, descended by a rope from the wall, and
 secretly proposed to the Gothic king to introduce his troops
 into the city.","('Four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Isaurian', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"Fourscore of their
 deputies were introduced as friends into the city; but on
 the dark suspicion of a conspiracy, they were massacred at
 the table of Sergius, and the clamor of arms and revenge was
 reechoed through the valleys of Mount Atlas from both the
 Syrtes to the Atlantic Ocean.","('Sergius', 'PERSON'), ('Mount Atlas', 'LOC'), ('Syrtes', 'LOC'), ('the Atlantic Ocean', 'LOC')"
"From his new acquisitions, Justinian expected that his avarice, as well as pride, should be richly gratified.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"From the Alps to the foot
 of Mount Vesuvius, the Gothic king, by rapid and secret
 marches, advanced to the relief of his brother, eluded the
 vigilance of the Roman chiefs, and pitched his camp on the
 banks of the Sarnus or Draco, (42) which flows from Nuceria
 into the Bay of Naples.","('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Mount Vesuvius', 'LOC'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Sarnus', 'PRODUCT'), ('Draco', 'PRODUCT'), ('42', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nuceria', 'GPE'), ('the Bay of Naples', 'LOC')"
"From the Straits
 of Sicily, Buccelin, with thirty thousand Franks and
 Alamanni, slowly moved towards Capua, occupied with a wooden
 tower the bridge of Casilinum, covered his right by the
 stream of the Vulturnus, and secured the rest of his
 encampment by a rampart of sharp stakes, and a circle of
 wagons, whose wheels were buried in the earth.","('the Straits\r\n of Sicily', 'LOC'), ('Buccelin', 'GPE'), ('thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Alamanni', 'NORP'), ('Capua', 'GPE'), ('Casilinum', 'GPE'), ('Vulturnus', 'FAC')"
"From the event of a single combat they drew an omen of success; and they beheld with pleasure the courage of fifty archers, who maintained a small eminence against three successive attacks of the Gothic cavalry.","('fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"From thence, tracing as it were a
 double path, it spread to the East, over Syria, Persia, and
 the Indies, and penetrated to the West, along the coast of
 Africa, and over the continent of Europe.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Indies', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"From this salutary slumber the emperor was awakened by the
 pope Vigilius and the patrician Cethegus, who appeared
 before his throne, and adjured him, in the name of God and
 the people, to resume the conquest and deliverance of Italy.","('Vigilius', 'PERSON'), ('Cethegus', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Future princes were more just or indulgent to his memory;
 the elder Andronicus, in the beginning of the fourteenth
 century, repaired and beautified his equestrian statue:
 since the fall of the empire it has been melted into cannon
 by the victorious Turks. (73)","('Andronicus', 'PERSON'), ('the beginning of the fourteenth\r\n century', 'DATE'), ('Turks', 'NORP')"
"He
 impatiently expected the return of Lothaire; ignorant, alas!","('Lothaire', 'PERSON')"
"He
 no longer entertained a wish of destroying the edifices of
 Rome, (23) which he now respected as the seat of the Gothic
 kingdom: the senate and people were restored to their
 country; the means of subsistence were liberally provided;
 and Totila, in the robe of peace, exhibited the equestrian
 games of the circus.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('23', 'DATE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Totila', 'PERSON')"
"He
 reposed in his winter quarters of Crotona, in the full
 assurance, that the two passes of the Lucanian hills were
 guarded by his cavalry.","('winter', 'DATE'), ('Crotona', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Lucanian', 'NORP')"
"He aspired to Praejecta, the emperor's niece,
 who wished to reward her deliverer; but the impediment of
 his previous marriage was asserted by the piety of Theodora.","('Praejecta', 'PERSON'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"He excelled in the private virtues of chastity and temperance: but the impartial love of beauty would have been less mischievous than his conjugal tenderness for Theodora; and his abstemious diet was regulated, not by the prudence of a philosopher, but the superstition of a monk.","('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"He exulted in the glorious act of restoring Africa and Italy to the republic; but the calamities which followed the departure of Belisarius betrayed the impotence of the conqueror, and accomplished the ruin of those unfortunate countries.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"He fell; and
 his head, exalted on a spear, proclaimed to the nations that
 the Gothic kingdom was no more.","('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"He forgot, or perhaps he secretly
 recollected, that the plague had touched the person of
 Justinian himself; but the abstemious diet of the emperor
 may suggest, as in the case of Socrates, a more rational and
 honorable cause for his recovery. (92)","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Socrates', 'PERSON')"
"He had
 previously sent orders to Bessas to second his operations by
 a timely sally from the town; and he had fixed his
 lieutenant, Isaac, by a peremptory command, to the station
 of the port.","('Bessas', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Isaac', 'PERSON')"
"He raised himself
 to a level with Belisarius, and the nephew of the emperor,
 by daring to encounter them in the field; and the victorious
 generals were compelled to acknowledge that Stoza deserved a
 purer cause, and a more legitimate command.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Stoza', 'PERSON')"
"He sincerely
 accomplished the articles of capitulation, without seeking
 or accepting any sinister advantage from ambiguous
 expressions or unforeseen events: the garrison of Naples had
 stipulated that they should be transported by sea; the
 obstinacy of the winds prevented their voyage, but they were
 generously supplied with horses, provisions, and a
 safe-conduct to the gates of Rome.","('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"He was permitted
 to select some squadrons of Thracian cavalry: the veterans,
 as well as the youth of Constantinople and Europe, engaged
 their voluntary service; and as far as the heart of Germany,
 his fame and liberality attracted the aid of the Barbarians.","('Thracian', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"His
 powers were still inadequate to the deliverance of Rome, which was closely besieged by the Gothic king.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"His
 valor had formerly triumphed over the Sclavonians of the
 Danube and the rebels of Africa: the first report of his
 promotion revived the hopes of the Italians; and he was
 privately assured, that a crowd of Roman deserters would
 abandon, on his approach, the standard of Totila.","('Sclavonians', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Italians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Totila', 'PERSON')"
"His disgrace and death, A.D. 561.","('A.D. 561', 'DATE')"
"His first public oration was addressed
 to the Goths and Romans, in the name of the emperor, who had
 suspended for a while the conquest of Persia, and listened
 to the prayers of his Italian subjects.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Persia', 'LOC'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
"His followers were impatient to fly;  A.D. 563, December 5. but flight
 must have been supported by rebellion, and he had lived
 enough for nature and for glory.","('A.D. 563', 'DATE'), ('December 5', 'DATE')"
"His hat, enriched with gems, and his bloody robe, were presented to Justinian by the messengers of triumph. (37)
Conquest of Rome by Narses.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('37', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"His infantry and provisions were
 distributed in two hundred large boats; and each boat was
 shielded by a high rampart of thick planks, pierced with
 many small holes for the discharge of missile weapons.","('two hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"His powers were the last effort of the state; the
 cost of each day accumulated the enormous account; and the
 nations, untrained to discipline or fatigue, might be rashly
 provoked to turn their arms against each other, or against
 their benefactor.","('each day', 'DATE')"
"His prudence, and the labor of the
 friendly peasants, secured, with a ditch and rampart, the
 repose of the night; innumerable fires, and clouds of dust,
 were artfully contrived to magnify the opinion of his
 strength; his soldiers suddenly passed from despondency to
 presumption; and, while ten thousand voices demanded the
 battle, Belisarius dissembled his knowledge, that in the
 hour of trial he must depend on the firmness of three
 hundred veterans.","('the night', 'TIME'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n hour', 'TIME'), ('three\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"His repasts
 were short and frugal: on solemn fasts, he contented himself with water and vegetables; and such was his strength, as well as fervour, that he frequently passed two days, and as
 many nights, without tasting any food.","('two days', 'DATE')"
"His second
 marriage with Malasontha, the granddaughter of Theodoric
 endeared Germanus to the Goths themselves; and they marched
 with reluctance against the father of a royal infant the
 last offspring of the line of Amali. (27)","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Malasontha', 'PERSON'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Germanus', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Amali', 'PERSON'), ('27', 'CARDINAL')"
"His skilful movements intercepted
 the subsistence of the Barbarian, deprived him of the
 advantage of the bridge and river, and in the choice of the
 ground and moment of action reduced him to comply with the
 inclination of his enemy.","('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
"His troops were disposed (51) in a long front,
 the cavalry on the wings; in the centre, the heavy-armed
 foot; the archers and slingers in the rear.","('51', 'CARDINAL')"
"His voice
 inclined the election in favor of Hildibald, whose personal
 merit was recommended by the vain hope that his kinsman
 Theudes, the Spanish monarch, would support the common
 interest of the Gothic nation.","('Hildibald', 'PERSON'), ('Theudes', 'PERSON'), ('Spanish', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"I desire to believe, but I dare not affirm, that Belisarius
 sincerely rejoiced in the triumph of Narses.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"I only find, that
 during three months, five, and at length ten, thousand
 persons died each day at Constantinople; that many cities of
 the East were left vacant, and that in several districts of
 Italy the harvest and the vintage withered on the ground.","('three months', 'DATE'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten, thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"I shall conclude this chapter with the comets, the
 earthquakes, and the plague, which astonished or afflicted
 the age of Justinian.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"I. In the fifth year of his reign,
 and in the month of September, a comet (74) was seen during
 twenty days in the western quarter of the heavens, and which
 shot its rays into the north.","('the fifth year', 'DATE'), ('the month of September', 'DATE'), ('74', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty days', 'DATE'), ('the western quarter of the heavens', 'DATE')"
"If the emperor could rejoice in the death of Belisarius, he enjoyed the base satisfaction only eight months, the last period of a reign of thirty- eight years, and a life of eighty-three years.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('only eight months', 'DATE'), ('thirty- eight years', 'DATE'), ('eighty-three years', 'DATE')"
"In
 the front, two large vessels were linked together to sustain
 a floating castle, which commanded the towers of the bridge,
 and contained a magazine of fire, sulphur, and bitumen.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In
 the great square before the church of St. Sophia, this
 monument was raised on a brass column and a stone pedestal
 of seven steps; and the pillar of Theodosius, which weighed
 seven thousand four hundred pounds of silver, was removed
 from the same place by the avarice and vanity of Justinian.","('St. Sophia', 'GPE'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('seven thousand four hundred pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"In a damp, hot, stagnating air, this African fever is
 generated from the putrefaction of animal substances, and
 especially from the swarms of locusts, not less destructive
 to mankind in their death than in their lives.","('African', 'NORP')"
"In a dark night, while the Gothic
 trumpets sounded on another side, they silently opened the
 gate of St. Paul: the Barbarians rushed into the city; and
 the flying garrison was intercepted before they could reach
 the harbor of Centumcellae.","('a dark night', 'TIME'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('St. Paul', 'FAC'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Centumcellae', 'GPE')"
"In a manly oration, not
 unworthy of a Roman censor, the eunuch reproved these
 disorderly vices, which sullied their fame, and endangered
 their safety.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In every step of his victories, the wise Barbarian repeated to Justinian the desire of peace, applauded the concord of their predecessors, and offered to employ the Gothic arms in the service of the empire.","('Barbarian', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"In his
 march from Ravenna, the Roman general chastised the garrison
 of Rimini, traversed in a direct line the hills of Urbino,
 and reentered the Flaminian way, nine miles beyond the
 perforated rock, an obstacle of art and nature which might
 have stopped or retarded his progress. (34)","('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Rimini', 'GPE'), ('Urbino', 'GPE'), ('Flaminian', 'NORP'), ('nine miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"In less than twenty years, that
 busy scene was converted into a silent solitude; the wealthy
 citizens escaped to Sicily and Constantinople; and the
 secret historian has confidently affirmed, that five
 millions of Africans were consumed by the wars and
 government of the emperor Justinian.","('less than twenty years', 'DATE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('five\r\n millions', 'CARDINAL'), ('Africans', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"In the
 conspiracy which unsheathed the dagger of Brutus against the
 life of Caesar, every circumstance is curious and important
 to the eyes of posterity; but the guilt or merit of these
 loyal or rebellious assassins could interest only the
 contemporaries of Procopius, who, by their hopes and fears,
 their friendship or resentment, were personally engaged in
 the revolutions of Africa. (2)
Rebellion of the Moors, A.D. 543-558","('Brutus', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('543-558', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the first attempt, the Roman forces were
 dissipated by a storm.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the government of the empire, he
 was less wise, or less successful: the age was unfortunate;
 the people was oppressed and discontented; Theodora abused
 her power; a succession of bad ministers disgraced his
 judgment; and Justinian was neither beloved in his life, nor
 regretted at his death.","('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"In the mean while, the artful governor soothed the discontent, and revived the hopes of the Romans, by the vague reports of the fleets and armies which were hastening to their relief from the extremities of the East.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"In the midst of wealth and honors, Artaban, who had
 chastised the African tyrant, complained of the ingratitude
 of courts.","('Artaban', 'PERSON'), ('African', 'NORP')"
"In the place of Liberius, the conspirator
 Artaban was raised from a prison to military honors; in the
 pious presumption, that gratitude would animate his valor
 and fortify his allegiance.","('Liberius', 'PERSON'), ('Artaban', 'PERSON')"
"In the second, they approached the
 shore; but they saw the hills covered with archers, the
 landing-place defended by a line of spears, and the king of
 the Goths impatient for battle.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"In the spring of
 the second year, Constantinople, during three or four
 months, was visited by the pestilence; and Procopius, who
 observed its progress and symptoms with the eyes of a
 physician, (89) has emulated the skill and diligence of
 Thucydides in the description of the plague of Athens. (90)","('the spring of\r\n the second year', 'DATE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('three or four\r\n months', 'DATE'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('89', 'DATE'), ('Thucydides', 'PERSON'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('90', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the thirty-second
 winter of Justinian's reign, the Danube was deeply frozen:
 Zabergan led the cavalry of the Bulgarians, and his standard
 was followed by a promiscuous multitude of Sclavonians.","(""the thirty-second\r\n winter of Justinian's reign"", 'DATE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Zabergan', 'PERSON'), ('Bulgarians', 'NORP'), ('Sclavonians', 'NORP')"
"In this
 ignoble warfare, the hero, invincible against the power of
 the Barbarians, was basely vanquished by the delay, the
 disobedience, and the cowardice of his own officers.","('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"In this
 perplexity, an officer of experience proposed a measure,
 secure by the appearance of rashness; that the Roman army
 should cautiously advance along the seashore, while the
 fleet preceded their march, and successively cast a bridge
 of boats over the mouths of the rivers, the Timavus, the
 Brenta, the Adige, and the Po, that fall into the Adriatic
 to the north of Ravenna.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Timavus', 'LOC'), ('Brenta', 'LOC'), ('Adige', 'FAC'), ('Po', 'LOC'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"In this action (so speedy
 was their flight) the Bulgarians lost only four hundred
 horse; but Constantinople was saved; and Zabergan, who felt
 the hand of a master, withdrew to a respectful distance.","('Bulgarians', 'NORP'), ('only four hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Zabergan', 'PERSON')"
"In this revolution, the sons and daughters of Roman consuls lasted the misery which they had spurned or relieved, wandered in tattered garments through the streets of the city and begged their bread, perhaps
 without success, before the gates of their hereditary mansions.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In time, its
 first malignity was abated and dispersed; the disease
 alternately languished and revived; but it was not till the
 end of a calamitous period of fifty-two years, that mankind
 recovered their health, or the air resumed its pure and
 salubrious quality.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('fifty-two years', 'DATE')"
"Instead
 of expecting the restoration of peace and industry, he
 imposed a heavy assessment on the fortunes of the Italians.","('Italians', 'NORP')"
"Instead of delivering
 Italy from the Goths, he had wandered like a fugitive along
 the coast, without daring to march into the country, or to
 accept the bold and repeated challenge of Totila.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Totila', 'PERSON')"
"Instead of one month, the
 audacious Barbarian granted them three, in the just
 confidence that famine would anticipate the term of their
 capitulation.","('one month', 'DATE'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was for his
 use that the granaries had been replenished: the charity of
 Pope Vigilius had purchased and embarked an ample supply of
 Sicilian corn; but the vessels which escaped the Barbarians
 were seized by a rapacious governor, who imparted a scanty
 sustenance to the soldiers, and sold the remainder to the
 wealthy Romans.","('Pope Vigilius', 'ORG'), ('Sicilian', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Its road in the heavens was observed with exquisite skill by Flamstead and Cassini: and the mathematical science of Bernoulli, Newton , and Halley, investigated the laws of its revolutions.","('Flamstead', 'PERSON'), ('Cassini', 'PERSON'), ('Bernoulli', 'GPE'), ('Newton', 'PERSON'), ('Halley', 'PERSON')"
"Joannina, their daughter, and the sole heiress of their
 fortunes, was betrothed to Anastasius, the grandson, or
 rather the nephew, of the empress, (21) whose kind
 interposition forwarded the consummation of their youthful
 loves.","('Joannina', 'PERSON'), ('Anastasius', 'PERSON'), ('21', 'DATE')"
"Justinian granted to the
 favorite what he might have denied to the hero: the Gothic
 war was rekindled from its ashes, and the preparations were
 not unworthy of the ancient majesty of the empire.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('the Gothic\r\n war', 'EVENT')"
"Justinian introduced his own
 jurisprudence into the schools and tribunals of the West; he
 ratified the acts of Theodoric and his immediate successors,
 but every deed was rescinded and abolished which force had
 extorted, or fear had subscribed, under the usurpation of
 Totila.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Totila', 'PERSON')"
"Justinian might dictate benevolent edicts, (57) and Narses
 might second his wishes by the restoration of cities, and
 more especially of churches.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"Justinian was afflicted by a pain in
 his head; and his private entry countenanced the rumor of
 his death.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Justinian was deaf to the voice of peace: but he neglected
 the prosecution of war; and the indolence of his temper
 disappointed, in some degree, the obstinacy of his passions.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Justinian, his gracious master, was inclined to pardon and reward; and it was their interest, as well as duty, to reclaim their deluded brethren, who had been seduced by the arts of the usurper.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
Last victory of Belisarius.,"('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Like Belisarius, he had deserved the
 honors of envy, calumny, and disgrace: but the favorite
 eunuch still enjoyed the confidence of Justinian; or the
 leader of a victorious army awed and repressed the
 ingratitude of a timid court.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Many of the Roman
 soldiers had married the widows and daughters of the
 Vandals.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Vandals', 'NORP')"
Narses awaited the charge; and it was delayed by Totila till he had received his last succours of two thousand Goths.,"('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Totila', 'PERSON'), ('two thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"Neither the fortifications of
 Hadrian's mole, nor of the port, could long delay the
 progress of the conqueror; and Justinian once more received
 the keys of Rome, which, under his reign, had been five
 times taken and recovered. (39)","('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('five', 'CARDINAL')"
"Nine days he reposed in the city,
 collected the fragments of the Italian army, and marching
 towards Rimini to meet the defiance of an insulting enemy.","('Nine days', 'DATE'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Rimini', 'GPE')"
"Ninety furlongs below the city, in the
 narrowest part of the river, he joined the two banks by
 strong and solid timbers in the form of a bridge, on which
 he erected two lofty towers, manned by the bravest of his
 Goths, and profusely stored with missile weapons and engines
 of offence.","('Ninety furlongs', 'QUANTITY'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"No restraints were imposed on the
 free and frequent intercourse of the Roman provinces: from
 Persia to France, the nations were mingled and infected by
 wars and emigrations; and the pestilential odor which lurks
 for years in a bale of cotton was imported, by the abuse of
 trade, into the most distant regions.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('years', 'DATE')"
"Not a hope could be entertained
 of shaking his long-tried fidelity; and they justly dreaded
 the revenge, or rather the justice, of the veteran general,
 who might speedily assemble an army in Thrace to punish the
 assassins, and perhaps to enjoy the fruits of their crime.","('Thrace', 'GPE')"
Not a man was tempted to desert the standard of the Gothic king.,"('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"Of such soldiers, few could be tempted to sally from the
 gates; and none could be persuaded to remain in the field,
 unless they wanted strength and speed to escape from the
 Bulgarians.","('Bulgarians', 'NORP')"
"Of the Vandals chosen by Belisarius, the far
 greater part, in the honors of the Eastern service, forgot
 their country and religion.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"Of the senators whom
 Totila had banished from their country, some were rescued by
 an officer of Belisarius, and transported from Campania to
 Sicily; while others were too guilty to confide in the
 clemency of Justinian, or too poor to provide horses for
 their escape to the sea-shore.","('Totila', 'PERSON'), ('Belisarius', 'GPE'), ('Campania', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Justinian', 'GPE')"
"On the
 confines of Samnium the two brothers divided their forces.","('Samnium', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"On the first attack, they abandoned their
 ensigns, threw down their arms, and dispersed on all sides
 with an active speed, which abated the loss, whilst it
 aggravated the shame, of their defeat.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"On the fragment of a rock Aligern
 stood alone and unshaken, till he calmly surveyed the
 hopeless condition of his country, and judged it more
 honorable to be the friend of Narses, than the slave of the
 Franks.","('Aligern', 'PERSON'), ('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"On the morning of the important
 day, when the ranks were already formed, a servant, for some
 trivial fault, was killed by his master, one of the leaders
 of the Heruli.","('the morning of the important\r\n day', 'TIME'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Heruli', 'PERSON')"
"On the suspicion of a
 monopoly, they massacred the governor, and announced to
 Justinian, by a deputation of the clergy, that unless their
 offence was pardoned, and their arrears were satisfied, they
 should instantly accept the tempting offers of Totila.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Totila', 'PERSON')"
"Perhaps the talents of the Roman general
 were most conspicuous in the calm operations which precede
 the tumult of a battle.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Pierced by the cries of five children, who vainly called on their father for bread, he ordered them to follow his steps, advanced with calm and silent despair to one of the bridges of the Tyber, and, covering his face, threw himself headlong into the stream, in the presence of his family and the Roman people.","('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tyber', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Plague its origins and nature, A.D. 542.","('542', 'CARDINAL')"
"Preparations by Justinian for the Gothic war, A.D. 549-551.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('the Gothic war', 'EVENT'), ('A.D. 549-551', 'DATE')"
"Pressed by remorse, or
 tempted by the hopes of safety, he accused two officers of
 the household of Belisarius; and torture forced them to
 declare that they had acted according to the secret
 instructions of their patron. (67)","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Belisarius', 'GPE')"
"Procopius praises his temper, to reproach him with calm and deliberate cruelty: but in the conspiracies which attacked his authority and person, a more candid judge will approve the justice, or admire the clemency, of Justinian.","('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Ravenna, Ancona, and Crotona, still resisted the Barbarians;
 and when Totila asked in marriage one of the daughters of
 France, he was stung by the just reproach that the king of
 Italy was unworthy of his title till it was acknowledged by
 the Roman people.","('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Ancona', 'GPE'), ('Crotona', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Totila', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Rebellions of Africa—  Restoration of the Gothic Kingdom by Totila— Loss and Recovery of Rome— Final Conquest of Italy by Narses—  Extinction of the Ostrogoths— Defeat of the Franks and Alemanni— Last Victory, Disgrace, and Death of Belisarius.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Loss and Recovery of Rome', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Final Conquest of Italy by Narses—  Extinction of the Ostrogoths— Defeat of the Franks and Alemanni— Last Victory, Disgrace', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Death of Belisarius', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Recovered by Belisarius, A.D. 547, February.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 547', 'DATE'), ('February', 'DATE')"
"Resolved to maintain a
 station so conspicuous in the eyes of mankind, he summoned
 the greatest part of his troops to the standard which he
 erected on the Capitol: the old inhabitants were recalled by
 the love of their country and the hopes of food; and the
 keys of Rome were sent a second time to the emperor
 Justinian.","('Capitol', 'FAC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Rome again taken by the Goths, A.D. 549.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 549', 'FAC')"
"Rome besieged by the Goths, A.D. 546, May.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 546', 'DATE'), ('May', 'DATE')"
"Rome taken by the Goths, A.D. 546, Dec. 17.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 546', 'DATE'), ('Dec. 17', 'DATE')"
"Rome was afflicted by the avarice, and guarded by
 the valor, of Bessas, a veteran chief of Gothic extraction,
 who filled, with a garrison of three thousand soldiers, the
 spacious circle of her venerable walls.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Bessas', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('three thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Round the wide circumference, Narses
 assigned to himself, and to each of his lieutenants, a real
 or a feigned attack, while he silently marked the place of
 easy and unguarded entrance.","('Narses', 'PERSON')"
Sardinia and Corsica obeyed the fortune of Italy; and the sea-coast of Greece was visited by a fleet of three hundred galleys. (24),"('Sardinia', 'GPE'), ('Corsica', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('24', 'CARDINAL')"
"Second command of Belissarius in Italy, A.D. 544-548.","('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Belissarius', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 544-548', 'DATE')"
"Settlement of Italy, A.D. 554-568.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('554-568', 'CARDINAL')"
"Seven thousand Goths, the
 relics of the war, defended the fortress of Campsa till the
 ensuing spring; and every messenger of Narses announced the
 reduction of the Italian cities, whose names were corrupted
 by the ignorance or vanity of the Greeks. (53)","('Seven thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Campsa', 'GPE'), ('the\r\n ensuing spring', 'DATE'), ('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('53', 'CARDINAL')"
"Six thousand of the Goths were slaughtered
 without mercy in the field of Tagina.","('Six thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Tagina', 'GPE')"
"Some decent portion was reserved, however for the use of his widow: and as Antonina had much to repent, she devoted the last remains of her life and fortune to the foundation of a convent.","('Antonina', 'PERSON')"
"Successive
 inroads had reduced the province of Africa to one third of the measure of Italy; yet the Roman emperors continued to reign above a century over Carthage and the fruitful coast of the Mediterranean.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('one third', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('a century', 'DATE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC')"
"Such is the simple and genuine narrative of the
 fall of Belisarius and the ingratitude of Justinian. (68)","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Such restless application prolonged
 his time for the acquisition of knowledge (72) and the
 despatch of business; and he might seriously deserve the
 reproach of confounding, by minute and preposterous
 diligence, the general order of his administration.","('72', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such was the universal
 corruption of the air, that the pestilence which burst forth
 in the fifteenth year of Justinian was not checked or
 alleviated by any difference of the seasons.","('the fifteenth year of Justinian', 'DATE')"
"Ten thousand Heruli and Lombards, of approved valour and doubtful faith, were placed in the centre.","('Ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Heruli', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"That city, on the coast of Phoenicia, was illustrated by the study of the civil law, which opened the surest road to wealth and dignity: the schools of Berytus were filled with the rising spirits of the age, and many a youth was lost in the earthquake, who might have lived to be the scourge or the guardian of his country.","('Phoenicia', 'GPE'), ('Berytus', 'GPE')"
"That country was rapidly sinking into the state of barbarism
 from whence it had been raised by the Phoenician colonies
 and Roman laws; and every step of intestine discord was
 marked by some deplorable victory of savage man over
 civilized society.","('Phoenician', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"That he was deprived of his eyes, and reduced by envy to beg his bread,  ""Give a penny to Belisarius the general!"" is a fiction of later times, (69) which has obtained credit, or rather favor, as a strange example of the vicissitudes of fortune. (70)
Death and character of Justinian, A.D. 565, Nov. 14.","('a penny', 'MONEY'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('69', 'DATE'), ('A.D. 565', 'DATE'), ('Nov. 14', 'DATE')"
"That nymph, the
 wife of Dardanus, was unable to support the ruin of her
 country: she abandoned the dances of her sister orbs, fled
 from the zodiac to the north pole, and obtained, from her
 dishevelled locks, the name of the comet.","('Dardanus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 banners of Narses soon approached the Vulturnus, and the
 eyes of Italy were anxiously fixed on the event of this
 final contest.","('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Vulturnus', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The
 combat was renewed with the return of light, and maintained
 with unabated vigor till the evening of the second day.","('the evening of the second day', 'TIME')"
"The
 emperor professed himself a musician and architect, a poet
 and philosopher, a lawyer and theologian; and if he failed
 in the enterprise of reconciling the Christian sects, the
 review of the Roman jurisprudence is a noble monument of his
 spirit and industry.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The
 life of Germanus was a lesson of implicit obedience: he
 nobly refused to prostitute his name and character in the
 factions of the circus: the gravity of his manners was
 tempered by innocent cheerfulness; and his riches were lent
 without interest to indigent or deserving friends.","('Germanus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 personal weight of Belisarius, the rank, the spirit, and the
 temper, of Germanus, the emperor's nephew, and the vigor and
 success of the second administration of the eunuch Solomon,
 restored the modesty of the camp, and maintained for a while
 the tranquillity of Africa.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Germanus', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Solomon', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"The
 repose of a second night, the want of water, and the loss of
 their bravest champions, determined the surviving Goths to
 accept the fair capitulation which the prudence of Narses
 was inclined to propose.","('a second night', 'TIME'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"The
 sixth return, in the year eleven hundred and six, is
 recorded by the chronicles of Europe and China: and in the
 first fervor of the crusades, the Christians and the Mahometans might surmise, with equal reason, that it portended the destruction of the Infidels.","('sixth', 'ORDINAL'), ('the year eleven hundred and six', 'DATE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Mahometans', 'NORP'), ('Infidels', 'NORP')"
"The
 spirit, as well as the situation, of Aligern prompted him to
 imitate rather than to bewail his brother: a strong and
 dexterous archer, he transpierced with a single arrow the
 armor and breast of his antagonist; and his military conduct
 defended Cumae (45) above a year against the forces of the
 Romans.","('Aligern', 'PERSON'), ('Cumae', 'PERSON'), ('45', 'CARDINAL'), ('a year', 'DATE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The
 strength of their armies was already wasted by the change of
 climate and contagion of disease: the Germans revelled in
 the vintage of Italy; and their own intemperance avenged, in
 some degree, the miseries of a defenceless people.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The
 supreme command was unanimously offered to the brave Uraias;
 and it was in his eyes alone that the disgrace of his uncle
 Vitiges could appear as a reason of exclusion.","('Uraias', 'PERSON'), ('Vitiges', 'PERSON')"
"The
 virtues of Belisarius were replaced by the various or
 uniform vices of eleven chiefs, at Rome, Ravenna, Florence,
 Perugia, Spoleto, etc., who abused their authority for the
 indulgence of lust or avarice.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('eleven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Florence', 'GPE'), ('Perugia', 'GPE'), ('Spoleto', 'GPE')"
"The Appian way, a march of forty days, was covered by the Barbarians;
 and as the prudence of Belisarius declined a battle, he
 preferred the safe and speedy navigation of five days from
 the coast of Epirus to the mouth of the Tyber.","('Appian', 'NORP'), ('forty days', 'DATE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('five days', 'DATE'), ('Epirus', 'LOC'), ('Tyber', 'PRODUCT')"
"The Arians deplored the ruin of their church,
 triumphant above a century in Africa; and they were justly
 provoked by the laws of the conqueror, which interdicted the
 baptism of their children, and the exercise of all religious
 worship.","('Arians', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"The Barbarian
 allies of Narses too frequently confounded the privileges of
 peace and war.","('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"The Barbarians, who annually
 visited the provinces of Europe, were less discouraged by
 some accidental defeats, than they were excited by the
 double hope of spoil and of subsidy.","('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"The Bulgarians wasted the
 summer in the plains of Thrace; but they were inclined to
 peace by the failure of their rash attempts on Greece and
 the Chersonesus.","('Bulgarians', 'NORP'), ('the\r\n summer', 'DATE'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Chersonesus', 'ORG')"
"The East
 could not supply vessels capable of transporting such
 multitudes of men and horses.","('East', 'LOC')"
"The Franks, who were Christians
 and Catholics, contented themselves with simple pillage and
 occasional murder.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Catholics', 'NORP')"
"The Franks, who, in the
 general confusion, had usurped the greater part of the
 Venetian province, refused a free passage to the friends of
 the Lombards.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Venetian', 'NORP'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"The Germans
 advanced in a sharp-pointed column, of the form of a
 triangle or solid wedge.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"The Gothic cavalry
 was astonished and disordered, pressed and broken; and the
 line of infantry, instead of presenting their spears, or
 opening their intervals, were trampled under the feet of the
 flying horse.","('Gothic', 'NORP')"
The Gothic war was yet alive.,"('The Gothic war', 'EVENT')"
"The Goths
 were thrice repulsed in three general assaults; they lost
 the flower of their troops; the royal standard had almost
 fallen into the hands of the enemy, and the fame of Totila
 sunk, as it had risen, with the fortune of his arms.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Totila', 'PERSON')"
The Goths fled from the city.,"('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The Goths were
 assembled in the neighborhood of Rome, they advanced without delay to seek a superior enemy, and the two armies approached each other at the distance of one hundred furlongs, between Tagina (35) and the sepulchres of the Gauls. (36)","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tagina', 'PERSON'), ('35', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('36', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Goths were landed in Corcyra and the ancient continent of Epirus; they advanced as far as Nicopolis, the trophy of Augustus, and Dodona, (25) once famous by the oracle of Jove.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Corcyra', 'LOC'), ('Epirus', 'LOC'), ('Nicopolis', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Dodona', 'PERSON'), ('25', 'DATE'), ('Jove', 'PERSON')"
"The Heruli
 felt the indignity; they halted: but the Roman general,
 without soothing their rage, or expecting their resolution,
 called aloud, as the trumpets sounded, that unless they
 hastened to occupy their place, they would lose the honor of
 the victory.","('Heruli', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Moors, (3) though ignorant of justice,
 were impatient of oppression: their vagrant life and
 boundless wilderness disappointed the arms, and eluded the
 chains, of a conqueror; and experience had shown, that
 neither oaths nor obligations could secure the fidelity of
 their attachment.","('Moors', 'NORP'), ('3', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Roman captives and
 deserters were tempted to enlist in the service of a liberal
 and courteous adversary; the slaves were attracted by the
 firm and faithful promise, that they should never be
 delivered to their masters; and from the thousand warriors
 of Pavia, a new people, under the same appellation of Goths,
 was insensibly formed in the camp of Totila.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pavia', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Totila', 'LOC')"
"The Roman chiefs,
 imprisoned in their respective cities, and accusing each
 other of the common disgrace, did not presume to disturb his
 enterprise.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Romans advanced to Sardica; an army of Sclavonians
 fled before their march; but within two days of their final
 departure, the designs of Germanus were terminated by his
 malady and death.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Sardica', 'GPE'), ('Sclavonians', 'NORP'), ('two days', 'DATE'), ('Germanus', 'PERSON')"
The answer of the Gothic king declared his resolution to die or conquer.,"('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"The approach of the bridge and towers was
 covered by a strong and massy chain of iron; and the chain,
 at either end, on the opposite sides of the Tyber, was
 defended by a numerous and chosen detachment of archers.","('Tyber', 'GPE')"
"The archdeacon Pelagius (13) stood before him, with the Gospels in his hand.","('The archdeacon Pelagius', 'PERSON'), ('13', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gospels', 'PERSON')"
The arrival of fresh troops and more skilful commanders soon checked the insolence of the Moors: seventeen of their princes were slain in the same battle; and the doubtful and transient submission of their tribes was celebrated with lavish applause by the people of Constantinople.,"('Moors', 'NORP'), ('seventeen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The astronomers dissembled their ignorance of
 the nature of these blazing stars, which they affected to
 represent as the floating meteors of the air; and few among
 them embraced the simple notion of Seneca and the Chaldeans,
 that they are only planets of a longer period and more
 eccentric motion.","('Seneca', 'PERSON'), ('Chaldeans', 'NORP')"
"The avarice of
 Antonina, which had been some times diverted by love, now
 reigned without a rival in her breast.","('Antonina', 'PERSON')"
The blow was instantly revenged by the faithful Goths: they transported their dying monarch seven miles beyond the scene of his disgrace; and his last moments were not embittered by the presence of an enemy.,"('Goths', 'NORP'), ('seven miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"The bravest of the nation
 retired beyond the Po; and Teias was unanimously chosen to
 succeed and revenge their departed hero.","('Po', 'PERSON'), ('Teias', 'PERSON')"
"The characters of
 Philip the Second and of Justinian are distinguished by the
 cold ambition which delights in war, and declines the
 dangers of the field.","('Philip', 'PERSON'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Justinian', 'NORP')"
"The cities of Italy resounded with the noise of
 drinking and dancing; the spoils of victory were wasted in
 sensual pleasures; and nothing (says Agathias) remained
 unless to exchange their shields and helmets for the soft
 lute and the capacious hogshead.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Agathias', 'PERSON')"
"The cities of Rhegium and
 Tarentum were reduced: he passed into Sicily, the object of
 his implacable resentment; and the island was stripped of its gold and silver, of the fruits of the earth, and of an infinite number of horses, sheep, and oxen.","('Rhegium', 'GPE'), ('Tarentum', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE')"
"The civil state of
 Italy, after the agitation of a long tempest, was fixed by a
 pragmatic sanction, which the emperor promulgated at the
 request of the pope.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The conqueror of Italy
 retired with a sigh, and continued to languish, inglorious
 and inactive, till Antonina, who had been sent to
 Constantinople to solicit succors, obtained, after the death
 of the empress, the permission of his return.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Antonina', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The conqueror of Italy opened a free passage
 to the irresistible torrent of Barbarians.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"The consort of
 Hildibald was deeply wounded by the beauty, the riches, and
 the pride, of the wife of Uraias; and the death of that
 virtuous patriot excited the indignation of a free people.","('Hildibald', 'PERSON'), ('Uraias', 'PERSON')"
"The conspirators
 were detected and seized, with daggers hidden under their
 garments: Marcellus died by his own hand, and Sergius was
 dragged from the sanctuary. (66)","('Marcellus', 'PERSON'), ('Sergius', 'PERSON')"
"The continuance of hostilities had imbittered
 the national hatred: the Arian clergy was ignominiously
 driven from Rome; Pelagius, the archdeacon, returned without
 success from an embassy to the Gothic camp; and a Sicilian
 bishop, the envoy or nuncio of the pope, was deprived of
 both his hands, for daring to utter falsehoods in the
 service of the church and state.","('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Pelagius', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Sicilian', 'NORP')"
"The death
 of Fulcaris, and the retreat of the surviving chiefs,
 decided the fluctuating and rebellious temper of the Goths;
 they flew to the standard of their deliverers, and admitted
 them into the cities which still resisted the arms of the
 Roman general.","('Fulcaris', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The death of Justinian was
 resolved, but the conspirators delayed the execution till
 they could surprise Belisarius disarmed, and naked, in the
 palace of Constantinople.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The defeat of the Vandals had formerly
 signalized his valor; the rudiments of justice and prudence
 were still more conspicuous in a Moor; and while he laid
 Adrumetum in ashes, he calmly admonished the emperor that
 the peace of Africa might be secured by the recall of
 Solomon and his unworthy nephews.","('Vandals', 'PERSON'), ('Moor', 'LOC'), ('Adrumetum', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Solomon', 'PERSON')"
"The design of the
 African and Italian wars was boldly conceived and executed;
 and his penetration discovered the talents of Belisarius in
 the camp, of Narses in the palace.","('African', 'NORP'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Narses', 'NORP')"
"The despair of the flying Goths found some
 consolation in sanguinary revenge; and three hundred youths
 of the noblest families, who had been sent as hostages
 beyond the Po, were inhumanly slain by the successor of
 Totila.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Po', 'PERSON'), ('Totila', 'PERSON')"
"The exaggerated rumor of his defeat was
 hastily carried to the ears of Belisarius: he paused;
 betrayed in that single moment of his life some emotions of
 surprise and perplexity; and reluctantly sounded a retreat
 to save his wife Antonina, his treasures, and the only
 harbor which he possessed on the Tuscan coast.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Antonina', 'PERSON'), ('Tuscan', 'NORP')"
"The example of Stoza, and
 the assurance that a fortunate soldier had been the first
 king, encouraged the ambition of Gontharis, and he promised,
 by a private treaty, to divide Africa with the Moors, if,
 with their dangerous aid, he should ascend the throne of
 Carthage.","('Stoza', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gontharis', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Moors', 'NORP'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"The exarch led forth his
 troops from Carthage: but, at the distance of six days'
 journey, in the neighborhood of Tebeste, (4) he was
 astonished by the superior numbers and fierce aspect of the
 Barbarians.","('Carthage', 'GPE'), (""six days'"", 'DATE'), ('Tebeste', 'GPE'), ('4', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"The fatal
 disease which depopulated the earth in the time of Justinian
 and his successors, (88) first appeared in the neighborhood
 of Pelusium, between the Serbonian bog and the eastern
 channel of the Nile.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('88', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Pelusium', 'GPE'), ('Serbonian', 'LOC'), ('Nile', 'LOC')"
"The feeble Areobindus, unskilled in the affairs
 of peace and war, was raised, by his marriage with the niece
 of Justinian, to the office of exarch.","('Areobindus', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"The ferment subsided; but
 every accident betrayed the impotence of the government, and
 the factious temper of the people: the guards were disposed
 to mutiny as often as their quarters were changed, or their
 pay was withheld: the frequent calamities of fires and
 earthquakes afforded the opportunities of disorder; the
 disputes of the blues and greens, of the orthodox and
 heretics, degenerated into bloody battles; and, in the
 presence of the Persian ambassador, Justinian blushed for
 himself and for his subjects.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"The fifth visit has been
 already ascribed to the fifth year of Justinian, which
 coincides with the five hundred and thirty-first of the
 Christian aera.","('fifth', 'ORDINAL'), ('the fifth year', 'DATE'), ('Justinian', 'EVENT'), ('five hundred and thirty-first', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The firm and temperate remonstrance of Belisarius
 suspended the execution; he warned the Barbarian not to
 sully his fame by the destruction of those monuments which
 were the glory of the dead, and the delight of the living;
 and Totila was persuaded, by the advice of an enemy, to
 preserve Rome as the ornament of his kingdom, or the fairest
 pledge of peace and reconciliation.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('Totila', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The first line of cavalry advanced with more courage than discretion, and left behind them the infantry of the second line.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"The first of the Romans still
 submitted to be the slave of his wife; but the servitude of
 habit and affection became less disgraceful when the death
 of Theodora had removed the baser influence of fear.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"The first, (77) which ascends beyond the Christian aera one
 thousand seven hundred and sixty-seven years, is coeval with
 Ogyges, the father of Grecian antiquity.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('77', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('one\r\n thousand seven hundred and sixty-seven years', 'DATE'), ('Ogyges', 'PERSON'), ('Grecian', 'NORP')"
"The five last campaigns of Belisarius might abate the envy
 of his competitors, whose eyes had been dazzled and wounded
 by the blaze of his former glory.","('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"The flower of the Roman archers, on horseback, and
 in complete armor, skirmished without peril round this
 immovable phalanx; supplied by active speed the deficiency
 of number; and aimed their arrows against a crowd of
 Barbarians, who, instead of a cuirass and helmet, were
 covered by a loose garment of fur or linen.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"The foresight of Totila had raised obstacles worthy of such
 an antagonist.","('Totila', 'ORG')"
"The former
 aspired to restore the Gothic kingdom; the latter, after a
 promise to his brother of speedy succors, returned by the
 same road to deposit his treasure beyond the Alps.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Alps', 'LOC')"
"The fourth apparition,
 forty-four years before the birth of Christ, is of all
 others the most splendid and important.","('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('forty-four years', 'DATE'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"The gates of Verona were secretly
 opened to Artabazus, at the head of one hundred Persians in
 the service of the empire.","('Verona', 'GPE'), ('Artabazus', 'GPE'), ('one hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"The guardians of Theodebald entertained with coldness and
 reluctance the magnificent promises of the Gothic
 ambassadors.","('Theodebald', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"The haughty message of Narses was an offer, not of peace, but of pardon.","('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"The hero had escaped the sword of the
 Barbarians.","('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"The horses of the royal stables, of private
 citizens, and even of the circus, were hastily collected;
 the emulation of the old and young was roused by the name of
 Belisarius, and his first encampment was in the presence of
 a victorious enemy.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The host of the
 Franks and Alamanni consisted of infantry: a sword and
 buckler hung by their side; and they used, as their weapons
 of offence, a weighty hatchet and a hooked javelin, which
 were only formidable in close combat, or at a short
 distance.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Alamanni', 'PERSON')"
The houses of the senators were plentifully stored with gold and silver; and the avarice of Bessas had laboured with so much guilt and shame for the benefit of the conqueror.,"('Bessas', 'PERSON')"
"The hut of a savage, or the tent of an Arab, may be thrown down without injury to the inhabitant; and the Peruvians had reason to deride the folly of their Spanish conquerors, who with so much cost and labour erected their own sepulchres.","('Arab', 'NORP'), ('Peruvians', 'NORP'), ('Spanish', 'NORP')"
"The improvement of the
 revenue was committed to Alexander, a subtle scribe, long
 practised in the fraud and oppression of the Byzantine
 schools, and whose name of Psalliction, the scissars, (9) was
 drawn from the dexterous artifice with which he reduced the
 size without defacing the figure, of the gold coin.","('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Psalliction', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('9', 'CARDINAL')"
"The indolence, perhaps the
 impotence, of a prince who despised his enemies, and envied
 his servants, protracted the calamities of Italy.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The institution of great cities, which include a nation within the limits of a wall, almost realizes the wish of Caligula, that the Roman people had but one neck.","('Caligula', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The jealousy of the Byzantine court had not permitted
 Belisarius to achieve the conquest of Italy; and his abrupt
 departure revived the courage of the Goths, (6) who respected
 his genius, his virtue, and even the laudable motive which
 had urged the servant of Justinian to deceive and reject
 them.","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('6', 'CARDINAL'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"The justice or passion of Narses was
 awakened: he summoned the offender to his presence, and
 without listening to his excuses, gave the signal to the
 minister of death.","('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"The king
 of the Lombards (31) satisfied or surpassed the obligations
 of a treaty, by lending two thousand two hundred of his
 bravest warriors,  who were followed by three thousand of their martial attendants.","('The king\r\n of the Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('31', 'CARDINAL'), ('two thousand two hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('three thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The king of the
 Goths, who blushed for the baseness of his enemies, pursued
 with rapid steps the path of honor and victory.","('The king of the\r\n Goths', 'PERSON')"
"The life of Belisarius was graciously
 spared; but his fortunes were sequestered, and, from
 December to July,  A.D. 564, July 19.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('December to July', 'DATE'), ('A.D. 564', 'DATE'), ('July 19', 'DATE')"
"The loss of Berytus (86) was of smaller account, but of much greater value.","('Berytus', 'ORG'), ('86', 'CARDINAL')"
"The loss of Rome was speedily retrieved by an action, to
 which, according to the event, the public opinion would
 apply the names of rashness or heroism.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The love of fame was deeply
 implanted in his breast, but he condescended to the poor
 ambition of titles, honors, and contemporary praise; and
 while he labored to fix the admiration, he forfeited the
 esteem and affection, of the Romans.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The maritime towns Ancona, Crotona, Centumcellae, resisted
 the assaults of Totila Sicily was reduced by the zeal of
 Artaban, and the Gothic navy was defeated near the coast of
 the Adriatic.","('Ancona', 'GPE'), ('Crotona', 'GPE'), ('Centumcellae', 'GPE'), ('Totila Sicily', 'LOC'), ('Artaban', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC')"
"The measure of his
 sleep was not less rigorous: after the repose of a single
 hour, the body was awakened by the soul, and, to the
 astonishment of his chamberlain, Justinian walked or studied
 till the morning light.","('a single\r\n hour', 'TIME'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"The medimnus, or fifth part of the quarter
 of wheat, was exchanged for seven pieces of gold; fifty
 pieces were given for an ox, a rare and accidental prize;
 the progress of famine enhanced this exorbitant value, and
 the mercenaries were tempted to deprive themselves of the
 allowance which was scarcely sufficient for the support of
 life.","('fifth', 'ORDINAL'), ('quarter', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifty', 'CARDINAL')"
"The mode of its
 propagation is explained by the remark of Procopius himself,
 that it always spread from the sea-coast to the inland
 country: the most sequestered islands and mountains were
 successively visited; the places which had escaped the fury
 of its first passage were alone exposed to the contagion of
 the ensuing year.","('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the ensuing year', 'DATE')"
"The mutiny was secretly
 inflamed by a thousand soldiers, for the most part Heruli,
 who had imbibed the doctrines, and were instigated by the
 clergy, of the Arian sect; and the cause of perjury and
 rebellion was sanctified by the dispensing powers of
 fanaticism.","('a thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Heruli', 'PERSON'), ('Arian', 'NORP')"
"The name of
 Belisarius can never die but instead of the funeral, the
 monuments, the statues, so justly due to his memory, I only
 read, that his treasures, the spoil of the Goths and
 Vandals, were immediately confiscated by the emperor.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Vandals', 'NORP')"
"The nation of the Vandals had disappeared: they once amounted to a hundred and sixty thousand warriors, without including the children, the women, or the slaves.","('Vandals', 'PRODUCT'), ('a hundred and sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The near approach of a comet may injure or destroy the
 globe which we inhabit; but the changes on its surface have
 been hitherto produced by the action of volcanoes and
 earthquakes. (82)","('82', 'CARDINAL')"
"The new king
 immediately sent ambassadors to implore, or rather to
 purchase, the aid of the Franks, and nobly lavished, for the
 public safety, the riches which had been deposited in the
 palace of Pavia.","('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Pavia', 'GPE')"
"The next
 day he pronounced two orations, to congratulate and admonish his victorious Goths, and to reproach the senate, as the vilest of slaves, with their perjury, folly, and ingratitude; sternly declaring, that their estates and
 honours were justly forfeited to the companions of his arms.","('The next\r\n day', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The next morning the Bulgarian cavalry
 advanced to the charge.","('The next morning', 'TIME'), ('Bulgarian', 'NORP')"
"The offer was entertained with coldness and
 suspicion; they returned in safety; they twice repeated
 their visit; the place was twice examined; the conspiracy
 was known and disregarded; and no sooner had Totila
 consented to the attempt, than they unbarred the Asinarian
 gate, and gave admittance to the Goths.","('Totila', 'PERSON'), ('Asinarian', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The parsimony or poverty of the emperor compelled him to
 deviate from the rule of conduct which had deserved the love
 and confidence of the Italians.","('Italians', 'NORP')"
"The patricians, who were still possessed of horses, Decius,
 Basilius, etc. accompanied the governor; their brethren,
 among whom Olybrius, Orestes, and Maximus, are named by the
 historian, took refuge in the church of St. Peter: but the
 assertion, that only five hundred persons remained in the
 capital, inspires some doubt of the fidelity either of his
 narrative or of his text.","('Decius', 'PERSON'), ('Basilius', 'PERSON'), ('Olybrius', 'PERSON'), ('Orestes', 'PERSON'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('only five hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The philosophy of Bayle dispelled a prejudice which Milton's muse had so recently adorned, that the comet, ""from its horrid hair shakes pestilence and war."" (81)","('Bayle', 'PERSON'), ('Milton', 'PERSON'), ('81', 'CARDINAL')"
"The physicians of Constantinople were zealous and
 skilful; but their art was baffled by the various symptoms
 and pertinacious vehemence of the disease: the same remedies
 were productive of contrary effects, and the event
 capriciously disappointed their prognostics of death or
 recovery.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The pillage
 of the city, and the indiscriminate slaughter of its
 inhabitants, were suspended only by darkness, sleep, and
 intoxication: the governor, with seven companions, among
 whom was the historian Procopius, escaped to Sicily: two
 thirds of the army were involved in the guilt of treason;
 and eight thousand insurgents, assembling in the field of
 Bulla, elected Stoza for their chief, a private soldier, who
 possessed in a superior degree the virtues of a rebel.","('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('two\r\n thirds', 'CARDINAL'), ('eight thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bulla', 'PERSON'), ('Stoza', 'PERSON')"
"The principal officer of the Romans was
 dragged, with a rope round his neck, to the foot of the
 wall, from whence, with a trembling voice, he exhorted the
 citizens to implore, like himself, the mercy of the
 conqueror.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The prudence of Narses impelled him to speedy and decisive
 action.","('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"The rapid success of Totila may be partly ascribed to the
 revolution which three years' experience had produced in the
 sentiments of the Italians.","('Totila', 'PERSON'), (""three years'"", 'DATE'), ('Italians', 'NORP')"
"The remains of
 the Gothic nation evacuated the country, or mingled with the
 people; the Franks, instead of revenging the death of
 Buccelin, abandoned, without a struggle, their Italian
 conquests; and the rebellious Sinbal, chief of the Heruli,
 was subdued, taken and hung on a lofty gallows by the
 inflexible justice of the exarch. (56)","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Buccelin', 'NORP'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Sinbal', 'PERSON'), ('Heruli', 'PERSON')"
"The report of the fugitives exaggerated the
 numbers and fierceness of an enemy, who had polluted holy
 virgins, and abandoned new-born infants to the dogs and
 vultures; a crowd of rustics, imploring food and protection,
 increased the consternation of the city, and the tents of
 Zabergan were pitched at the distance of twenty miles, (62)
 on the banks of a small river, which encircles Melanthias,
 and afterwards falls into the Propontis. (63) Justinian
 trembled: and those who had only seen the emperor in his old
 age, were pleased to suppose, that he had lost the alacrity
 and vigor of his youth.","('Zabergan', 'GPE'), ('twenty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('62', 'CARDINAL'), ('Melanthias', 'GPE'), ('Propontis', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"The resemblance of Justinian to the bust of Domitian, is
 maliciously urged; (71) with the acknowledgment, however, of a well-proportioned figure, a ruddy complexion, and a pleasing countenance.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON'), ('71', 'CARDINAL')"
"The residue of the royal treasure was
 guarded by his brother Aligern, at Cumaea, in Campania; but
 the strong castle which Totila had fortified was closely
 besieged by the arms of Narses.","('Aligern', 'PERSON'), ('Cumaea', 'LOC'), ('Campania', 'GPE'), ('Totila', 'PERSON'), ('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"The return of Belisarius to save the country which he had
 subdued, was pressed with equal vehemence by his friends and
 enemies; and the Gothic war was imposed as a trust or an
 exile on the veteran commander.","('Belisarius', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"The review of the nations from the Danube to the Nile has exposed, on every side, the weakness of the Romans; and our wonder is reasonably excited that they should presume to enlarge an empire whose ancient limits they were incapable of defending.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The riches of Rusticiana, the daughter of Symmachus and widow of Boethius, had been generously devoted to alleviate the calamities of famine.","('Rusticiana', 'PERSON'), ('Symmachus', 'PERSON'), ('Boethius', 'PERSON')"
"The river separated the two armies:
 sixty days were consumed in distant and fruitless combats,
 and Teias maintained this important post till he was
 deserted by his fleet and the hope of subsistence.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('sixty days', 'DATE'), ('Teias', 'PERSON')"
"The same considerations might have
 tempered the ardor of Totila.","('Totila', 'PERSON')"
"The same, the next, or the succeeding day, it was
 declared by the swelling of the glands, particularly those
 of the groin, of the armpits, and under the ear; and when
 these buboes or tumors were opened, they were found to
 contain a coal, or black substance, of the size of a lentil.","('the succeeding day', 'DATE')"
"The savage chief passed, without opposition, the river and
 the mountains, spread his troops over Macedonia and Thrace,
 and advanced with no more than seven thousand horse to the
 long wall, which should have defended the territory of
 Constantinople.","('Macedonia', 'GPE'), ('Thrace', 'GPE'), ('no more than seven thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The sea was open to the Romans: the ships and soldiers were
 assembled at Salona, near the palace of Diocletian: he
 refreshed and reviewed his troops at Pola in Istria, coasted
 round the head of the Adriatic, entered the port of Ravenna,
 and despatched orders rather than supplies to the
 subordinate cities.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Salona', 'GPE'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Pola', 'GPE'), ('Istria', 'GPE'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"The second visit, in the year eleven
 hundred and ninety-three, is darkly implied in the fable of
 Electra, the seventh of the Pleiads, who have been reduced
 to six since the time of the Trojan war.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('the year eleven\r\n hundred and ninety-three', 'DATE'), ('Electra', 'PERSON'), ('seventh', 'ORDINAL'), ('Pleiads', 'NORP'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Trojan war', 'EVENT')"
"The senators
 were dragged in his train, and afterwards confined in the
 fortresses of Campania: the citizens, with their wives and
 children, were dispersed in exile; and during forty days
 Rome was abandoned to desolate and dreary solitude. (16)","('Campania', 'GPE'), ('forty days', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('16', 'CARDINAL')"
