Sentence,Entities
(33),"('33', 'CARDINAL')"
(34),"('34', 'CARDINAL')"
(55),"('55', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 wise prince should have rewarded the crime of Taurus: the
 faithful minister, when he was no longer able to oppose the
 progress of a rebel, had taken refuge in the court of his
 benefactor and his lawful sovereign.","('Taurus', 'PERSON')"
"A 
 legal fiction was introduced and gradually established, that
 one half of the national council had migrated into the East,
 and the despotic successors of Julian, accepting the title
 of Senators, acknowledged themselves the members of a
 respectable body which was permitted to represent the
 majesty of the Roman name.","('one half', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"A chosen detachment was 
 despatched away in post-waggons, to secure, if it were yet
 possible, the pass of Succi; the recruits; the horses, the
 arms, and the magazines, which had been prepared against
 Sapor, were appropriated to the service of the civil war;
 and the domestic victories of Constantius inspired his
 partisans with the most sanguine assurances of success.","('Succi', 'ORG'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('the civil war', 'EVENT'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"A citizen of Ancyra had prepared for his
 own use a purple garment, and this indiscreet action, which,
 under the reign of Constantius, would have been considered
 as a capital offence, (68) was reported to Julian by the 
 officious importunity of a private enemy.","('Ancyra', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"A more dangerous conspiracy was formed by
 ten of the domestic guards, who had resolved to assassinate
 Julian in the field of exercise near Antioch.","('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"A motive of superstition prevented the
 execution of the design which Julian had frequently
 meditated, of relieving his head from the weight of a costly
 diadem;(72) but he absolutely refused the title of Dominus
 or Lord ,(73) a word which was grown so familiar to the ears of the Romans, that they no longer remembered its servile
 and humiliating origin.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Dominus', 'PERSON'), ('73', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"A part of the letter was afterwards read, in which the emperor arraigned the ingratitude of Julian, whom he had invested with the
 honours of the purple; whom he had educated with so much care and tenderness; whom he had preserved in his infancy, when he was left a helpless orphan.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"A similar
 division of troops, under the orders of Jovius and Jovinus,
 prepared to follow the oblique course of the highways
 through the Alps and the northern confines of Italy.","('Jovius', 'GPE'), ('Jovinus', 'GPE'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"A slight fever, which was
 perhaps occasioned by the agitation of his spirits, was
 increased by the fatigues of the journey, and Constantius
 was obliged to halt at the little town of Mopsucrene, twelve
 miles beyond Tarsus, where he expired, after a short
 illness, in the forty-fifth year of his age, and the
 twenty-fourth of his reign.(42)","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Mopsucrene', 'GPE'), ('twelve\r\n miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Tarsus', 'GPE'), ('forty-fifth year', 'DATE'), ('twenty-fourth', 'CARDINAL'), ('42', 'CARDINAL')"
"A thousand barbers, a thousand cupbearers, a thousand cooks, were distributed in the several offices of luxury; and the number of eunuchs could be compared only with the insects of a summer's day.","('A thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('a thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('a thousand', 'CARDINAL'), (""a summer's day"", 'DATE')"
"A.D. 360,361.","('360,361', 'CARDINAL')"
"Adorned with the designs of
 military and imperial pomp, Julian showed himself in the
 field of Mars to the soldiers, who glowed with ardent
 enthusiasm in the cause of their pupil, their leader, and
 their friend.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Mars', 'LOC')"
"After
 he had given peace to the barbarians, the emperor carefully
 visited the fortifications along the Rhine from Cleves to
 Basel; surveyed, with peculiar attention, the territories
 which he had recovered from the hands of the Alemanni;
 passed through Besancon,(18) which had severely suffered from 
 their fury; and fixed his headquarters at Vienne for the
 ensuing winter.","('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Cleves', 'LOC'), ('Basel', 'GPE'), ('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Besancon', 'PERSON'), ('18', 'CARDINAL'), ('Vienne', 'GPE'), ('winter', 'DATE')"
"After a painful conflict, Julian was compelled to
 acknowledge that obedience was the virtue of the most
 eminent subject, and that the sovereign alone was entitled
 to judge of the public welfare.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"After an interval of one hundred and twenty years from the
 death of Alexander Severus, the Romans beheld an emperor who
 made no distinction between his duties and his pleasures,
 who laboured to relieve the distress and to revive the
 spirit of his subjects, and who endeavoured always to
 connect authority with merit, and happiness with virtue.","('one hundred and twenty years', 'DATE'), ('Alexander Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"After distinguishing the officers and soldiers who by
 their rank or merit deserved a peculiar attention, Julian
 addressed himself in a studied oration to the surrounding
 multitude: he celebrated their exploits with grateful
 applause; encouraged them to accept, with alacrity, the
 honour of serving under the eyes of a powerful and liberal
 monarch; and admonished them that the commands of Augustus
 required an instant and cheerful obedience.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"After losing one of his hands by the stroke of a
 sword, he embraced the knees of the prince whom he had
 offended.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"After this message, which might be considered as a signal of irreconcilable war, Julian, who some weeks before had celebrated the Christian festival of the Epiphany, (22) made a public declaration that 
 he committed the care of his safety to the IMMORTAL GODS; and thus publicly renounced the religion as well as the friendship of Constantius. (23)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('some weeks before', 'DATE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('the Epiphany', 'DATE'), ('22', 'DATE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('23', 'CARDINAL')"
"Although he was firmly resolved to maintain
 the station which he had assumed, he was still desirous of
 saving his country from the calamities of civil war, of
 declining a contest with the superior forces of Constantius,
 and of preserving his own character from the reproach of
 perfidy and ingratitude.","('Constantius', 'ORG')"
"An artful expression, which, according to the chance of war, might be differently explained — as a manly reproof of the ingratitude of the usurper or as a flattering confession that a single act of such benefit to the state ought to atone for all the failings of Constantius.","('Constantius', 'ORG')"
"An assembly was summoned by
 Tertullus, praefect of the city; the epistle of Julian was
 read and, as he appeared to be master of Italy, his claims were admitted without a dissenting voice.","('Tertullus', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"An innumerable multitude pressed around him with eager respect, and were perhaps disappointed when they beheld the small stature and simple garb of a hero, whose inexperienced youth had vanquished the barbarians of Germany, and who had now traversed, in a successful career, the whole continent of Europe from the shores of the Atlantic to those of the Bosphorus.(43) A few days afterwards, when the remains of the deceased emperor were landed in the harbour, the subjects of Julian applauded the real or affected humanity of their sovereign.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Atlantic', 'LOC'), ('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('43', 'CARDINAL'), ('A few days afterwards', 'DATE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"And death of Constantius, A.D. 361, November 30.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 361', 'DATE'), ('November 30', 'DATE')"
"Arbetio, whom the public would have seen with less surprise at the bar than on the bench, was supposed to possess the secret of the commission, the armed and angry leaders of the Jovian and Herculian bands encompassed the tribunal, and the judges were alternately swayed by the laws of justice and by the clamours of faction. (62)","('Arbetio', 'PERSON'), ('Jovian', 'NORP'), ('Herculian', 'NORP')"
"Artemius had reigned the
 cruel and corrupt tyrant of a great province; Gaudentius had
 long practised the arts of calumny against the innocent, the
 virtuous, and even the person of Julian himself.","('Artemius', 'PERSON'), ('Gaudentius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"As he entered the long suburb of Sirmium, he was received by the joyful acclamations of the army and people, who, crowned with flowers, and holding lighted tapers in their hands, conducted their acknowledged sovereign to the imperial residence.","('Sirmium', 'GPE')"
"As long as the fame of
 Julian was doubtful, the buffoons of the palace, who were
 skilled in the language of satire, tried the efficacy of
 those arts which they had so often practised with success.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as the 
 season of the year permitted Julian to take the field, he
 appeared at the head of his legions; threw a bridge over the
 Rhine in the neighbourhood of Cleves; and prepared to
 chastise the perfidy of the Attuarii, a tribe of Franks, who
 presumed that they might ravage with impunity the frontiers
 of a divided empire.","('the \r\n season of the year', 'DATE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Cleves', 'LOC'), ('Attuarii', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as the approach of the troops was announced, the
 Caesar went out to meet them, and ascended his tribunal,
 which had been erected in a plain before the gates of the
 city.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as the legions of Aquileia were assured of the death of the emperor, they opened the gates of the city, and, by the sacrifice of their guilty leaders, obtained an easy pardon from the prudence or lenity of Julian; who, in the thirty-second year of his age, and is acknowledged by the whole empire acquired the undisputed possession of the Roman empire.(45)","('Aquileia', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('the thirty-second year', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('45', 'CARDINAL')"
"As soon as the provinces were
 exhausted of their military strength, the Germans would
 violate a treaty which had been imposed on their fears; and
 notwithstanding the abilities and valour of Julian, the
 general of a nominal army, to whom the public calamities
 would be imputed, must find himself, after a vain
 resistance, either a prisoner in the camp of the barbarians,
 or a criminal in the palace of Constantius.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'GPE')"
"Astonished and perplexed, he 
 addressed his prayers to the great Jupiter, who immediately
 signified, by a clear and manifest omen, that he should
 submit to the will of heaven and of the army.","('Jupiter', 'LOC')"
"At the
 dawn of day the soldiers, whose zeal was irritated by
 opposition, forcibly entered the palace, seized, with
 respectful violence, the object of their choice, guarded
 Julian with drawn swords through the streets of Paris,
 placed him on the tribunal, and with repeated shouts saluted
 him as their emperor.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Paris', 'GPE')"
"At the hour of midnight
 the impetuous multitude, with swords, and bows, and torches
 in their hands, rushed into the suburbs, encompassed the
 palace;(7) and, careless of future dangers, pronounced the 
 fatal and irrevocable words, JULIAN AUGUSTUS!","('the hour of midnight', 'TIME')"
"Attached, either from birth or long habit, to
 the climate and manners of Gaul, they loved and admired
 Julian; they despised, and perhaps hated, the emperor; they
 dreaded the laborious march, the Persian arrows, and the
 burning deserts of Asia.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"Before Constantius expired, he is said to have named Julian
 for his successor; nor does it seem improbable that his
 anxious concern for the fate of a young and tender wife,
 whom he left with child, may have prevailed in his last
 moments over the harsher passions of hatred and revenge.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Before the
 barbarians were recovered from their amazement, the emperor
 appeared in arms on the banks of the Rhine, and, once more
 crossing the river, renewed the deep impressions of terror
 and respect which had been already made by four preceding
 expeditions.(20)
Fruitless treaty and declaration of war, A.D. 361.","('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('20', 'CARDINAL'), ('361', 'CARDINAL')"
"Before the end of
 the year in which they had been adorned with the ensigns of
 the prefecture and consulship,(64) Taurus and Florentius were 
 reduced to implore the clemency of the inexorable tribunal
 of Chalcedon.","('the end of\r\n the year', 'DATE'), ('64', 'CARDINAL'), ('Florentius', 'PERSON'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE')"
"But
 he reserves for himself the nomination of his other civil
 and military officers, with the troops, the revenue, and the
 sovereignty of the provinces beyond the Alps.","('Alps', 'LOC')"
"But 
 the behaviour of Julian was uniformly supported.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"But Justice herself
 (if we may use the pathetic expression of Ammianus(63) ) 
 appeared to weep over the fate of Ursulus, the treasurer of
 the empire, and his blood accused the ingratitude of Julian,
 whose distress had been seasonably relieved by the intrepid
 liberality of that honest minister.","('Ammianus', 'PERSON'), ('Ursulus', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"But Lucilian had no sooner recovered his spirits
 than he betrayed his want of discretion, by presuming to
 admonish his conqueror that he had rashly ventured, with a
 handful of men, to expose his person in the midst of his
 enemies.","('Lucilian', 'PERSON')"
"But as soon as they were landed,
 he issued an absolute order, which prohibited the watermen
 from transporting any Egyptian to Constantinople, and thus
 detained his disappointed clients on the Asiatic shore,
 till, their patience and money being utterly exhausted, they
 were obliged to return with indignant murmurs to their
 native country. (67)
Clemency of Julian.","('Egyptian', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"But in
 their passage through Italy and Illyricum they were detained
 by the tedious and affected delays of the provincial
 governors; they were conducted by slow journeys from
 Constantinople to Caesarea in Cappadocia; and when at length
 they were admitted to the presence of Constantius, they
 found that he had already conceived, from the despatches of
 his own officers, the most unfavourable opinion of the
 conduct of Julian and of the Gallic army.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Illyricum', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Caesarea', 'GPE'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP')"
"But in the execution of this
 salutary work Julian is accused of proceeding with too much
 haste and inconsiderable severity.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"But it is impossible
 for us to calculate the respective weight and operation of
 these sentiments; or to ascertain the principles of action
 which might escape the observation, while they guided, or
 rather impelled, the steps of Julian himself.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"But that youth was
 the son of Marcellus, the general of cavalry, who, in the
 first campaign of the Gallic war, had deserted the standard
 of the Caesar and the republic.","('Marcellus', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the Gallic war', 'EVENT'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"But the
 soldiers, who were conscious of their guilt, chose rather to
 depend on the gratitude of Julian than on the clemency of
 the emperor.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"But the Imperial legions were
 still in their distant quarters of Asia; the Danube was
 feebly guarded; and if Julian could occupy, by a sudden
 incursion, the important provinces of Illyricum, he might
 expect that a people of soldiers would resort to his
 standard, and that the rich mines of gold and silver would
 contribute to the expenses of the civil war.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Illyricum', 'GPE')"
"But the civil wisdom of two magistrates was overbalanced by the ferocious violence of four generals, Nevitta, Agilo, Jovinus, and Arbetio.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nevitta', 'PERSON'), ('Agilo', 'PERSON'), ('Jovinus', 'NORP'), ('Arbetio', 'PERSON')"
"But the guilt of
 Florentius justified the severity of the judges, and his
 escape served to display the magnanimity of Julian, who
 nobly checked the interested diligence of an informer, and
 refused to learn what place concealed the wretched fugitive
 from his just resentment.(65) Some months after the tribunal 
 of Chalcedon had been dissolved, the praetorian vicegerent
 of Africa, the notary Gaudentius, and Artemius,(66) duke of 
 Egypt, were executed at Antioch.","('Florentius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Gaudentius', 'PERSON'), ('Artemius', 'NORP'), ('66', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"But the humanity of Julian was preserved from the cruel
 alternative which he pathetically laments of destroying or
 of being himself destroyed: and the seasonable death of
 Constantius delivered the Roman empire from the calamities
 of civil war.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But the legionaries, who seemed to have
 rejected the yoke of discipline, conducted the defence of
 the place with skill and perseverance; invited the rest of
 Italy to imitate the example of their courage and loyalty;
 and threatened the retreat of Julian, if he should be forced
 to yield to the superior numbers of the armies of the East.
 (41)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('41', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the personal merit of Julian was,
 in some measure, independent of his fortune.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"But the terror of a foreign
 invasion obliged him to suspend the punishment of a private
 enemy; he continued his march towards the confines of
 Persia, and thought it sufficient to signify the conditions
 which might entitle Julian and his guilty followers to the
 clemency of their offended sovereign.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"But the work of public reformation would have remained imperfect if Julian had only corrected the abuses, without punishing the crimes, of his predecessor's reign.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"But they darkly
 insinuated that the virtues of the Caesar might instantly be
 converted into the most dangerous crimes, if the inconstant
 multitude should prefer their inclinations to their duty; or
 if the general of a victorious army should be tempted from his allegiance by the hopes of revenge and independent greatness.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"But with the
 fopperies Julian affected to renounce the decencies of
 dress; and seemed to value himself for his neglect of the
 laws of cleanliness.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"By a single edict he
 reduced the palace of Constantinople to an immense desert,
 and dismissed with ignominy the whole train of slaves and
 dependents,(57) without providing any just, or at least  benevolent, exceptions for the age, the services, or the poverty of the faithful domestics of the Imperial family.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"By a well-concerted
 stratagem he seized a fleet of light brigantines(31) as it 
 lay at anchor; secured a supply of coarse provisions
 sufficient to satisfy the indelicate, but voracious,
 appetite of a Gallic army; and boldly committed himself to
 the stream of the Danube.","('31', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"By his order,
 Jovinus led back a part of the army into Italy; and the
 siege of Aquileia was formed with diligence and prosecuted
 with vigour.","('Jovinus', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Aquileia', 'GPE')"
"By this avarice of time he seemed to protract the short 
 duration of his reign; and, if the dates were less securely
 ascertained, we should refuse to believe that only sixteen
 months elapsed between the death of Constantius and the
 departure of his successor for the Persian war.","('only sixteen\r\n months', 'DATE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('the Persian war', 'EVENT')"
"Conscious that success alone could justify his attempt, and that boldness only could command success, he instantly advanced, at the head of three thousand soldiers, to attack the strongest and most populous city of the Illyrian provinces.","('three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP')"
"Constantius signified his pleasure
 that four entire legions—the Celtae and Petulants, the
 Heruli and the Batavians—should be separated from the
 standard of Julian, under which they had acquired their fame
 and discipline; that in each of the remaining bands three
 hundred of the bravest youths should be selected and that
 this numerous detachment, the strength of the Gallic army,
 should instantly begin their march, and exert their utmost
 diligence to arrive, before the opening of the campaign, on
 the frontiers of Persia. (4)","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Celtae', 'NORP'), ('Petulants', 'NORP'), ('Heruli', 'NORP'), ('Batavians', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('three\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('4', 'CARDINAL')"
"Disguising the anguish of his soul under the semblance of
 contempt, Constantius professed his intention of returning
 into Europe, and of giving chase to Julian; for he never
 spoke of this military expedition in any other light than
 that of a hunting party. (39)","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"During the
 games of the Circus, he had, imprudently or designedly,
 performed the manumission of a slave in the presence of the
 consul.","('Circus', 'EVENT')"
"Eusebius and his guilty associates made a faint attempt to
 prolong the reign of the eunuchs by the election of another
 emperor; but their intrigues were rejected with disdain by
 an army which now abhorred the thought of civil discord and
 two officers of rank were instantly despatched to assure
 Julian that every sword in the empire would be drawn for his
 service.","('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Even faction, and religious faction, was constrained to
 acknowledge the superiority of his genius in peace as well
 as in war, and to con fess, with a sigh, that the apostate
 Julian was a lover of his country, and that he deserved the
 empire of the world.(85)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('85', 'CARDINAL')"
Fears and envy of Constantius.,"('Constantius', 'ORG')"
Florentius was a fugitive; Lupicinus a prisoner.,"('Florentius', 'PERSON'), ('Lupicinus', 'PERSON')"
"For himself Julian had reserved a more
 difficult and extraordinary part.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"From Constantinople the attention
 of the monarch was extended to the municipal senates of the
 provinces.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"From his palace, or, more properly, from his
 headquarters of Sirmium and Naissus, he distributed to the
 principal cities of the empire a laboured apology for his
 own conduct; published the secret despatches of Constantius;
 and solicited the judgment of mankind between two
 competitors, the one of whom had expelled, and the other had
 invited, the barbarians. (36) Julian, whose mind was deeply 
 wounded by the reproach of ingratitude, aspired to maintain,
 by argument as well as by arms, the superior merits of his
 cause; and to excel not only in the arts of war, but in
 those of composition.","('Sirmium and Naissus', 'ORG'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"From this principle he justly concluded that the man
 who presumes to reign should aspire to the perfection of the
 divine nature; that he should purify his soul from her
 mortal and terrestrial part; that he should extinguish his
 appetites, enlighten his understanding, regulate his
 passions, and subdue the wild beast which, according to the
 lively metaphor of Aristotle,(48) seldom fails to ascend the 
 throne of a despot.","('Aristotle', 'PERSON'), ('48', 'DATE')"
"From this tribute the cities of Elis, of Delphi, and of Argos, which had inherited from their remote ancestors the sacred office of perpetuating the Olympic, the Pythian, and the Nemean games, claimed a just exemption","('Elis', 'PERSON'), ('Delphi', 'GPE'), ('Argos', 'ORG'), ('Olympic', 'EVENT'), ('Pythian', 'NORP'), ('Nemean', 'NORP')"
"Had Julian consulted the simple
 dictates of reason, the first magistrate of the Romans would
 have scorned the affectation of Diogenes, as well as that of
 Darius.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Diogenes', 'PERSON'), ('Darius', 'PERSON')"
"He
 carefully distinguished the judge from the legislator;(84) 
 and though he meditated a necessary reformation of the Roman
 jurisprudence, he pronounced sentence according to the
 strict and literal interpretation of those laws which the
 magistrates were bound to execute and the subjects to obey.","('84', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"He
 possessed such flexibility of thought, and such firmness of
 attention, that he could employ his hand to write, his ear
 to listen, and his voice to dictate; and pursue at once
 three several trains of ideas without hesitation, and
 without error.","('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"He admonishes
 the emperor to consult the dictates of justice; to distrust
 the arts of those venal flatterers who subsist only by the
 discord of princes; and to embrace the offer of a fair and
 honourable treaty, equally advantageous to the republic and
 to the house of Constantine.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"He allows the supremacy of
 his brother Constantius; and engages to send him an annual
 present of Spanish horses, to recruit his army with a select
 number of barbarian youths, and to accept from his choice a
 Praetorian praefect of approved discretion and fidelity.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Spanish', 'NORP'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP')"
"He alternately practised,
 as in a school of declamation, the several modes of praise,
 of censure, of exhortation; and his friend Libanius has
 remarked that the study of Homer taught him to imitate the
 simple, concise style of Menelaus, the copiousness of
 Nestor, whose words descended like the flakes of a winter's
 snow, or the pathetic and forcible eloquence of Ulysses.","('Libanius', 'PERSON'), ('Homer', 'PERSON'), ('Menelaus', 'NORP'), ('Nestor', 'PERSON'), ('winter', 'DATE'), ('Ulysses', 'PERSON')"
"He gave a
 public and military audience to the quaestor Leonas: the
 haughty epistle of Constantius was read to the attentive
 multitude; and Julian protested, with the most flattering
 deference, that he was ready to resign the title of
 Augustus, if he could obtain the consent of those whom he
 acknowledged as the authors of his elevation.","('Leonas', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"He had
 taken some slow and irresolute measures for the purpose of
 collecting his troops, when he was surprised by Dagalaiphus,
 an active officer, whom Julian, as soon as he landed at
 Bononia, had pushed forward with some light infantry.","('Dagalaiphus', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Bononia', 'GPE')"
"He had discovered from intercepted letters that
 his adversary, sacrificing the interest of the state to that
 of the monarch, had again excited the barbarians to invade
 the provinces of the West.","('West', 'LOC')"
"He issued the necessary
 orders for carrying into execution the commands of
 Constantius; a part of the troops began their march for the
 Alps; and the detachments from the several garrisons moved
 towards their respective places of assembly.","('Constantius', 'PRODUCT'), ('Alps', 'LOC')"
"He might perhaps sincerely have preferred the groves
 of the Academy and the society of Athens; but he was
 constrained, at first by the will, and afterwards by the
 injustice of Constantius, to expose his person and fame to
 the dangers of Imperial greatness; and to make himself
 accountable to the world and to posterity for the happiness
 of millions. (46) Julian recollected with terror the 
 observation of his master Plato,(47) that the government of 
 our flocks and herds is always committed to beings of a
 superior species; and that the conduct of nations requires
 and deserves the celestial powers of the Gods or of the
 Genii.","('Academy', 'ORG'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('millions', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('47', 'CARDINAL'), ('Genii', 'NORP')"
"He questioned the man concerning the profits of his employment, and was informed that, besides a large salary and some valuable perquisites, he enjoyed a daily allowance for twenty servants and as many horses.","('twenty', 'CARDINAL')"
"He recapitulated their victories, lamented
 their sufferings, applauded their resolution, animated their
 hopes, and checked their impetuosity; nor did he dismiss the
 assembly till he had obtained a solemn promise from the
 troops that, if the emperor of the East would subscribe an
 equitable treaty, they would renounce any views of conquest,
 and satisfy themselves with the tranquil possession of the
 Gallic provinces.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Gallic', 'NORP')"
"He relieved the distress and
 restored the beauty of the cities of Epirus and Peloponnesus.(78) Athens acknowledged him for her benefactor, Argos for her deliverer.","('Epirus', 'ORG'), ('Peloponnesus', 'ORG'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Argos', 'PERSON')"
"He required that the
 presumptuous Caesar should expressly renounce the
 appellation and rank of Augustus which he had accepted from
 the rebels; that he should descend to his former station of
 a limited and dependent minister; that he should vest the
 powers of the state and army in the hands of those officers
 who were appointed by the Imperial court; and that he should
 trust his safety to the assurances of pardon, which were
 announced by Epictetus, a Gallic bishop, and one of the
 Arian favourites of Constantius.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Epictetus', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'ORG')"
"He selected three thousand
 brave and active volunteers, resolved, like their leader, to
 cast behind them every hope of a retreat; at the head of
 this faithful band he fearlessly plunged into the recesses
 of the Marcian, or Black Forest, which conceals the sources
 of the Danube;(29) and, for many days, the fate of Julian was 
 unknown to the world.","('three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Marcian', 'NORP'), ('Black Forest', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('29', 'CARDINAL'), ('many days', 'DATE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"He solemnly declares, in the presence of
 Jupiter, of the Sun, of Mars, of Minerva, and of all the
 other deities, that till the close of the evening which
 preceded his elevation he was utterly ignorant of the
 designs of the soldiers; (12) and it may seem ungenerous to 
 distrust the honour of a hero, and the truth of a
 philosopher.","('Jupiter', 'LOC'), ('Sun', 'LOC'), ('Mars', 'LOC'), ('Minerva', 'LOC'), ('12', 'CARDINAL')"
"He was assisted by the eloquent Mamertinus,(61) one of the consuls elect, whose merit is loudly celebrated by the doubtful evidence of his own applause.","('Mamertinus', 'PERSON'), ('61', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"He was exalted on a
 shield in the presence and amidst the unanimous acclamations
 of the troops; a rich military collar, which was offered by
 chance, supplied the want of a diadem;(8) the ceremony was 
 concluded by the promise of a moderate donative;(9) and the 
 new emperor, overwhelmed with real or affected grief,
 retired into the most secret recesses of his apartment.(10)
His protestations of innocence .","('8', 'CARDINAL'), ('9', 'CARDINAL'), ('10', 'CARDINAL')"
"He was soon 
 awakened by the entrance of fresh secretaries, who had slept
 the preceding day; and his servants were obliged to wait
 alternately, while their indefatigable master allowed
 himself scarcely any other refreshment than the change of
 occupations.","('the preceding day', 'DATE')"
"His
 application to the senate of Rome, which was still permitted
 to bestow the titles of imperial power, was agreeable to the
 forms of the expiring republic.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"His
 spirited discourse was received with the loudest
 acclamations, and the same troops which had taken up arms
 against Constantius, when he summoned them to leave Gaul,
 now declared with alacrity that they would follow Julian to
 the farthest extremities of Europe or Asia.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"His care of the Graecian cities and by imposing an equal distribution of public duties, he restored the strength, the splendour, or, according to the glowing
 expression of Libanius, (77) the soul of the expiring cities  of his empire.","('Graecian', 'NORP'), ('Libanius', 'PERSON'), ('77', 'CARDINAL')"
His envoy to Constantius.,"('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"His epistle to the senate and people
 of Athens(37) seems to have been dictated by an elegant 
 enthusiasm, which prompted him to submit his actions and his
 motives to the degenerate Athenians of his own times, with
 the same humble deference as if he had been pleading in the
 days of Aristides before the tribunal of the Areopagus.","('Athens', 'GPE'), ('37', 'DATE'), ('Athenians', 'NORP'), ('Aristides', 'PERSON'), ('Areopagus', 'ORG')"
"His genius was less powerful
 and sublime than that of Caesar, nor did he possess the
 consummate prudence of Augustus.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
His march from the Rhine to Illyricum.,"('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Illyricum', 'GPE')"
"His oblique censure of the innovations of Constantine, and his passionate invective against the vices of Constantius, were heard with less satisfaction; and the senate, as if Julian had been present, unanimously exclaimed, ""Respect, we beseech you, the author of your own fortune."" (38)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('38', 'CARDINAL')"
"If Julian
 complied with the orders which he had received he subscribed
 to his own destruction, and that of a people who deserved
 his affection.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Impatient to visit the place of his birth and the new capital of the empire, he advanced from Naissus through the
 mountains of Haemus and the cities of Thrace.","('Naissus', 'GPE'), ('Haemus', 'GPE'), ('Thrace', 'LOC')"
"In a satirical performance, which was
 designed for the public eye, the emperor descants with
 pleasure, and even with pride, on the length of his nails
 and the inky blackness of his hands; protests that although
 the greatest part of his body was covered with hair, the use
 of the razor was confined to his head alone; and celebrates
 with visible complacency the shaggy and populous (58) beard which he fondly cherished, after the example of the
 philosophers of Greece.","('58', 'CARDINAL'), ('Greece', 'GPE')"
"In the
 course of this long and rapid navigation, the mind of Julian
 was fixed on the object of his enterprise; and though he
 accepted the deputation of some cities, which hastened to
 claim the merit of an early submission, he passed before the
 hostile stations, which were placed along the river, without
 indulging the temptation of signalising a useless and
 ill-timed valour.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"In the
 letters crowned with laurel, which, according to ancient
 custom, were addressed to the provinces, the name of Julian
 was omitted.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"In the camp of Hierapolis, in  Syria, he communicated this design to his army; slightly mentioned the guilt and rashness, of the Caesar; and
 ventured to assure them that, if the mutineers of Gaul
 presumed to meet them in the field, they would be unable to
 sustain the fire of their eyes and the irresistible weight
 of their shout of onset.","('Hierapolis', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"In the meanwhile
 the Caesar was oppressed by the rude and importunate
 solicitations of the Imperial messengers, who presumed to
 suggest that, if he expected the return of his ministers, he
 could charge himself with the guilt of the delay, and
 reserve for them the merit of the execution.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"In the neighbourhood of
 Basel he assembled and divided his army.(28)","('Basel', 'GPE')"
"In this negotiation Julian
 claimed no more than he already possessed.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Julian covered the praefect with his Imperial
 mantle, and protecting him from the zeal of his followers,
 dismissed him to his own house, with less respect than was
 perhaps due to the virtue of an enemy.(26)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('26', 'CARDINAL')"
"Julian had received the submission of two legions and a
 cohort of archers who were stationed at Sirmium, but he
 suspected, with reason, the fidelity of those troops which
 had been distinguished by the emperor; and it was thought
 expedient, under the pretence of the exposed state of the
 Gallic frontier, to dismiss them from the most important
 scene of action.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sirmium', 'ORG'), ('Gallic', 'NORP')"
Julian is declared emperor by the legions of Gaul—,"('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
Julian prepares to attack Constantius.,"('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"Julian was not insensible of the advantages of freedom.(70) 
 From his studies he had imbibed the spirit of ancient sages
 and heroes; his life and fortunes had depended on the
 caprice of a tyrant; and, when he ascended the throne, his
 pride was sometimes mortified by the reflection that the
 slaves who would not dare to censure his defects were not
 worthy to applaud his virtues.(71) He sincerely abhorred the 
 system of oriental despotism which Diocletian, Constantine,
 and the patient habits of four score years, had established
 in the empire.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"Julian was slow in his suspicions,
 and gentle in his punishments, and his contempt of treason
 was the result of judgment, of vanity, and of courage.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Julian was tormented by
 the importunities of a multitude, particularly of Egyptians,
 who loudly redemanded the gifts which they had imprudently
 or illegally bestowed; he foresaw the endless prosecution of
 vexatious suits, and he engaged a promise, which ought
 always to have been sacred, that if they would repair to
 Chalcedon, he would meet them in person, to hear and
 determine their complaints.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Egyptians', 'NORP'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE')"
"Lucilian, who, with the rank
 of general of the cavalry commanded the military powers of
 Illyricum, was alarmed and perplexed by the doubtful
 reports, which he could neither reject nor believe.","('Lucilian', 'PERSON'), ('Illyricum', 'ORG')"
"Most of the
 auxiliaries, who engaged their voluntary service, had
 stipulated that they should never be obliged to pass the
 Alps.","('Alps', 'LOC')"
"On foot, without his diadem, and clothed in a mourning habit, he accompanied the funeral as far as the church of the Holy Apostles, where the body was deposited: and if these marks of respect may be interpreted as a selfish tribute to the birth and dignity of his Imperial kinsman, the tears of Julian professed to the world that he had forgot the injuries, and remembered only the obligations, which he had received from Constantius.(44)","('the Holy Apostles', 'ORG'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"On solemn festivals, Julian, who felt and
 professed an unfashionable dislike to these frivolous
 amusements, condescended to appear in the Circus; and, after
 bestowing a careless glance on five or six of the races, he
 hastily withdrew with the impatience of a philosopher, who
 considered every moment as lost that was not devoted to the
 advantage of the public or the improvement of his own mind.
 (52)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('six', 'CARDINAL')"
"On the
 calends of January, at break of day, the new consuls,
 Mamertinus and Nevitta, hastened to the palace to salute the
 emperor.","('January', 'DATE'), ('Mamertinus', 'PERSON'), ('Nevitta', 'PERSON')"
"On this foundation he composed, in his own
 name, and in that of the army, a specious and moderate
 epistle,(15) which was delivered to Pentadius, his master of 
 the offices, and to his chamberlain Eutherius; two
 ambassadors whom he appointed to receive the answer and
 observe the dispositions of Constantius.","('Pentadius', 'PERSON'), ('Eutherius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"One body, which 
 consisted of ten thousand men, was directed, under the
 command of Nevitta, general of the cavalry, to advance
 through the midland parts of Rhaetia and Noricum.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nevitta', 'PERSON'), ('Rhaetia', 'GPE'), ('Noricum', 'GPE')"
"One of his most intimate friends,(49) who had often shared the frugal simplicity of his table, has remarked that his
 light and sparing diet (which was usually of the vegetable
 kind) left his mind and body always free and active for the
 various and important business of an author, a pontiff, a
 magistrate, a general, and a prince.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('49', 'DATE')"
"Philosophy had instructed Julian to compare the advantages
 of action and retirement; but the elevation of his birth and
 the accidents of his life never allowed him the freedom of
 choice.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Prudence as well as loyalty inculcated
 the propriety of resisting their treasonable designs, and of
 preparing for his oppressed virtue the excuse of violence.","('Prudence', 'PERSON')"
"Secretly conscious that the applause and favour of the
 Romans accompanied the rising fortunes of Julian, his
 discontented mind was prepared to receive the subtle poison
 of those artful sycophants who coloured their mischievous
 designs with the fairest appearances of truth and candour. (3)  Instead of depreciating the merits of Julian, they acknowledged, and even exaggerated, his popular fame,
 superior talents, and important services.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Seven years after this sentence Julian(79) allowed the cause to be referred to a superior tribunal, and his eloquence was interposed, most probably with success, in the defence of a city which had been the royal seat of
 Agamemnon,(80) and had given to Macedonia a race of kings and conquerors.(81)
Julian, an orator and a judge.","('Seven years', 'DATE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('79', 'DATE'), ('Agamemnon', 'PERSON'), ('80', 'CARDINAL'), ('Macedonia', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Several months were
 ineffectually consumed in a treaty which was negotiated at
 the distance of three thousand miles between Paris and
 Antioch; and, as soon as Julian perceived that his moderate
 and respectful behaviour served only to irritate the pride
 of an implacable adversary, he boldly resolved to commit his
 life and fortune to the chance of a civil war.","('Several months', 'DATE'), ('three thousand miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Solitude increased the perplexity of Julian; he could no
 longer apply to the faithful counsels of Sallust, who had
 been removed from his office by the judicious malice of the
 eunuchs: he could not even enforce his representations by
 the concurrence of the ministers, who would have been afraid
 or ashamed to approve the ruin of Gaul.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Sallust', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"Such an act of treachery and oppression would
 destroy the confidence, and excite the resentment of the
 independent warriors of Germany, who considered truth as the
 noblest of their virtues, and freedom as the most valuable
 of their possessions.","('Germany', 'GPE')"
"Such indeed was the temper of Julian, who seldom recollected
 the fundamental maxim of Aristotle, that true virtue is
 placed at an equal distance between the opposite vices.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Aristotle', 'PERSON')"
"That faithful
 minister, alone and unassisted, asserted the rights of
 Constantius in the midst of an armed and angry multitude, to
 whose fury he had almost fallen an honourable, but useless
 sacrifice.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The
 assemblies of the senate, which Constantius had avoided,
 were considered by Julian as the place where he could
 exhibit with the most propriety the maxims of a republican
 and the talents of a rhetorician.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('republican', 'NORP')"
"The
 captive general, uncertain of his life or death, was hastily
 thrown upon a horse, and conducted to the presence of
 Julian, who kindly raised him from the ground, and dispelled
 the terror and amazement which seemed to stupefy his
 faculties.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The
 functions of a judge, which are sometimes incompatible with
 those of a prince, were exercised by Julian not only as a
 duty, but as an amusement; and although he might have
 trusted the integrity and discernment of his Braetorian
 praefects, he often placed himself by their side on the seat
 of judgment.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Braetorian', 'NORP')"
"The
 instructions to the generals were conceived with energy and
 precision: to hasten their march in close and compact
 columns, which, according to the disposition of the ground,
 might readily be changed into any order of battle; to secure
 themselves against the surprises of the night by strong
 posts and vigilant guards; to prevent resistance by their
 unexpected arrival; to elude examination by their sudden
 departure; to spread the opinion of their strength, and the
 terror of his name; and to join their sovereign under the
 walls of Sirmium.","('the night', 'TIME'), ('Sirmium', 'ORG')"
"The
 notary Gaudentius had occupied in his name the provinces of
 Africa; the subsistence of Rome was intercepted; and the
 distress of Julian was increased by an unexpected event,
 which might have been productive of fatal consequences.","('Gaudentius', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The
 splendid and effeminate dress of the Asiatics, the curls and
 paint, the collars and bracelets, which had appeared so
 ridiculous in the person of Constantine, were consistently
 rejected by his philosophic successor.","('Asiatics', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The Caesar foresaw and lamented 
 the consequences of this fatal mandate.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"The Misopogon, the
 Caesars, several of his orations, and his elaborate work
 against the Christian religion, were composed in the long
 nights of the two winters, the former of which he passed at
 Constantinople, and the latter at Antioch.","('Misopogon', 'PERSON'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('the two winters', 'DATE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"The actions
 of Julian can only be preserved by the care of the
 historian; but the portion of his voluminous writings which
 is still extant remains as a monument of the application, as
 well as of the genius, of the emperor.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The ambassadors of Julian had been instructed to execute
 with the utmost diligence their important commission.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The apprehensions of
 the Gauls were derived from the knowledge of the impending
 and inevitable danger.","('Gauls', 'NORP')"
"The approach of winter could not detain the
 monarch at Antioch; and his favourites durst not oppose his
 impatient desire of revenge.","('winter', 'DATE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"The army, which
 Julian held in readiness for immediate action, was recruited
 and augmented by the disorders of the times.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The arts of persuasion, so diligently cultivated by the
 first Caesars, were neglected by the military ignorance and
 Asiatic pride of their successors, and, if they condescended
 to harangue the soldiers, whom they feared, they treated
 with silent disdain the senators, whom they despised.","('Asiatic', 'NORP')"
"The assembly was dismissed; and Leonas, who with some difficulty had been protected from the popular fury, was sent back to his master with an epistle in which Julian expressed, in a strain of the most vehement eloquence, the sentiments of contempt, of hatred, and of resentment, which had been suppressed and embittered by the dissimulation of twenty years.","('Leonas', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('twenty years', 'DATE')"
"The banks of the Danube were crowded on
 either side with spectators, who gazed on the military pomp,
 anticipated the importance of the event, and diffused
 through the adjacent country the fame of a young hero, who
 advanced with more than mortal speed at the head of the
 innumerable forces of the West.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"The barbarians of Germany had felt,
 and still dreaded, the arms of the young Caesar; his
 soldiers were the companions of his victory; the grateful
 provincials enjoyed the blessings of his reign; but the
 favourites, who had opposed his elevation, were offended by
 his virtues; and they justly considered the friend of the
 people as the enemy of the court.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"The barrier of Gaul was improved and
 strengthened with additional fortifications; and Julian
 entertained some hopes that the Germans, whom he had so
 often vanquished, might, in his absence, be restrained by
 the terror of his name.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"The chamberlain Eusebius, who had so long abused the favour
 of Constantius, expiated, by an ignominious death, the
 insolence, the corruption, and cruelty of his servile reign.","('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The cruel
 persecution of the faction of Magnentius had filled Gaul
 with numerous bands of outlaws and robbers.","('Magnentius', 'ORG'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
The death of Constantius—Civil Administration of Julian,"('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The decrees of Julian were almost always founded on
 the principles of justice, and he had the firmness to resist
 the two most dangerous temptations which assault the
 tribunal of a sovereign under the specious forms of
 compassion and equity.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The defence of this important post  was intrusted to the brave Nevitta, who, as well as the generals of the Italian division, successfully executed the plan of the march and junction which their master had so ably conceived.","('Nevitta', 'PERSON'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
"The delegated
 authority which he had long exercised over the provinces of
 Gaul, Spain, and Britain, was still obeyed under a name more
 independent and august.","('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"The difficulty, as well as glory, of
 this enterprise consisted in a laborious march; and Julian
 had conquered, as soon as he could penetrate into, a country
 which former princes had considered as inaccessible.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The discontent
 of the troops was produced by the malice of his enemies;
 their tumult was the natural effect of interest and of
 passion; and if Julian had tried to conceal a deep design
 under the appearances of chance, he must have employed the
 most consummate artifice without necessity, and probably
 without success.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The domestic connection, which might
 have reconciled the brother and the husband of Helena, was
 recently dissolved by the death of that princess, whose
 pregnancy had been several times fruitless, and was at last
 fatal to herself. (21)","('Helena', 'PERSON')"
"The empress Eusebia had preserved, to 
 the last moment of her life, the warm, and even jealous,
 affection which she had conceived for Julian; and her mild
 influence might have moderated the resentment of a prince
 who, since her death, was abandoned to his own passions, and
 to the arts of his eunuchs.","('Eusebia', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The executions of Paul and Apodemius (the former of whom was
 burnt alive) were accepted as an inadequate atonement by the
 widows and orphans of so many hundred Romans whom those
 legal tyrants had betrayed and murdered.","('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Apodemius', 'PERSON'), ('so many hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The faint
 proposal was impetuously silenced; and the acclamations of thundered at once from every part of the field, and terrified the pale ambassador of Constantius.","('Constantius', 'GPE')"
"The former was banished to Vercellae in Italy,
 and a sentence of death was pronounced against the latter.","('Vercellae', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The grief of Julian could proceed only from his innocence;
 but his innocence must appear extremely doubtful(11) in the 
 eyes of those who have learned to suspect the motives and
 the professions of princes.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The grief of an armed
 multitude is soon converted into rage, their licentious
 murmurs, which every hour were communicated from tent to
 tent with more boldness and effect, prepared their minds for
 the most daring acts of sedition; and by the connivance of
 their tribunes a seasonable libel was secretly dispersed,
 which painted in lively colours the disgrace of the Caesar,
 the oppression of the Gallic army, and the feeble vices of
 the tyrant of Asia.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The high office of 
 Nebridius was bestowed on Sallust; and the provinces of
 Gaul, which were now delivered from the intolerable
 oppression of taxes, enjoyed the mild and equitable
 administration of the friend of Julian, who was permitted to
 practise those virtues which he had instilled into the mind
 of his pupil.(27)","('Nebridius', 'GPE'), ('Sallust', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The homage which Julian obtained from the fears or the
 inclination of the people extended far beyond the immediate
 effect of his arms. (35)","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The hopes of Julian depended much less on the number of his
 troops than on the celerity of his motions.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The immunity of Elis and Delphi was respected by the Corinthians, but the poverty of Argos tempted the insolence of oppression, and the feeble complaints of its deputies were silenced by the decree of a provincial magistrate, who seems to have consulted only the interest of the capital in which he resided.","('Elis', 'PERSON'), ('Delphi', 'ORG'), ('Corinthians', 'PERSON'), ('Argos', 'ORG')"
"The inexorable jealousy
 of the emperor, the peremptory, and perhaps insidious,
 nature of his commands, left not any room for a fair apology
 or candid interpretation; and the dependent station of the
 Caesar scarcely allowed him to pause or to deliberate.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"The inflexible
 Caesar sustained, till the third hour of the day, their
 prayers, their reproaches, and their menaces; nor did he
 yield till he had been repeatedly assured that, if he wished
 to live, he must consent to reign.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('the third hour of the day', 'TIME')"
"The intelligence of the march and rapid progress of Julian
 was speedily transmitted to his rival, who, by the retreat
 of Sapor, had obtained some respite from the Persian war.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('the Persian war', 'EVENT')"
The jealousy of Constantius against Julian.,"('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The laborious administration of military and civil affairs,
 which were multiplied in proportion to the extent of the
 empire, exercised the abilities of Julian; but he frequently
 assumed the two characters of Orator (82) and of Judge,(83) 
 which are almost unknown to the modern sovereigns of Europe.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Orator', 'PERSON'), ('82', 'CARDINAL'), ('83', 'CARDINAL'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"The labours of his mariners, who
 plied their oars with incessant diligence, and the steady
 continuance of a favourable wind, carried his fleet above
 seven hundred miles in eleven days;(32) and he had already 
 disembarked his troops at Bononia, only nineteen miles from
 Sirmium, before his enemies could receive any certain
 intelligence that he had left the banks of the Rhine.","('seven hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('eleven days', 'DATE'), ('32', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bononia', 'GPE'), ('only nineteen miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Sirmium', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"The latter, a crafty and corrupt
 statesman, declining to assume a responsible part on this
 dangerous occasion, eluded the pressing and repeated
 invitations of Julian, who represented to him that in every
 important measure the presence of the praefect was
 indispensable in the council of the prince.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The legionaries, who enjoyed the title
 and privileges of Romans, were enlisted for the general
 defence of the republic; but those mercenary troops heard
 with cold indifference the antiquated names of the republic
 and of Rome.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The legions of Gaul are ordered to march into the East. A.D. 360, April T
he apparent tranquillity of Gaul, and the imminent danger
 of the eastern provinces, offered a specious pretence for
 the design which was artfully concerted by the Imperial
 ministers.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('360', 'CARDINAL'), ('April T', 'DATE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The long abuse of power
 rendered him a considerable object in the eyes of his
 contemporaries; but, as personal merit can alone deserve the
 notice of posterity, the last of the sons of Constantine may
 be dismissed from the world with the remark that he
 inherited the defects, without the abilities, of his father.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The luxury of
 the palace excited the contempt and indignation of Julian,
 who usually slept on the ground, who yielded with reluctance
 to the indispensable calls of nature, and who placed his
 vanity not in emulating, but in despising the pomp of
 royalty.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The military designs of that prince, who had formed
 three different attacks against Thrace, were prevented by
 this fortunate event.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Thrace', 'LOC')"
"The moment had been
 chosen when Lupicinus, (5) the general of the cavalry, was 
 despatched into Britain, to repulse the inroads of the Scots
 and Picts; and Florentius was occupied at Vienne by the
 assessment of the tribute.","('Lupicinus', 'PERSON'), ('5', 'CARDINAL'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Scots', 'NORP'), ('Picts', 'NORP'), ('Florentius', 'PERSON'), ('Vienne', 'PERSON')"
"The moment he was reminded that he had trespassed on
 the jurisdiction of another magistrate, he condemned himself
 to pay a fine of ten pounds of gold, and embraced this
 public occasion of declaring to the world that he was
 subject, like the rest of his fellow-citizens, to the laws,
 (75) and even to the forms, of the republic.","('ten pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"The monarch, after
 making some inquiry into the rank and character of his
 rival, despatched the informer with a present of a pair of
 purple slippers, to complete the magnificence of his
 Imperial habit.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The most exquisite dainties were procured to gratify their pride rather than their taste; birds of the most distant climates, fish from the most remote seas, fruits out of their natural season, winter roses, and summer snows. (56)","('summer', 'DATE'), ('56', 'DATE')"
"The numerous army of spies, of agents, and informers,
 enlisted by Constantius to secure the repose of one man, and
 to interrupt that of millions, was immediately disbanded by
 his generous successor.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('millions', 'CARDINAL')"
"The oath of
 fidelity was administered; and the soldiers, clashing their
 shields, and pointing their drawn swords to their throats,
 devoted themselves, with horrid imprecations, to the service
 of a leader whom they celebrated as the deliverer of Gaul
 and the conqueror of the Germans.(25)","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('25', 'CARDINAL')"
"The office of president was exercised by the venerable praefect of the East, a second  Sallust, (60) whose virtues conciliated the esteem of Greek sophists and of Christian bishops.","('East', 'LOC'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Sallust', 'NORP'), ('60', 'CARDINAL'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The office, or rather the name, of
 consul was cherished by a prince who contemplated with
 reverence the ruins of the republic; and the same behaviour
 which had been assumed by the prudence of Augustus was
 adopted by Julian from choice and inclination.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The only instance in
 which Julian seemed to depart from his accustomed clemency
 was the execution of a rash youth, who, with a feeble hand,
 had aspired to seize the reins of empire.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The personal fears of Constantius were
 interpreted by his council as a laudable anxiety for the
 public safety; whilst in private, and perhaps in his own
 breast, he disguised, under the less odious appellation of
 fear, the sentiments of hatred and envy which he had
 secretly conceived for the inimitable virtues of Julian.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The persons who were disaffected to the new government were
 disarmed and secured; and the vacant offices were
 distributed, according to the recommendation of merit, by a
 prince who despised the intrigues of the palace and the
 clamours of the soldiers.(16)
His fourth and fifth expedition beyond the Rhine.","('16', 'CARDINAL'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('fifth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"The policy of Julian
 condescended to surprise the prince of the Alemanni by his
 own arts: and Vadomair, who, in the character of a friend,
 had incautiously accepted an invitation from the Roman
 governors, was seized in the midst of the entertainment, and
 sent away prisoner into the heart of Spain.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Vadomair', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE')"
"The position of two magazines,
 one of them collected on the banks of the lake of Constance,
 the other formed at the foot of the Cottian Alps, seemed to
 indicate the march of two armies; and the size of those
 magazines, each of which consisted of six hundred thousand
 quarters of wheat, or rather flour, (24) was a threatening 
 evidence of the strength and numbers of the enemy who
 prepared to surround him.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constance', 'LOC'), ('the Cottian Alps', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('six hundred thousand\r\n quarters', 'CARDINAL'), ('24', 'CARDINAL')"
"The praefectures of Italy and 
 Illyricum were administered by Taurus and Florentius, who
 united that important office with the vain honours of the
 consulship; and, as those magistrates had retired with
 precipitation to the court of Asia, Julian, who could not
 always restrain the levity of his temper, stigmatised their
 flight by adding, in all the Acts of the Year, the epithet
 of fugitive  to the names of the two consuls.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Illyricum', 'GPE'), ('Taurus', 'PERSON'), ('Florentius', 'PERSON'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('the Year', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The predecessors of Julian, his uncle, his
 brother, and his cousin, indulged their puerile taste for
 the games of the Circus, under the specious pretence of
 complying with the inclinations of the people; and they
 frequently remained the greatest part of the day as idle
 spectators, and as a part of the splendid spectacle, till
 the ordinary round of twenty-four races(51) was completely 
 finished.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Circus', 'EVENT'), ('the day', 'DATE'), ('twenty-four', 'CARDINAL'), ('51', 'CARDINAL')"
"The pride of Corinth, again rising
 from her ruins with the honours of a Roman colony, exacted a tribute from the adjacent republics for the purpose of defraying the games of the Isthmus, which were celebrated in the amphitheatre with the hunting of bears and panthers.","('Corinth', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Isthmus', 'LOC')"
"The principal officers were entertained by the Caesar, who
 professed, in the warmest language of friendship, his desire
 and his inability to reward, according to their deserts, the
 brave companions of his victories.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"The provinces
 which had been deserted by their first magistrates
 acknowledged the authority of an emperor who, conciliating
 the qualities of a soldier with those of a philosopher, was
 equally admired in the camps of the Danube and in the cities
 of Greece.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Greece', 'GPE')"
"The public faith of Rome, and the personal honour of
 Julian, had been pledged for the observance of this
 condition.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The rage of the
 soldiers, whom he had provoked by his indiscretion, was the
 cause and the excuse of his death; and the emperor, deeply
 wounded by his own reproaches and those of the public,
 offered some consolation to the family of Ursulus by the
 restitution of his confiscated fortunes.","('Ursulus', 'PERSON')"
The reformation of the Imperial court was one of the first and most necessary acts of the government of Julian.(53) Soon after his entrance into the palace of Constantinople he had occasion for the service of a barber.,"('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The secrecy of his march, his
 diligence, and vigour, surmounted every obstacle; he forced
 his way over mountains and morasses, occupied the bridges or
 swam the rivers, pursued his direct course (30) without 
 reflecting whether he traversed the territory of the Romans
 or of the barbarians, and at length emerged, between
 Ratisbon and Vienna, at the place where he designed to
 embark his troops on the Danube.","('30', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Ratisbon', 'GPE'), ('Vienna', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"The servants of Constantius were
 astonished and alarmed by the progress of this dangerous
 spirit.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The situation of Julian required a vigorous and immediate
 resolution.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The speech of the emperor was
 received with military applause; and Theodotus, the
 president of the council of Hierapolis, requested, with
 tears of adulation, that his  city might be adorned with the
 head of the vanquished rebel. (40)","('Theodotus', 'PERSON'), ('Hierapolis', 'GPE')"
"The spirit of his 
 administration, and his regard for the place of his
 nativity, induced Julian to confer on the senate of
 Constantinople the same honours, privileges, and authority
 which were still enjoyed by the senate of ancient Rome.(76)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('the senate of\r\n Constantinople', 'ORG'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('76', 'CARDINAL')"
The stately palaces erected by Constantine and his sons were decorated with many-coloured marbles and ornaments of massy gold.,"('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The supper of the
 emperor was still less substantial than the former meal; his
 sleep was never clouded by the fumes of indigestion; and,
 except in the short interval of a marriage which was the
 effect of policy rather than love, the chaste Julian never
 shared his bed with a female companion. (50)","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The throne of Julian, which the death of
 Constantius fixed on an independent basis, was the seat of
 reason, of virtue, and perhaps of vanity.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The venerable age of Greece excited the most tender compassion in the mind of Julian, which kindled into
 rapture when he recollected the gods, the heroes, and the men superior to heroes and to gods, who had bequeathed to the latest posterity the monuments of their genius or the example of their virtues.","('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The vigilance of Julian
 perceived at once the extent of the mischief, and the
 necessity of applying an immediate remedy.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The virtues of Trajan
 appear more steady and natural, and the philosophy of Marcus
 is more simple and consistent.","('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Marcus', 'PERSON')"
"The voice of malicious folly was at length silenced by the shouts of victory; the conqueror of the Franks and Alemanni could no longer be painted as an object of contempt; and the
 monarch himself was meanly ambitious of stealing from his
 lieutenant the honourable reward of his labours.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON')"
"Their
 intemperance revealed their guilt, and they were conducted
 in chains to the presence of their injured sovereign, who,
 after a lively representation of the wickedness and folly of
 their enterprise, instead of a death of torture, which they
 deserved and expected, pronounced a sentence of exile
 against the two principal offenders.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"They advanced, with reluctance, as far as
 the confines of Italy; but, as they dreaded the length of
 the way and the savage fierceness of the Germans, they
 resolved, by the instigation of one of their tribunes, to
 halt at Aquileia, and to erect the banners of Constantius on
 the walls of that impregnable city.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aquileia', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'GPE')"
"They cheerfully
 accepted the offer of a general pardon from a prince whom
 they could trust, submitted to the restraints of military
 discipline, and retained only their implacable hatred to the
 person and government of Constantius. (17)","('Constantius', 'ORG'), ('17', 'CARDINAL')"
"They easily discovered that his simplicity was not exempt
 from affectation: the ridiculous epithets of an hairy
 savage, of an ape invested with the purple, were applied to
 the dress and person of the philosophic warrior; and his
 modest despatches were stigmatised as the vain and elaborate
 fictions of a loquacious Greek, a speculative soldier, who
 had studied the art of war amidst the groves of the Academy.
 (1)","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Academy', 'ORG'), ('1', 'CARDINAL')"
"They pressed the Caesar to hasten the departure of
 the troops; but they imprudently rejected the honest and
 judicious advice of Julian, who proposed that they should
 not march through Paris, and suggested the danger and
 temptation of a last interview.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Paris', 'GPE')"
They proclaim Julian emperor.,"('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"They resolved to disarm the Caesar; to recall
 those faithful troops who guarded his person and dignity;
 and to employ, in a distant war against the Persian monarch,
 the hardy veterans who had vanquished, on the banks of the
 Rhine, the fiercest nations of Germany.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"This epistle is
 inscribed with the modest appellation of Caesar; but Julian
 solicits in a peremptory, though respectful manner, the
 confirmation of the title of Augustus.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"This scene of general
 distress afflicted the humanity of the Caesar; he granted a
 sufficient number of post-waggons to transport the wives and
 families of the soldiers, (6) endeavoured to alleviate the 
 hardships which he was constrained to inflict, and increased
 by the most laudable arts his own popularity and the
 discontent of the exiled troops.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"This solemn engagement, 
 which seemed to be dictated by affection rather than by
 duty, was singly opposed by Nebridius, who had been admitted
 to the office of Praetorian praefect.","('Nebridius', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP')"
"To conduct this inquiry, Julian named six judges of the highest rank in the state and army, and, as he wished to escape the reproach of condemning his personal enemies, he fixed this extraordinary tribunal at Chalcedon, on the Asiatic side of the Bosphorous, and transferred to the commissioners an absolute power to pronounce and execute their final sentence, without delay and without appeal.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Bosphorous', 'ORG')"
"To moderate the zeal of his party, to protect the persons of
 his enemies, (14) to defeat and to despise the secret 
 enterprises which were formed against his life and dignity,
 were the cares which employed the first days of the reign of
 the new emperor.","('14', 'CARDINAL'), ('the first days', 'DATE')"
"Two days were devoted to the public joy, which was celebrated by the games of the Circus; but, early on the morning of the third day, Julian marched to occupy the narrow pass of Succi, in the defiles of Mount Haemus; which, almost in the midway between Sirmium and Constantinople, separates the provinces of Thrace and Dacia, by an abrupt
 descent towards the former, and a gentle declivity on the side of the latter.","('Two days', 'DATE'), ('Circus', 'EVENT'), ('the morning of the third day', 'TIME'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Succi', 'LOC'), ('Mount Haemus', 'LOC'), ('Sirmium', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Dacia', 'GPE')"
"Unable to
 resist, unwilling to comply, Julian expressed in the most
 serious terms his wish, and even his intention, of resigning
 the purple, which he could not preserve with honour, but
 which he could not abdicate with safety.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Vadomair(19) was the only prince of 
 the Alemanni whom he esteemed or feared; and while the
 subtle barbarian affected to observe the faith of treaties,
 the progress of his arms threatened the state with an
 unseasonable and dangerous war.","('Vadomair', 'PERSON'), ('19', 'DATE'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON')"
"Whatever had
 been his choice of life, by the force of intrepid courage,
 lively wit, and intense application, he would have obtained,
 or at least he would have deserved, the highest honours of
 his profession, and Julian might have raised himself to the
 rank of minister or general of the state in which he was
 born a private citizen.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"When Julian had received the intelligence of the
 conspiracy, he resigned himself to a short slumber; and
 afterwards related to his friends that he had seen the
 Genius of the empire waiting with some impatience at his
 door, pressing for admittance, and reproaching his want of
 spirit and ambition.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"When he reached Heraclea, at the distance of sixty miles, all Constantinople was poured forth to receive him; Julian enters Constantinople, December 11.","('Heraclea', 'GPE'), ('sixty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('December 11', 'DATE')"
"When we
 inspect with minute, or perhaps malevolent, attention the
 portrait of Julian, something seems wanting to the grace and
 perfection of the whole figure.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"While Julian used
 the laborious hours of his winter quarters at Paris in the
 administration of power, which, in his hands, was the
 exercise of virtue, he was surprised by the hasty arrival of
 a tribune and a notary, with positive orders from the
 emperor, which they  were directed to execute, and he  was
 commanded not to oppose.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('the laborious hours', 'TIME'), ('winter', 'DATE'), ('Paris', 'GPE')"
"While his ministers reposed, the prince flew
 with agility from one labour to another; and, after a hasty
 dinner, retired into his library till the public business
 which he had appointed for the evening summoned him to
 interrupt the prosecution of his studies.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('the evening', 'TIME')"
"While the Romans languished under the ignominious tyranny of
 eunuchs and bishops, the praises of Julian were repeated
 with transport in every part of the empire, except in the
 palace of Constantius.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'GPE')"
"Without appearing to indulge
 his personal resentment, Julian might easily confound the
 crime of the son and of the father; but he was reconciled by
 the distress of Marcellus, and the liberality of the emperor
 endeavoured to heal the wound which had been inflicted by
 the hand of justice.(69)","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Marcellus', 'PERSON')"
"Yet Julian sustained
 adversity with firmness, and prosperity with moderation.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Yet the
 circumstances of their trial and condemnation were so
 unskilfully managed that these wicked men obtained, in the
 public opinion, the glory of suffering for the obstinate
 loyalty with which they had supported the cause of
 Constantius.","('Constantius', 'ORG')"
"Yet the superstitious confidence that
 Constantius was the enemy, and that he himself was the
 favourite, of the gods, might prompt him to desire, to
 solicit, and even to hasten the auspicious moment of his
 reign, which was predestined to restore the ancient religion
 of mankind.","('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
from which he was at that time distant above forty days' journey. (2),"(""forty days'"", 'DATE'), ('2', 'CARDINAL')"
