Sentence,Entities
"(1)
(19),"('19', 'CARDINAL')"
(34),"('34', 'CARDINAL')"
(72),"('72', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 false and servile epistle was subscribed by the reluctant
 hand of the captive queen; but the confession of the Roman
 senators who were sent to Constantinople revealed the truth
 of her deplorable situation, and Justinian, by the voice of
 a new ambassador, most powerfully interceded for her life
 and liberty.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"A
 large portion of Rome, from the Praenestine gate to the
 church of St. Paul, was never invested by the Goths; their
 excursions were restrained by the activity of the Moorish
 troops: the navigation of the Tyber, and the Latin, Appian,
 and Ostian ways, were left free and unmolested for the
 introduction of corn and cattle, or the retreat of the
 inhabitants, who sought refuge in Campania or Sicily.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('the Praenestine gate', 'FAC'), ('St. Paul', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Moorish', 'NORP'), ('Tyber', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Appian', 'NORP'), ('Ostian', 'NORP'), ('Campania', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE')"
"A
 national council was immediately held, and the new monarch
 reconciled the impatient spirit of the Barbarians to a
 measure of disgrace, which the misconduct of his predecessor
 rendered wise and indispensable.","('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"A
 sharp perpendicular rock rises above the level of the
 mountain, where the African princes deposited their wives
 and treasure; and a proverb is familiar to the Arabs, that
 the man may eat fire who dares to attack the craggy cliffs
 and inhospitable natives of Mount Aurasius.","('African', 'NORP'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Mount Aurasius', 'LOC')"
"A Goth,
 whom he had injured in his love, overtook Theodatus on the
 Flaminian way, and, regardless of his unmanly cries,
 slaughtered him, as he lay, prostrate on the ground, like a
 victim (says the historian) at the foot of the altar.","('Goth', 'PERSON'), ('Theodatus', 'PERSON'), ('Flaminian', 'NORP')"
"A Gothic prince, who had married the daughter of Theodatus,
 was stationed with an army to guard the entrance of Italy;
 but he imitated, without scruple, the example of a sovereign
 faithless to his public and private duties.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Theodatus', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"A chain was drawn across the Tyber; the
 arches of the aqueducts were made impervious, and the mole
 or sepulchre of Hadrian (82) was converted, for the first
 time, to the uses of a citadel.","('Tyber', 'PRODUCT'), ('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('82', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"A chosen troop of guards, who served
 on horseback and were armed with lances and bucklers,
 attended the person of Belisarius; his cavalry was composed
 of two hundred Huns, three hundred Moors, and four thousand
 confederates, and the infantry consisted only of three
 thousand Isaurians.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('two hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moors', 'NORP'), ('four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('three\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Isaurians', 'NORP')"
"A citadel was
 erected to secure this important conquest, and to remind the
 barbarians of their defeat; and as Solomon pursued his march
 to the west, the long-lost province of Mauritanian Sitifi was again
 annexed to the Roman empire.","('Solomon', 'PERSON'), ('Mauritanian Sitifi', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"A detachment
 of five thousand soldiers, and one hundred and twenty
 galleys, would have joined the remaining forces of the
 Vandals; and the descendant of Genseric might have surprised
 and oppressed a fleet of deep laden transports, incapable of
 action, and of light brigantines that seemed only qualified
 for flight.","('five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred and twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Vandals', 'PRODUCT'), ('Genseric', 'ORG')"
"A feeble rampart, and a
 shallow ditch, were maintained by the skill and valour of
 John the Sanguinary, who shared the danger and fatigue of
 the meanest soldier, and emulated, on a theatre less
 illustrious, the military virtues of his great commander.","('John the Sanguinary', 'PERSON')"
"A fine of one hundred and twenty thousand pounds sterling was levied on the fortunes of Belisarius; and with the office of count, or master of the royal stables, he accepted the conduct of the Italian war.","('one hundred and twenty thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('the Italian war', 'EVENT')"
"A flattering senate was
 sometime admitted to gaze on the magnificent spectacle; but
 it was enviously secluded from the public view: and the
 conqueror of Italy renounced, without a murmur, perhaps
 without a sigh, the well-earned honours of a second triumph.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
A fleet of three thousand Isaurians cast anchor in the Bay of Naples and afterwards at Ostia.,"('three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Isaurians', 'NORP'), ('the Bay of Naples', 'LOC'), ('Ostia', 'GPE')"
"A fleet, which had surprised Ancona,
 sailed along the coast of the Hadriatic, to the relief of
 the besieged city.","('Ancona', 'GPE'), ('Hadriatic', 'LOC')"
"A hasty flight into Asia saved Theodosius from the justice of an injured husband, who had signified to one of his guards the order of his death; but the tears of Antonina, and her artful seductions, assured the credulous hero of her innocence: and he stooped, against his faith and judgment, to abandon those imprudent friends, who had presumed to accuse or doubt the chastity of his wife.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antonina', 'PERSON')"
"A letter was intercepted, which assured the
 king of the Goths that the Asinarian gate, adjoining to the
 Lateran church, should be secretly opened to his troops.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Asinarian', 'NORP'), ('Lateran', 'NORP')"
"A nation of two hundred thousand soldiers might have smiled at the vain menace of Justinian and his lieutenant but a spirit of discord and disaffection prevailed in Italy, and the Goths supported with reluctance
the indignity of a female reign.(51)
Government and death of Amalasontha, queen of Italy, A.D. 522-534.","('two hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('51', 'CARDINAL'), ('Amalasontha', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('522-534', 'CARDINAL')"
"A rash though judicious saying of Constantine, ""I would sooner have punished the adulteress than the boy,"" was deeply remembered by Antonina; and two years afterwards, when despair had armed that officer against his general, her sanguinary advice decided and hastened his execution.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Antonina', 'PERSON'), ('two years afterwards', 'DATE')"
"A reinforcement
 of sixteen hundred Sclavonians and Huns was led by Martin and Valerian; and as they reposed during the winter season in the harbours of Greece, the strength of the men and horses was not impaired by the fatigues of a sea-voyage; and they distinguished their valour in the first sally against the
 besiegers.","('sixteen hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sclavonians', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'PERSON'), ('Martin', 'PERSON'), ('Valerian', 'PERSON'), ('the winter season', 'DATE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"A secret passage was discovered in one of the aqueducts; two
 citizens of the Vatican were tempted by bribes to intoxicate
 the guards of the Aurelian gate; an attack was meditated on
 the walls beyond the Tyber, in a place which was not
 fortified with towers; and the Barbarians advanced, with
 torches and scaling-ladders, to the assault of the Pincian
 gate.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Aurelian', 'GPE'), ('Tyber', 'PRODUCT'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Pincian', 'GPE')"
"A sister of the great Theodoric had been given in
 marriage to Thrasimond the African king: (49) on this
 occasion the fortress of Lilybaeum,(50) in Sicily, was
 resigned to the Vandals, and the princess Amalafrida was
 attended by a martial train of one thousand nobles and five
 thousand Gothic soldiers, who signalised their valour in the
 Moorish wars.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Thrasimond', 'PERSON'), ('African', 'NORP'), ('49', 'CARDINAL'), ('Lilybaeum', 'PERSON'), ('50', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Amalafrida', 'PERSON'), ('one thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('five\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Moorish', 'NORP')"
"A youth of consular  rank, and a sickly constitution, was punished, without a
 trial, like a malefactor and a slave: yet such was the
 constancy of his mind, that Photius sustained the tortures
 of the scourge and the rack, ! without violating the faith  which he had sworn to Belisarius.","('Photius', 'PERSON'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"About the time of the summer solstice, Euthalius landed at Terracina with large sums of money for the payment of the troops: he cautiously proceeded along the Appian way,
 and this convoy entered Rome through the gate Capena, (92) while Belisarius, on the other side, diverted the attention of the Goths by a vigorous and successful skirmish.","('Euthalius', 'PERSON'), ('Terracina', 'GPE'), ('Appian', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Capena', 'PERSON'), ('92', 'CARDINAL'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"Above two thousand horse, of whom a part were Thracians, landed at Tarentum; and, after the junction of five hundred soldiers of Campania, and a train of wagons
 laden with wine and flour, they directed their march on the
 Appian way, from Capua to the neighbourhood of Rome.","('two thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Thracians', 'NORP'), ('Tarentum', 'GPE'), ('five hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Campania', 'GPE'), ('Appian', 'NORP'), ('Capua', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"According to
 military practice, the bread or biscuit of the Romans was
 twice prepared in the oven, and the diminution of one fourth
 was cheerfully allowed for the loss of weight.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('one fourth', 'CARDINAL')"
"According to the degrees of rank or merit, the Gothic king
 distributed arms and horses, rich gifts, and liberal
 promises; he moved along the Flaminian way, declined the
 useless sieges of Perusia and Spoleto, respected he
 impregnable rock of Narni, and arrived within two miles of
 Rome at the foot of the Milvian bridge.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Flaminian', 'NORP'), ('Perusia', 'GPE'), ('Spoleto', 'GPE'), ('Narni', 'GPE'), ('two miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Milvian', 'GPE')"
"Accused by
 credible witnesses, and the evidence of his own
 subscription, the successor of St. Peter was despoiled of
 his pontifical ornaments, clad in the mean habit of a monk,
 and embarked, without delay, for a distant exile in the
 East.","('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"Adversity had awakened the Romans from
 the dreams of grandeur and freedom, and taught them the
 humiliating lesson, that it was of small moment to their
 real happiness, whether the name of their master was derived
 from the Gothic or the Latin language.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE')"
"Adversity swept away these extraneous ornaments, and left
 naked and desolate a considerable part even of the seven
 hills.","('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"After Belisarius had left sufficient garrisons in Palermo
 and Syracuse, he embarked his troops at Messina, and landed
 them, without resistance, on the opposite shores of Rhegium.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Palermo', 'GPE'), ('Syracuse', 'GPE'), ('Messina', 'GPE'), ('Rhegium', 'GPE')"
"After Rome herself had been stripped of the
 Imperial purple, the princes of Constantinople assumed the
 sole and sacred sceptre of the monarchy; demanded, as their
 rightful inheritance, the provinces which had been subdued
 by the consuls, or possessed by the Caesars; and feebly
 aspired to deliver their faithful subjects of the West from
 the usurpation of heretics and Barbarians.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"After a bold inroad into Persarmenia, in which his glory was
 shared by a colleague, and his progress was checked by an
 enemy, Belisarius repaired to the important station of Dara,
 where he first accepted the service of Procopius, the
 faithful companion, and diligent historian, of his exploits.
 (6)","('Persarmenia', 'GPE'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Dara', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('6', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a specious discourse to
 vindicate the justice of his cause, they declared, that, for
 the sake of peace, they were disposed to renounce the
 possession of Sicily.","('Sicily', 'GPE')"
"After an
 obstinate siege, the capital of Liguria was reduced by
 famine; but no capitulation could be obtained, except for
 the safe retreat of the Roman garrison.","('Liguria', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"After despatching a light detachment to tread the footsteps of Gelimer, he advanced, with his whole army, about ten days' march, as far as Hippo Regius, which no longer possessed the relics of St. Augustin. (22)","('Gelimer', 'PERSON'), (""about ten days'"", 'DATE'), ('Hippo Regius', 'PERSON'), ('St. Augustin', 'GPE'), ('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"After his death
 the sceptre of Spain was disputed by a civil war.","('Spain', 'GPE')"
"After the departure of Belisarius, who acted by a
 high and special commission, no ordinary provision was made
 for a master- general of the forces; but the office of
 Praetorian praefect was entrusted to a soldier; the civil
 and military powers were united, according to the practice
 of Justinian, in the chief governor; and the representative
 of the emperor in Africa, as well as in Italy, was soon
 distinguished by the appellation of Exarch. (27)","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Exarch', 'ORG'), ('27', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the exile of their
 king and nobles, the servile crowd might purchase their
 safety by adjuring their character, religion, and language;
 and their degenerate posterity would be insensibly mingled
 with the common herd of African subjects.","('African', 'NORP')"
"After the failure of the royal line, Theudes, a
 valiant and powerful chief, ascended the throne of Spain
 which he had formerly administered in the name of Theodoric
 and his infant grandson.","('Theudes', 'PERSON'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON')"
"After the second victory of Belisarius, envy again whispered, Justinian listened, and the hero was recalled.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"After their separation from
 the army, the naval commanders had proceeded with slow
 caution along the coast till they reached the Hermaean
 promontory, and obtained the first intelligence of the
 victory of Belisarius.","('the Hermaean\r\n promontory', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"After this
 disappointment, Vitiges still continued, or feigned to
 continue, the assault of the Salarian gate, that he might
 divert the attention of his adversary, while his principal
 forces more strenuously attacked the Praenestine gate and
 the sepulchre of Hadrian, at the distance of three miles
 from each other.","('Vitiges', 'PERSON'), ('Salarian', 'NORP'), ('Praenestine', 'NORP'), ('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('three miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"After this easy though
 successful campaign, the conqueror entered Syracuse in
 triumph, at the head of his victorious bands, distributing
 gold medals to the people, on the day which so gloriously
 terminated the year of the consulship.","('Syracuse', 'GPE'), ('the day', 'DATE'), ('the year', 'DATE')"
"After this first and unsuccessful trial of their enemies,
 the whole army of the Goths passed the Tyber, and formed the
 siege of the city, which continued above a year, till their
 final departure.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Tyber', 'PRODUCT'), ('a year', 'DATE')"
"After this fruitless
 cruelty, the son of Antonina, while his mother feasted with
 the empress, was buried in her subterraneous prisons, which
 admitted not the distinction of night and day.","('Antonina', 'PERSON')"
"All dissensions were healed, and all opposition was subdued, by the temperate authority of the Roman general, to whom his enemies could not refuse their esteem; and Belisarius inculcated the salutary lesson that the forces of the state
 should compose one body, and be animated by one soul.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"Although Theodatus descended from a race of heroes, he was
 ignorant of the art, and averse to the dangers, of war.","('Theodatus', 'PERSON')"
"Although he had studied the writings of Plato and Tully,
 philosophy was incapable of purifying his mind from the
 basest passions, avarice and fear.","('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('Tully', 'PERSON')"
"Among
 the cities which they ruined, Genoa, not yet constructed of
 marble, is particularly enumerated; and the deaths of
 thousands, according to the regular practice of war, appear
 to have excited less horror than some idolatrous sacrifices
 of women and children, which were performed with impunity in
 the camp of the most Christian king.","('Genoa', 'GPE'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"An
 extraordinary supply of corn was imported from Sicily: the
 harvests of Campania and Tuscany were forcibly swept for the
 use of the city; and the rights of private property were
 infringed by the strong plea of the public safety.","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Campania', 'GPE'), ('Tuscany', 'GPE')"
"An
 honourable alternative, of remaining in the province, or of
 returning to the capital, was indeed submitted to the
 discretion of Belisarius; but he wisely concluded, from
 intercepted letters and the knowledge of his sovereign's
 temper, that he must either resign his head, erect his
 standard, or confound his enemies by his presence and
 submission.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"An
 indisposition, feigned or real, had confined Antonina to her
 apartment; and she walked disdainfully silent in the
 adjacent portico, while Belisarius threw himself on his bed,
 and expected, in an agony of grief and terror, the death
 which he had so often braved under the walls of Rome.","('Antonina', 'PERSON'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"An active
 and discreet tribune sailed as far as the Straits, where he
 occupied Septem or Ceuta, (23) which rises opposite to
 Gibraltar on the African coast; that remote place was
 afterwards adorned and fortified by Justinian; and he seems
 to have indulged the vain ambition of extending his empire
 to the columns of Hercules.","('Straits', 'LOC'), ('Septem', 'LOC'), ('Ceuta', 'LOC'), ('23', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gibraltar', 'GPE'), ('the African coast', 'LOC'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Hercules', 'ORG')"
"An officer of confidence and
 merit, John the Armenian, led the vanguard of three hundred
 horse; six hundred Massagetae covered at a certain distance
 the left flank; and the whole fleet, steering along the
 coast, seldom lost sight of the army, which moved each day
 about twelve miles, and lodged in the evening in strong
 camps, or in friendly towns.","('John', 'PERSON'), ('Armenian', 'NORP'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('six hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Massagetae', 'NORP'), ('about twelve miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('evening', 'TIME')"
"An order was
 despatched to his brother Ammatas, to collect all the forces
 of Carthage, and to encounter the van of the Roman army at
 the distance of ten miles from the city: his nephew
 Gibamund, with two thousand horse, was destined to attack
 their left, when the monarch himself, who silently followed,
 should charge their rear, in a situation which excluded them
 from the aid or even the view of their fleet.","('Ammatas', 'PERSON'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('ten miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Gibamund', 'PERSON'), ('two thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Antonina convened a council of war: it was
 resolved to surmount, with sails and oars, the adverse
 stream of the river; and the Goths were apprehensive of
 disturbing, by any rash hostilities, the negotiation to
 which Belisarius had craftily listened.","('Antonina', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Antonina pursued her son
 with implacable hatred; and the gallant Photius (116) was exposed to her secret persecutions in the camp beyond the Tigris.","('Antonina', 'PERSON'), ('Photius', 'PERSON'), ('Tigris', 'LOC')"
"Anxious to relieve himself from a useless and devouring
 multitude, Belisarius issued his peremptory orders for the
 instant departure of the women, the children, and slaves;
 required his soldiers to dismiss their male and female
 attendants, and regulated their allowance that one moiety
 should be given in provisions, and the other in money.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"As soon as
 Belisarius had fortified his new conquests, Naples and
 Cumae, he advanced about twenty miles to the banks of the
 Vulturnus, contemplated the decayed grandeur of Capua, and
 halted at the separation of the Latin and Appian ways.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Cumae', 'GPE'), ('about twenty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Vulturnus', 'FAC'), ('Capua', 'GPE'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Appian', 'NORP')"
"As soon as Belisarius was delivered from his foreign and
 domestic enemies, he seriously applied his forces to the
 final reduction of Italy.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"As soon as fear or hunger compelled the Goths to evacuate Alba, Porto, and Centumcellae, their place was instantly supplied; the garrisons of Narni, Spoleto, and Perusia, were reinforced, and the seven camps of the besiegers were gradually encompassed with the calamities of a siege.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Alba', 'GPE'), ('Porto', 'GPE'), ('Centumcellae', 'GPE'), ('Narni', 'GPE'), ('Spoleto', 'GPE'), ('Perusia', 'GPE'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"As soon as the curiosity and impatience of Antonina were kindled, the door of a bed-chamber was thrown open, and she beheld her lover, whom
 the diligence of the eunuchs had discovered in his secret
 prison.","('Antonina', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as the enemy approached the ditch,
 Belisarius himself drew the first arrow; and such was his
 strength and dexterity, that he transfixed the foremost of
 the Barbarian leaders.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
"As soon as the place was
 invested by sea and land, Belisarius gave audience to the
 deputies of the people, who exhorted him to disregard a
 conquest unworthy of his arms, to seek the Gothic king in a
 field of battle, and, after his victory, to claim, as the
 sovereign of Rome, the allegiance of the dependent cities.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"As soon as the public danger had subsided,
 Presidius complained of the loss and injury: his complaint
 was heard, but the order of restitution was disobeyed by the
 pride and avarice of the offender.","('Presidius', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as the tumult had subsided, the several parts of the
 army informed each other of the accidents of the day; and
 Belisarius pitched his camp on the field of victory, to
 which the tenth mile-stone from Carthage had applied the
 Latin appellation of Decimus.","('the day', 'DATE'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('tenth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Decimus', 'PERSON')"
"As the fleet was surprised by a calm, sixteen days were
 consumed in the slow navigation; and even the general would
 have suffered the intolerable hardship of thirst, if the
 ingenuity of Antonina had not preserved the water in glass
 bottles, which she buried deep in the sand in a part of the
 ship impervious to the rays of the sun.","('sixteen days', 'DATE'), ('Antonina', 'GPE')"
"As the level plain of Dara
 refused all shelter to stratagem and ambush, Belisarius
 protected his front with a deep trench, which was prolonged
 at first in perpendicular, and afterwards in parallel,
 lines, to cover the wings of cavalry advantageously posted
 to command the flanks and rear of the enemy.","('Dara', 'PERSON'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Astonished by the recent example of Gelimer, he saw himself
 dragged in chains through the streets of Constantinople: the
 terrors which Belisarius inspired were heightened by the
 eloquence of Peter, the Byzantine ambassador; and that bold
 and subtle advocate persuaded him to sign a treaty, too
 ignominious to become the foundation of a lasting peace.","('Gelimer', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"At his departure from Constantinople, his friends, and even the public, were persuaded that as soon as he regained his
 freedom, he would renounce his dissimulation, and that his wife, Theodora, and perhaps the emperor himself, would be sacrificed to the just revenge of a virtuous rebel.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"At length the
 harbour of Caucana, (13) on the southern side of Sicily,
 afforded a secure and hospitable shelter.","('Caucana', 'GPE'), ('13', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sicily', 'GPE')"
"At supper he entertained his principal
 officers with the form and magnificence of a royal banquet.
 (20)","('20', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the age of about
 twenty-eight years, the endowments of her mind and person
 had attained their perfect maturity.","('the age of about\r\n twenty-eight years', 'DATE')"
"At the emperor's command, the clergy of Rome
 proceeded to the choice of a new bishop; and after a solemn
 invocation of the Holy Ghost, elected the deacon Vigilius,
 who had purchased the papal throne by a bribe of two hundred
 pounds of gold.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('the Holy Ghost', 'PERSON'), ('Vigilius', 'PERSON'), ('two hundred\r\n pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"At the end of the campaign, Belisarius was recalled; he
 complied, as usual, with the Imperial mandate.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"At the end of three years, the
 prophet Zachariah, or some mortal friend, indicated the
 means of an escape: he eluded the spies and guards of the
 empress, reached the holy sepulchre of Jerusalem, embraced
 the profession of a monk; and the abbot Photius was
 employed, after the death of Justinian, to reconcile and
 regulate the churches of Egypt.","('the end of three years', 'DATE'), ('Zachariah', 'PERSON'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Photius', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"At the end of twenty days, that of Belisarius
 was almost exhausted, and he had reconciled himself to the
 disgrace of abandoning the siege, that he might march,
 before the winter season, against Rome and the Gothic king.","('the end of twenty days', 'DATE'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('the winter season', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"At the head of his
 principal army, he besieged Rimini, only thirty-three miles
 distant from the Gothic capital.","('Rimini', 'GPE'), ('thirty-three miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"At the head of one thousand horse,
 the Roman general sallied from the Flaminian gate to mark
 the ground of an advantageous position, and to survey the
 camp of the Barbarians; but while he still believed them on
 the other side of the Tyber, he was suddenly encompassed and
 assaulted by their numerous squadrons.","('one thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Flaminian', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Tyber', 'PRODUCT')"
"At the same time, John the Sanguinary, (94) the nephew of Vitalian, was detached with two thousand chosen horse, first to Alba, on the Fucine Lake, and afterwards to the frontiers of Picenum, on the Hadriatic Sea.","('John the Sanguinary', 'PERSON'), ('94', 'DATE'), ('Vitalian', 'NORP'), ('two thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Alba', 'GPE'), ('the Fucine Lake', 'LOC'), ('Picenum', 'GPE'), ('the Hadriatic Sea', 'LOC')"
"Athalaric was diligently instructed in the arts and
 sciences either useful or ornamental for a Roman prince, and
 three venerable Goths were chosen to instil the principles
 of honour and virtue into the mind of their young king.","('Athalaric', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
Autumn .,"('Autumn', 'DATE')"
"Before he allowed them to
 enter the gates of Carthage, he exhorted them, in a
 discourse worthy of himself and the occasion, not to
 disgrace the glory of their arms; and to remember that the
 Vandals had been the tyrants, but that they were the
 deliverers, of the Africans, who must now be respected as
 the voluntary and affectionate subjects of their common
 sovereign.","('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Africans', 'NORP')"
"Before her marriage with Belisarius, Antonina had one husband and many lovers: Photius, the son of her former nuptials, was of an age to distinguish himself at the siege of Naples; and it was not till the autumn of her age and beauty (113) that she indulged a scandalous attachment to a Thracian youth.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Antonina', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Photius', 'PERSON'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Thracian', 'NORP')"
"Before the Goths could recover from the first
 surprise, and claim the accomplishment of their doubtful
 hopes, the victor established his power in Ravenna, beyond
 the danger of repentance and revolt.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"Before the end of the siege, an
 act of blood, ambiguous and indiscreet, sullied the fair
 fame of Belisarius.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Before they touched the shores of Africa, this holy kindred degenerated into sensual love: and as Antonina soon overleaped the bounds of modesty and caution, the Roman general was alone ignorant of his own dishonor.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Antonina', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Belisarius
 saw and pitied their sufferings; but he had foreseen, and he
 watched the decay of their loyalty, and the progress of
 their discontent.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
Belisarius besieges Ravenna;,"('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"Belisarius fixed his residence in the
 palace; seated himself on the throne of Genseric; accepted
 and distributed the Barbaric spoil; granted their lives to
 the suppliant Vandals; and labored to repair the damage
 which the suburb of Mandracium had sustained in the
 preceding night.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Genseric', 'PERSON'), ('Barbaric', 'NORP'), ('Vandals', 'PRODUCT'), ('Mandracium', 'GPE'), ('the\r\n preceding night', 'TIME')"
"Belisarius had secretly trembled when he
 overheard his soldiers, in the passage, emboldening each
 other to confess their apprehensions: if they were once on
 shore, they hoped to maintain the honour of their arms; but
 if they should be attacked at sea, they did not blush to
 acknowledge that they wanted courage to contend at the same
 time with the winds, the waves, and the Barbarians. (16)","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('16', 'CARDINAL')"
"Belisarius instantly sallied from the gates; and while the soldiers chanted his name and victory, the hostile engines
 of war were reduced to ashes.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Belisarius introduced his ships into the
 deepest recess of the harbour; their boats were laboriously
 hoisted with ropes and pulleys to the top-mast head, and he
 filled them with archers, who, from that superior station,
 commanded the ramparts of the city.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Belisarius invades and subdues Siciliy, A.D. 535, Dec. 31.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Siciliy', 'PERSON'), ('535', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dec. 31', 'DATE')"
"Belisarius lands on the coast of Africa - September
 If Gelimer had been informed of the approach of the enemy,
 he must have delayed the conquest of Sardinia for the
 immediate defence of his person and kingdom.","('Belisarius', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Gelimer', 'PERSON'), ('Sardinia', 'GPE')"
"Belisarius praised the spirit of his troops, condemned their
 presumption, yielded to their clamours, and prepared the
 remedies of a defeat, the possibility of which he alone had
 courage to suspect.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
Belisarius recovers many cities of Italy.,"('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Belisarius rejected  with equal firmness and contempt the offer of a tribute; but he allowed the Gothic ambassadors to seek their fate from the mouth of Justinian himself; and consented, with seeming reluctance, to a truce of three months, from the winter solstice to the equinox of spring.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('three months', 'DATE'), ('winter', 'DATE'), ('spring', 'DATE')"
Belisarius spoke the language of truth.,"('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Belisarius understood the suspicion, accepted the excuse, embarked at Ravenna his spoils and trophies; and proved, by his ready obedience, that such an abrupt removal from the government of Italy was not less unjust than it might have been indiscreet.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
Belisarius was chaste and sober.,"('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Belisarius, however, preferred the Latin way,
 which, at a distance from the sea and the marshes, skirted
 in a space of one hundred and twenty miles along the foot of
 the mountains.","('Belisarius', 'GPE'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('one hundred and twenty miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"Both treaties were entrusted to the hands of the ambassador, on the frail security of an oath not to produce the second till the first had been positively rejected.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But
 fear, devotion, and lassitude perhaps, inspired Theodosius
 with more serious thoughts.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"But Theodatus was exasperated by
 the contempt which he deserved: her justice had repressed
 and reproached the oppression which he exercised against his
 Tuscan neighbours; and the principal Goths, united by common
 guilt and resentment, conspired to instigate his slow and
 timid disposition.","('Theodatus', 'PERSON'), ('Tuscan', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"But as soon as they were
 commanded to dismount, they derided this contemptible
 obstacle: as soon as the columns ascended the hills, the
 naked and disorderly crowd was dazzled by glittering arms
 and regular evolutions - and the menace of their female
 prophets was repeatedly fulfilled, that the Moors should be
 discomfited by a beardless antagonist.","('Moors', 'NORP')"
"But as the fears of Belisarius
 were the result of calm and intrepid reason, he was soon
 satisfied that he might confide, without danger, in the
 peaceful and friendly aspect of the capital.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"But every attempt was defeated by the intrepid
 vigilance of Belisarius and his band of veterans, who, in
 the most perilous moments, did not regret the absence of
 their companions; and the Goths, alike destitute of hope and
 subsistence, clamorously urged their departure before the
 truce should expire, and the Roman cavalry should again be
 united.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But her warm entreaties,
 fortified by the prayers of Belisarius, were insufficient to
 draw the holy monk from the solitude of Ephesus.","('Belisarius', 'NORP'), ('Ephesus', 'GPE')"
"But his
 just confidence was placed in the veterans who had fought
 under his banner in the Persian and African wars; and
 although that gallant band was reduced to five thousand men,
 he undertook, with such contemptible numbers, to defend a
 circle of twelve miles, against an army of one hundred and
 fifty thousand Barbarians.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('African', 'NORP'), ('five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('twelve miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('one hundred and\r\n fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"But his anxiety was relieved by the bold curiosity of an
 Isaurian, who explored the dry channel of an aqueduct, and
 secretly reported, that a passage might be perforated to
 introduce a file of armed soldiers into the heart of the
 city.","('Isaurian', 'NORP')"
"But his approaching departure soon
 relieved the apprehensions of a savage and superstitious
 people; the number of their wives allowed them to disregard
 the safety of their infant hostages; and when the Roman
 general hoisted sail in the port of Carthage, he heard the
 cries and almost beheld the flames of the desolated
 province.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"But his army,
 four thousand soldiers perhaps, was lost in a spacious
 plain; they were encompassed and oppressed by fresh
 multitudes, who continually relieved the broken ranks of the
 Barbarians.","('four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"But his inflexible loyalty rejected, except as
 the substitute of Justinian, their oaths of allegiance; and
 he was not offended by the reproach of their deputies, that
 he rather chose to be a slave than a king.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"But if she had lamented the disorders of her
 son, she soon wept his irreparable loss; and the death of
 Athalaric, who, at the age of sixteen, was consumed by
 premature intemperance, left her destitute of any firm
 support or legal authority.","('Athalaric', 'PERSON'), ('sixteen', 'DATE')"
"But in the day of her greatness, the space within
 her walls was crowded with habitations and inhabitants; and
 the populous suburbs, that stretched along the public roads,
 were darted like so many rays from one common centre.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"But in the interval of discord, the Goths were permitted to breathe; an important season was lost, Milan was destroyed, and the northern provinces of Italy were afflicted by an
 inundation of the Franks.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('an important season', 'DATE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"But in the interval of suspense, two Roman generals, who had entered the province of Dalmatia, were defeated and slain by the Gothic troops.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"But instead of sacrificing these unworthy passions to the
 dictates of generosity and prudence, Theudes amused the
 ambassadors till he was secretly informed of the loss of
 Carthage, and then dismissed them, with obscure and
 contemptuous advice, to seek in their native country a true
 knowledge of the state of the Vandals.(47) Conquests of the Romans in Spain, A.D. 550-620.","('Theudes', 'PERSON'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('47', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('550-620', 'CARDINAL')"
"But no sooner had he returned, alone and defenceless, than a
 hostile commission was sent to the East, to seize his
 treasures and criminate his actions; the guards and
 veterans, who followed his private banner, were distributed
 among the chiefs of the army, and even the eunuchs presumed
 to cast lots for the partition of his martial domestics.","('East', 'LOC')"
"But the
 arms of Belisarius, and the revolt of the Italians, had no
 sooner shaken the Gothic monarchy, than Theodebert of
 Austrasia, the most powerful and warlike of the Merovingian
 kings, was persuaded to succor their distress by an indirect
 and seasonable aid.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Italians', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Theodebert', 'PERSON'), ('Austrasia', 'GPE'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP')"
"But the
 lieutenant of Justinian was conscious of his own rectitude;
 he entered into a dark and crooked path, as it might lead to
 the voluntary submission of the Goths; and his dexterous
 policy persuaded them that he was disposed to comply with
 their wishes, without engaging an oath or a promise for the
 performance of a treaty which he secretly abhorred.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"But the
 rashness of Ammatas was fatal to himself and his country.","('Ammatas', 'PERSON')"
"But the Imperial fleet, advancing with a fair wind,
 steered through the narrow entrance of the Goletta, and
 occupied, in the deep and capacious lake of Tunis, a secure
 station about five miles from the capital.","('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Goletta', 'GPE'), ('Tunis', 'GPE'), ('about five miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"But the brazen temple of Janus was left standing
 in the forum; of a size sufficient only to contain the
 statue of the god, five cubits in height, of a human form,
 but with two faces directed to the east and west.","('Janus', 'PERSON'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the fame of
 Belisarius was not sullied by a defeat, in which he alone
 had saved his army from the consequences of their own
 rashness: the approach of peace relieved him from the guard
 of the eastern frontier, and his conduct in the sedition of
 Constantinople amply discharged his obligations to the
 emperor.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"But the friends of the captive king were
 more inclined to accept the invitations, than to resist the
 progress, of Belisarius; and many a proud Barbarian
 disguised his aversion to war under the more specious name
 of his hatred to the usurper.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
"But the future happiness of
 the queen of Italy depended on the education of her son, who
 was destined, by his birth, to support the different and
 almost incompatible characters of the chief of a barbarian camp and the first
 magistrate of a civilised nation.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But the mind of Amalasontha was inflamed by
 ambition and revenge; and while her ships lay at anchor in
 the port, she waited for the success of a crime which her
 passions excused or applauded as an act of justice.","('Amalasontha', 'PERSON')"
"But the principal forces of the
 Goths were dispersed in Dalmatia, Venetia, and Gaul; and the
 feeble mind of their king was confounded by the unsuccessful
 event of a divination, which seemed to presage the downfall
 of his empire.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('Venetia', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"But the purest reward of Belisarius was in the faithful
 execution of a treaty for which his honour had been pledged
 to the king of the Vandals.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Vandals', 'PRODUCT')"
"But the use of a Sclavonian dialect more clearly represents
 them as the last remnant of the new colonies who succeeded
 to the genuine Vandals, already scattered or destroyed in
 the age of Procopius. (39)
Manners and defeat of the Moors, A.D. 535.","('Sclavonian', 'NORP'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('39', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moors', 'NORP'), ('535', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the wiser citizens, who judged of the
 future by the past, revolved in their memory the immense
 loss, both of men and money, which the empire had sustained
 in the expedition of Basiliscus.","('Basiliscus', 'PRODUCT')"
"But these
 intentions were disappointed by accident, treachery, and the
 indefatigable pursuit of his enemies, who intercepted his
 flight from the sea-shore, and chased the unfortunate
 monarch, with some faithful followers, to the inaccessible
 mountain of Papua, (28) in the inland country of Numidia.","('Papua', 'GPE'), ('28', 'CARDINAL'), ('Numidia', 'GPE')"
"But these powers were under the command of Belisarius; and, as he was conscious of their superior merit, he permitted the Barbarians to surprise him at an unseasonable hour.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('an unseasonable hour', 'TIME')"
"But these rare exceptions, the reward of birth or valour,
 are insufficient to explain the fate of a nation whose
 numbers, before a short and bloodless war amounted to more
 than six hundred thousand persons.","('more\r\n than six hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"By the loss of the port,
 or, as it is now called, the city of Porto, he was deprived
 of the country on the right of the Tyber, and the best
 communication with the sea; and he reflected, with grief and
 anger, that three hundred men, could he have spared such a
 feeble band, might have defended its impregnable works.","('Porto', 'GPE'), ('Tyber', 'NORP'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"By this disgraceful and precarious
 agreement, Italy and the Gothic treasure were divided, and
 the provinces beyond the Po were left with the regal title
 to the successor of Theodoric.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Po', 'PERSON'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON')"
"Caesarea, a royal city, which in
 looser geography may be confounded with the modern Algiers,
 was situate thirty days' march to the westward of Carthage:
 by land, the road was infested by the Moors; but the sea was
 open, and the Romans were now masters of the sea.","('Caesarea', 'GPE'), ('Algiers', 'GPE'), (""thirty days'"", 'DATE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Moors', 'LOC'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Carthage
 blazed with innumerable torches, the signals of the public
 joy; the chain was removed that guarded the entrance of the
 port; the gates were thrown open, and the people, with
 acclamations of gratitude, hailed and invited their Roman
 deliverers.","('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Carthage was saved by the presence of Belisarius, who
 suddenly landed with a thousand guards.","('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('a thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Casting away their lances and missile weapons, they drew their swords, and expected the charge: the Roman cavalry
 thrice passed the rivulet; they were thrice repulsed; and the conflict was firmly maintained, till Zano fell, and the standard of Belisarius was displayed.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Zano', 'PERSON'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
Character and choice of Belisarius.,"('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Conquest of Africa by Belisarius, A.D. 534.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 534', 'DATE')"
"Conquests of Justinian in the West — Character and First Campaigns of Belisarius— He Invades and Subdues the Vandal Kingdom of Africa— His Triumph— The Gothic War—  He Recovers Sicily, Naples, and Rome—  Siege of Rome by the Goths— Their Retreat and Losses— Surrender of Ravenna— Glory of Belisarius— His Domestic Shame and Misfortunes","('First Campaigns of Belisarius', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Subdues the Vandal Kingdom of Africa— His Triumph— The Gothic War—  He Recovers Sicily, Naples', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Rome—  Siege of Rome by the Goths— Their Retreat and Losses— Surrender of Ravenna— Glory of Belisarius— His Domestic Shame and Misfortunes', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Constantine, viewing their entrance as the signal
 of death, drew his sword, and rushed on the general, who
 nimbly eluded the stroke, and was protected by his friends;","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Datius, the
 orthodox bishop, who had seduced his countrymen to rebellion
 (98) and ruin, escaped to the luxury and honours of the
 Byzantine court; (99) but the clergy, perhaps the Arian
 clergy, were slaughtered at the foot of their own altars by
 the defenders of the Catholic faith.","('Datius', 'PERSON'), ('98', 'CARDINAL'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('99', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
Death of Constantine.,"('Death of Constantine', 'PERSON')"
Debates on the African war.,"('the African war', 'EVENT')"
"Deeply sensible of the disgrace and danger, Belisarius passed an apprehensive night on the field of victory: at the dawn of day, he planted his standard on a hill, recalled his guardians and veterans, and gradually restored the modesty
 and obedience of the camp.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
Defeats the Vandals in the first battle.,"('Vandals', 'PRODUCT'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Departure of the fleet, A.D. 533, June.","('533', 'CARDINAL'), ('June', 'DATE')"
Disgrace and submission of Belisarius.,"('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Distress and captivity of Gelimer, A.D. 534 - the Spring.","('Gelimer', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 534 - the Spring', 'DATE')"
"Doubtful of the event, Gelimer had
 given secret orders that a part of his treasure should be
 transported to Spain, where he hoped to find a secure refuge
 at the court of the king of the Visigoths.","('Gelimer', 'PERSON'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Visigoths', 'PRODUCT')"
"During the five first years of his reign, he
 reluctantly waged a costly and unprofitable war against the
 Persians; till his pride submitted to his ambition, and he
 purchased at the price of four hundred and forty thousand
 pounds sterling, the benefit of a precarious truce, which,
 in the language of both nations, was dignified with the
 appellation of the endless peace.","('the five first years', 'DATE'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('four hundred and forty thousand\r\n pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"During the whole
 summer, the designs of the enemy were baffled by his skilful
 dispositions: he pressed their retreat, occupied each night
 their camp of the preceding day, and would have secured a
 bloodless victory, if he could have resisted the impatience
 of his own troops.","('the whole\r\n summer', 'DATE'), ('the preceding day', 'DATE')"
"During their residence at Carthage, he surprised the two lovers in a subterraneous chamber, solitary, warm, and almost naked.","('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Each of his officers gave a written opinion
 that the siege of Ravenna was impracticable and hopeless:
 the general then rejected the treaty of partition, and
 declared his own resolution of leading Vitiges in chains to
 the feet of Justinian.","('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Vitiges', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Each plebeian conceived
 himself to be a hero, and the infantry, who, since the decay
 of discipline, were rejected from the line of battle,
 aspired to the ancient honours of the Roman legion.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Education and experience had
 cultivated her talents; her philosophic studies were exempt
 from vanity; and, though she expressed herself with equal
 elegance and ease in the Greek, the Latin, and the Gothic
 tongues, the daughter of Theodoric maintained in her
 counsels a discreet and impenetrable silence.","('Greek', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON')"
"Eight thousand rebels trembled at his approach;
 they were routed at the first onset by the dexterity of
 their master, and this ignoble victory would have restored
 the peace of Africa, if the conqueror had not been hastily
 recalled to Sicily to appease a sedition which was
 kindled during his absence in his own camp.(59) Disorder and
 disobedi ence were the common malady of the times: the
 genius to command and the virtue to obey resided only in the
 mind of Belisarius.","('Eight thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Eighteen days were employed by the besiegers, to provide all
 the instruments of attack which antiquity had invented.","('Eighteen days', 'DATE')"
"Encompassed with domestic foes,
 she entered into a secret negotiation with the emperor
 Justinian, obtained the assurance of a friendly reception,
 and had actually deposited at Dyrrachium, in Epirus, a
 treasure of forty thousand pounds of gold.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Epirus', 'LOC'), ('forty thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"Encouraged by this successful inroad, Theodebert himself, in
 the ensuing spring, invaded the plains of Italy with an army
 of one hundred thousand Barbarians. (101)","('Theodebert', 'PERSON'), ('the ensuing spring', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('one hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('101', 'CARDINAL')"
End of Gelimer and the Vandals.,"('Gelimer', 'PERSON'), ('Vandals', 'NORP')"
"Enraged by his own wrongs, and by the dishonor of his blood, he cast away in his turn the sentiments of nature, and revealed to Belisarius the turpitude of a woman who had violated all the duties of a mother and a wife.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Even his removal was
 colored by the assurance, that the sinking state of Italy
 would be retrieved by the single presence of its conqueror.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Even the indignation of Photius was not forgiven by his mother; the exile of her son prepared the recall of her lover; and
 Theodosius condescended to accept the pressing and humble
 invitation of the conqueror of Italy.","('Photius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Every Barbarian who met their swords was inhumanly massacred; their widows and daughters, as rich heirs, or beautiful concubines, were embraced by the licentious soldiers; and avarice itself was almost satiated with the treasures of gold and silver, the accumulated fruits of conquest or economy in a long period of prosperity and peace.","('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
"Every bow was bent, every javelin was directed, against that fatal object, and the command was repeated and obeyed by thousands who were ignorant of its real motive.","('thousands', 'CARDINAL')"
"Every crime
 which is punished by social justice was practised as the
 rights of war; the Huns were distinguished by cruelty and
 sacrilege, and Belisarius alone appeared in the streets and
 churches of Naples to moderate the calamities which he
 predicted.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Naples', 'GPE')"
"Every spectator
 admired, without peril, the strength and stature of the
 young Barbarians: they adored the majesty of the throne, and
 promised to shed their blood in the service of their
 benefactor.","('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"Exasperated by the delay,
 Presidius boldly arrested the general's horse as he passed
 through the forum; and, with the spirit of a citizen,
 demanded the common benefit of the Roman laws.","('Presidius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Experience and Christianity had refuted the superstitious
 hope, that Rome was founded by the gods to reign forever
 over the nations of the earth.","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Faithful to his instructions, they
 would have cast anchor about twenty miles from Carthage, if
 the more skilful seamen had not represented the perils of
 the shore, and the signs of an impending tempest.","('about twenty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"Final defeat of Gelimer and the Vandals, A.D. 533, November.","('Gelimer', 'PERSON'), ('Vandals', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 533', 'DATE'), ('November', 'DATE')"
Firmness and authority of Belisarius.,"('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"Five hundred transports, navigated by twenty thousand mariners of Egypt, Cilicia, and Ionia, were collected in the harbour of Constantinople.","('Five hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Cilicia', 'GPE'), ('Ionia', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Five thousand horse
 and ten thousand foot were embarked at Constantinople, for
 the conquest of Africa; but the infantry, for the most part
 levied in Thrace and Isauria, yielded to the more prevailing use and reputation of the cavalry; and the Scythian bow was the weapon on which the armies of Rome were now reduced to place their principal dependence.","('Five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten thousand foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Isauria', 'GPE'), ('Scythian', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Four hundred of the bravest of the Heruli
 marched under the banner of the faithful and active Pharas;
 their untractable valour was more highly prized than the tame
 submission of the Greeks and Syrians; and of such importance
 was it deemed to procure a reinforcement of six hundred
 Massagetae, or Huns, that they were allured by fraud and
 deceit to engage in a naval expedition.","('Four hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Heruli', 'PERSON'), ('Pharas', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Syrians', 'NORP'), ('six hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Massagetae', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'ORG')"
"From Rhegium to Naples, the fleet and army of Belisarius, almost always in view of each other, advanced near three hundred miles along the sea-coast.","('Rhegium', 'GPE'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Belisarius', 'GPE'), ('three hundred miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"From a laudable desire to assert the dignity of his theme, Procopius defends the
 soldiers of his own time against the morose critics, who confined that respectable name to the heavy-armed warriors of antiquity, and maliciously observed, that the word archer is introduced by Homer (8) as a term of contempt.","('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Homer', 'PERSON'), ('8', 'CARDINAL')"
"From a wise suspicion of the
 stratagems and resources of the Vandals, he marched the next
 day in order of battle, halted in the evening before the
 gates of Carthage, and allowed a night of repose, that he
 might not, in darkness and disorder, expose the city to the
 license of the soldiers, or the soldiers themselves to the
 secret ambush of the city.","('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('the next\r\n day', 'DATE'), ('evening', 'TIME'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('a night', 'TIME')"
"From blind and
 abject despair, Theodatus capriciously rose to groundless and fatal presumption, (61) and dared to receive, with menace and contempt, the ambassador of Justinian; who claimed his promise, solicited the allegiance of his subjects, and boldly asserted the inviolable privilege of his own character.","('Theodatus', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"From the Vandal messenger, Pharas was informed of the motives of this singular request.","('Pharas', 'PERSON')"
"From the age of ten years
 (54)","('the age of ten years\r\n (54', 'DATE')"
"From the domestic service of the palace, and
 the administration of the private revenue, Narses the eunuch
 was suddenly exalted to the head of an army; and the spirit
 of a hero, who afterwards equalled the merit and glory of
 Belisarius, served only to perplex the operations of the
 Gothic war.","('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n Gothic war', 'EVENT')"
"From the moment that Belisarius had determined to sustain a
 siege, his assiduous care provided Rome against the danger
 of famine, more dreadful than the Gothic arms.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"From the palace of Belisarius, the
 procession was conducted through the principal streets to
 the hippodrome; and this memorable day seemed to avenge the
 injuries of Genseric, and to expiate the shame of the
 Romans.","('Belisarius', 'GPE'), ('Genseric', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"From the port of
 Methone, the pilots steered along the western coast of
 Peloponnesus, as far as the Isle of Zacynthus, or Zante,
 before they undertook the voyage (in their eyes a most
 arduous voyage) of one hundred leagues over the Ionian Sea.","('Methone', 'GPE'), ('Peloponnesus', 'GPE'), ('the Isle of Zacynthus', 'FAC'), ('Zante', 'GPE'), ('one hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Ionian Sea', 'LOC')"
"From the softest habits of pleasure, from the
 unbounded command of industry and wealth, he was reduced to
 share the poverty of the Moors, (29) supportable only to
 themselves by their ignorance of a happier condition.","('Moors', 'NORP'), ('29', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the surprise and indignation of the Roman general, his former credulity appears to have been sincere: he embraced the knees of the son of Antonina, adjured him to remember his obligations rather than his birth, and confirmed at the altar their holy vows of revenge and mutual defence.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Antonina', 'PERSON')"
"From their rustic
 habitations, from their distant garrisons, the Goths
 assembled at Ravenna for the defence of their country; and
 such were their numbers, that, after an army had been
 detached for the relief of Dalmatia, one hundred and fifty
 thousand fighting men marched under the royal standard.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('one hundred and fifty\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"From thence he despatched his principal lieutenant, to inform the emperor, that in the space of three months he had achieved the conquest of Africa.","('three months', 'DATE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"From thence the fleet pursued their course
 through the midst of the Propontis; but as they struggled to
 pass the Straits of the Hellespont, an unfavourable wind
 detained them four days at Abydus, where the general
 exhibited a memorable lesson of firmness and severity.","('Straits', 'LOC'), ('Hellespont', 'GPE'), ('four days', 'DATE'), ('Abydus', 'GPE')"
"From this pleasing and perhaps voluntary delusion, Belisarius was awakened at Syracuse, by the officious information of Macedonia; and that female attendant, after requiring an oath for her security, produced two chamberlains, who, like herself, had often beheld the adulteries of Antonina.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Syracuse', 'GPE'), ('Macedonia', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antonina', 'PERSON')"
"Gelimer retired with hasty
 steps towards the desert of Numidia: but he had soon the
 consolation of learning that his private orders for the
 execution of Hilderic and his captive friends had been
 faithfully obeyed.","('Gelimer', 'PERSON'), ('Numidia', 'PERSON'), ('Hilderic', 'PERSON')"
Gelimer retreated to his camp; the Huns joined the pursuit; and the victors despoiled the bodies of the slain.,"('Gelimer', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"Gelimer slowly advanced: he was clad in a
 purple robe, and still maintained the majesty of a king.","('Gelimer', 'PERSON')"
"Happy would it
 have been for her fame and safety if she had calmly retired
 from barbarous faction to the peace and splendour of
 Constantinople.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"He anticipated the hour of the attack, outstripped his tardy
 followers, and was pierced with a mortal wound, after he had
 slain with his own hand twelve of his boldest antagonists.","('the hour', 'TIME'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL')"
"He dreaded the busy scandal of
 the capital, and the indiscreet fondness of the wife of
 Belisarius; escaped from her embraces, and retiring to
 Ephesus, shaved his head, and took refuge in the sanctuary
 of a monastic life.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Ephesus', 'GPE')"
"He drew a second arrow, and the stroke was followed
 with the same success and the same acclamation.","('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"He encamped in the fields of Bulla,
 four days' journey from Carthage; insulted the capital,
 which he deprived of the use of an aqueduct; proposed a high
 reward for the head of every Roman; affected to spare the
 persons and property of his African subjects, and secretly
 negotiated with the Arian sectaries and the confederate
 Huns.","('Bulla', 'GPE'), (""four days'"", 'DATE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('African', 'NORP'), ('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'PERSON')"
"He encountered an adversary equal to himself, by
 the new title of General of the East; his superior in the
 science of war, but much inferior in the number and quality
 of his troops, which amounted only to twenty-five thousand
 Romans and strangers, relaxed in their discipline, and
 humbled by recent disasters.","('East', 'LOC'), ('twenty-five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"He enjoyed
 only a short time the charms of Amalasontha and the hopes of
 the succes sion; and his widow, after the death of her
 husband and father, was left the guardian of her son
 Athalaric and the kingdom of Italy.","('Amalasontha', 'PERSON'), ('Athalaric', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"He fell prostrate before his wife, he kissed the feet of his saviour, and he devoutly promised to live the grateful and submissive slave of Antonina.","('Antonina', 'PERSON')"
"He had purchased a
 sceptre by ingratitude and murder: at the first menace of an
 enemy, he degraded his own majesty and that of a nation,
 which already disdained their unworthy sovereign.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"He passed the winter
 season in the palace of ancient kings, amidst the ruins of a
 Grecian colony which once extended to a circumference of
 two-and-twenty miles;(58) but in the spring, about the
 festival of Easter, the prosecution of his designs was
 interrupted by a dangerous revolt of the African forces.","('winter', 'DATE'), ('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('two-and-twenty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('58', 'CARDINAL'), ('the spring', 'DATE'), ('Easter', 'DATE'), ('African', 'NORP')"
"He prudently wished to protract the war till
 his brother, with his veteran troops, should return from the
 conquest of Sardinia; and he now lamented the rash policy of
 his ancestors, who, by destroying the fortifications of
 Africa, had left him only the dangerous resource of risking
 a battle in the neighbourhood of his capital.","('Sardinia', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"He received the messengers of
 victory at the time when he was preparing to publish the
 Pandects of the Roman laws; and the devout or jealous
 emperor celebrated the divine goodness, and confessed, in
 silence, the merit of his successful general. (24)","('Pandects', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('24', 'CARDINAL')"
"He received the proposal with profound respect and affected
 gratitude; and the eloquent Cassiodorus announced to the
 senate and the emperor that Amalasontha and Theodatus had
 ascended the throne of Italy.","('Cassiodorus', 'PERSON'), ('Amalasontha', 'PERSON'), ('Theodatus', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"He subdued Africa, Italy, and the adjacent islands; led away
 captives the successors of Genseric and Theodoric; filled
 Constantinople with the spoils of their palaces; and in the
 space of six years recovered half the provinces of the
 Western empire.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Genseric', 'NORP'), ('Theodoric', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('six years', 'DATE'), ('half', 'CARDINAL'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"He twice
 escaped to the most venerable sanctuaries of Constantinople,
 the churches of St. Sophia, and of the Virgin: but his
 tyrants were insensible of religion as of pity; and the
 helpless youth, amidst the clamours of the clergy and people,
 was twice dragged from the altar to the dungeon.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('St. Sophia', 'GPE'), ('Virgin', 'LOC')"
"He was immediately besieged by Pharas, an officer whose truth and sobriety were the more applauded, as such qualities
 could seldom be found among the Heruli, the most corrupt of
 the Barbarian tribes.","('Pharas', 'PERSON'), ('Heruli', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
"He was immediately declared consul for
 the ensuing year, and the day of his inauguration resembled
 the pomp of a second triumph: his curule chair was borne
 aloft on the shoulders of captive Vandals; and the spoils of
 war, gold cups, and rich girdles, were profusely scattered
 among the populace.","('the ensuing year', 'DATE'), ('the day', 'DATE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Vandals', 'NORP')"
"He wept the fate of his brother and of Carthage,
 charged with irresistible fury the advancing squadrons, and
 might have pursued, and perhaps decided, the victory, if he
 had not wasted those inestimable moments in the discharge of
 a vain, though pious, duty to the dead.","('Carthage', 'PERSON')"
"Her beauty, which, in
 the apprehension of Theodora herself, might have disputed
 the conquest of an emperor, was animated by manly sense,
 activity, and resolution.","('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"Her exile and death, A.D. 535, April 30.","('A.D. 535', 'DATE'), ('April 30', 'DATE')"
"Her jurisdiction,
 wealth, and immunites, perhaps the most essential part of
 episcopal religion, were restored and amplified with a
 liberal hand; the Arian worship was suppressed; the Donatist
 meetings were proscribed; (25) and the synod of Carthage, by
 the voice of two hundred and seventeen bishops, (26)
 applauded the just measure of pious retaliation.","('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Donatist', 'NORP'), ('25', 'CARDINAL'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('two hundred and seventeen', 'CARDINAL'), ('26', 'DATE')"
Her lover Theodosius.,"('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Her mother, the sister of Clovis, was descended from the
 long-haired kings of the Merovingian race,(53) and the regal succession of the Amali was illustrated in the
 eleventh generation by her father, the great Theodoric,
 whose merit might have ennobled a plebeian origin.","('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('53', 'DATE'), ('Amali', 'PERSON'), ('eleventh', 'ORDINAL'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON')"
"Her salutary measures were directed by the wisdom
 and celebrated by the eloquence of Cassiodorus; she
 solicited and deserved the friendship of the emperor; and
 the kingdoms of Europe respected, both in peace and war, the
 majesty of the Gothic throne.","('Cassiodorus', 'PERSON'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"Her silent wonder burst into passionate exclamations
 of gratitude and joy, and she named Theodora her queen, her
 benefactress, and her savior.","('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"His
 colleague Buzes, who concurred in the same sentiments, lost
 his rank, his liberty, and his health, by the persecution of
 the empress: but the disgrace of Belisarius was alleviated
 by the dignity of his own character, and the influence of
 his wife, who might wish to humble, but could not desire to
 ruin, the partner of her fortunes.","('Buzes', 'PERSON'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"His
 foresight was justified by the increase of the public
 distress, as soon as the Goths had occupied two important
 posts in the neighbourhood of Rome.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"His Vandals fled to Carthage; the highway, almost ten miles,
 was strewed with dead bodies; and it seemed incredible that
 such multitudes could be slaughtered by the swords of three
 hundred Romans.","('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('almost ten miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('three\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"His ambassadors, in their
 public audience, demanded the fortress of Lilybaeum, ten
 barbarian fugitives, and a just compensation for the pillage
 of a small town on the Illyrian borders; but they secretly
 negotiated with Theodatus to betray the province of Tuscany,
 and tempted Amalasontha to extricate herself from danger and
 perplexity by a free surrender of the kingdom of Italy.","('Lilybaeum', 'GPE'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP'), ('Theodatus', 'PERSON'), ('Tuscany', 'GPE'), ('Amalasontha', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"His birth (for his mother was
 the sister of Theodoric) might be considered as an imperfect
 title; and the choice of Amalasontha was more strongly
 directed by her contempt of his avarice and pusillanimity,
 which had deprived him of the love of the Italians and the
 esteem of the barbarians.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Amalasontha', 'PERSON'), ('Italians', 'NORP')"
"His countenance was indeed disfigured by sweat, dust, and blood; his voice was hoarse, his strength was almost exhausted; but his unconquerable spirit still remained; he imparted that spirit to his desponding companions; and their last desperate charge was felt by the flying Barbarians, as if a new army, vigorous and entire, had been poured from the city.","('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
His defence of Rome.,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
"His departure was secret; but as soon as the Vandals discovered that their king had deserted them, they hastily dispersed, anxious only for their personal safety, and careless of every object that is dear or valuable to mankind.","('Vandals', 'PERSON')"
"His enemies had disappeared: Belisarius enters Rome, A.D. 536, Dec. 10. when he made
 his entrance through the Asinarian gate, the garrison
 departed without molestation along the Flaminian way; and
 the city, after sixty years' servitude, was delivered from
 the yoke of the Barbarians.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 536', 'DATE'), ('Dec. 10', 'DATE'), ('the Asinarian gate', 'FAC'), ('Flaminian', 'NORP'), (""sixty years'"", 'DATE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"His indefatigable agent returned from Constantinople to Ravenna, with ample instructions; and a fair epistle, which praised the wisdom and generosity of the royal philosopher, granted his pension, with the assurance of such honours as a
 subject and a Catholic might enjoy; and wisely referred the final execution of the treaty to the presence and authority of Belisarius.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"His intelligence determined Belisarius to hasten
 his operations, and his wise impatience was seconded by the
 winds.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"His liberality encouraged the workmen; the
 soldiers, the mariners, and the citizens, vied with each
 other in the salutary labor; and Gelimer, who had feared to
 trust his person in an open town, beheld with astonishment
 and despair, the rising strength of an impregnable fortress.","('Gelimer', 'PERSON')"
"His lofty stature and majestic
 countenance fulfilled their expectations of a hero; the
 meanest of his fellow-citizens were emboldened by his gentle
 and gracious demeanor; and the martial train which attended
 his footsteps left his person more accessible than in a day
 of battle.","('a day', 'DATE')"
"His prudence refused to subscribe the safe
 conduct which they asked, to join their brethren of Ravenna;
 but they saved, by an honourable capitulation, one moiety at
 least of their wealth, with the free alternative of retiring
 peaceably to their estates, or enlisting to serve the
 emperor in his Persian wars.","('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"His services in the Persian war, A.D. 529-532.","('the Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('A.D. 529-532', 'DATE')"
"His skill and perseverance overcame every obstacle: Urbino was taken, the sieges of Faesulae Orvieto, and Auximum, were undertaken and vigorously prosecuted; and the eunuch Narses was at length recalled to the domestic cares of the palace.","('Urbino', 'GPE'), ('Faesulae Orvieto', 'FAC'), ('Auximum', 'PERSON'), ('Narses', 'PERSON')"
"His soldiers were relieved
 by the zeal and diligence of the people, who watched while
  they slept, and labored while they reposed: he accepted the
 voluntary service of the bravest and most indigent of the
 Roman youth; and the companies of townsmen sometimes
 represented, in a vacant post, the presence of the troops
 which had been drawn away to more essential duties.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"His sole consulship, A.D. 535, January 1.","('A.D. 535', 'DATE'), ('January 1', 'DATE')"
"His third
 attempt was more successful.","('third', 'ORDINAL')"
"If Belisarius had been tempted to hesitate in his
 allegiance, he might have urged, even against the emperor
 himself, the indispensable duty of saving Africa from an
 enemy more barbarous than the Vandals.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Vandals', 'NORP')"
"If Belisarius had possessed only
 the courage of a soldier, the laurel would have been
 snatched from his hand by timid and envious counsels; but in
 this decisive moment, he resolved, with the magnanimity of a
 statesman, to sustain alone the danger and merit of generous
 disobedience.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"If any credit be due to an intelligent spectator, one
 third at least of their enormous host was destroyed, in
 frequent and bloody combats under the walls of the city.","('one\r\n third', 'CARDINAL')"
"If it were not a
 melancholy truth, that the first and most cruel sufferings
 must be the lot of the innocent and helpless, history might
 exult in the misery of the conquerors, who, in the midst of
 riches, were left destitute of bread or wine, reduced to
 drink the waters of the Po, and to feed on the flesh of
 distempered cattle.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Po', 'LOC')"
"If the false lustre of a diadem could have tempted the
 loyalty of a faithful subject, his prudence must have
 foreseen the inconstancy of the Barbarians, and his rational
 ambition would prefer the safe and honourable station of a
 Roman general.","('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Impatient
 to abolish the temporal and spiritual tyranny of the
 Vandals, he proceeded, without delay, to the full
 establishment of the Catholic church.","('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"In
 a much later period, the circumference of Naples (67)
 measured only two thousand three hundred and sixty three
 paces: (68) the fortifications were defended by precipices or
 the sea; when the aqueducts were intercepted, a supply of
 water might be drawn from wells and fountains; and the stock
 of provisions was sufficient to consume the patience of the
 besiegers.","('Naples', 'GPE'), ('67', 'CARDINAL'), ('two thousand three hundred and sixty three', 'CARDINAL'), ('68', 'CARDINAL')"
"In
 this hasty act of violence, the guilt of Constantine was no
 longer remembered; the despair and death of that valiant
 officer were secretly imputed to the revenge of Antonina;
 and each of his colleagues, conscious of the same rapine,
 was apprehensive of the same fate.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Antonina', 'PERSON')"
"In Italy, as well as in Africa, the
 guilt of a usurper appeared to justify the arms of
 Justinian; but the forces which he prepared were
 insufficient for the subversion of a mighty kingdom, if their feeble
 numbers had not been multiplied by the name, the spirit, and
 the conduct of a hero.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"In a march of ten or twelve days, the vigilance of
 Belisarius was constantly awake and active against his
 unseen enemies, by whom, in every place, and at every hour,
 he might be suddenly attacked.","('ten or twelve days', 'DATE'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('every hour', 'TIME')"
"In his fame and merit, in wealth and power,
 he remained without a rival, the first of the Roman
 subjects; the voice of envy could only magnify his dangerous
 importance; and the emperor might applaud his own discerning
 spirit, which had discovered and raised the genius of
 Belisarius.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"In the
 darkness of the night, four hundred Romans entered the
 aqueduct, raised themselves by a rope, which they fastened
 to an olive-tree, into the house or garden of a solitary
 matron, sounded their trumpets, surprised the sentinels, and
 gave admittance to their companions, who on all sides scaled
 the walls, and burst open the gates of the city.","('the\r\n darkness of the night', 'TIME'), ('four hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"In the
 familiar conversation of a hero, the Romans acquired some
 notion of the virtues which history ascribed to their
 ancestors; they were edified by the apparent respect of
 Belisarius for the successor of St. Peter, and his rigid
 discipline secured in the midst of war the blessings of
 tranquillity and justice.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('St. Peter', 'PERSON')"
"In the
 navigation from the Hellespont to Peloponnesus, which the
 Greeks, after the siege of Troy, had performed in four days,
 (12) the fleet of Belisarius was guided in their course by
 his master-galley, conspicuous in the day by the redness of
 the sails, and in the night by the torches blazing from the
 mast head.","('Hellespont', 'PRODUCT'), ('Peloponnesus', 'PRODUCT'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Troy', 'GPE'), ('four days', 'DATE'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('the day', 'DATE'), ('the night', 'TIME')"
"In the absolute
 direction of his household, and in the important commissions
 of peace and war, (115) the favorite youth most rapidly  acquired a fortune of four hundred thousand pounds sterling;
 and after their return to Constantinople, the passion of
 Antonina, at least, continued ardent and unabated.","('115', 'CARDINAL'), ('four hundred thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Antonina', 'GPE')"
"In the ages of
 victory, as often as the senate decreed some distant
 conquest, the consul denounced hostilities, by unbarring, in
 solemn pomp, the gates of the temple of Janus. (84)","('Janus', 'PERSON'), ('84', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the blind impotence of grief and
 indignation they joyfully saluted the approach of the
 Romans, entertained the fleet of Belisarius in the ports of
 Sicily, and were speedily delighted or alarmed by the
 surprising intelligence that their revenge was executed
 beyond the measure of their hopes, or perhaps of their
 wishes.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Belisarius', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'LOC')"
"In the country between the Elbe and the Oder several populous villages of Lusatia are
 inhabited by the Vandals: they still preserve their
 language, their customs, and the purity of their blood;
 support, with some impatience, the Saxon or Prussian yoke;
 and serve, with secret and voluntary allegiance, the
 descendant of their ancient kings, who in his garb and
 present fortune is confounded with the meanest of his
 vassals.(38) The name and
 situation of this unhappy people might indicate their
 descent from one common stock with the conquerors of Africa.","('Elbe', 'LOC'), ('Oder', 'LOC'), ('Lusatia', 'GPE'), ('Vandals', 'LOC'), ('Saxon', 'NORP'), ('Prussian', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"In the evening Belisarius led his infantry to the attack of the camp; and the pusillanimous flight of Gelimer exposed
 the vanity of his recent declarations, that to the vanquished, death was a relief, life a burden, and infamy the only object of terror.","('the evening', 'TIME'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Gelimer', 'PERSON')"
"In the exercise of this doubtful right, the eunuch perpetually dissented from the opinions of Belisarius; and, after yielding with reluctance to the siege
 of Urbino, he deserted his colleague in the night, and marched away to the conquest of the Aemilian province.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Urbino', 'GPE'), ('Aemilian', 'NORP')"
"In the first invasion some
 detachments, with two officers of merit, were surprised and
 intercepted; but Solomon speedily assembled his troops,
 marched from Carthage into the heart of the country, and in
 two great battles destroyed sixty thousand of the
 barbarians.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Solomon', 'PERSON'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the license of a
 military life, none could boast that they had seen him
 intoxicated with wine: the most beautiful captives of Gothic
 or Vandal race were offered to his embraces; but he turned
 aside from their charms, and the husband of Antonina was
 never suspected of violating the laws of conjugal fidelity.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Vandal', 'PERSON'), ('Antonina', 'PERSON')"
"In the mean
 while, Gelimer himself, ignorant of the event, and misguided
 by the windings of the hills, inadvertently passed the Roman
 army, and reached the scene of action where Ammatas had
 fallen.","('Gelimer', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Ammatas', 'PERSON')"
"In the more improved state of the art of war, a general is seldom required, or even permitted to display the personal prowess of a soldier; and the example of Belisarius may be added to the rare examples of Henry IV., of Pyrrhus, and of Alexander.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Henry IV.', 'PERSON'), ('Pyrrhus', 'GPE'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON')"
"In the next campaign, Syria was invaded on the side of the
 desert; and Belisarius, with twenty thousand men, hastened
 from Dara to the relief of the province.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dara', 'PERSON')"
"In the quarter of the Vatican, the
 Romans prevailed; and if the irreparable moments had not
 been wasted in the pillage of the camp, they might have
 occupied the Milvian bridge, and charged in the rear of the
 Gothic host.","('the quarter of the', 'DATE'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Milvian', 'GPE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"In the seventh year of the reign of Justinian, and about the
 time of the summer solstice, the whole fleet of six hundred
 ships was ranged in martial pomp before the gardens of the
 palace.","('the seventh year of the reign of Justinian', 'DATE'), ('summer', 'DATE'), ('six hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the siege of Osimo, the
 general was nearly transpierced with an arrow, if the mortal
 stroke had not been intercepted by one of his guards, who
 lost, in that pious office, the use of his hand.","('Osimo', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the succeeding campaign, Belisarius was again sent
 against the Persians: he saved the East, but he offended
 Theodora, and perhaps the emperor himself.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"In the various situations of their fortune she
 became the companion, the enemy, the servant, and the
 favorite of the empress Theodora: these loose and ambitious
 females had been connected by similar pleasures; they were
 separated by the jealousy of vice, and at length reconciled by the partnership of guilt.","('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"In the walls of Rome, which
 Belisarius constructed or restored, the materials of ancient
 architecture may be discerned; (79) and the whole
 fortification was completed, except in a chasm still extant
 between the Pincian and Flaminian gates, which the
 prejudices of the Goths and Romans left under the effectual
 guard of St. Peter the apostle. (80)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Belisarius', 'GPE'), ('Pincian', 'NORP'), ('Flaminian', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('80', 'CARDINAL')"
"In their villas and gardens, which might deserve the Persian name of  Paradise, (18) they enjoyed a cool and elegant repose; and, after the daily use of the bath, the Barbarians were seated at a table profusely spread with the delicacies of the land and sea.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('18', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"In this frantic search, the troops, even of Belisarius, forgot their caution and respect.","('Belisarius', 'GPE')"
"In this place they experienced how avarice, invested
 with authority, may sport with the lives of thousands which
 are bravely exposed for the public service.","('thousands', 'CARDINAL')"
"In three generations, prosperity and a warm
 climate had dissolved the hardy virtue of the Vandals, who insensibly became the most luxurious of mankind.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Vandals', 'NORP')"
"Innocence and courage decided his choice; his
 guards, captives, and treasures, were diligently embarked;
 and so prosperous was the navigation, that his arrival at
 Constantinople preceded any certain account of his departure
 from the port of Carthage.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"Inspired by
 such selfish motives, (for we may not suspect him of any
 zeal for the public good,) John of Cappadocia ventured to
 oppose in full council the inclinations of his master.","('John', 'PERSON'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE')"
"Instead of ascending a
 triumphal car drawn by four horses or elephants, the modest
 conqueror marched on foot at the head of his brave
 companions; his prudence might decline an honour too
 conspicuous for a subject; and his magnanimity might justly
 disdain what had been so often sullied by the vilest of
 tyrants.","('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"Instead of being injured, the country was enriched
 by the march of the Roman armies; and such was the rigid
 discipline of their camp, that not an apple was gathered
 from the tree, not a path could be traced in the fields of
 corn.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Instead of conferring, the king of Italy was reduced
 to solicit, the honours of the senate; and the consent of the
 emperor was made indispensable before he could execute,
 against a priest or senator, the sentence either of death or
 confiscation.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Instead of soliciting and expecting the aid of the
 king of Italy, they yielded to the first summons a cheerful
 obedience; and this province, the first fruits of the Punic
 wars, was again, after a long separation, united to the
 Roman empire.(57)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the Punic\r\n wars', 'EVENT'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('57', 'CARDINAL')"
"Instead of submitting to the
 laws of her country, which held as a fundamental maxim that
 the succession could never pass from the lance to the
 distaff, the daughter of Theodoric conceived the
 impracticable design of sharing, with one of her cousins,
 the regal title, and of reserving in her own hands the substance of supreme power.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"Instead of uniting their arms, they
 fled with equal precipitation; and the fertile, though
 desolate provinces of Liguria and Aemilia, were abandoned to
 a licentious host of Barbarians, whose rage was not
 mitigated by any thoughts of settlement or conquest.","('Liguria', 'GPE'), ('Aemilia', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"Intoxicated with lust and rapine, they explored, in small parties, or alone, the adjacent fields, the woods, the rocks, and the caverns, that might possibly conceal any desirable prize: laden with booty, they deserted their ranks, and wandered without a guide, on the high road to Carthage; and if the flying enemies had dared to return, very few of the conquerors would have escaped.","('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"Invasion of Italy by the Franks, A.D. 538, 539.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('538', 'CARDINAL'), ('539', 'CARDINAL')"
"It
 was impossible for cowards te surmount the barriers of
 unknown seas and hostile barbarians - it was impossible for
 brave men to expose their nakedness and defeat before the
 eyes of their countrymen, to describe the kingdoms which
 they had lost, and to claim a share of the humble
 inheritance which, in a happier hour, they had almost
 unanimously renounced.(37)","('a happier hour', 'TIME')"
"It
 was stipulated, that in the acclamations of the Roman
 people, the name of the emperor should be always proclaimed
 before that of the Gothic king; and that as often as the
 statue of Theodatus was erected in brass on marble, the
 divine image of Justinian should be placed on its right
 hand.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Theodatus', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"It might
 easily be foreseen that the enemy would intercept the
 aqueducts; and the cessation of the water-mills was the
 first inconvenience, which was speedily removed by mooring
 large vessels, and fixing mill-stones in the current of the
 river.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"It was
 not long before his pride and resentment were gratified by a
 suppliant embassy from the unfortunate Gelimer, who
 implored, in his distress, the aid of the Spanish monarch.","('Gelimer', 'PERSON'), ('Spanish', 'NORP')"
"It was equally the concern of the Roman general to subdue the hostile, and to save the prostrate, Barbarian; and the suppliant Vandals, who could be found only in churches, were protected by his authority, disarmed, and separately confined, that they might neither disturb the public peace, nor become the victims of popular revenge.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Barbarian', 'PERSON'), ('Vandals', 'NORP')"
"It was long since the king of Africa had tasted bread; a defluxion had fallen on his eyes, the effect
 of fatigue or incessant weeping; and he wished to solace the
 melancholy hours, by singing to the lyre the sad story of
 his own misfortunes.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('the\r\n melancholy hours', 'TIME')"
"It was not
 till the general moved forward for the Persian war, that
 Theodosius could be tempted to return to Constantinople; and
 the short interval before the departure of Antonina herself
 was boldly devoted to love and pleasure.","('the Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Antonina', 'PERSON')"
"It was the custom of the Roman triumphs, that a slave should
 be placed behind the chariot to remind the conqueror of the
 instability of fortune, and the infirmities of human nature.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It was the duty of the pilots, as they steered
 between the islands, and turned the Capes of Malea and
 Taenarium, to preserve the just order and regular intervals
 of such a multitude of ships: as the wind was fair and
 moderate, their labours were not unsuccessful, and the troops
 were safely disembarked at Methone on the Messenian coast,
 to repose themselves for a while after the fatigues of the
 sea.","('the Capes of Malea', 'LOC'), ('Taenarium', 'GPE'), ('Methone', 'GPE'), ('the Messenian coast', 'LOC')"
"Italy trembled at the march of the Franks; and both the
 Gothic prince and the Roman general, alike ignorant of their
 designs, solicited, with hope and terror, the friendship of
 these dangerous allies.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Jealousy of the Roman generals, A.D. 538.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 538', 'DATE')"
"Justinian and
 Theodora received him with cold ingratitude; the servile
 crowd, with insolence and contempt; and in the evening he
 retired with trembling steps to his deserted palace.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"Justinian beheld with joy the dissensions of the Goths, and
 the mediation of an ally concealed and promoted the
 ambitious views of the conqueror.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"Justinian deposited in the Byzantine palace the
 treasures of the Gothic monarchy.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"Justinian felt the weight of this salutary advice; he was confounded by the unwonted freedom of an obsequious servant; and the design of the war would perhaps have been relinquished, if his courage had not been revived by a voice which silenced the doubts of profane reason.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Justinian listened with too patient an ear; and his silence
 was the result of jealousy rather than of confidence.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Justininain resolves to invade Africa, A.D. 533","('Justininain', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('A.D. 533', 'DATE')"
"Leuderis alone, from a motive of
 pride or discontent, refused to accompany the fugitives; and
 the Gothic chief, himself a trophy of the victory, was sent
 with the keys of Rome to the throne of the emperor
 Justinian. (74)","('Leuderis', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Leuderis, an ancient warrior, was left in
 the capital with four thousand soldiers; a feeble garrison,
 which might have seconded the zeal, though it was incapable
 of opposing the wishes, of the Romans.","('Leuderis', 'PERSON'), ('four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Mournful was the interview: the two brothers embraced; they wept in silence; no questions were asked of the Sardinian victory; no inquiries were made of the African misfortunes: they saw before their eyes the whole extent of their
 calamities; and the absence of their wives and children afforded a melancholy proof that either death or captivity had been their lot.","('Mournful', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sardinian', 'NORP'), ('African', 'NORP')"
"Much room could not be found, in this
 disorderly battle, for the talents of a general; but the
 king fled before the hero; and the Vandals, accustomed only
 to a Moorish enemy, were incapable of withstanding the arms
 and discipline of the Romans.","('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Moorish', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Naples, which has swelled to a great and
 populous capital, long cherished the language and manners of
 a Grecian colony; (65) and the choice of Virgil had ennobled
 this elegant retreat, which attracted the lovers of repose
 and study, elegant retreat, which attracted the lovers of
 repose and study, from the noise, the smoke, and the
 laborious opulence of Rome. (66)","('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('Virgil', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('66', 'CARDINAL')"
"Near the former, the double walls of the
 Vivarium (85) were low or broken; the fortifications of the
 latter were feebly guarded: the vigor of the Goths was
 excited by the hope of victory and spoil; and if a single
 post had given way, the Romans, and Rome itself, were
 irrecoverably lost.","('Vivarium', 'FAC'), ('85', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
Neutrality of the Visigoths.,"('Visigoths', 'NORP')"
"No sooner was
 Belisarius informed of their arrival, than he despatched
 orders that the greatest part of the mariners should be
 immediately landed to join the triumph, and to swell the
 apparent numbers, of the Romans.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Not a tear escaped from his eyes, not a sigh was heard; but
 his pride or piety derived some secret consolation from the
 words of Solomon, (33) which he repeatedly pronounced,
 VANITY!","('Solomon', 'PERSON'), ('33', 'DATE')"
"Notwithstanding the
 decay of agriculture, Sicily still supplied the granaries of
 Rome; the farmers were graciously exempted from the
 oppression of military quarters; and the Goths, who trusted
 the defence of the island to the inhabitants, had some
 reason to complain that their confidence was ungratefully
 betrayed.","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"On
 the proof or suspicion of treason, several senators were
 banished, Exile of Pope sylverius, A.D. 537, Nov. 17.","('Exile of Pope', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('A.D. 537', 'DATE'), ('Nov. 17', 'DATE')"
"On a solemn
 festival, when the Goths were assembled in the palace of
 Ravenna, the royal youth escaped from his mother's
 apartment, and, with tears of pride and anger, complained of
 a blow which his stubborn disobedience had provoked her to
 inflict.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"On the
 morning of the nineteenth day, a general attack was made
 from the Praenestine gate to the Vatican: seven Gothic
 columns, with their military engines, advanced to the
 assault; and the Romans, who lined the ramparts, listened
 with doubt and anxiety to the cheerful assurances of their
 commander.","('the\r\n morning of the nineteenth day', 'TIME'), ('Praenestine', 'GPE'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"On the Tuscan side of
 the river, a seventh encampment was formed in the field or
 circus of the Vatican, for the important purpose of
 commanding the Milvian bridge and the course of the Tyber;
 but they approached with devotion the adjacent church of St.
 Peter; and the threshold of the holy apostles was respected
 during the siege by a Christian enemy.","('Tuscan', 'NORP'), ('seventh', 'ORDINAL'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Milvian', 'NORP'), ('Tyber', 'NORP'), ('St.\r\n Peter', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"On the first
 rumor, the abdicated monarch fled from the justice of his
 country; but he was pursued by private revenge.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"On the other side of the Tyber, Belisarius
