Sentence,Entities
"""Do you despise your lives?"" cried the indignant monarch: the blues rose with fury from
 their seats; their hostile clamours thundered in the hippodrome; and their adversaries, deserting the unequal contest spread terror and despair through the streets of Constantinople.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"(111) From Belgrade to the Euxine, from the conflux of the Save to the mouth of the Danube, a chain of above fourscore fortified places was extended along the banks of the great river.","('Belgrade', 'GPE'), ('Euxine', 'FAC'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
(51),"('51', 'CARDINAL')"
(6),"('6', 'CARDINAL')"
(75),"('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"A Gothic historian
 applauds the consulship of Theodoric as the height of all
 temporal glory and greatness; (156) the king of Italy himself
 congratulated those annual favorites of fortune who, without
 the cares, enjoyed the splendor of the throne; and at the
 end of a thousand years, two consuls were created by the
 sovereigns of Rome and Constantinople, for the sole purpose
 of giving a date to the year, and a festival to the people.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('156', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('the\r\n end of a thousand years', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('the year', 'DATE')"
"A Greek cross, inscribed in a quadrangle, represents the form of the edifice; the exact breadth is two hundred and forty-three feet, and two hundred and sixty-nine may be assigned for the extreme length from the sanctuary in the east, to the nine western doors, which open into the vestibule, and from thence into the narthex or
 exterior portico.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('two hundred and forty-three feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('two hundred and sixty-nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL')"
"A brother of the last emperor usurped the title of Augustus; his cause was powerfully supported by the arms, the
 treasures, and the magazines, collected by Zeno; and the native Isaurians must have formed the smallest portion of the hundred and fifty thousand Barbarians under his standard, which was sanctified, for the first time, by the presence of a fighting bishop.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Zeno', 'PERSON'), ('Isaurians', 'NORP'), ('the hundred and fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"A citizen of Tralles in
 Asia had five sons, who were all distinguished in their respective professions by merit and success.","('Tralles', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('five', 'CARDINAL')"
"A ditch and palisade might be sufficient
 to resist the artless force of the cavalry of Scythia; but
 more elaborate works were required to sustain a regular
 siege against the arms and treasures of the great king.","('Scythia', 'PRODUCT')"
"A dress which showed the turn of the limbs, and color of the skin, might gratify vanity, or provoke desire; the silks which had been closely woven in China were sometimes unravelled by the Phoenician women, and the precious materials were multiplied by a looser texture, and the intermixture of linen threads. (64)","('China', 'GPE'), ('Phoenician', 'NORP'), ('64', 'CARDINAL')"
"A fortress, designed by
 Alexander perhaps, or one of his successors, to command that
 important pass, had descended by right of conquest or
 inheritance to a prince of the Huns, who offered it for a
 moderate price to the emperor; but while Anastasius paused,
 while he timorously computed the cost and the distance, a
 more vigilant rival interposed, and Cabades forcibly
 occupied the Straits of Caucasus.","('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Anastasius', 'PERSON'), ('Cabades', 'PERSON'), ('the Straits of Caucasus', 'LOC')"
"A glorious
 repentance (the words of the edict) was left open for the
 unhappy females who had prostituted their persons on the
 theatre, and they were permitted to contract a legal union
 with the most illustrious of the Romans. (28)","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('28', 'CARDINAL')"
"A great minister, who had been invested with the honours of consul and patrician, was ignominiously scourged like the vilest of malefactors; a tattered cloak was the sole remnant of his fortunes; he was transported in a bark to the place of his banishment at Antinopolis in Upper Egypt, and the praefect of the East begged his bread through the cities which had trembled at his name.","('Antinopolis', 'GPE'), ('Upper Egypt', 'LOC'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"A larger view of the globe might at least have promoted the
 improvement of speculative science, but the Christian
 geography was forcibly extracted from texts of Scripture,
 and the study of nature was the surest symptom of an
 unbelieving mind.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Scripture', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"A law was thought necessary to discriminate the dress of comedians from that of senators; and of the silk exported from its native country the far greater part was consumed by the
 subjects of Justinian.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"A machine was fixed on the walls
 of the city, consisting of a hexagon mirror of polished brass, with many smaller and movable polygons to receive and reflect the rays of the meridian sun; and a consuming flame was darted, to the distance, perhaps of two hundred feet. (97)","('two hundred feet', 'QUANTITY')"
"A magnificent temple is a laudable monument of national taste and religion; and the enthusiast who entered the dome of St. Sophia might be tempted to suppose that it was the
residence, or even the workmanship, of the Deity.","('St. Sophia', 'GPE')"
"A material difference may be observed in the games of
 antiquity: the most eminent of the Greeks were actors, the
 Romans were merely spectators.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"A military force,
 which had been despatched to the aid of the civil magistrate, was fiercely encountered by an armed multitude, whose numbers and boldness continually increased; and the Heruli, the wildest Barbarians in the service of the empire, overturned the priests and their relics, which, from a pious motive, had been rashly interposed to separate the bloody conflict.","('Heruli', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"A palace, on the Asiatic side of the Bosphorus, was converted into a stately and spacious monastery, and a liberal maintenance was assigned to five hundred women, who had been collected from the streets and brothels of Constantinople.","('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('five hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"A poet, (105) who beheld the primitive lustre of St. Sophia, enumerates the Marbles  colours, the shades, and the spots of ten or  twelve marbles, jaspers, and porphyries, which nature had profusely diversified, and which were blended and contrasted as it were by a skilful painter.","('105', 'CARDINAL'), ('St. Sophia', 'LOC'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL')"
"A province might suffer by the decay of its manufactures, but in this example of silk, Procopius has partially overlooked the inestimable and lasting benefit which the empire received from the curiosity of Justinian.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"A secret attachment to the family
 or sect of Anastasius was imputed to the greens; the blues
 were zealously devoted to the cause of orthodoxy Justinian favours the blues.","('Anastasius', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"A sedition, which almost laid Constantinople in ashes, was excited by the mutual hatred and momentary reconciliation of the two factions.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"A sense of the disgrace and mischief of this venal practice, at length awakened the slumbering virtue of Justinian; and he attempted, by the sanction of oaths (88) and penalties, to guard the integrity of his government: but at the end of a year of perjury, his rigorous edict was suspended, and corruption licentiously abused her triumph
 over the impotence of the laws.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('88', 'CARDINAL'), ('the end of a year', 'DATE')"
"A similar instance, in Grecian history, admonished the emperor of the honourable part prescribed for his imitation.","('Grecian', 'NORP')"
"A thin gauze was procured from their webs, and this Cean manufacture, the invention of a woman, for female use, was long admired both in the East and at Rome.","('Cean', 'PRODUCT'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"A tradition has prevailed, that the Roman fleet was reduced to ashes in the port of Syracuse, by the burning-glasses of Archimedes; (95) and it is asserted, that
 a similar expedient was employed by Proclus to destroy the Gothic vessels in the harbour of Constantinople, and to protect his benefactor Anastasius against the bold enterprise of Vitalian. (96)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Syracuse', 'GPE'), ('Archimedes', 'PRODUCT'), ('95', 'CARDINAL'), ('Proclus', 'ORG'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Anastasius', 'PERSON'), ('Vitalian', 'NORP'), ('96', 'CARDINAL')"
A valuable merchandise of small bulk is capable of defraying the expense of land-carriage; and the caravans traversed the whole latitude of Asia in two hundred and forty-three days from the Chinese Ocean to the sea-coast of Syria.,"('Asia', 'LOC'), ('two hundred and forty-three days', 'DATE'), ('the Chinese Ocean', 'LOC'), ('Syria', 'GPE')"
"A variety of ornaments and figures was curiously expressed in mosaic; and the images of Christ, of the Virgin, of saints, and of angels, which have been defaced by Turkish fanaticism, were dangerously exposed to the superstition of the Greeks.","('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
A.D. 488.,"('A.D. 488', 'DATE')"
A.D. 492-498.,"('A.D. 492-498', 'DATE')"
"About a century after the reign of Julian, (151) Proclus (152) was permitted to teach in the philosophic chair of the
 academy; and such was his industry, that he frequently, in
 the same day, pronounced five lessons, and composed seven
 hundred lines.","('About a century', 'DATE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('151', 'CARDINAL'), ('Proclus', 'PERSON'), ('152', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"About the same time that Pythagoras first invented the
 appellation of philosopher, liberty and the consulship were
 founded at Rome by the elder Brutus.","('Pythagoras', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Brutus', 'PERSON')"
"Above Trebizond
 immediately, and five days' journey to the south, the
 country rises into dark forests and craggy mountains, as
 savage though not so lofty as the Alps and the Pyrenees.","(""five days'"", 'DATE'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC')"
"Abraham (55) had been relieved by the well-known plenty of Egypt; the same country, a small and populous tract, was still capable of exporting, each year, two hundred and sixty thousand quarters of wheat for the use of Constantinople; (56) and the capital of Justinian was supplied with the manufactures of Sidon, fifteen centuries after they had been celebrated in the poems of Homer. (57)","('Abraham', 'PERSON'), ('55', 'DATE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('two hundred and sixty thousand quarters', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('56', 'CARDINAL'), ('Justinian', 'GPE'), ('Sidon', 'GPE'), ('fifteen centuries', 'DATE'), ('Homer', 'PERSON'), ('57', 'CARDINAL')"
"Acacius had left three daughters,
 Comito, (21) Theodora, and Anastasia, the eldest of whom did
 not then exceed the age of seven years.","('Acacius', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Comito', 'PERSON'), ('21', 'DATE'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('Anastasia', 'PERSON'), ('the age of seven years', 'DATE')"
"According to a recent
 description, huge stones, seven feet thick, and twenty-one
 feet in length or height, are artificially joined without
 iron or cement, to compose a wall, which runs above three
 hundred miles from the shores of Derbend, over the hills,
 and through the valleys of Daghestan and Georgia.","('seven feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('twenty-one\r\n feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('three\r\n hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Derbend', 'GPE'), ('Daghestan', 'GPE'), ('Georgia', 'GPE')"
"According to another story, Proclus applied sulphur to the destruction of the Gothic fleet; (100) in a modern imagination, the name of sulphur is instantly connected with the suspicion of gunpowder, and that suspicion is propagated by the secret arts of his disciple Anthemius. (101)","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('100', 'CARDINAL'), ('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('101', 'CARDINAL')"
"Adoption and succession of Justinian, A.D. 520-527.","('Justinian', 'ORG')"
"After
 the fall of his rival, he was promoted, without any claim of
 military service, to the office of master-general of the
 Eastern armies, whom it was his duty to lead into the field
 against the public enemy.","('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"After a fruitless representation, that obedience might lead to involuntary treason, they retired to their houses, and in the morning of
 the sixth day, Hypatius was surrounded and seized by the people, who, regardless of his virtuous resistance, and the tears of his wife, transported their favorite to the forum of Constantine, and instead of a diadem, placed a rich collar on his head.","('the morning of\r\n the sixth day', 'DATE'), ('Hypatius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"After a schism of thirty-four years, he reconciled
 the proud and angry spirit of the Roman pontiff, and spread
 among the Latins a favorable report of his pious respect for
 the apostolic see.","('thirty-four years', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Latins', 'NORP')"
"After exhausting the arts of sensual
 pleasure, (25) she most ungratefully murmured against the
 parsimony of Nature; (26) but her murmurs, her pleasures, and
 her arts, must be veiled in the obscurity of a learned
 language.","('25', 'DATE'), ('26', 'CARDINAL')"
"After reigning for some time, the delight and
 contempt of the capital, she condescended to accompany
 Ecebolus, a native of Tyre, who had obtained the government
 of the African Pentapolis.","('Ecebolus', 'PERSON'), ('Tyre', 'GPE'), ('the African Pentapolis', 'ORG')"
"After the death of
 Marcus, these liberal donations, and the privileges attached
 to the thrones of science, were abolished and revived,
 diminished and enlarged; but some vestige of royal bounty
 may be found under the successors of Constantine; and their
 arbitrary choice of an unworthy candidate might tempt the
 philosophers of Athens to regret the days of independence
 and poverty. (149)","('Marcus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('the days', 'DATE'), ('149', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the death of Zeno, his successor Anastasius suppressed their pensions, exposed their persons to the revenge of the people, banished them
 from Constantinople, and prepared to sustain a war, which left only the alternative of victory or servitude.","('Zeno', 'PERSON'), ('Anastasius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"After the siege of Amida, the war continued three years, and
 the unhappy frontier tasted the full measure of its
 calamities.","('Amida', 'GPE'), ('three years', 'DATE')"
"After this popular concession, Justinian proceeded to the hippodrome to confess his own errors, and to accept the repentance of his grateful subjects; but they distrusted his assurances, though solemnly pronounced in the presence of the holy Gospels; and the emperor, alarmed by their distrust, retreated with precipitation to the strong fortress of the palace.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Gospels', 'NORP')"
"After this precaution, I shall briefly relate the anecdotes
 of avarice and rapine under the following heads:  I. 
 Justinian was so profuse that he could not be liberal.","('I. \r\n Justinian', 'PERSON')"
Agriculture and manufactures of the Eastern empire.,"('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"Along
 the African coast, they penetrated to the equator in search
 of gold, emeralds, and aromatics; but they wisely declined
 an unequal competition, in which they must be always
 prevented by the vicinity of the Persians to the markets of
 India; and the emperor submitted to the disappointment, till
 his wishes were gratified by an unexpected event.","('African', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('India', 'GPE')"
"Although he was suspected of magic and Pagan superstition, he appeared insensible to the fear of God or the reproaches of man; and his aspiring fortune was raised on the death of thousands, the poverty of millions, the ruins of cities, and the desolation of provinces.","('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('millions', 'CARDINAL')"
"Although the Isaurians were not remarkable for stature or bravery, want rendered them bold, and experience made them skilful in the exercise of predatory war.","('Isaurians', 'NORP')"
"Amantius lost his head; three of his companions, the first domestics of the palace, were punished  either with death or exile; and their unfortunate candidate
 for the purple was cast into a deep dungeon, overwhelmed
 with stones, and ignominiously thrown, without burial, into
 the sea.","('Amantius', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Ambiguous actions are imputed to the worst motives; error is
 confounded with guilt, accident with design, and laws with
 abuses; the partial injustice of a moment is dexterously
 applied as the general maxim of a reign of thirty-two years;
 the emperor alone is made responsible for the faults of his
 officers, the disorders of the times, and the corruption of
 his subjects; and even the calamities of nature, plagues,
 earthquakes, and inundations, are imputed to the prince of
 the daemons, who had mischievously assumed the form of
 Justinian. (84)
Pernicious savings","('thirty-two years', 'DATE'), ('Justinian', 'ORG')"
"Amida sustained a long and destructive siege: at
 the end of three months the loss of fifty thousand of the
 soldiers of Cabades was not balanced by any prospect of
 success, and it was in vain that the Magi deduced a
 flattering prediction from the indecency of the women  on  the ramparts, who had revealed their most secret charms to  the eyes of the assailants.","('Amida', 'PERSON'), ('the end of three months', 'DATE'), ('fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Cabades', 'PRODUCT'), ('Magi', 'PERSON')"
"Amidst their
 pious occupations, they viewed with a curious eye the common
 dress of the Chinese, the manufactures of silk, and the
 myriads of silk-worms, whose education (either on trees or
 in houses) had once been considered as the labor of queens.","('Chinese', 'NORP')"
"Among the
 Roman cities beyond the Euphrates, we distinguish two recent
 foundations, which were named from Theodosius, and the
 relics of the martyrs; and two capitals, Amida and Edessa,
 which are celebrated in the history of every age.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Amida', 'NORP'), ('Edessa', 'PERSON')"
"Among the forms of rapine, a philosopher may be permitted to name the conversion of Pagan or heretical riches to the use of the faithful; but in the time of Justinian this holy plunder was condemned by the sectaries alone, who became the victims of his orthodox avarice. (90)","('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('90', 'CARDINAL')"
"An
 ambuscade of guards and eunuchs had been posted by the command of Theodora; they rushed with drawn swords to seize or to punish the guilty minister: he was saved by the fidelity of his attendants; but instead of appealing to a
 gracious sovereign, who had privately warned him of his danger, he pusillanimously fled to the sanctuary of the church.","('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"An active government would have
 restored the trade of Egypt and the navigation of the Red
 Sea, which had decayed with the prosperity of the empire;
 and the Roman vessels might have sailed, for the purchase of
 silk, to the ports of Ceylon, of Malacca, or even of China.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('the Red\r\n Sea', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Ceylon', 'GPE'), ('Malacca', 'GPE'), ('China', 'GPE')"
"An ambassador from the emperor Zeno
 accompanied the rash and unfortunate Perozes,  in his
 expedition against the Nepthalites,  or white Huns, whose
 conquests had been stretched from the Caspian to the heart
 of India, whose throne was enriched with emeralds, (133) and
 whose cavalry was supported by a line of two thousand
 elephants. (134)","('Zeno', 'PERSON'), ('Perozes', 'PERSON'), ('Nepthalites', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Caspian', 'LOC'), ('India', 'GPE'), ('133', 'CARDINAL'), ('two thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('134', 'CARDINAL')"
"An eclipse of the sun
 announced his approaching end; and his life, with that of
 his scholar Isidore, (153) compiled by two of their most
 learned disciples, exhibits a deplorable picture of the
 second childhood of human reason.","('Isidore', 'PERSON'), ('153', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"And a more direct sale of honours and offices was transacted in the palace, with the permission, or at least with the connivance, of Justinian and Theodora.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"Anthemius formed the design, and his genius directed the hands of ten thousand workmen, whose payment in pieces of fine silver was never delayed beyond the evening.","('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('the evening', 'TIME')"
"As he was never more seen, even after the decease
 of Theodora, she deserves the foul imputation of
 extinguishing with his life a secret so offensive to her
 Imperial virtue.","('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"As one of these criminals was of the blue, and the other of the green livery, the two factions were equally provoked by the cruelty of their oppressor, or the ingratitude of their patron; and a short truce was concluded till they had delivered their prisoners and satisfied their revenge.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"As silk became of indispensable use, the emperor Justinian
 saw with concern that the Persians had occupied by land and
 sea the monopoly of this important supply, and that the
 wealth of his subjects was continually drained by a nation
 of enemies and idolaters.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"As they improved in age and beauty, the three sisters were
 successively devoted to the public and private pleasures of
 the Byzantine people: and Theodora, after following Comito
 on the stage, in the dress of a slave, with a stool on her
 head, was at length permitted to exercise her independent
 talents.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('Comito', 'PERSON')"
"Asia Minor, after the submission of the Isaurians, (119) remained without enemies and without fortifications.","('Asia Minor', 'LOC'), ('Isaurians', 'NORP'), ('119', 'CARDINAL')"
"At
 each of these gates of the city, a praetor was stationed,
 the minister of Imperial avarice; heavy customs were imposed
 on the vessels and their merchandise; the oppression was
 retaliated on the helpless consumer; the poor were afflicted
 by the artificial scarcity, and exorbitant price of the
 market; and a people, accustomed to depend on the liberality
 of their prince, might sometimes complain of the deficiency
 of water and bread. (86)","('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"At a  time when Belisarius, unless he had been a hero, must have shown himself a rebel, his wife Antonina, who enjoyed the secret confidence of the empress, communicated his feigned discontent to Euphemia, the daughter of the praefect; the credulous virgin imparted to her father the dangerous project, and John, who might have known the value of oaths and promises, was tempted to accept a nocturnal, and almost treasonable, interview with the wife of Belisarius.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Antonina', 'PERSON'), ('Euphemia', 'PERSON'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"At another time, the friends of Zeno, as they sat at table, were dazzled by the intolerable light which flashed in their eyes from the reflecting mirrors of Anthemius; they were astonished by the noise which he produced from the collision of certain minute and sonorous particles; and the orator declared in tragic style to the senate, that a mere mortal must yield to the power of an antagonist, who shook the earth with the trident of Neptune, and imitated the thunder and lightning of Jove himself.","('Zeno', 'PERSON'), ('Anthemius', 'PERSON'), ('certain minute', 'TIME'), ('Neptune', 'LOC'), ('Jove', 'PERSON')"
"At length, in a silent night,
 they ascended the most accessible tower, which was guarded
 only by some monks, oppressed, after the duties of a
 festival, with sleep and wine.","('a silent night', 'TIME')"
"At length, in the twenty-fourth year of her marriage, and the twenty-second of her reign, she was consumed by a cancer; (39) and the irreparable loss was deplored by her husband, who, in the room of a theatrical prostitute, might have selected the purest and most noble virgin of the East. (40)","('the twenty-fourth year', 'DATE'), ('twenty-second', 'DATE'), ('39', 'DATE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('40', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the accession of the younger Justin, the
 proclamation of equal and rigorous justice indirectly
 condemned the partiality of the former reign.","('Justin', 'PERSON')"
"At the distance only of forty miles, Anastasius was constrained to establish a last frontier; his long wall, of sixty miles from the Propontis to the Euxine, proclaimed the impotence of his arms; and as the danger became more imminent, new fortifications were added by the indefatigable prudence of
 Justinian. (118)
Security of Asia, after the conquest of Isauria.","('forty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Anastasius', 'PERSON'), ('sixty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Propontis', 'NORP'), ('Euxine', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('118', 'CARDINAL'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Isauria', 'GPE')"
"At the extremity of Europe, another peninsula, the Thracian Chersonesus, runs three days' journey into the sea, to form, with the adjacent shores of Asia, the Straits of the Hellespont.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('the Thracian Chersonesus', 'ORG'), (""three days'"", 'DATE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('the Straits of the Hellespont', 'LOC')"
"At this dangerous moment, seven notorious assassins of both factions, who had been condemned by the praefect, were carried round the city, and afterwards transported to the place of execution in the suburb of Pera.","('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pera', 'GPE')"
"Athens, though situate in a barren soil,
 possessed a pure air, a free navigation, and the monuments
 of ancient art.","('Athens', 'GPE')"
"Aurelian complained, that a pound of silk was sold at Rome for twelve ounces of gold; but the supply increased with the demand, and the price diminished with the supply.","('Aurelian', 'ORG'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('twelve ounces', 'QUANTITY')"
Avarice and profusion of Justinian.,"('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Before the structure of the church had arisen two cubits above the ground, Riches  forty-five thousand two hundred pounds were already consumed; and the whole expense amounted to three hundred and twenty thousand: each reader, according to the measure of his belief, may estimate their value either in gold or silver; but the sum of one million sterling is the result of the lowest computation.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('forty-five thousand two hundred pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('three hundred and twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('one million', 'CARDINAL')"
"Between the Euxine and the Caspian, the countries of
 Colchos, Iberia, and Albania, are intersected in every
 direction by the branches of Mount Caucasus; and the two
 principal gates, or passes, from north to south, have been
 frequently confounded in the geography both of the ancients
 and moderns.","('Euxine', 'LOC'), ('Caspian', 'LOC'), ('Colchos', 'GPE'), ('Iberia', 'LOC'), ('Albania', 'GPE'), ('Mount Caucasus', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
Birth and vices of the empress Theodora.,"('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"Both the theory and practice of the arts which depend on mathematical science and mechanical power, were cultivated under the patronage of the emperors; the fame of Archimedes was rivalled by Proclus and Anthemius; and if their miracles had been related by intelligent spectators, they might now enlarge the speculations, instead of exciting the distrust, of philosophers.","('Archimedes', 'PRODUCT'), ('Proclus', 'PERSON'), ('Anthemius', 'PERSON')"
"But
 the dangers of the desert were found less intolerable than
 toil, hunger, and the loss of time; the attempt was seldom
 renewed, and the only European who has passed that
 unfrequented way, applauds his own diligence, that, in nine
 months after his departure from Pekin, he reached the mouth
 of the Indus.","('European', 'NORP'), ('nine\r\n months', 'DATE'), ('Pekin', 'GPE'), ('Indus', 'LOC')"
"But
 the reproach of cruelty, so repugnant even to her softer
 vices, has left an indelible stain on the memory of
 Theodora.","('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"But
 this request, which too clearly admonished him of his
 approaching end, was unwelcome to the jealous temper of an
 aged monarch, desirous to retain the power which he was
 incapable of exercising; and Justin, holding his purple with
 both his hands, advised them to prefer, since an election
 was so profitable, some older candidate.","('Justin', 'PERSON')"
"But a
 senator, or even a citizen, conscious of his dignity, would
 have blushed to expose his person, or his horses, in the
 circus of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But in the ensuing year they recalled the hasty
 decree, restored the liberty of the schools, and were
 convinced by the experience of ages, that the moral
 character of philosophers is not affected by the diversity
 of their theological speculations. (150)","('the ensuing year', 'DATE'), ('150', 'CARDINAL')"
"But in the intervals of study, he
personally conversed with Pan, Aesculapius, and Minerva, in
 whose mysteries he was secretly initiated, and whose
 prostrate statues he adored; in the devout persuasion that
 the philosopher, who is a citizen of the universe, should be
 the priest of its various deities.","('Pan', 'PERSON'), ('Aesculapius', 'PERSON'), ('Minerva', 'PERSON')"
"But no sooner was the vigilance of power relaxed or diverted, than the light-armed squadrons descended from the hills, and invaded the peaceful plenty of Asia.","('Asia', 'LOC')"
"But some property of lands and houses
 was settled by the permission of the laws, and the legacies
 of deceased friends, on the philosophic chairs of Athens.","('Athens', 'GPE')"
"But that name was divested of its terrors; the Barbarians, in their annual inroads, passed, and contemptuously repassed, before these useless bulwarks; and the inhabitants of the frontier, instead of reposing under the shadow of the general defence, were compelled to guard, with incessant vigilance, their separate habitations.","('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('annual', 'DATE')"
"But the
 laws of Rome expressly prohibited the marriage of a senator
 with any female who had been dishonored by a servile origin
 or theatrical profession: the empress Lupicina, or Euphemia,
 a Barbarian of rustic manners, but of irreproachable virtue,
 refused to accept a prostitute for her niece; and even
 Vigilantia, the superstitious mother of Justinian, though
 she acknowledged the wit and beauty of Theodora, was
 seriously apprehensive, lest the levity and arrogance of
 that artful paramour might corrupt the piety and happiness
 of her son.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Lupicina', 'PERSON'), ('Euphemia', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('Vigilantia', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"But the architect who first erected and aerial cupola, is entitled to the praise of bold design and skilful execution.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But the difficult and perilous march from
 Samarcand to the first town of Shensi, could not be
 performed in less than sixty, eighty, or one hundred days:
 as soon as they had passed the Jaxartes they entered the
 desert; and the wandering hordes, unless they are restrained
 by armies and garrisons, have always considered the citizen
 and the traveller as the objects of lawful rapine.","('Samarcand', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Shensi', 'GPE'), ('less than sixty, eighty', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred days', 'DATE'), ('Jaxartes', 'NORP')"
"But the expenses of this festival, in which the wealthy and
 the vain aspired to surpass their predecessors, insensibly
 arose to the enormous sum of fourscore thousand pounds; the
 wisest senators declined a useless honor, which involved the
 certain ruin of their families, and to this reluctance I
 should impute the frequent chasms in the last age of the
 consular Fasti.","('fourscore thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('Fasti', 'PERSON')"
"But the genius of Justin was far inferior to that of the Gothic king: the experience of a soldier had not qualified him for the government of an empire; and though personally brave, the consciousness of his own weakness was naturally attended with doubt, distrust, and political apprehension.","('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"But the national enmity, at least the effects of that
 enmity, had been suspended by a truce, which continued above
 fourscore years.","('fourscore years', 'DATE')"
"But the official business of the state was diligently and faithfully transacted by the quaestor Proclus; (5) and the aged emperor adopted the talents and ambition of his nephew Justinian, an
 aspiring youth, whom his uncle had drawn from the rustic solitude of Dacia, and educated at Constantinople, as the heir of his private fortune, and at length of the Eastern empire.","('Proclus', 'PERSON'), ('5', 'CARDINAL'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Dacia', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"But the repetition of partial and passionate invectives degraded, in their eyes, the majesty of the purple; they renounced allegiance to the prince who refused justice to his people; lamented that the father of Justinian had been born; and branded his son with the opprobrious names of a homicide, an ass, and a perjured tyrant.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"But the splendid fortune of Eulalius had been consumed by fire, and the inventory of his goods did not exceed the trifling sum of five hundred and sixty-four pieces of gold.","('Eulalius', 'ORG'), ('five hundred and sixty-four', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the tradition of ancient dignity was long
 revered by the Romans and Barbarians.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"But the usual honors which the severity of Roman manners had
 allowed to the wives of princes, could not satisfy either
 the ambition of Theodora or the fondness of Justinian.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"But their wealth served only to attract the bold and rapacious Barbarians; the noblest of the Romans, in the bosom of peaceful indolence, were led away into Scythian captivity, and their sovereign might view from his palace the hostile flames which were insolently spread to the gates of the Imperial city.","('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"But these weighty arguments were
 treacherously employed by Justin in his own favor; and as no competitor presumed to appear, the Dacian peasant was invested with the purple by the unanimous consent of the soldiers, who knew him to be brave and gentle, of the clergy and people, who believed him to be orthodox, and of the provincials, who yielded a blind and implicit submission to the will of the capital.","('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Dacian', 'NORP')"
"But this union was frail and
 transient; Ecebolus soon rejected an expensive or faithless
 concubine; she was reduced at Alexandria to extreme
 distress; and in her laborious return to Constantinople,
 every city of the East admired and enjoyed the fair Cyprian,
 whose merit appeared to justify her descent from the
 peculiar island of Venus.","('Ecebolus', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Cyprian', 'PERSON'), ('Venus', 'LOC')"
"But, if she employed her influence to assuage the intolerant fury of the emperor, the present age will allow some merit to her
 religion, and much indulgence to her speculative errors. (34)","('34', 'CARDINAL')"
"But, in the pursuit of fame,
 Justinian might have lost his present dominion over the age
 and weakness of his uncle; and instead of acquiring by
 Scythian or Persian trophies the applause of his countrymen,
 (9) the prudent warrior solicited their favor in the
 churches, the circus, and the senate, of Constantinople.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('9', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Capriciously trusted, disgraced, and pardoned, by the jealous levity of the monarch, they had appeared as loyal servants before the throne; and, during five days of the tumult, they were detained as important hostages; till at length, the fears of Justinian prevailing over his prudence, he viewed the two brothers in the light of spies, perhaps of assassins, and sternly commanded them to depart from the palace.","('five days', 'DATE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Ceylon,
 Serendib, or Taprobana, was divided between two hostile
 princes; one of whom possessed the mountains, the elephants,
 and the luminous carbuncle, and the other enjoyed the more
 solid riches of domestic industry, foreign trade, and the
 capacious harbor of Trinquemale, which received and
 dismissed the fleets of the East and West.","('Ceylon', 'GPE'), ('Serendib', 'GPE'), ('Taprobana', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Trinquemale', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"Conscious of her
 approaching greatness, she returned from Paphlagonia to
 Constantinople; assumed, like a skilful actress, a more
 decent character; relieved her poverty by the laudable
 industry of spinning wool; and affected a life of chastity
 and solitude in a small house, which she afterwards changed
 into a magnificent temple. (27)","('Paphlagonia to\r\n Constantinople', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Constantinople adopted the follies, though not the virtues,
 of ancient Rome; and the same factions which had agitated
 the circus, raged with redoubled fury in the hippodrome.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Dara
 continued more than sixty years to fulfil the wishes of its
 founders, and to provoke the jealousy of the Persians, who
 incessantly complained, that this impregnable fortress had
 been constructed in manifest violation of the treaty of
 peace between the two empires.","('Dara', 'PERSON'), ('more than sixty years', 'DATE'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Death of Perozes, king of Persia.","('Death of Perozes', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"Dioscorus and Alexander became learned
 physicians; but the skill of the former was exercised for the benefit of his fellow-citizens, while his more ambitious brother acquired wealth and reputation at Rome.","('Dioscorus', 'PERSON'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Disappointment might urge the flatterer to secret revenge;
 and the first glance of favor might again tempt him to
 suspend and suppress a libel, (17) in which the Roman Cyrus
 is degraded into an odious and contemptible tyrant, in which
 both the emperor and his consort Theodora are seriously
 represented as two daemons, who had assumed a human form for
 the destruction of mankind.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the Roman Cyrus', 'ORG'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Dishonour might be ultimately reflected on the character of Justinian; but much of the guilt, and still more of the profit, was intercepted by the ministers, who were seldom promoted for their virtues, and not always selected for their talents.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
Division of the reign of Justinian.,"('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"During an exile of seven years, his life was protracted and threatened by the ingenious cruelty of Theodora; and when her death permitted the emperor to recall a servant whom he had abandoned with regret, the ambition of John of Cappadocia was reduced to the humble duties of the sacerdotal profession.","('seven years', 'DATE'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE')"
"Eight columns of porphyry, which Aurelian had placed in the temple of the sun, were offered by the piety of a Roman matron; eight others of green marble were presented by the ambitious zeal of the magistrates of Ephesus: both are admirable by their size and beauty, but every order of architecture disclaims their fantastic
 capital.","('Eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aurelian', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ephesus', 'GPE')"
"Elevation and reign of his uncle Justin I., A.D. 518, July 10; A.D. 527, April 1 - or August 1.","('Justin I.', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 518', 'DATE'), ('July 10', 'DATE'), ('A.D. 527', 'DATE'), ('April 1 - or August 1', 'DATE')"
Elevation of Justin the Elder —  Reign of Justinian—,"('Justin the Elder —  Reign of Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Epicurus bequeathed to his disciples the gardens which he
 had purchased for eighty minae or two hundred and fifty
 pounds, with a fund sufficient for their frugal subsistence
 and monthly festivals; (146) and the patrimony of Plato
 afforded an annual rent, which, in eight centuries, was
 gradually increased from three to one thousand pieces of
 gold.","('Epicurus', 'PERSON'), ('eighty minae', 'QUANTITY'), ('two hundred and fifty\r\n pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('monthly', 'DATE'), ('146', 'CARDINAL'), ('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('eight centuries', 'DATE'), ('three to one thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Europe was overrun by the
 Barbarians, and Asia by the monks: the poverty of the West
 discouraged the trade and manufactures of the East: the
 produce of labor was consumed by the unprofitable servants
 of the church, the state, and the army; and a rapid decrease
 was felt in the fixed and circulating capitals which
 constitute the national wealth.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"Even Theodora herself was constrained to dissemble, to wait a favourable moment, and, by an artful conspiracy, to render John of Coppadocia the accomplice of his own destruction.","('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('John of Coppadocia', 'PERSON')"
"Every art was tried to extort from the people
 the gold and silver which he scattered with a lavish hand
 from Persia to France: (81) his reign was marked by the
 vicissitudes or rather by the combat, of rapaciousness and
 avarice, of splendor and poverty; he lived with the
 reputation of hidden treasures, (82) and bequeathed to his
 successor the payment of his debts. (83)","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('81', 'CARDINAL'), ('82', 'CARDINAL')"
"Experience
 and reflection corrected the errors of a new attempt, and
 the Sogdoite ambassadors acknowledged, in the succeeding
 reign, that the Romans were not inferior to the natives of
 China in the education of the insects, and the manufactures
 of silk, (76) in which both China and Constantinople have
 been surpassed by the industry of modern Europe.","('Sogdoite', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"Factions of the Circus, and Sedition of Constantinople—  Trade and Manufacture of Silk—  Finances and Taxes—  Edifices of Justinian— Church of St. Sophia—  Fortifications and Frontiers of the Eastern Empire—  Abolition of the Schools of Athens, and the Consulship of Rome Birth of the emperor Justinian, A.D. 482, May 5 - or A.D. 483 , may 11.","('Frontiers of the Eastern Empire—  Abolition of the Schools of Athens', 'LAW'), ('the Consulship of Rome Birth of the emperor Justinian', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('A.D. 482', 'DATE'), ('May 5 - or A.D. 483', 'DATE'), ('11', 'CARDINAL')"
"Filled with ambitious hopes, the
 unsuspecting youth immediately hastened to the palace of
 Constantinople, and was admitted to the presence of his
 mother.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
Firmness of Theodora.,"('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"For the use of the emperor's countryman, a cathedral, a place, and an aqueduct, were speedily constructed; the public and private edifices were adapted to the greatness of a royal city; and the strength of the walls resisted, during the lifetime of Justinian, the unskilful assaults of the Huns and Sclavonians.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Sclavonians', 'NORP')"
"For this purpose, the town of Dara, (137) fourteen miles
 from Nisibis, and four days' journey from the Tigris, was
 peopled and adorned; the hasty works of Anastasius were
 improved by the perseverance of Justinian; and, without
 insisting on places less important, the fortifications of
 Dara may represent the military architecture of the age.","('Dara', 'GPE'), ('137', 'CARDINAL'), ('fourteen miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Nisibis', 'GPE'), (""four days'"", 'DATE'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Anastasius', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'NORP'), ('Dara', 'PERSON')"
Fortifications of Dara.,"('Dara', 'PERSON')"
"Fortifications of the empire, from the Euxine to the Persian frontier.","('Euxine', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"Four were immediately beheaded; a fifth was hanged: but when the same punishment was inflicted on the remaining two, the rope broke, they fell alive to the ground, the populace applauded their escape, and the monks of St. Conon, issuing from the neighbouring convent, conveyed them in a boat to the sanctuary of the church.","('Four', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifth', 'ORDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('St. Conon', 'GPE')"
"From a motive of shame, or contempt, she
 often declined the servile homage of the multitude, escaped
 from the odious light of the capital, and passed the
 greatest part of the year in the palaces and gardens which
 were pleasantly seated on the sea-coast of the Propontis and
 the Bosphorus.","('the year', 'DATE'), ('Propontis', 'LOC'), ('Bosphorus', 'LOC')"
"From his elevation to his death, Justinian governed the
 Roman empire thirty-eight years, seven months, and thirteen
 days.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('thirty-eight years', 'DATE'), ('seven months', 'DATE'), ('thirteen\r\n days', 'DATE')"
"From such scenes of horror and distress, the wise and wealthy citizens escaped over the Bosphorus to the Asiatic side; and during five days Constantinople was abandoned to the factions, whose watchword, NIKA, vanquish!","('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('five days', 'DATE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"From that maritime city, frontier line of five
 hundred miles may be drawn to the fortress of Circesium, the
 last Roman station on the Euphrates. (127)","('five\r\n hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Circesium', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('127', 'CARDINAL')"
"From that peninsula to
 Trebizond, the eastern curve of the Euxine was secured by
 forts, by alliance, or by religion; and the possession of
 Lazica, the Colchos of ancient, the Mingrelia of modern,
 geography, soon became the object of an important war.","('Trebizond', 'GPE'), ('Euxine', 'LOC'), ('Lazica', 'NORP'), ('Colchos', 'NORP'), ('Mingrelia', 'NORP')"
"From the dawn of light to the moment of dinner, he assiduously laboured to enrich his master and himself at the expense of
 the Roman world; the remainder of the day was spent in sensual and obscene pleasures,  and the silent hours of  the night were interrupted by the perpetual dread of the justice of an assassin.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('the silent hours of  the night', 'TIME')"
"From the edge of the sea-shore, through the forests and valleys, and as far as the summit of the Thessalian mountains, a strong wall was continued, which occupied every practicable entrance.","('the Thessalian mountains', 'LOC')"
"From the great river to the tropic
 of Cancer, the provinces of China were subdued and civilized
 by the emperors of the North; they were filled about the
 time of the Christian aera with cities and men, mulberry-
 trees and their precious inhabitants; and if the Chinese,
 with the knowledge of the compass, had possessed the genius
 of the Greeks or Phoenicians, they might have spread their
 discoveries over the southern hemisphere.","('Cancer', 'LOC'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Phoenicians', 'NORP')"
"From these various materials, I shall now proceed to
 describe the reign of Justinian, which will deserve and
 occupy an ample space.","('Justinian', 'GPE')"
"From this capital, the
 pestilence was diffused into the provinces and cities of the
 East, and the sportive distinction of two colors produced
 two strong and irreconcilable factions, which shook the
 foundations of a feeble government.","('East', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"From this journey, however, they derived a benefit which reflects the purest lustre on the character of Chosroes.","('Chosroes', 'PERSON')"
"He
 seated her on the throne as an equal and independent
 colleague in the sovereignty of the empire, and an oath of
 allegiance was imposed on the governors of the provinces in
 the joint names of Justinian and Theodora. (29)","('Justinian', 'ORG'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('29', 'CARDINAL')"
"He checked the selfish murmurs of the treasury, applauded the confidence of his friend, discharged the legacies and debts, educated the
 three virgins under the eye of the empress Theodora, and doubled the marriage portion which had satisfied the tenderness of their father. (89)","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"He had dexterously
 chosen a subject of apparent splendour, in which he could
 loudly celebrate the genius, the magnificence, and the piety
 of a prince, who, both as a conqueror and legislator, had
 surpassed the puerile virtues of Themistocles and Cyrus. (16)","('Themistocles', 'PERSON'), ('Cyrus', 'PERSON'), ('16', 'CARDINAL')"
"He patiently expected the death of
 the empress; he despised the tears of his mother, who soon
 sunk under the weight of her affliction; and a law was
 promulgated in the name of the emperor Justin, which
 abolished the rigid jurisprudence of antiquity.","('Justin', 'PERSON')"
"He required, that the seven sages who had visited the court of Persia should be
 exempted from the penal laws which Justinian enacted against his Pagan subjects; and this privilege, expressly stipulated in a treaty of peace, was guarded by the vigilance of a powerful mediator. (155)","('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('155', 'CARDINAL')"
"Her beauty, assisted by art or accident, soon attracted, captivated, and fixed, the patrician Justinian, who already reigned with absolute sway
 under the name of his uncle.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Her chastity, from the moment of her union with Justinian, is founded on the silence of her implacable enemies; and although the daughter of Acacius might be satiated with love, yet some applause is due to the firmness of a mind which could sacrifice pleasure and habit to the stronger sense either of duty or interest.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Acacius', 'PERSON')"
"Her incomparable
 writers address themselves to the human race; the living
 masters emigrated to Italy and Asia; Berytus, in later
 times, was devoted to the study of the law; astronomy and
 physic were cultivated in the musaeum of Alexandria; but the
 Attic schools of rhetoric and philosophy maintained their
 superior reputation from the Peloponnesian war to the reign
 of Justinian.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Berytus', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('the Peloponnesian war', 'EVENT'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
Her marriage with Justinian.,"('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Her rapacious avarice to accumulate an immense
 treasure, may be excused by the apprehension of her
 husband's death, which could leave no alternative between
 ruin and the throne; and fear as well as ambition might
 exasperate Theodora against two generals, who, during the
 malady of the emperor, had rashly declared that they were
 not disposed to acquiesce in the choice of the capital.","('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Her secret apartments were occupied by the
 favorite women and eunuchs, whose interests and passions she
 indulged at the expense of justice; the most illustrious
 person ages of the state were crowded into a dark and sultry
 antechamber, and when at last, after tedious attendance,
 they were admitted to kiss the feet of Theodora, they
 experienced, as her humor might suggest, the silent
 arrogance of an empress, or the capricious levity of a
 comedian.","('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"His
 example was neglected, and his treasure was abused, by the
 nephew of Justin.","('Justin', 'PERSON')"
"His abilities, perhaps his vices, recommended him to the lasting friendship of Justinian: the emperor yielded with reluctance to the fury of the people;
 his victory was displayed by the immediate restoration of their enemy; and they felt above ten years, under his oppressive administration, that he was stimulated by revenge, rather than instructed by misfortune.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('ten years', 'DATE')"
"His addition of one seventh to the ordinary price of copper money may be interpreted with the same candour; and the alteration, which might be wise, appears to have been innocent; since he neither alloyed the purity, nor enhanced the value, of the gold coin, (87) the legal measure of public and private payments.","('one seventh', 'CARDINAL'), ('87', 'CARDINAL')"
"His elevation was prepared by the adventurous spirit of his uncle Justin, who, with two other peasants of the same village, deserted, for the profession of arms, the more useful employment of husbandmen or shepherds.","('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"His favourite architects submitted their designs and difficulties to Justinian, and discreetly confessed how much their laborious meditations were surpassed by the intuitive knowledge of celestial inspiration of an emperor, whose views were always directed to the benefit of his people, the glory of his
reign, and the salvation of his soul. (102)
Foundation of the church of St. Sophia.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('102', 'CARDINAL'), ('St. Sophia', 'GPE')"
"His ignorance was similar to that of Theodoric; and it is remarkable that in an age not destitute of learning, two contemporary monarchs had never been instructed in the knowledge of the alphabet.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"His long and laudable service in the Isaurian and Persian wars would not have preserved from oblivion the name of Justin; yet they might warrant the military promotion, which in the course of fifty years he gradually obtained; the rank of tribune, of count, and of general; the dignity of senator, and the command of the guards, who obeyed him as their chief, at the important crisis when the emperor Anastasius was removed from the world.","('Isaurian', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('fifty years', 'DATE'), ('Anastasius', 'PERSON')"
"His physical and metaphysical commentaries on Aristotle have passed away with the fashion of the times; but his moral interpretation of Epictetus is preserved in the library of nations, as a classic book, most excellently adapted to direct the will, to purify the heart, and to confirm the understanding, by a just confidence in the nature both of God and man.","('Aristotle', 'PERSON'), ('Epictetus', 'PERSON')"
"His sagacious mind explored the deepest
 questions of morals and metaphysics, and he ventured to urge
 eighteen arguments against the Christian doctrine of the
 creation of the world.","('eighteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"His successors convinced the subjects of Justinian, that the arts of oppression might still be improved by experience and industry; the frauds of a Syrian banker were introduced into the administration of the finances; and the example of the praefect was diligently copied by the quaestor, the public and private treasurer, the governors of provinces, and the principal magistrates of
the Eastern empire. (94)","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Syrian', 'NORP'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('94', 'CARDINAL')"
"His successors, A.D. 485-529.","('A.D. 485-529', 'DATE')"
"Hypatius was dragged from his throne, and conducted, with his brother Pompey, to the feet of the emperor: they implored his clemency; but their crime was manifest, their innocence uncertain, and Justinian had been too much terrified to forgive.","('Hypatius', 'PERSON'), ('Pompey', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"I am not
 insensible of the benefits of elegant luxury; yet I reflect
 with some pain, that if the importers of silk had introduced
 the art of printing, already practised by the Chinese, the
 comedies of Menander and the entire decads of Livy would
 have been perpetuated in the editions of the sixth century.","('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('Menander', 'PERSON'), ('Livy', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('the sixth century', 'DATE')"
"I am not
 qualified to examine, and I am not disposed to believe,
 their distant voyages to the Persian Gulf, or the Cape of
 Good Hope; but their ancestors might equal the labors and
 success of the present race, and the sphere of their
 navigation might extend from the Isles of Japan to the
 Straits of Malacca, the pillars, if we may apply that name,
 of an Oriental Hercules. (70)","('the Persian Gulf', 'LOC'), ('the Cape of\r\n Good Hope', 'PRODUCT'), ('the Isles of Japan', 'GPE'), ('the\r\n Straits of Malacca', 'LOC'), ('an Oriental Hercules', 'ORG'), ('70', 'CARDINAL')"
"I. In the exercise of supreme power, the first act of
 Justinian was to divide it with the woman whom he loved, the
 famous Theodora, (20) whose strange elevation cannot be
 applauded as the triumph of female virtue.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('20', 'DATE')"
"If accident or monopoly sometimes raised the value even above the standard of Aurelian, the manufacturers of Tyre and Berytus were sometimes compelled, by the operation of the same causes, to content themselves with a ninth part of that extravagant rate. (65)","('Aurelian', 'ORG'), ('Tyre', 'ORG'), ('Berytus', 'ORG'), ('ninth', 'ORDINAL'), ('65', 'CARDINAL')"
"If the creed of Theodora had not been tainted with heresy, her exemplary devotion might have atoned, in the opinion of her contemporaries, for pride, avarice, and cruelty.","('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"If the usurper, who afterwards pleaded the merit of his delay, had complied with the advice of his senate, and urged the fury of the multitude, their first irresistible effort might have oppressed or expelled his trembling competitor.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"If we extend our view from the tropic to the mouth of the
 Tanais, we may observe, on one hand, the precautions of
 Justinian to curb the savages of Aethiopia, (125) and on the
 other, the long walls which he constructed in Crimaea for
 the protection of his friendly Goths, a colony of three
 thousand shepherds and warriors. (126)","('Tanais', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Justinian', 'NORP'), ('Aethiopia', 'GPE'), ('125', 'CARDINAL'), ('Crimaea', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('three\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('126', 'CARDINAL')"
Importation from China by land and sea.,"('China', 'GPE')"
"In
 the first days of the new reign, he prompted and gratified
 the popular enthusiasm against the memory of the deceased
 emperor.","('the first days', 'DATE')"
"In
 this rigorous climate, (128) where the snows seldom melt, the
 fruits are tardy and tasteless, even honey is poisonous: the
 most industrious tillage would be confined to some pleasant
 valleys; and the pastoral tribes obtained a scanty
 sustenance from the flesh and milk of their cattle.","('128', 'CARDINAL')"
"In Constantinople alone and the adjacent suburbs, he dedicated twenty-five churches to the honour of Christ, the Virgin, and the saints: most of these
 churches were decorated with marble and gold; and their various situation was skilfully chosen in a populous square, or a pleasant grove; on the margin of the sea-shore, or on some lofty eminence which overlooked the continents of Europe and Asia.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('twenty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('Virgin', 'PERSON'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"In a lower room, Anthemius arranged several vessels or caldrons of water, each of them covered by the wide bottom of a leathern tube, which rose to a narrow top, and was artificially conveyed among the joists and rafters of the adjacent building.","('Anthemius', 'ORG')"
"In a time of scarcity, an extraordinary requisition was made
 to the adjacent provinces of Thrace, Bithynia, and Phrygia:
 but the proprietors, after a wearisome journey and perilous
 navigation, received so inadequate a compensation, that they
 would have chosen the alternative of delivering both the
 corn and price at the doors of their granaries.","('Thrace', 'GPE'), ('Bithynia', 'GPE'), ('Phrygia', 'GPE')"
"In a trifling dispute
 relative to the walls or windows of their contiguous houses, he had been vanquished by the eloquence of his neighbour Zeno; but the orator was defeated in his turn by the master of mechanics, whose malicious, though harmless, stratagems are darkly represented by the ignorance of Agathias.","('Zeno', 'PERSON'), ('Agathias', 'PERSON')"
"In an age of freedom and valor, the slightest rampart may prevent a surprise; and Procopius appears insensible of the superiority of ancient times, while he praises the solid construction and double parapet of a wall, whose long arms
 stretched on either side into the sea; but whose strength was deemed insufficient to guard the Chersonesus, if each city, and particularly Gallipoli and Sestus, had not been secured by their peculiar fortifications.","('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Chersonesus', 'NORP'), ('Gallipoli', 'GPE'), ('Sestus', 'GPE')"
"In the choice of those colours (58) which imitate the beauties of nature, the freedom of taste and fashion was indulged; but the deep purple (59)
 which the Phoenicians extracted from a shell-fish, was restrained to the sacred person and palace of the emperor; and the penalties of treason were denounced against the ambitious subjects who dared to usurp the prerogative of the throne. (60)","('58', 'CARDINAL'), ('59', 'CARDINAL'), ('Phoenicians', 'NORP')"
"In the day they concealed
 their two-edged poniards, but in the night they boldly
 assembled in arms, and in numerous bands, prepared for every
 act of violence and rapine.","('the day', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the fifth year of his reign, Justinian celebrated the festival of the ides of January; the games were incessantly disturbed by the clamorous discontent of the greens: till the twenty-second race, the emperor maintained his silent gravity; at length, yielding to his impatience, he condescended to hold, in abrupt sentences, and by the voice of a crier, the most singular dialogue (50) that ever passed between a prince and his subjects.","('the fifth year', 'DATE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('January', 'DATE'), ('twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('50', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the great
 cities of the East, the disadvantage of space, perhaps of
 position, was compensated by the zeal of the people, who
 seconded the garrison in the defence of their country and
 religion; and the fabulous promise of the Son of God, that
 Edessa should never be taken, filled the citizens with
 valiant confidence, and chilled the besiegers with doubt and
 dismay. (132)","('East', 'LOC'), ('the Son of God', 'PERSON'), ('Edessa', 'PERSON'), ('132', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the midst of a council, where Belisarius was present, Theodora alone displayed the spirit of a hero; and she alone, without apprehending his future hatred, could save the emperor from the imminent danger, and his unworthy fears.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"In the most abject state of her fortune, and reputation,
 some vision, either of sleep or of fancy, had whispered to
 Theodora the pleasing assurance that she was destined to
 become the spouse of a potent monarch.","('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"In the republics of Greece and Rome, the art of
 speaking was the powerful engine of patriotism or ambition;
 and the schools of rhetoric poured forth a colony of
 statesmen and legislators.","('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In the suburbs of the city, the academy of the
 Platonists, the lycaeum of the Peripatetics, the portico of
 the Stoics, and the garden of the Epicureans, were planted
 with trees and decorated with statues; and the philosophers,
 instead of being immured in a cloister, delivered their
 instructions in spacious and pleasant walks, which, at
 different hours, were consecrated to the exercises of the
 mind and body.","('Platonists', 'NORP'), ('Peripatetics', 'LOC'), ('Stoics', 'LOC'), ('Epicureans', 'NORP')"
"In the three succeeding chapters, I shall relate
 the wars of Justinian, which achieved the conquest of Africa
 and Italy; and I shall follow the victories of Belisarius
 and Narses, without disguising the vanity of their triumphs,
 or the hostile virtue of the Persian and Gothic heroes.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Belisarius', 'NORP'), ('Narses', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"In the vain capital of China, the Sogdian caravans were entertained as the
 suppliant embassies of tributary kingdoms, and if they
 returned in safety, the bold adventure was rewarded with
 exorbitant gain.","('China', 'GPE'), ('Sogdian', 'NORP')"
"In this
 hospitable isle, at an equal distance (as it was computed)
 from their respective countries, the silk merchants of
 China, who had collected in their voyages aloes, cloves,
 nutmeg, and sandal wood, maintained a free and beneficial
 commerce with the inhabitants of the Persian Gulf.","('China', 'GPE'), ('the Persian Gulf', 'LOC')"
"In this journey, the empress was followed by the Praetorian praefect, the great treasurer, several counts and patricians, and a splendid train of four thousand attendants: the highways were repaired at her approach; a palace was erected for her reception; and as she passed through Bithynia, she distributed liberal alms to the churches, the monasteries, and the hospitals, that they might implore Heaven for the restoration of her health. (38) and death, A.D. 548, June 11.","('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bithynia', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 548', 'DATE'), ('June 11', 'DATE')"
"In this narrow space, the disorderly and affrighted crowd was incapable of resisting on either side a firm and regular attack; the blues signalized the fury of their repentance; and it is computed, that above thirty thousand persons were slain in the merciless and promiscuous carnage of the day.","('thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('the day', 'DATE')"
"Insolent with royal favor, the blues affected to
 strike terror by a peculiar and Barbaric dress, the long
 hair of the Huns, their close sleeves and ample garments, a
 lofty step, and a sonorous voice.","('Barbaric', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"Instead of a hasty crowd of peasants, a garrison of two thousand soldiers was stationed along the rampart; granaries of corn and reservoirs of water were provided for their use; and by a precaution that inspired the cowardice which it foresaw, convenient fortresses were erected for their retreat.","('two thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
Introducion of silk-worms into Greece,"('Greece', 'GPE')"
"It is remarkable, that the impartial favor
 of the Antonines was bestowed on the four adverse sects of
 philosophy, which they considered as equally useful, or at
 least, as equally innocent.","('Antonines', 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"Its splendor was again restored by the perseverance of the same prince; and in the thirty- sixth year of his reign, Justinian celebrated the second dedication of a temple which remains, after twelve centuries, a stately monument of his fame.","('the thirty- sixth year', 'DATE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('twelve centuries', 'DATE')"
"Justin suppresses the schools of Athens
VI.","('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Athens\r\nVI', 'ORG')"
"Justinian delighted to ennoble and
 enrich the object of his affection; the treasures of the
 East were poured at her feet, and the nephew of Justin was
 determined, perhaps by religious scruples, to bestow on his
 concubine the sacred and legal character of a wife.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Justin', 'PERSON')"
"Justinian embraced a more humble expedient, and solicited
 the aid of his Christian allies, the Aethiopians of
 Abyssinia, who had recently acquired the arts of navigation,
 the spirit of trade, and the seaport of Adulis, (73)  still
 decorated with the trophies of a Grecian conqueror.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Aethiopians', 'NORP'), ('Abyssinia', 'NORP'), ('Adulis', 'PERSON'), ('73', 'CARDINAL'), ('Grecian', 'NORP')"
"Justinian reigned over sixty-four provinces, and nine hundred and thirty-five cities; (54) his dominions were blessed by nature with the advantages of soil, situation, and climate: and the improvements of human art had been perpetually diffused along the coast of the Mediterranean and the banks of the Nile from ancient Troy to the Egyptian Thebes.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('sixty-four', 'CARDINAL'), ('nine hundred and thirty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('54', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Troy', 'LOC'), ('the Egyptian Thebes', 'LOC')"
"Justinian suppressed the schools of Athens and the
 consulship of Rome, which had given so many sages and heroes
 to mankind.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Justinian was lost, if the prostitute whom he raised from the theatre had not renounced the timidity, as well as the virtues, of her sex.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Lebanon furnished her loftiest cedars for the timbers of the church; and the seasonable discovery of a vein of red marble supplied its beautiful columns, two of which, the supporters of the exterior portico, were esteemed the largest in the world.","('Lebanon', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Nature had
 interposed a vacant solitude between the ambition of two
 rival empires; the Arabians, till Mahomet arose, were
 formidable only as robbers; and in the proud security of
 peace the fortifications of Syria were neglected on the most
 vulnerable side.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabians', 'NORP'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Syria', 'GPE')"
"No sooner did the tumult subside, than the Christian populace deplored their sacrilegious rashness; but they might have rejoiced in the calamity, had they foreseen the glory of the new temple, which at the end of forty days was strenuously undertaken by the piety of Justinian. (103)","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('the end of forty days', 'DATE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('103', 'CARDINAL')"
"Not withstanding
 this reproach, the senate proceeded to decorate Justinian
 with the royal epithet of nobilissimus; and their decree was
 ratified by the affection or the fears of his uncle.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Notwithstanding
 these precautions, and his own example, the succession of
 consuls finally ceased in the thirteenth year of Justinian,
 whose despotic temper might be gratified by the silent
 extinction of a title which admonished the Romans of their
 ancient freedom. (158)","('the thirteenth year of Justinian', 'DATE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('158', 'CARDINAL')"
"Notwithstanding this disappointment, her dominion was permanent and absolute; she preserved, by art or merit, the affections of Justinian; and their seeming dissensions were always fatal to the courtiers who believed them to be sincere.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
Olympius excelled in the knowledge and practice of the Roman jurisprudence.,"('Olympius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"On a solemn
 festival, these helpless orphans were sent by their
 distressed and indignant mother, in the garb of suppliants,
 into the midst of the theatre: the green faction received
 them with contempt, the blues with compassion; and this
 difference, which sunk deep into the mind of Theodora, was
 felt long afterwards in the administration of the empire.","('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"On foot, with a scanty provision of biscuit in their knapsacks, the three youths followed the high road of Constantinople, and were soon enrolled, for their strength and stature, among the guards of the emperor Leo.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Leo', 'PERSON')"
"On the Asiatic shore of the Propontis, at a small distance to the east of Chalcedon, the costly palace and gardens of Heraeum (108) were prepared for the summer residence of Justinian, and more especially of Theodora.","('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Propontis', 'LOC'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('Heraeum', 'GPE'), ('108', 'CARDINAL'), ('Justinian', 'GPE'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"Our sense of
 the dignity of human nature is exalted by the simple
 recollection, that Isocrates (143) was the companion of Plato
 and Xenophon; that he assisted, perhaps with the historian
 Thucydides, at the first representation of the Oedipus of
 Sophocles and the Iphigenia of Euripides; and that his
 pupils Aeschines and Demosthenes contended for the crown of
 patriotism in the presence of Aristotle, the master of
 Theophrastus, who taught at Athens with the founders of the
 Stoic and Epicurean sects. (144)","('Isocrates', 'PERSON'), ('143', 'CARDINAL'), ('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('Xenophon', 'PERSON'), ('Thucydides', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the Oedipus of\r\n Sophocles and the Iphigenia of Euripides', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Aeschines', 'PERSON'), ('Demosthenes', 'PERSON'), ('Aristotle', 'PERSON'), ('Theophrastus', 'PERSON'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Stoic', 'NORP'), ('Epicurean', 'NORP'), ('144', 'CARDINAL')"
"Perhaps her health had been impaired by the licentiousness of her youth; but it was always delicate, and she was directed by her physicians to use the Pythian
 warm baths.","('Pythian', 'NORP')"
"Procopius (12) successively composed the history, the
 panegyric, and the satire of his own times.","('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('12', 'CARDINAL')"
"Procopius has not condescended to explain the system of
 taxation, which fell like a hail-storm upon the land, like a
 devouring pestilence on its inhabitants: but we should
 become the accomplices of his malignity, if we imputed to
 Justinian alone the ancient though rigorous principle, that
 a whole district should be condemned to sustain the partial
 loss of the persons or property of individuals.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Religion or interest had more power over
 the Persian monks than the love of their country: after a
 long journey, they arrived at Constantinople, imparted their
 project to the emperor, and were liberally encouraged by the
 gifts and promises of Justinian.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"Scaling-ladders were applied
 at the dawn of day; the presence of Cabades, his stern
 command, and his drawn sword, compelled the Persians to
 vanquish; and before it was sheathed, fourscore thousand of
 the inhabitants had expiated the blood of their companions.","('Cabades', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Sedition of Constantinople, surnamed Nika, A.D. 532, January.","('Sedition of Constantinople', 'ORG'), ('Nika', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 532', 'DATE'), ('January', 'DATE')"
"Seven friends and philosophers, Diogenes and
 Hermias, Eulalius and Priscian, Damascius, Isidore, and
 Simplicius, who dissented from the religion of their
 sovereign, embraced the resolution of seeking in a foreign
 land the freedom which was denied in their native country.","('Seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Diogenes', 'PERSON'), ('Hermias', 'PERSON'), ('Eulalius', 'PERSON'), ('Priscian', 'NORP'), ('Damascius', 'PERSON'), ('Isidore', 'PERSON'), ('Simplicius', 'PERSON')"
"Seven processions or spectacles were the number to which his
 edict confined the horse and chariot races, the athletic
 sports, the music, and pantomimes of the theatre, and the
 hunting of wild beasts; and small pieces of silver were
 discreetly substituted to the gold medals, which had always
 excited tumult and drunkenness, when they were scattered
 with a profuse hand among the populace.","('Seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"She neither danced, nor sung, nor played on the
 flute; her skill was confined to the pantomime arts; she
 excelled in buffoon characters, and as often as the comedian
 swelled her cheeks, and complained with a ridiculous tone
 and gesture of the blows that were inflicted, the whole
 theatre of Constantinople resounded with laughter and
 applause.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Silk was immediately delivered to the Romans by the Persian merchants, (67) who frequented the fairs of Armenia and Nisibis; but this trade, which in the intervals of truce was oppressed by avarice and jealousy, was totally interrupted by the long wars of the rival monarchies.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('67', 'CARDINAL'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Nisibis', 'GPE')"
"Simplicius and his companions ended their lives in peace and obscurity; and as they left no disciples, they terminate the long list of Grecian  philosophers, who may be justly praised, notwithstanding their defects, as the wisest and most virtuous of their contemporaries.","('Simplicius', 'PERSON'), ('Grecian', 'NORP')"
"Since the eunuch Amantius had been defrauded of his money,
 it became necessary to deprive him of his life.","('Amantius', 'PERSON')"
"Single watch-towers were changed into spacious citadels; vacant walls, which the engineers contracted or enlarged according to the nature of the ground, were filled with colonies or garrisons; a strong fortress defended the ruins of Trajan's bridge, (112) and several military stations affected to spread beyond the Danube the pride of the Roman name.","('Trajan', 'GPE'), ('112', 'CARDINAL'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Six hundred of these forts were built or repaired by the emperor; but it seems reasonable to believe, that the far greater part consisted only of a stone or brick tower, in the midst of a square or circular area, which was surrounded by a wall and ditch, and afforded in a moment of danger some protection to the peasants and cattle of the neighbouring villages.","('Six hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"So minute a description of an edifice which time has respected, may attest the truth, and excuse the relation, of the innumerable works, both in the capital and provinces, which Justinian constructed on a smaller scale and less durable foundations. (106)","('Justinian', 'GPE'), ('106', 'CARDINAL')"
"Socrates had formerly been the
 glory and the reproach of his country; and the first lessons
 of Epicurus so strangely scandalized the pious ears of the
 Athenians, that by his exile, and that of his antagonists,
 they silenced all vain disputes concerning the nature of the
 gods.","('Socrates', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Epicurus', 'PERSON'), ('Athenians', 'NORP')"
"Such a character has
 been justly accused by the voice of the people and of
 posterity: but public discontent is credulous; private
 malice is bold; and a lover of truth will peruse with a
 suspicious eye the instructive anecdotes of Procopius.","('Procopius', 'PERSON')"
"Such base inconsistency must
 doubtless sully the reputation, and detract from the credit,
 of Procopius: yet, after the venom of his malignity has been
 suffered to exhale, the residue of the anecdotes, even the
 most disgraceful facts, some of which had been tenderly
 hinted in his public history, are established by their
 internal evidence, or the authentic monuments of the times.
 (19)","('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('19', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such folly was disdained
 and indulged by the wisest princes; but the names of
 Caligula, Nero, Vitellius, Verus, Commodus, Caracalla, and
 Elagabalus, were enrolled in the blue or green factions of
 the circus; At Rome.","('Caligula', 'PERSON'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Vitellius', 'PERSON'), ('Verus', 'NORP'), ('Commodus', 'NORP'), ('Caracalla', 'NORP'), ('Elagabalus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Such imperfect revenge could not satisfy the unrelenting hatred of Theodora; the murder of his old enemy, the bishop of Cyzicus, afforded a decent pretence; and John of Cappadocia, whose actions had deserved a thousand deaths, was at last condemned for a crime of which he was innocent.","('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('Cyzicus', 'GPE'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE'), ('a thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such is the language of the secret historian, who expressly denies that
 any indulgence was granted to Palestine after the revolt of the Samaritans; a false and odious charge, confuted by the authentic record which attests a relief of thirteen centenaries of gold (fifty-two thousand pounds) obtained for that desolate province by the intercession of St. Sabas. (85)
 III.","('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('Samaritans', 'NORP'), ('thirteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifty-two thousand pounds)', 'QUANTITY'), ('St. Sabas', 'GPE'), ('85', 'CARDINAL')"
"Ten, twenty, forty
 chariots were allowed to start at the same instant; a crown
 of leaves was the reward of the victor; and his fame, with
 that of his family and country, was chanted in lyric strains
 more durable than monuments of brass and marble.","('Ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('forty', 'CARDINAL')"
"That Gothic chief had rendered himself popular
 by the civil war which he boldly waged against Anastasius
 for the defence of the orthodox faith, and after the
 conclusion of an advantageous treaty, he still remained in
 the neighborhood of Constantinople at the head of a
 formidable and victorious army of Barbarians.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Anastasius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"That empire, after Rome was barbarous, still embraced the nations whom she had conquered beyond the Adriatic, and as far as the frontiers of Aethiopia and Persia.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC'), ('Aethiopia', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'LOC')"
"That rare and elegant luxury was censured, in the reign of Tiberius, by the
 gravest of the Romans; and Pliny, in affected though forcible language, has condemned the thirst of gain, which explores the last confines of the earth, for the pernicious purpose of exposing to the public eye naked draperies and
 transparent matrons. (63)","('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Pliny', 'PERSON'), ('63', 'CARDINAL')"
"That sacred retirement was seldom disturbed
 by the business of trade or government; and the last of the
 Athenians were distinguished by their lively wit, the purity
 of their taste and language, their social manners, and some
 traces, at least in discourse, of the magnanimity of their
 fathers.","('Athenians', 'NORP')"
"That venerable name seemed to
 qualify its members to declare the sense of the nation, and
 to regulate the succession of the Imperial throne: the
 feeble Anastasius had permitted the vigor of government to
 degenerate into the form or substance of an aristocracy; and
 the military officers who had obtained the senatorial rank
 were followed by their domestic guards, a band of veterans,
 whose arms or acclamations might fix in a tumultuous moment
 the diadem of the East.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Anastasius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The
  Chalybians (129) derived their name and temper from the iron quality of the soil; and, since the days of Cyrus, they
 might produce, under the various appellations of Cha daeans
 and Zanians, an uninterrupted prescription of war and
 rapine.","('Chalybians', 'PERSON'), ('129', 'CARDINAL'), ('Cyrus', 'PERSON'), ('Zanians', 'NORP')"
"The
 Catholics were attached to the nephew of Justin, who,
 between the Nestorian and Eutychian heresies, trod the
 narrow path of inflexible and intolerant orthodoxy. (10)","('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Nestorian', 'NORP'), ('Eutychian', 'NORP')"
"The
 civil and military officers, when they were admitted into
 the service of the palace, obtained an humble rank and a
 moderate stipend; they ascended by seniority to a station of
 affluence and repose; the annual pensions, of which the most
 honorable class was abolished by Justinian, amounted to four
 hundred thousand pounds; and this domestic economy was
 deplored by the venal or indigent courtiers as the last
 outrage on the majesty of the empire.","('Justinian', 'ORG'), ('four\r\n hundred thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"The
 disappointment of the philosophers provoked them to overlook
 the real virtues of the Persians; and they were scandalized,
 more deeply perhaps than became their profession, with the
 plurality of wives and concubines, the incestuous marriages,
 and the custom of exposing dead bodies to the dogs and
 vultures, instead of hiding them in the earth, or consuming
 them with fire.","('Persians', 'NORP')"
"The
 emperor refused, at the return of each fifth year, the
 customary donative of five pieces of gold, reduced his
 veterans to beg their bread, and suffered unpaid armies to
 melt away in the wars of Italy and Persia.","('each fifth year', 'DATE'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"The
 gospel had been preached to the Indians: a bishop already
 governed the Christians of St. Thomas on the pepper-coast of
 Malabar; a church was planted in Ceylon, and the
 missionaries pursued the footsteps of commerce to the
 extremities of Asia. (74)","('Indians', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('St. Thomas', 'GPE'), ('Malabar', 'GPE'), ('Ceylon', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('74', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 satirical historian has not blushed (23) to describe the
 naked scenes which Theodora was not ashamed to exhibit in
 the theatre. (24)","('23', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('24', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 secret historian represents only the vices of Justinian, and
 those vices are darkened by his malevolent pencil.","('Justinian', 'NORP')"
"The
 series of this and the following volume will embrace the
 jurisprudence and theology of the emperor; the controversies
 and sects which still divide the Oriental church; the
 reformation of the Roman law which is obeyed or respected by
 the nations of modern Europe.","('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"The
 subjects of the great king exalted, without a rival, his
 power and magnificence: and the Roman, who confounded their
 vanity by comparing his paltry coin with a gold medal of the
 emperor Anastasius, had sailed to Ceylon, in an Aethiopian
 ship, as a simple passenger. (72)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Anastasius', 'PERSON'), ('Ceylon', 'GPE'), ('Aethiopian', 'NORP'), ('72', 'CARDINAL')"
"The  imperfect mode of distinguishing each year by the name of a  magistrate, was usefully supplied by the date of a permanent aera: the creation of the world, according to the Septuagint
 version, was adopted by the Greeks; (160) and the Latins,
 since the age of Charlemagne, have computed their time from
 the birth of Christ. (161)","('Septuagint', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('160', 'CARDINAL'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('161', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Albanian and Iberian
 gates excluded the horsemen of Scythia from the shortest and
 most practicable roads, and the whole front of the mountains
 was covered by the rampart of Gog and Magog, the long wall
 which has excited the curiosity of an Arabian caliph (140)  and a Russian conqueror. (141)","('Albanian', 'NORP'), ('Iberian', 'NORP'), ('Scythia', 'GPE'), ('Gog', 'PERSON'), ('Magog', 'PERSON'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('140', 'CARDINAL'), ('Russian', 'NORP'), ('141', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Anona,
 or supply of corn for the use of the army and capital, was a
 grievous and arbitrary exaction, which exceeded, perhaps in
 a tenfold proportion, the ability of the farmer; and his
 distress was aggravated by the partial injustice of weights
 and measures, and the expense and labor of distant carriage.","('Anona', 'PRODUCT')"
"The Athenian
 professors were paid by their disciples: according to their
 mutual wants and abilities, the price appears to have
 varied; and Isocrates himself, who derides the avarice of
 the sophists, required, in his school of rhetoric, about
 thirty pounds from each of his hundred pupils.","('Athenian', 'NORP'), ('Isocrates', 'PERSON'), ('about\r\n thirty pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Byzantine palace enjoyed a free
 communication with the sea; vessels lay ready at the garden stairs; and a secret resolution was already formed, to convey the emperor with his family and treasures to a safe retreat, at some distance from the capital.","('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"The Byzantine palace, which had been damaged by the conflagration, was restored with new magnificence; and some notion may be conceived of the whole edifice, by the
 vestibule or hall, which, from the doors perhaps, or the roof, was surnamed chalce, or the brazen.","('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
The Caspian or Iberian gates.,"('Caspian', 'LOC'), ('Iberian', 'NORP')"
"The Eastern
 world fell prostrate before the genius and fortune of the
 daughter of Acacius.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Acacius', 'PERSON')"
The Empress Theodora.,"('The Empress Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"The Gothic arms were less fatal to the schools of Athens
 than the establishment of a new religion, whose ministers
 superseded the exercise of reason, resolved every question
 by an article of faith, and condemned the infidel or sceptic
 to eternal flames.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Athens', 'GPE')"
"The Iberian gates (139)  are formed by a narrow
 passage of six miles in Mount Caucasus, which opens from the
 northern side of Iberia, or Georgia, into the plain that
 reaches to the Tanais and the Volga.","('Iberian', 'NORP'), ('139', 'CARDINAL'), ('six miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Mount Caucasus', 'LOC'), ('Iberia', 'LOC'), ('Georgia', 'GPE'), ('Tanais', 'GPE'), ('Volga', 'LOC')"
"The Isaurians retired to their mountains; their fortresses were successively besieged and ruined; their communication with the sea was intercepted; the bravest of their leaders died in arms; the surviving chiefs, before their execution, were dragged in chains through the hippodrome; a colony of their
 youth was transplanted into Thrace, and the remnant of the people submitted to the Roman government.","('Isaurians', 'NORP'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Latin conquerors respectfully listened
 to the instructions of their subjects and captives; the
 names of Cicero and Horace were enrolled in the schools of
 Athens; and after the perfect settlement of the Roman
 empire, the natives of Italy, of Africa, and of Britain,
 conversed in the groves of the academy with their
 fellow-students of the East.","('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Cicero', 'PERSON'), ('Horace', 'PERSON'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The Olympic stadium was open
 to wealth, merit, and ambition; and if the candidates could
 depend on their personal skill and activity, they might
 pursue the footsteps of Diomede and Menelaus, and conduct
 their own horses in the rapid career. (41)","('Olympic', 'EVENT'), ('Diomede', 'PERSON'), ('Menelaus', 'PERSON'), ('41', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Persian monarch held in his hand the keys
 both of peace and war; but he stipulated, in every treaty,
 that Justinian should contribute to the expense of a common
 barrier, which equally protected the two empires from the
 inroads of the Scythians. (142)","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Scythians', 'NORP'), ('142', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Persian war, A.D. 502-505.","('The Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('502-505', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Persians  were twice circumvented, in
 a situation which made valor useless and flight impossible;
 and the double victory of the Huns was achieved by military
 stratagem.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"The Roman consulship extinguished by Justinian, A.D. 541.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 541', 'DATE')"
"The Straits of Thermopylae, which seemed to protect, but which had so often betrayed, the safety of Greece, were diligently strengthened by the labours of Justinian.","('The Straits of Thermopylae', 'LOC'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"The Virgin of Jerusalem might exult in the temple erected by her Imperial votary on a most ungrateful spot, which afforded neither ground nor materials to the architect.","('The Virgin of Jerusalem', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"The aerial tribute, without a name, a law, or a definite object, was an annual gift of one
 hundred and twenty thousand pounds, which the emperor
 accepted from his Praetorian praefect; and the means of
 payment were abandoned to the discretion of that powerful
 magistrate.","('one\r\n hundred and twenty thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('Praetorian', 'PERSON')"
"The altar itself, a name which insensibly became familiar to Christian ears, was placed in the eastern recess, artificially built in the form of a demi-cylinder; and this sanctuary communicated by several doors with the sacristy, the vestry, the baptistery, and the
contiguous buildings, subservient either to the pomp of worship, or the private use of the ecclesiastical ministers.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The annual powers of vegetation,
 instead of being exhausted by two thousand harvests, were renewed and invigorated by skilful husbandry, rich manure, and seasonable repose.","('two thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The architecture of St. Sophia, which is now converted into the principal mosch, has been imitated by the Turkish sultans, and that venerable pile continues to excite the fond admiration of the Greeks, and the more rational curiosity of European travellers.","('St. Sophia', 'LOC'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('European', 'NORP')"
"The balustrade of the choir, the capitals of the pillars, the ornaments of the doors and galleries, were of gilt bronze; the spectator was dazzled by the glittering aspect of the cupola; the sanctuary contained forty thousand pounds weight of silver; and the holy vases and vestments of the altar were of the purest gold, enriched with inestimable gems.","('forty thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"The beauty of Theodora (22) was the subject of
 more flattering praise, and the source of more exquisite
 delight.","('Theodora', 'PERSON'), ('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"The bloody and tumultuous contest
 continued to disturb the public festivity, till the last age
 of the spectacles of Rome; and Theodoric, from a motive of
 justice or affection, interposed his authority to protect
 the greens against the violence of a consul and a patrician,
 who were passionately addicted to the blue faction of the
 circus. (43)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('43', 'CARDINAL')"
"The church of the Holy Apostles at Constantinople, and that of St. John at Ephesus, appear to have been framed on the same model: their domes aspired to imitate the cupolas of St. Sophia; but the altar was more judiciously placed under the centre of the dome, at the junction of four stately porticos, which more accurately expressed the figure of the Greek cross.","('the Holy Apostles at Constantinople', 'ORG'), ('St. John', 'GPE'), ('Ephesus', 'GPE'), ('St. Sophia', 'LOC'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"The circle which encompasses the dome, lightly reposes on four strong arches, and their weight is firmly supported by four massy piles, whose strength is assisted, on the northern and southern sides, by four columns of Egyptian granite.","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP')"
"The city was surrounded with two walls, and the interval
 between them, of fifty paces, afforded a retreat to the
 cattle of the besieged.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifty', 'CARDINAL')"
"The conflagration involved the
 cathedral of St. Sophia, the baths of Zeuxippus, a part of the palace, from the first entrance to the altar of Mars, and the long portico from the palace to the forum of Constantine: a large hospital, with the sick patients, was
 consumed; many churches and stately edifices were destroyed and an immense treasure of gold and silver was either melted or lost.","('St. Sophia', 'FAC'), ('Zeuxippus', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Mars', 'LOC'), ('Constantine', 'GPE')"
"The conscious dignity of independence
 was subdued by the hopes and fears of a slave; and the
 secretary of Belisarius labored for pardon and reward in the
 six books of the Imperial edifices.","('Belisarius', 'ORG'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The death of Perozes abandoned Persia to her foreign and
 domestic enemies; !! and twelve years of confusion elapsed  before his son Cabades, or Kobad, could embrace any designs
 of ambition or revenge.","('Perozes', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('twelve years', 'DATE'), ('Cabades', 'PERSON'), ('Kobad', 'PERSON')"
"The direct interval between Sumatra
 and Ceylon is about three hundred leagues: the Chinese and
 Indian navigators were conducted by the flight of birds and
 periodical winds; and the ocean might be securely traversed
 in square-built ships, which, instead of iron, were sewed
 together with the strong thread of the cocoanut.","('Sumatra', 'GPE'), ('Ceylon', 'GPE'), ('about three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('Indian', 'NORP')"
"The dissolute youth of Constantinople adopted the blue
 livery of disorder; the laws were silent, and the bonds of
 society were relaxed: creditors were compelled to resign
 their obligations; judges to reverse their sentence; masters
 to enfranchise their slaves; fathers to supply the
 extravagance of their children; noble matrons were
 prostituted to the lust of their servants; beautiful boys
 were torn from the arms of their parents; and wives, unless
 they preferred a voluntary death, were ravished in the
 presence of their husbands. (47)","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
The distress of Justinian.,"('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"The dome of St. Sophia, illuminated by four-and-twenty windows, is formed with so small a curve, that the depth is equal only to one sixth of its diameter; the measure of that diameter is one hundred and fifteen feet, and the lofty centre, where a crescent has supplanted the cross, rises to the perpendicular height of one hundred and eighty feet above the pavement.","('St. Sophia', 'FAC'), ('four-and-twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('one sixth', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred and fifteen feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('one hundred and eighty feet', 'QUANTITY')"
