Sentence,Entities
(176),"('176', 'CARDINAL')"
(179),"('179', 'CARDINAL')"
(2),"('2', 'CARDINAL')"
"(3) A crowd of temples and of votive altars, 
 profusely scattered along its steep and woody banks,
 attested the unskilfulness, the terrors, and the devotion of
 the Grecian navigators who, after the example of the
 Argonauts, explored the dangers of the inhospitable Euxine.","('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('Argonauts', 'LOC'), ('Euxine', 'NORP')"
(45),"('45', 'CARDINAL')"
(51),"('51', 'CARDINAL')"
(54),"('54', 'CARDINAL')"
(6),"('6', 'CARDINAL')"
"1. For the preservation of peace and order, the governors of the provinces were armed with the sword of
 justice.","('1', 'CARDINAL')"
"1. The
 praefect of the East stretched his ample jurisdiction into
 the three parts of the globe which were subject to the
 Romans, from the cataracts of the Nile to the banks of the
 Phasis, and from the mountains of Thrace to the frontiers of
 Persia.","('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Phasis', 'LOC'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Persia', 'LOC')"
"2. As it was reasonably apprehended that the integrity of the judge might be biased, if his interest was concerned or his affections were engaged, the strictest regulations were established to exclude any person, without the special dispensation of the emperor, from the government of the province where he was born, (116) and to prohibit the governor or his son from  contracting marriage with a native or an inhabitant, (117) or 
 from purchasing slaves, lands, or houses within the extent of his jurisdiction.","('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('116', 'CARDINAL'), ('117', 'CARDINAL')"
"2. The important provinces of Pannonia, Dacia,
 Macedonia, and Greece once acknowledged the authority of the
 praefect of Illyricum.","('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pannonia', 'GPE'), ('Dacia', 'GPE'), ('Macedonia', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Illyricum', 'ORG')"
2. The principal administration of public affairs was committed to the diligence and abilities of the master of the 0ffices. (145),"('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('145', 'CARDINAL')"
"3. The power of the praefect of
 Italy was not confined to the country from whence he derived
 his title; it extended over the additional territory of
 Rhaetia as far as the banks of the Danube, over the
 dependent islands of the Mediterranean, and over that part
 of the continent of Africa which lies between the confines
 of Cyrene and those of Tingitania.","('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Rhaetia', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Cyrene', 'LOC'), ('Tingitania', 'GPE')"
"4. The praefect of the
 Gauls comprehended under that plural denomination the
 kindred provinces of Britain and Spain, and his authority
 was obeyed from the wall of Antoninus to the foot of Mount
 Atlas. (99)","('4', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Antoninus', 'GPE'), ('Mount\r\n Atlas', 'LOC'), ('99', 'CARDINAL')"
5.,"('5', 'CARDINAL')"
"6, 7. The chosen bands of cavalry and infantry, which guarded the person of the emperor, were under the immediate command of the two counts of the domestics.","('6', 'CARDINAL'), ('7', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"A faithful subject, of Syria
 perhaps, or of Britain, was exposed to the danger, or at
 least to the dread, of being dragged in chains to the court
 of Milan or Constantinople, to defend his life and fortune
 against the malicious charge of these privileged informers.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"A few years afterwards these gigantic bodies were
 shrunk to a very diminutive size; and when seven legions,
 with some auxiliaries, defended the city of Amida against
 the Persians, the total garrison, with the inhabitants of
 both sexes, and the peasants of the deserted country, did
 not exceed the number of twenty thousand persons. (132)","('A few years afterwards', 'DATE'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Amida', 'GPE'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('132', 'CARDINAL')"
"A gold belt was the
 ensign which distinguished the office of the counts and
 dukes; and, besides their pay, they received a liberal
 allowance sufficient to maintain one hundred and ninety
 servants and one hundred and fifty-eight horses.","('one hundred and ninety', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred and fifty-eight', 'CARDINAL')"
"A just 
 analogy would seem to countenance the opinion of an
 ingenious historian,  (188) that the free and tributary 
 citizens did not surpass the number of half a million; and
 if, in the ordinary administration of government, their
 annual payments may be computed at about four millions and a
 half of our money, it would appear that, although the share
 of each individual was four times as considerable, a fourth
 part only of the modern taxes of France was levied on the
 Imperial province of Gaul.","('188', 'CARDINAL'), ('half a million', 'CARDINAL'), ('annual', 'DATE'), ('about four millions and a\r\n half', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"A moderate proportion between these 
 opposite extremes of extraordinary oppression and of
 transient indulgence may therefore be fixed at sixteen
 pieces of gold, or about nine pounds sterling, the common
 standard, perhaps, of the impositions of Gaul. (181)","('sixteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('about nine pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('181', 'CARDINAL')"
"A more particular 
 enumeration, drawn from the Notitia, might exercise the
 diligence of an antiquary; but the historian will content
 himself with observing that the number of permanent stations
 or garrisons established on the frontiers of the empire
 amounted to five hundred and eighty-three; and that, under
 the successors of Constantine, the complete force of
 military establishment was computed at six hundred and
 forty-five thousand soldiers.","('Notitia', 'PERSON'), ('five hundred and eighty-three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('six hundred and\r\n forty-five thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"A multitude 
 of labourers and artificers urged the conclusion of the work
 with incessant toil; but the impatience of Constantine soon
 discovered that, in the decline of the arts, the skill as
 well as numbers of his architects bore a very unequal
 proportion to the greatness of his designs.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"A nation of
 legislators and conquerors might assert their claim to the
 harvests of Africa, which had been purchased with their
 blood; and it was artfully contrived by Augustus, that, in
 the enjoyment of plenty, the Romans should lose the memory
 of freedom.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"A particular description composed about a century after its foundation, enumerates a capitol or school
 of learning, a circus, two theatres, eight public and one
 hundred and fifty-three private baths, fifty-two porticoes,
 five granaries, eight aqueducts or reservoirs of water, four
 spacious halls for the meetings of the senate or courts of
 justice, fourteen churches, fourteen palaces, and four
 thousand three hundred and eighty-eight houses which, for
 their size or beauty, deserved to be distinguished from the
 multitude of plebeian habitations. (52)
Population","('about a century', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('one\r\n hundred and fifty-three', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifty-two', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('fourteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('fourteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('four\r\n thousand three hundred and eighty-eight', 'CARDINAL')"
"A perfect
 equality was established between the dignity of the two
 municipal and that of the four Praetorian praefects. (109)","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('109', 'CARDINAL')"
"A sea contracted 
 within such narrow limit may seem but ill to deserve the
 singular epithet of broad, which Homer, as well as Orpheus,
 has frequently bestowed on the Hellespont.","('Homer', 'PERSON'), ('Orpheus', 'PERSON'), ('Hellespont', 'PRODUCT')"
"A third and more numerous class of
 inhabitants will insensibly be formed, of servants, of
 artificers, and of merchants, who derive their subsistence
 from their own labour, and from the wants or luxury of the
 superior ranks.","('third', 'ORDINAL')"
A.D. 324,"('A.D. 324', 'DATE')"
A.D. 330 or 334.,"('330', 'CARDINAL'), ('334', 'CARDINAL')"
"About
 thirty years after the foundation of Constantinople a
 similar magistrate was created in that rising metropolis,
 for the same uses and with the same powers.","('About\r\n thirty years', 'DATE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"About 
 a century after the death of the founder, the new buildings,
 extending on one side up the harbour, and on the other along
 the Propontis, already covered the narrow ridge of the sixth
 and the broad summit of the seventh hill.","('About \r\n a century', 'DATE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Propontis', 'FAC'), ('sixth', 'ORDINAL'), ('seventh', 'ORDINAL')"
"About the same time that Constantine gave a
 legal sanction to the ecclesiastical order, he instituted in
 the Roman empire the nice balance of the civil and the
 military powers.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"According to the different nature of
 lands, their real produce in the various articles of wine or
 oil, corn or barley, wood or iron, was transported by the
 labour or at the expense of the provincials to the Imperial
 magazines, from whence they were occasionally distributed,
 for the use of the court, of the army, and of the two
 capitals, Rome and Constantinople.","('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"According to the new division of Italy, the fertile
 and happy province of Campania, the scene of the early
 victories and of the delicious retirements of the citizens
 of Rome, extended between the sea and the Apennine from the
 Tiber to the Silarus.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Campania', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Apennine', 'LOC'), ('Tiber', 'LOC'), ('Silarus', 'LOC')"
"According to the plan of government instituted by
 Diocletian, the four princes had each their Praetorian
 praefect; and after the monarchy was once more united in the
 person of Constantine, he still continued to create the same
 number of FOUR PRAEFECTS, and intrusted to their care the
 same provinces which they already administered.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('FOUR', 'CARDINAL')"
"After Ajax had fallen a sacrifice to his
 disappointed pride and to the ingratitude of the Greeks, his
 sepulchre was created on the ground where he had defended
 the navy against the rage of Jove and Hector; and the
 citizens of the rising town of Rhoeteum celebrated his
 memory with divine honours. (20)","('Ajax', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Jove', 'PERSON'), ('Hector', 'PERSON'), ('Rhoeteum', 'GPE'), ('20', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a
 regular course of education, which lasted five years, the
 students dispersed themselves through the provinces in
 search of fortune and honours; nor could they want an
 inexhaustible supply of business in a great empire already
 corrupted by the multiplicity of laws, of arts, and of
 vices.","('five years', 'DATE')"
"After a tranquil and prosperous reign the conqueror bequeathed to his family the inheritance of the Roman empire; a new capital, a new policy, and a new religion; and the innovations which he established have been embraced and consecrated by succeeding generations.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"After the Praetorian praefects had been dismissed from all
 military command, the civil functions which they were
 ordained to exercise over so many subject nations were
 adequate to the ambition and abilities of the most
 consummate ministers.","('Praetorian', 'NORP')"
"After the defeat and abdication of Licinius his victorious
 rival proceeded to lay the foundations of a city destined to
 reign in future times the mistress of the East, and to
 survive the empire and religion of Constantine.","('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"After the office of Roman consuls
 had been changed into a vain pageant, which was rarely
 displayed in the capital, the praefects assumed their vacant
 place in the senate, and were soon acknowledged as the
 ordinary presidents of that venerable assembly.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"After the use of these internal garrisons had
 ceased with the civil war, the conqueror wanted either
 wisdom or firmness to revive the severe discipline of
 Diocletian, and to suppress a fatal indulgence which habit
 had endeared and almost confirmed to the military order.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"All the magistrates of sufficient importance to find a place
 in the general state of the empire were accurately divided
 into three classes - 1, The Illustrious; 2, The
 Spectabiles, or Respectable; and, 3, The Clarissimi,
 whom we may translate by the word Honourable.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Illustrious', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Spectabiles', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Clarissimi', 'PERSON')"
"All these provincial generals
 were therefore dukes; but no more than ten among them were
 dignified with the rank of counts or companions, a title
 of honour, or rather of favour, which had been recently
 invented in the court of Constantine.","('more than ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"An accurate census,
  (174) or survey, was the only equitable mode of ascertaining 
 the proportion which every citizen should be obliged to
 contribute for the public service; and from the well-known
 period of the indictions, there is reason to believe that
 this difficult and expensive operation was repeated at the
 regular distance of fifteen years.","('174', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifteen years', 'DATE')"
"And not a vestige was left of that severe
 simplicity which, in the ages of freedom and victory, had
 distinguished the line of battle of a Roman army from the
 confused host of an Asiatic monarch. (134)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('134', 'CARDINAL')"
"As
 the safety of the emperor was avowedly preferred to every
 consideration of justice or humanity, the dignity of age and
 the tenderness of youth were alike exposed to the most cruel
 tortures; and the terrors of a malicious information, which
 might select them as the accomplices, or even as the
 witnesses, perhaps, of an imaginary crime, perpetually hung
 over the heads of the principal citizens of the Roman world.
  (168)
Finances","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('168', 'CARDINAL')"
"As Constantine urged the progress of the work with the
 impatience of a lover, the walls, the porticoes, and the
 principal edifices were completed in a few years, or,
 according to another account, in a few months: (64) but this 
 extraordinary diligence should excite the less admiration,
 since many of the buildings were finished in so hasty and
 imperfect a manner, that, under the succeeding reign, they
 were preserved with difficulty from impending ruin. (65)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('a few years', 'DATE'), ('a few months', 'DATE'), ('64', 'CARDINAL')"
"As long as the Roman consuls were the first magistrates
 of a free state, they derived their right to power from the
 choice of the people.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"As long as they maintained their ancient
 establishment of six thousand men, they subsisted, under the
 reign of Diocletian, each of them singly, a visible and
 important object in the military history of the Roman
 empire.","('six thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"As often as the
 birthday of the city returned, the statue of Constantine,
 framed by his order, of gilt wood, and bearing in its right
 hand a small image of the genius of the place, was erected
 on a triumphal car.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as the consuls had discharged 
 these customary duties, they were at liberty to retire into
 the shade of private life, and to enjoy during the remainder
 of the year the undisturbed contemplation of their own
 greatness.","('the year', 'DATE')"
"As the
 vicissitudes of tides are scarcely felt in those seas, the
 constant depth of the harbour allows goods to be landed on
 the quays without the assistance of boats; and it has been
 observed that, in many places, the largest vessels may rest
 their prows against the houses while their sterns are
 floating in the water. (12)","('12', 'CARDINAL')"
"As the footsteps of the barbarians had not yet
 been seen in Italy, the cause of this amazing desolation,
 which is recorded in the laws, can be ascribed only to the
 administration of the Roman emperors. (178)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('178', 'CARDINAL')"
"As the immediate representatives of the Imperial majesty,
 they were empowered to explain, to enforce, and on some
 occasions to modify, the general edicts by their
 discretionary proclamations.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"As the orations which he composed in the name of the emperor (150) acquired the force, and at length the form, of absolute edicts, he was considered as the representative of the legislative power, the oracle of the council, and the original source of the civil jurisprudence.","('150', 'CARDINAL')"
"As the sense of 
 liberty became less exquisite, the advantages of order were
 more clearly understood; and the praefect, who seemed to
 have been designed as a terror only to slaves and vagrants,
 was permitted to extend his civil and criminal jurisdiction
 over the equestrian and noble families of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"As this general tax upon industry was collected
 every fourth year, it was styled the Lustral Contribution:
 and the historian Zosimus (190) laments that the approach of 
 the fatal period was announced by the tears and terrors of
 the citizens, who were often compelled by the impending
 scourge to embrace the most abhorred and unnatural methods
 of procuring the sum at which their poverty had been
 assessed.","('every fourth year', 'DATE'), ('the Lustral Contribution', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Zosimus', 'PERSON'), ('190', 'CARDINAL')"
"At a small distance 
 from the old castles we discover the little town of
 Chrysopolis, or Scutari, which may almost be considered as
 the Asiatic suburb of Constantinople.","('Chrysopolis', 'GPE'), ('Scutari', 'GPE'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"At the festival of the dedication, an 
 edict, engraved on a column of marble, bestowed the title of
 SECOND or NEW ROME on the city of Constantine. (68)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('68', 'CARDINAL')"
"Barbarians are urged by their love
 of war; the citizens of a free republic may be prompted by a
 principle of duty; the subjects, or at least the nobles, of
 a monarchy are animated by a sentiment of honour; but the
 timid and luxurious inhabitants of a declining empire must
 be allured into the service by the hopes of profit, or
 compelled by the dread of punishment.","('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"Before Constantine gave a 
 just preference to the situation of Byzantium, he had
 conceived the design of erecting the seat of empire on this
 celebrated spot, from whence the Romans derived their
 fabulous origin.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantium', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Besides the magistrates and generals, who at a distance
 from the court diffused their delegated authority over the
 provinces and armies, the emperor conferred the rank of
 Illustrious on seven of his more immediate servants, to
 whose fidelity he intrusted his safety, or his counsels, or
 his treasures.","('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"But 
 these were not the valuable inhabitants: the plains that
 stretch from the foot of Mount Argaeus to the banks of the
 Sarus bred a generous race of horses, renowned above all
 others in the ancient world for their majestic shape and
 incomparable swiftness.","('Mount Argaeus', 'LOC'), ('Sarus', 'LOC')"
"But 
 when the passages of the straits were thrown open for trade,
 they alternately admitted the natural and artificial riches
 of the north and south, of the Euxine and of the
 Mediterranean.","('Euxine', 'LOC'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC')"
"But a fatal maxim was introduced into the new 
 jurisprudence of the empire, that in the case of treason,
 which included every offence that the subtlety of lawyers
 could derive from an hostile intention towards the prince or
 republic, (167) all privileges were suspended, and all 
 conditions were reduced to the same ignominious level.","('167', 'CARDINAL')"
"But as some decent mixture of prodigy and fable
 has, in every age, been supposed to reflect a becoming
 majesty on the origin of great cities, (25) the emperor was 
 desirous of ascribing his resolution not so much to the
 uncertain counsels of human policy as to the infallible and
 eternal decrees of divine wisdom.","('25', 'CARDINAL')"
"But as the account between the monarch and the subject was
 perpetually open, and as the renewal of the demand
 anticipated the perfect discharge of the preceding
 obligation, the weighty machine of the finances was moved by
 the same hands round the circle of its yearly revolution.","('yearly', 'DATE')"
"But it is
 not in the city of Constantine, nor in the declining period
 of an empire, when the human mind was depressed by civil and
 religious slavery, that we should seek for the souls of
 Homer and of Demosthenes.","('Constantine', 'GPE'), ('Homer', 'PERSON'), ('Demosthenes', 'PERSON')"
"But it should be
 recollected that the second of those appellations is only a
 corruption of the Latin word which was indiscriminately
 applied to any military chief.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE')"
"But our ideas of
 greatness are of a relative nature: the traveller, and
 especially the poet, who sailed along the Hellespont, who
 pursued the windings of the stream, and contemplated the
 rural scenery, which appeared on every side to terminate the
 prospect, insensibly lost the remembrance of the sea; and
 his fancy painted those celebrated straits with all the
 attributes of a mighty river, flowing with a swift current,
 in the midst of a woody and inland country, and at length,
 through a wide mouth, discharging itself into the Aegean or
 Archipelago. (18) Ancient Troy, (19) seated on an eminence at 
 the foot of Mount Ida, overlooked the mouth of the
 Hellespont, which scarcely received an accession of waters
 from the tribute of those immortal rivulets the Simois and
 Scamander.","('Hellespont', 'NORP'), ('Aegean', 'LOC'), ('Archipelago', 'LOC'), ('18', 'CARDINAL'), ('Troy', 'PERSON'), ('19', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mount Ida', 'LOC'), ('Hellespont', 'GPE'), ('Simois', 'PERSON'), ('Scamander', 'PERSON')"
"But the civil 
 government of the empire was distributed into thirteen great
 DIOCESES, each of which equalled the just measure of a
 powerful kingdom.","('thirteen', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the far greater part
 of the lands of ancient Gaul, as well as of the other
 provinces of the Roman world, were cultivated by slaves, or
 by peasants, whose dependent condition was a less rigid
 servitude. (184)","('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But the name of Constantinople (69) has prevailed over that honourable epithet, and after the revolution of fourteen centuries
 still perpetuates the fame of its author. (70)","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('69', 'CARDINAL'), ('fourteen centuries', 'DATE'), ('70', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the narrowest part of the channel is found to the
 northward of the old Turkish castles, between the cities of
 Sestus and Abydus.","('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Sestus', 'GPE'), ('Abydus', 'GPE')"
"But the prodigality of Constantine could not be
 excused by any consideration either of public or private
 interest; and the annual tribute of corn imposed upon Egypt
 for the benefit of his new capital was applied to feed a
 lazy and insolent populace, at the expense of the husbandmen
 of an industrious province. (59)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('59', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the suburbs of Pera and Galata, though situate 
 beyond the harbour, may deserve to be considered as a part
 of the city; (35) and this addition may perhaps authorise the 
 measure of a Byzantine historian, who assigns sixteen Greek
 (about fourteen Roman) miles for the circumference of his
 native city. (36)","('Pera', 'GPE'), ('Galata', 'GPE'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('sixteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('fourteen Roman) miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('36', 'CARDINAL')"
"But their spirit was
 degraded by the humiliating reflection that they, who were
 exposed to the hardships and dangers of a perpetual warfare,
 were rewarded only with about two-thirds of the pay and
 emoluments which were lavished on the troops of the court.","('about two-thirds', 'CARDINAL')"
"But these 
 artificial supplies (in which the reigning house was always
 included) were rapidly swept away by the rage of tyrants, by
 frequent revolutions, by the change of manners, and by the
 intermixture of nations. (97)","('97', 'CARDINAL')"
"But these distinctions, so incompatible
 with the spirit of a free people, were removed, after a long
 struggle, by the persevering efforts of the Tribunes.","('Tribunes', 'ORG')"
"But this
 reflection, which would tend to alleviate the miseries of
 despotism, is contradicted at least by the history of the
 Roman empire; which accuses the same princes of despoiling
 the senate of its authority, and the provinces of their
 wealth.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But this 
 calculation, or rather indeed the facts from whence it is
 deduced, cannot fail of suggesting two difficulties to a
 thinking mind, who will be at once surprised by the equality
 and by the enormity of the capitation.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"But when they lost 
 even the semblance of those virtues which were derived from
 their ancient freedom, the simplicity of Roman manners was
 insensibly corrupted by the stately affectation of the
 courts of Asia.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"By a philosophic observer the system of the Roman government might have been mistaken for a splendid theatre, filled with players of every character and degree, who repeated the language, and imitated the passions, of their original model. (76)","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"By his commands the cities of
 Greece and Asia were despoiled of their most valuable
 ornaments. (42)","('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"Careless of fame and of justice, they
 are described for the most part as ignorant and rapacious
 guides, who conducted their clients through a maze of
 expense, of delay, and of disappointment from whence, after
 a tedious series of years, they were at length dismissed,
 when their patience and fortune were almost exhausted.","('years', 'DATE')"
"During the late operations of the war against Licinius he
 had sufficient opportunity to contemplate, both as a soldier
 and as a statesman, Situation of Byzantium the incomparable position of Byzantium;
 and to observe how strongly it was guarded by nature against
 an hostile attack, whilst it was accessible on every side to
 the benefits of commercial intercourse.","('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantium', 'GPE'), ('Byzantium', 'GPE')"
"During the siege of Byzantium the conqueror had pitched his
 tent on the commanding eminence of the second hill.","('Byzantium', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"During the vigour
 of his age Constantine, according to the various exigencies
 of peace and war, moved with slow dignity or with active
 diligence along the frontiers of his extensive dominions;
 and was always prepared to take the field either against a
 foreign or a domestic enemy.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Each of these was directed by an inferior master of  respectable dignity, and the whole business was despatched by an hundred and forty-eight secretaries, chosen for the most part from the profession of the law, on account of the variety of abstracts of reports and references which frequently occurred in the exercise of their several functions.","('an hundred and forty-eight', 'CARDINAL')"
"Foundation of Constantinople — 
Political System of Constantine and His Successors —Military Discipline —The Palace —Finances","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"From a condescension which in former ages would have been deemed unworthy of the Roman majesty, a particular secretary was allowed for the Greek language; and
 interpreters were appointed to receive the ambassadors of the barbarians; but the department of foreign affairs, which constitutes so essential a part of modern policy, seldom diverted the attention of the master of the offices.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'LANGUAGE')"
"From all the inferior
 jurisdictions an appeal in every matter of importance,
 either civil or criminal, might be brought before the
 tribunal of the praefect: but his sentence was final and
 absolute; and the emperors themselves refused to admit any
 complaints against the judgment or the integrity of a
 magistrate whom they honoured with such unbounded
 confidence. (100)","('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the Cyanean rocks to the point and harbour of 
 Byzantium the winding length of the Bosphorus extends about
 sixteen miles, (7) and its most ordinary breadth may be 
 computed at about one mile and a half.","('Cyanean', 'NORP'), ('Byzantium', 'GPE'), ('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('about\r\n sixteen miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('7)', 'QUANTITY'), ('about one mile and a half', 'QUANTITY')"
"From the eastern promontory to the golden gate, the 
 extreme length of Constantinople was about three Roman
 miles, (33) the circumference measured between ten and eleven, 
 and the surface might be computed as equal to about two
 thousand English acres.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('three Roman\r\n miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('33', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten and eleven', 'CARDINAL'), ('about two\r\n thousand English acres', 'QUANTITY')"
"From the mouth of the Lycus to 
 that of the harbour this arm of the Bosphorus is more than
 seven miles in length.","('Lycus', 'LOC'), ('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('more than\r\n seven miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"From the reign of Constantine a popular and even legal
 distinction was admitted between the Palatines (129) and the Borderers; the troops of the court, as they were
 improperly styled, and the troops of the frontier.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Palatines', 'PERSON'), ('129', 'CARDINAL'), ('Borderers', 'ORG')"
"From the reign of Diocletian even these vestiges of
 liberty were abolished, and the successful candidates, who
 were invested with the annual honours of the consulship,
 affected to deplore the humiliating condition of their
 predecessors.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"From the reign of Severus
 to that of Diocletian, the guards and the palace, the laws
 and the finances, the armies and the provinces, were
 intrusted to their superintending care; and, like the vizirs
 of the East, they held with one hand the seal, and with the
 other the standard, of the empire.","('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the seven schools 
 two companies of horse and foot were selected, of the protectors, whose advantageous station was the hope and reward of the most deserving soldiers.","('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the throne, whence the emperor viewed the Circensian games a winding staircase (49) descended to the palace, a magnificent edifice, which scarcely yielded to the residence of Rome itself, and which, together with the dependent courts, gardens, and porticoes, covered a considerable extent of ground upon the banks of the Propontis, between the Hippodrome and the church of St. Sophia. (50)","('Circensian', 'NORP'), ('49', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Propontis', 'ORG'), ('Hippodrome', 'FAC'), ('St. Sophia', 'GPE'), ('50', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the time of Commodus to
 the reign of Constantine near one hundred governors might be
 enumerated, who, with various success, erected the standard
 of revolt; and though the innocent were too often
 sacrificed, the guilty might be sometimes prevented, by the
 suspicious cruelty of their master. (126)","('Commodus', 'EVENT'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('one hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"From their superior importance and dignity, 
 Rome and Constantinople were alone excepted from the
 jurisdiction of the Praetorian praefects.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP')"
"From this fact, and from similar examples, there is reason to
 believe that the constitution of the legionary troops, to
 which they partly owed their valour and discipline, was
 dissolved by Constantine; and that the bands of Roman
 infantry, which still assumed the same names and the same
 honours, consisted only of one thousand or fifteen hundred
 men. (133)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('one thousand or fifteen hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('133', 'CARDINAL')"
"He bestowed
 on his favourites the palaces which he had built in the
 several quarters of the city, assigned them lands and
 pensions for the support of their dignity, (55) and alienated 
 the demesnes of Pontus and Asia to grant hereditary estates
 by the easy tenure of maintaining a house in the capital. (56)","('the\r\n several quarters', 'DATE'), ('Pontus', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"He divided Constantinople into fourteen
 regions or quarters, (60) dignified the public council with 
 the appellation of senate, (61) communicated to the citizens 
 the privileges of Italy, (62) and bestowed on the rising city 
 the title of Colony, the first and most favoured daughter of
 ancient Rome.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('fourteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Colony', 'EVENT'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"He was sometimes invited to take his seat in the supreme judicature of the Imperial consistory, with the Praetorian praefects and the master of the offices; and he was frequently requested to resolve the doubts of inferior judges: but as he was not oppressed with a variety of subordinate business, his leisure and talents were employed to cultivate that dignified style of eloquence which, in the corruption of taste and language, still preserves the majesty of the Roman laws.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"He will adopt the division unknown to the ancients of civil and ecclesiastical affairs: the victory of  the Christians and their intestine discord, will supply copious and distinct materials both for edification and for scandal.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"His appointments were suitable to his 
 dignity; (101) and, if avarice was his ruling passion, he 
 enjoyed frequent opportunities of collecting a rich harvest
 of fees, of presents, and of perquisites.","('101', 'CARDINAL')"
"His duty was to attend the emperor in his hours
 of state or in those of amusement, and to perform about his
 person all those menial services which can only derive their
 splendour from the influence of royalty.","('hours', 'TIME')"
"If we survey Byzantium in the extent which it acquired with
 the august name of Constantinople, the figure of the
 Imperial city may be represented under that of an unequal
 triangle.","('Byzantium', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Imperial city', 'GPE')"
"In a poetical request, addressed to
 one of the last and most deserving of the Roman princes who
 reigned in Gaul, Sidonius Apollinaris personifies his
 tribute under the figure of a triple monster, the Geryon of
 the Grecian fables, and entreats the new Hercules that he
 would most graciously be pleased to save his life by cutting
 off three of his heads. (182)","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Sidonius Apollinaris', 'PERSON'), ('Geryon', 'PERSON'), ('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('Hercules', 'PRODUCT'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('182', 'CARDINAL')"
"In less than a century Constantinople
 disputed with Rome itself the pre-eminence of riches and
 numbers.","('less than a century', 'DATE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In one of his laws he has
 been careful to instruct posterity that, in obedience to the
 commands of God, he laid the everlasting foundations of
 Constantinople; (26) and though he has not condescended to 
 relate in what manner the celestial inspiration was
 communicated to his mind, the defect of his modest silence
 has been liberally supplied by the ingenuity of succeeding
 writers, who describe the nocturnal vision which appeared to
 the fancy of Constantine as he slept within the walls of
 Byzantium.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('26', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantium', 'LOC')"
"In some respects the office of the Imperial quaestor may be compared with that of a modern chancellor; but the use of a great seal, which seems to have been adopted by the illiterate barbarians, was never introduced to attest the public acts of the emperors.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"In the 
 course of this history such exaggerations will be reduced to
 their just value; yet since the growth of Constantinople
 cannot be ascribed to the general increase of mankind and of
 industry, it must be admitted that this artificial colony
 was raised at the expense of the ancient cities of the
 empire.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"In the 
 discharge of his laborious employment the governor of Rome
 was assisted by fifteen officers, some of whom had been
 originally his equals, or even his superiors.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('fifteen', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the actual state of the city, the palace and gardens of
 the Seraglio occupy the eastern promontory, the first of the
 seven hills, and cover about one hundred and fifty acres of
 our own measure.","('Seraglio', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('about one hundred and fifty acres', 'QUANTITY')"
"In the choice
 of an advantageous situation he preferred the confines of
 Europe and Asia; to curb with a powerful arm the barbarians
 who dwelt between the Danube and the Tanais; to watch with
 an eye of jealousy the conduct of the Persian monarch, who
 indignantly supported the yoke of an ignominious treaty.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Tanais', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
In the course of nine centuries the office of quaestor had experienced a very singular revolution.,"('nine centuries', 'DATE')"
"In the dark
 ages which succeeded the translation of the empire, the
 remote and the immediate consequences of that memorable
 event were strangely confounded by the vanity of the Greeks
 and the credulity of the Latins.  (53)","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('53', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the epistles which the 
 emperor addressed to the two consuls elect, it was declared
 that they were created by his sole authority. (82)","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the infancy of Rome, two inferior magistrates were annually elected by the people, to relieve the consuls from the invidious management of the public treasure; (146) a similar assistant was granted to every proconsul and to every praetor who exercised a military or provincial command; with the extent of conquest, the two quaestors were gradually multiplied to the number of four, of eight, of twenty, and
 for a short time, perhaps, of forty; (147) and the noblest citizens ambitiously solicited an office which gave them a seat in the senate, and a just hope of obtaining the honours of the republic.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('146', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('forty', 'CARDINAL'), ('147', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the primitive
 simplicity of small communities this method may be well
 adapted to collect the almost voluntary offerings of the
 people; but it is at once susceptible of the utmost latitude
 and of the utmost strictness, which in a corrupt and
 absolute monarchy must introduce a perpetual contest between
 the power of oppression and the arts of fraud. (177)","('177', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the pursuit of any remarkable
 institution, we may be frequently led into the more early or
 the more recent times of the Roman history; but the proper
 limits of this inquiry will be included within a period of
 about one hundred and thirty years, from the accession of
 Constantine to the publication of the Theodosian code; (71) 
 from which, as well as from the Notitia of the East and
 West, (72) we derive the most copious and authentic 
 information of the state of the empire.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('a period of\r\n about one hundred and thirty years', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosian', 'NORP'), ('71', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('72', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the system of policy introduced by Augustus, the
 governors, those at least of the Imperial provinces, were
 invested with the full powers of the sovereign himself.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"In the time of Constantine the territory of the Aedui
 afforded no more than twenty-five thousand heads of
 capitation, of whom seven thousand were discharged by that
 prince from the intolerable weight of tribute. (187)","('Constantine', 'GPE'), ('Aedui', 'GPE'), ('no more than twenty-five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('187', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the times
 of Roman simplicity, the last-mentioned epithet was used
 only as a vague expression of deference, till it became at
 length the peculiar and appropriated title of all who were
 members of the senate, (77) and consequently of all who, from that venerable body, were selected to govern the provinces.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('77', 'DATE')"
"In the two capitals of the empire 
 the annual games of the theatre, the circus, and the
 amphitheatre (90) cost four thousand pounds of gold, (about) 
 one hundred and sixty thousand pounds sterling; and if so
 heavy an expense surpassed the faculties or the inclination
 of the magistrates themselves, the sum was supplied from the
 Imperial treasury.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('90', 'CARDINAL'), ('four thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('one hundred and sixty thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"In this class the proconsuls
 of Asia, Achaia, and Africa claimed a pre-eminence, which
 was yielded to the remembrance of their ancient dignity; and
 the appeal from their tribunal to that of the praefects was
 almost the only mark of their dependence.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Achaia', 'LOC'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
Increase of Barbarian auxillaries,"('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
"It is impossible to justify the vain
 and credulous exaggerations of modern travellers, who have
 sometimes stretched the limits of Constantinople over the
 adjacent villages of the European and even of the Asiatic
 coast. (34)","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('34', 'CARDINAL')"
"It may be
 sufficient for the historian to select two singular and
 salutary provisions, intended to restrain the abuse of
 authority.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"It may be added that the lieutenant-generals of the
 Roman armies, the military counts and dukes, who will be
 hereafter mentioned, were allowed the rank and title of
 Respectable.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It may be sufficient to observe that whatever could adorn the dignity of a great capital, or contribute to the benefit or pleasure of its numerous inhabitants, was contained within the walls of Constantinople.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"It may likewise be considered that exile, considerable fines, or the choice of an easy death, relate more particularly to the rich and the
 noble; and the persons the most exposed to the avarice or resentment of a provincial magistrate were thus removed from his obscure persecution to the more august and impartial tribunal of the Praetorian praefect.","('Praetorian', 'PERSON')"
"It was
 communicated only, Four divisions of office","('Four', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was an ancient custom that the allies of
 the republic, who ascribed their safety or deliverance to
 the success of the Roman arms, and even the cities of Italy,
 who admired the virtues of their victorious general, adorned
 the pomp of his triumph by their voluntary gifts of crowns
 of gold, which, after the ceremony, were consecrated in the
 temple of Jupiter, to remain a lasting monument of his glory
 to future ages.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Jupiter', 'LOC')"
"It was asserted and 
 believed that all the noble families of Rome, the senate,
 and the equestrian order, with their innumerable attendants,
 had followed their emperor to the banks of the Propontis;
 that a spurious race of strangers and plebeians was left to
 possess the solitude of the ancient capital; and that the
 lands of Italy, long since converted into gardens, were at
 once deprived of cultivation and inhabitants.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Propontis', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"It was here likewise, in a place where the 
 distance between the opposite banks cannot exceed five
 hundred paces, that Xerxes imposed a stupendous bridge of
 boats, for the purpose of transporting into Europe a hundred
 and seventy myriads of barbarians. (17)","('five\r\n hundred paces', 'QUANTITY'), ('Xerxes', 'PERSON'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('a hundred\r\n and seventy', 'CARDINAL'), ('17', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was here that the adventurous Leander
 braved the passage of the flood for the possession of his
 mistress.","('Leander', 'PERSON')"
"It was in vain that Constantine repeated the most
 dreadful menaces of fire and sword against the Borderers who
 should dare to desert their colours, to connive at the
 inroads of the barbarians, or to participate in the spoil.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Borderers', 'NORP')"
"It was of bronze, had been transported
 either from Athens or from a town of Phrygia, and was
 supposed to be the work of Phidias.","('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Phrygia', 'GPE'), ('Phidias', 'GPE')"
"Little more was left when 
 Constantine ascended the throne than a vague and imperfect
 tradition that the Patricians had once been the first of the
 Romans.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Patricians', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Many ages before
 Constantine, one of the most judicious historians of
 antiquity (1) had described the advantages of a situation from 
 whence a feeble colony of Greeks derived the command of the
 sea, and the honours of a flourishing and independent
 republic.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"Many opulent senators of Rome and of the eastern
 provinces were probably invited by Constantine to adopt for
 their country the fortunate spot which he had chosen for his
 own residence.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Ministers of peace and war, the distribution of rewards and
 punishments depended on them alone, and they successively
 appeared on their tribunal in the robes of civil magistracy,
 and in complete armour at the head of the Roman legions. (125)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('125', 'CARDINAL')"
"Notwithstanding these rigorous  precautions, the emperor Constantine, after a reign of
 twenty-five years still deplores the venal and oppressive administration of justice, and expresses the warmest indignation that the audience of the judge, his despatch of business, his seasonable delays, and his final sentence, were publicly sold, either by himself or by the officers of his court.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('twenty-five years', 'DATE')"
"Of these, three were governed by
 proconsuls, thirty-seven by consulars, five by
 correctors, and seventy-one by presidents.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirty-seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('seventy-one', 'CARDINAL')"
"On the morning of the first of 
 January the consuls assumed the ensigns of their dignity.","('the morning of the first of \r\n January', 'DATE')"
"On the summit of the pillar, above one 
 hundred and twenty feet from the ground, stood the colossal
 statue of Apollo.","('one \r\n hundred and twenty feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('Apollo', 'PRODUCT')"
"On these banks tradition long preserved the memory of the
 palace of Phineus, infested by the obscene harpies; (4) and of 
 the sylvan reign of Amycus, who defied the son of Leda to
 the combat of the Cestus. (5)","('Phineus', 'GPE'), ('4', 'CARDINAL'), ('Amycus', 'PERSON'), ('Leda', 'PERSON'), ('Cestus', 'PERSON'), ('5', 'CARDINAL')"
"On this 
 solemn occasion they were attended by the most eminent
 officers of the state and army in the habit of senators; and
 the useless fasces, armed with the once formidable axes,
 were borne before them by the lictors. (86)","('86', 'CARDINAL')"
"Rome was
 insensibly confounded with the dependent kingdoms which had
 once acknowledged her supremacy; and the country of the
 Caesars was viewed with cold indifference by a martial
 prince, born in the neighbourhood of the Danube, educated in
 the courts and armies of Asia, and invested with the purple
 by the legions of Britain.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Caesars', 'PERSON'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"Seven millions of these, in the capacity 
 of fathers, or brothers, or husbands, may discharge the
 obligations of the remaining multitude of women and
 children; yet the equal proportion of each tributary subject
 will scarcely rise above fifty shillings of our money,
 instead of a proportion almost four times as considerable,
 which was regularly imposed on their Gallic ancestors.","('Seven millions', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifty shillings', 'MONEY'), ('almost four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gallic', 'NORP')"
Seven ministers of the palace.,"('Seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"Situated in the forty-first degree of latitude,
 the Imperial city commanded, from her seven hills, (22) the 
 opposite shores of Europe and Asia; the climate was healthy
 and temperate, the soil fertile, the harbour secure and
 capacious, and the approach on the side of the continent was
 of small extent and easy defence.","('forty-first', 'DATE'), ('Imperial city', 'GPE'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('22', 'CARDINAL'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"Some estimate may be formed of the expense
 bestowed with Imperial liberality on the foundation of
 Constantinople by the allowance of about two millions five
 hundred thousand pounds for the construction of the walls,
 the porticoes, and the aqueducts. (39)","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('about two millions five\r\n hundred thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('39', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such an extent may seem not unworthy of an 
 Imperial residence.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"Such was the horror for the profession of a 
 soldier which had affected the minds of the degenerate
 Romans that many of the youth of Italy and the provinces
 chose to cut off the fingers of their right hand to escape
 from being pressed into the service; and this strange
 expedient was so commonly practised as to deserve the severe
 animadversion of the laws, (139) and a peculiar name in the 
 Latin language. (140)","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('140', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such, indeed, might be the theory of the Roman
 capitation; but, in the practice, this unjust equality was
 no longer felt, as the tribute was collected on the
 principle of a real, not of a personal imposition.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"THE unfortunate Licinius was the last rival who opposed the greatness, and the last captive who adorned the triumph, of Constantine.","('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The
 cruel treatment of the insolvent debtors of the state is
 attested, and was perhaps mitigated, by a very humane edict
 of Constantine, who, disclaiming the use of racks and of
 scourges, allots a spacious and airy prison for the place of
 their confinement. (191)","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The
 execution of these laws (which it would be tedious to pursue
 in their minute and intricate detail) consisted of two
 distinct operations: the resolving the general imposition
 into its constituent parts, which were assessed on the
 provinces, the cities, and the individuals of the Roman
 world; and the collecting the separate contributions of the
 individuals, the cities, and the provinces, till the
 accumulated sums were poured into the Imperial treasuries.","('minute', 'TIME'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The
 humane policy of his successor reduced the capitation to
 seven pieces. (180)","('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('180', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 most active and successful of the Plebeians accumulated
 wealth, aspired to honours, deserved triumphs, contracted
 alliances, and, after some generations, assumed the pride of
 ancient nobility.","('Plebeians', 'NORP')"
"The
 numbers of slaves and cattle constituted an essential part
 of the report; an oath was administered to the proprietors
 which bound them to disclose the true state of the affairs;
 and their attempts to prevaricate, or elude the intention of
 the legislator, were severely watched, and punished as a
 capital crime, which included the double guilt of treason
 and sacrilege. (175)","('175', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 praetors, annually created as the judges of law and equity,
 could not long dispute the possession of the Forum with a
 vigorous and permanent magistrate who was usually admitted
 into the confidence of the prince.","('Forum', 'ORG')"
"The
 reason of this difference may be found, not so much in the
 relative scarcity or plenty of gold and silver, as in the
 different state of society in ancient Gaul and in modern
 France.","('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('France', 'GPE')"
"The
 seacoasts of Thrace and Bithynia, which languish under the
 weight of Turkish oppression, still exhibit a rich prospect
 of vineyards, of gardens, and of plentiful harvests; and the
 Propontis has ever been renowned for an inexhaustible store
 of the most exquisite fish, that are taken in their stated
 seasons, without skill, and almost without labour. (23)","('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Bithynia', 'LOC'), ('Turkish', 'NORP')"
"The
 splendid and popular class was composed of the advocates,
 who filled the Forum with the sound of their turgid and
 loquacious rhetoric.","('Forum', 'ORG')"
"The
 taxes of France cannot be magnified, either by fear or by
 flattery, beyond the annual amount of eighteen millions
 sterling, which ought, perhaps to be shared among four-and-twenty millions
 of inhabitants. (183)","('France', 'GPE'), ('eighteen millions\r\n sterling', 'MONEY'), ('four-and-twenty millions', 'CARDINAL'), ('183', 'CARDINAL')"
"The 
 agriculture of the Roman provinces was insensibly ruined,
 and, in the progress of despotism, which tends to disappoint
 its own purpose, the emperors were obliged to derive some
 merit from the forgiveness of debts, or the remission of
 tributes, which their subjects were utterly incapable of
 paying.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The 
 buildings of the new city were executed by such artificers
 as the reign of Constantine could afford; but they were
 decorated by the hands of the most celebrated masters of the
 age of Pericles and Alexander.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Pericles', 'PERSON'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON')"
"The 
 emperor subscribed with his own hand, and in purple ink, the
 solemn edict, or indiction, which was fixed up in the
 principal city of each diocese during two months previous to
 the first day of September.","('two months', 'DATE'), ('the first day of September', 'DATE')"
"The 
 epithet of golden was expressive of the riches which every
 wind wafted from the most distant countries into the secure
 and capacious port of Constantinople.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The 
 place of Augustal praefect of Egypt was no longer filled
 by a Roman knight, but the name was retained; and the
 extraordinary powers which the situation of the country and
 the temper of the inhabitants had once made indispensable
 were still continued to the governor.","('Augustal', 'NORP'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Aedui, one of the most powerful and civilised tribes or
 cities of Gaul, occupied an extent of territory which now
 contains above five hundred thousand inhabitants, in the two
 ecclesiastical dioceses of Autun and Nevers; (185) and with 
 the probable accession of those of Chalons and Macon, (186) 
 the population would amount to eight hundred thousand souls.","('Aedui', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('five hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Autun', 'GPE'), ('Nevers', 'GPE'), ('185', 'CARDINAL'), ('Chalons', 'GPE'), ('Macon', 'GPE'), ('186', 'CARDINAL'), ('eight hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
The Bosphorus,"('Bosphorus', 'LOC')"
"The Bosphorus and the
 Hellespont may be considered as the two gates of
 Constantinople, and the prince who possessed those important
 passages could always shut them against a naval enemy and
 open them to the fleets of commerce.","('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Hellespont', 'PRODUCT'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The Bosphorus, as it
 begins to open into the Propontis, passes between Byzantium
 and Chalcedon.","('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Propontis', 'PRODUCT'), ('Byzantium', 'GPE'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE')"
"The Circus, or Hippodrome, was a stately building about four hundred paces in length, and one hundred in breadth. (47)","('Circus', 'FAC'), ('Hippodrome', 'FAC'), ('about four hundred paces', 'QUANTITY'), ('one hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Grecian camp had stretched twelve miles along
 the shore, from the Sigean to the Rhoetean promontory; and
 the flanks of the army were guarded by the bravest chiefs
 who fought under the banners of Agamemnon.","('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('twelve miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Sigean', 'LOC'), ('the Rhoetean promontory', 'LOC'), ('Agamemnon', 'PERSON')"
The Hellespont,"('Hellespont', 'PERSON')"
"The Imperial
 estates were scattered through the provinces from Mauritania
 to Britain; but the rich and fertile soil of Cappadocia
 tempted the monarch to acquire in that country his fairest
 possessions, (154) and either Constantine or his successors 
 embraced the occasion of justifying avarice by religious
 zeal.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Mauritania', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE'), ('154', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The Italians, who had received
 Constantine as their deliverer, submissively obeyed the
 edicts which he sometimes condescended to address to the
 senate and people of Rome; but they were seldom honoured
 with the presence of their new sovereign.","('Italians', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The Patrician families, on the other 
 hand, whose original number was never recruited till the end
 of the commonwealth, either failed in the ordinary course of
 nature, or were extinguished in so many foreign and domestic
 wars, or, through a want of merit or fortune, insensibly
 mingled with the mass of the people. (95)","('Patrician', 'NORP'), ('95', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Propontis 
Between the Bosphorus and the Hellespont, the shores of
 Europe and Asia receding on either side inclose the Sea of
 Marmora, which was known to the ancients by the denomination
 of Propontis.","('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Hellespont', 'LOC'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('the Sea of\r\n Marmora', 'LOC'), ('Propontis', 'ORG')"
"The Scipios and the Catos had been reduced to
 solicit the votes of plebians, to pass through the tedious
 and expensive forms of a popular election, and to expose
 their dignity to the shame of a public refusal; while their
 own happier fate had reserved them for an age and government
 in which the rewards of virtue were assigned by the unerring
 wisdom of a gracious sovereign.","('Scipios', 'PERSON'), ('Catos', 'PERSON')"
"The accomplished citizens of the Greek and
 Roman republics, whose characters could adapt themselves to
 the bar, the senate, to the camp, or the schools, had
 learned to write, to speak, and to act with the same spirit,
 and with equal abilities.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The acquiescence of the 
 provincials encouraged their governors to acquire, or
 perhaps to usurp, a discretionary power of employing the
 rack, to extort from vagrants or plebeian criminals the
 confession of their guilt, till they insensibly proceeded to
 confound the distinctions of rank, and to disregard the
 privileges of Roman citizens.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The actual
 account employed several hundred persons, distributed into eleven different offices, which were artfully contrived to examine and control their respective operations.","('several hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('eleven', 'CARDINAL')"
"The age of the great Constantine and his sons is filled with important events; but the historian must be oppressed by their number and variety, unless he diligently separates from each other the scenes which are connected only by the order of time.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The ambition of the
 praefects, always formidable, and sometimes fatal to the
 masters whom they served, was supported by the strength of
 the Praetorian bands; but, after those haughty troops had
 been weakened by Diocletian and finally suppressed by
 Constantine, the praefects, who survived their fall, were
 reduced without difficulty to the station of useful and
 obedient ministers.","('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The annals of tyranny, from the 
 reign of Tiberius to that of Domitian, circumstantially
 relate the executions of many innocent victims; but, as long
 as the faintest remembrance was kept alive of the national
 freedom and honour, the last hours of a Roman were secure
 from the danger of ignominious torture.","('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON'), ('the last hours', 'TIME'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The artist had represented the god of day, or, as it was afterwards interpreted, the emperor Constantine himself, with a sceptre in his right hand, the globe of the world in his left, and a crown of rays glittering on his head. (46)","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The basis of the triangle is opposed to
 the west, and terminates the continent of Europe.","('Europe', 'LOC')"
"The beauty of the Hippodrome has been long since  defaced by the rude hands of the Turkish conquerors, but, under the similar appellation of Atmeidan, it still serves as a place of exercise for their horses.","('Hippodrome', 'FAC'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Atmeidan', 'GPE')"
"The camps and the palace of the son of Constantine
 were governed by the powerful faction of the Franks, who
 preserved the strictest connection with each other and with
 their country, and who resented every personal affront as a
 national indignity.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"The celebrated Institutes of Justinian are
 addressed to the youth of his dominions who had devoted
 themselves to the study of Roman jurisprudence; and the
 sovereign condescends to animate their diligence by the
 assurance that their skill and ability would in time be
 rewarded by an adequate share in the government of the
 republic. (120)","('Institutes of Justinian', 'ORG'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('120', 'CARDINAL')"
"The chain of fortifications which Diocletian and his colleagues had extended along the banks of the great rivers
 was no longer maintained with the same care, or defended
 with the same vigilance.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
The chamberlain 1.,"('1', 'CARDINAL')"
"The codicils or patents of their office were  curiously emblazoned with such emblems as were best adapted to explain its nature and high dignity — the image or portrait of the reigning emperors; a triumphal car; the book of mandates placed on a table, covered with a rich carpet, and illuminated by four tapers; the allegorical figures of the provinces which they governed; or the appellations and standards of the troops whom they commanded.","('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"The coin, the highways, the posts, the granaries, the
 manufactures, whatever could interest the public prosperity,
 was moderated by the authority of the Praetorian praefects.","('Praetorian', 'NORP')"
"The conspiracy of so many separate detachments, 
 each of which was awed by the sense of its own weakness,
 could easily be checked; and the successors of Constantine
 might indulge their love of ostentation, by issuing their
 orders to one hundred and thirty-two legions, inscribed on
 the muster-roll of their numerous armies.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('one hundred and thirty-two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The continuance, and perhaps the impunity, of these crimes is attested by the repetition of impotent laws and ineffectual menaces. (119)","('119', 'CARDINAL')"
"The correspondence between the prince and his subjects was managed by the four scrinia, or offices of
 this minister of state.","('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"The counts of the domestics had succeeded to the office of the Praetorian praefects; like the praefects, they aspired from the service of the palace to the command of armies.","('Praetorian', 'NORP')"
"The court of the Praetorian praefect of the East
 could alone furnish employment for one hundred and fifty
 advocates, sixty-four of whom were distinguished by peculiar
 privileges, and two were annually chosen with a salary of
 sixty pounds of gold to defend the causes of the treasury.","('Praetorian', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('one hundred and fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('sixty-four', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('sixty pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"The day
 which gave birth to a city or colony was celebrated by the
 Romans with such ceremonies as had been ordained by a
 generous superstition; (28) and though Constantine might omit 
 some rites which savoured too strongly of their Pagan
 origin, yet he was anxious to leave a deep impression of
 hope and respect on the minds of the spectators.","('The day', 'DATE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('28', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Pagan', 'NORP')"
"The deceitful and dangerous experiment of the criminal
 question, as it is emphatically styled, was admitted,
 rather than approved, in the jurisprudence of the Romans.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The degenerate grandsons of Theodosius, who
 were invisible to their subjects, and contemptible to their
 enemies, exalted the praefects of their bed-chamber above
 the heads of all the ministers of the palace; (143) and even 
 his deputy, the first of the splendid train of slaves who
 waited in the presence, was thought worthy to rank before the respectable proconsuls of Greece or Asia.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('143', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The demesnes of Cappadocia were important enough 
 to require the inspection of a count, (157) officers of an inferior rank were stationed in the other parts of the empire; and the deputies of the private, as well as those of the public treasurer, were maintained in the exercise of
 their independent functions, and encouraged to control the authority of the provincial magistrates. (158)","('Cappadocia', 'GPE'), ('157', 'CARDINAL'), ('158', 'CARDINAL')"
"The difficulty of
 allowing an annual sum of about nine pounds sterling, even
 for the average of the capitation of Gaul, may be rendered
 more evident by the comparison of the present state of the
 same country, as it is now governed by the absolute monarch
 of an industrious, wealthy, and affectionate people.","('about nine pounds', 'MONEY'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The distinct view of the complicated system
 of policy introduced by Diocletian, improved by Constantine,
 and completed by his immediate successors, may not only
 amuse the fancy by the singular picture of a great empire,
 but will tend to illustrate the secret and internal causes
 of its rapid decay.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The divided administration, which had been
 formed by Constantine, relaxed the vigour of the state,
 while it secured the tranquillity of the monarch.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The eleven remaining
 dioceses - of Asiana, Pontica, and Thrace; of Macedonia,
 Dacia, and Pannonia, or Western Illyricum; of Italy and
 Africa; of Gaul, Spain, and Britain - were governed by
 twelve vicars or vice-praefects, (112) whose name sufficiently explains the nature and dependence of their
 office.","('eleven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Asiana', 'GPE'), ('Pontica', 'GPE'), ('Thrace', 'GPE'), ('Macedonia', 'GPE'), ('Dacia', 'GPE'), ('Pannonia', 'GPE'), ('Western Illyricum', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('112', 'CARDINAL')"
"The emperors themselves who
 disdained the faint shadow of the republic, were conscious
 that they acquired an additional splendour and majesty as
 often as they assumed the annual honours of the consular
 dignity. (92)","('92', 'CARDINAL')"
"The emulation, and sometimes the discord,
 which reigned between two professions of opposite interests
 and incompatible manners, was productive of beneficial and
 of pernicious consequences.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The entrance is about five hundred
 yards broad, and a strong chain could be occasionally drawn
 across it to guard the port and city from the attack of an
 hostile navy.","('about five hundred\r\n yards', 'QUANTITY')"
"The exactions of Constantius may
 be calculated at seven millions sterling, which were reduced
 to two millions by the humanity or the wisdom of Julian.","('Constantius', 'ORG'), ('seven millions sterling', 'MONEY'), ('two millions', 'CARDINAL'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The extensive plain which lies below
 ancient Troy, towards the Rhoetean promontory and the tomb
 of Ajax, was first chosen for his new capital; and, though
 the undertaking was soon relinquished, the stately remains
 of unfinished walls and towers attracted the notice of all
 who sailed through the straits of the Hellespont. (21)
Advantages of Constantinople","('Troy', 'LOC'), ('the Rhoetean promontory', 'LOC'), ('Ajax', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Hellespont', 'GPE'), ('21', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The first experiment was made of their judicial talents by
 appointing them to act occasionally as assessors to the
 magistrates; from thence they were often raised to preside
 in the tribunals before which they had pleaded.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The first of
 those promontories was occupied by Achilles with his
 invincible myrmidons, and the dauntless Ajax pitched his
 tents on the other.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Achilles', 'PERSON'), ('Ajax', 'PRODUCT')"
"The first of these dioceses was subject to
 the jurisdiction of the court of the East; and we may convey
 some idea of the importance and variety of his functions by
 observing that six hundred apparitors, who would be styled
 at present either secretaries, or clerks, or ushers, or
 messengers, were employed in his immediate office.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('six hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The first was appropriated to memorials, the second to epistles, the third to petitions, and the fourth to papers and orders of a miscellaneous kind.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL')"
"The forests that 
 overshadowed the shores of the Euxine, and the celebrated
 quarries of white marble in the little island of
 Proconnesus, supplied an inexhaustible stock of materials,
 ready to be conveyed, by the convenience of a short
 water-carriage, to the harbour of Byzantium. (40)","('Euxine', 'LOC'), ('Proconnesus', 'LOC'), ('Byzantium', 'GPE'), ('40', 'CARDINAL')"
"The former, rising by degrees from the most
 humble condition, were invested with the civil and military
 administration of the Roman world.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The forms, the pomp, and the expense of the civil administration contributed to restrain the irregular licence of the soldiers; and although the laws were violated by power, or perverted by subtlety, the sage principles of the Roman jurisprudence preserved a sense of order and equity unknown to the despotic governments of the East.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The fortune of Sidonius far 
 exceeded the customary wealth of a poet; but if he had
 pursued the allusion, he must have painted many of the
 Gallic nobles with the hundred heads of the deadly Hydra,
 spreading over the face of the country, and devouring the
 substance of an hundred families.","('Sidonius', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hydra', 'PRODUCT'), ('hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The fortunes of the Praetorian praefects were
 essentially different from those of the consuls and
 Patricians.","('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Patricians', 'NORP')"
"The frequent and regular distributions of wine and oil, of
 corn or bread, of money or provisions, had almost exempted
 the poorer citizens of Rome from the necessity of labour.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The games and largesses which crowned the pomp of this
 memorable festival may easily be supposed; but there is one
 circumstance of a more singular and permanent nature, which
 ought not entirely to be overlooked.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The geographers who, with the most skilful accuracy, have
 surveyed the form and extent of the Hellespont, assign about
 sixty miles for the winding course, and about three miles
 for the ordinary breadth, of those celebrated straits.","('Hellespont', 'GPE'), ('about\r\n sixty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('about three miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"The guards, carrying white tapers, and
 clothed in their richest apparel, accompanied the solemn
 procession as it moved through the Hippodrome.","('Hippodrome', 'FAC')"
"The harbour of Constantinople, which may be considered as an
 arm of the Bosphorus, obtained, in a very remote period, the
 denomination of the  Golden Horn.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('the  Golden Horn', 'ORG')"
"The honour of a liberal profession has indeed been
 vindicated by ancient and modern advocates, who have filled
 the most important stations with pure integrity and
 consummate wisdom; but in the decline of Roman jurisprudence
 the ordinary promotion of lawyers was pregnant with mischief
 and disgrace.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The honourable merchant of Alexandria, who imported the
 gems and spices of India for the use of the western world;
 the usurer, who derived from the interest of money a silent
 and ignominious profit, the ingenious manufacturer, the
 diligent mechanic, and even the most obscure retailer of a
 sequestered village, were obliged to admit the officers of
 the revenue into the partnership of their gain; and the
 sovereign of the Roman empire, who tolerated the profession,
 consented to share the infamous salary of public
 prostitutes.","('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('India', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The immense size
 of the city, and the experience of the tardy, ineffectual
 operation of the laws, had furnished the policy of Augustus
 with a specious pretence for introducing a new magistrate,
 who alone could restrain a servile and turbulent populace by
 the strong arm of arbitrary power. (103) Valerius Messalla was 
 appointed the first praefect of Rome, that his reputation
 might countenance so invidious a measure; but at the end of
 a few days that accomplished citizen (104) resigned his 
 office, declaring, with a spirit worthy of the friend of
 Brutus, that he found himself incapable of exercising a
 power incompatible with public freedom. (105)","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Valerius Messalla', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('the end of\r\n a few days', 'DATE'), ('104', 'CARDINAL'), ('Brutus', 'PERSON'), ('105', 'CARDINAL')"
"The introduction of barbarians into the 
 Roman armies became every day more universal, more
 necessary, and more fatal.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The jurisdiction of the chamberlain was acknowledged by the counts, or superintendents, who regulated the two important provinces of the magnificence of the wardrobe, and of the luxury of the Imperial table. (144)","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('144', 'CARDINAL')"
"The laborious offices, which could be productive
 only of envy and reproach, of expense and danger, were
 imposed on the Decurions, who formed the corporations of
 the cities, and whom the severity of the Imperial laws had
 condemned to sustain the burdens of civil society.","('Decurions', 'ORG'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The lands bestowed on the veterans, as the
 free reward of their valour, were henceforward granted under
 a condition which contains the first rudiments of the feudal
 tenures - that their sons, who succeeded to the inheritance,
 should devote themselves to the profession of arms as soon
 as they attained the age of manhood; and their cowardly
 refusal was punished by the loss of honour, of fortune, or
 even of life.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The lands were measured
 by surveyors, who were sent into the provinces; their
 nature, whether arable or pasture, or vineyards or woods,
 was distinctly reported; and an estimate was made of their
 common value from the average produce of five years.","('five years', 'DATE')"
"The latter of those cities was built by the
 Greeks a few years before the former; and the blindness of
 its founders, who overlooked the superior advantages of the
 opposite coast, has been stigmatised by a proverbial
 expression of contempt. (10)","('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"The magnificence of the first Caesars was in some measure
 imitated by the founder of Constantinople: (58) but his 
 liberality, however it might excite the applause of the
 people, has incurred the censure of posterity.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Constantinople', 'ORG'), ('58', 'CARDINAL')"
"The manly pride of the Romans, content with substantial
 power, had left to the vanity of the East the forms and
 ceremonies of ostentatious greatness.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The master of the Roman world, who aspired to erect an
 eternal monument of the glories of his reign, could employ
 in the prosecution of that great work the wealth, the
 labour, and all that yet remained of the genius, of obedient
 millions.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('millions', 'CARDINAL')"
"The memory of Constantine has been deservedly censured for
 another innovation which corrupted military discipline, and
 prepared the ruin of the empire.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The mischiefs which flow from injudicious counsels are
 seldom removed by the application of partial severities; and
 though succeeding princes laboured to restore the strength
 and numbers of the frontier garrisons he empire, till the
 last moment of its dissolution, continued to languish under
 the mortal wound which had been so rashly or so weakly
 incited by the hand of Constantine.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The most daring of the Scythians,
 of the Goths, and of the Germans, who delighted in war, and
 who found it more profitable to defend than to ravage the
 provinces, were enrolled not only in the auxiliaries of
 their respective nations, but in the legions themselves, and
 among the most distinguished of the Palatine troops.","('Scythians', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Palatine', 'NORP')"
"The motives,
 whether of pride or of policy, which first induced
 Diocletian to withdraw himself from the ancient seat of
 government, had acquired additional weight by the example of
 his successors and the habits of forty years.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('forty years', 'DATE')"
"The multitude of these agents had a natural tendency to increase; and it was more than once thought expedient to dismiss to their native homes the useless supernumeraries, who, deserting their honest labours, had pressed with too
 much eagerness into the lucrative profession of the
 finances. (152)","('152', 'CARDINAL')"
"The name and use of the indictions, (171) which serve to ascertain the chronology of the middle ages, was derived
 from the regular practice of the Roman tributes. (172)","('171', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('172', 'CARDINAL')"
"The navigation from the issue of the Bosphorus
 to the entrance of the Hellespont is about one hundred and
 twenty miles.","('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Hellespont', 'GPE'), ('one hundred and\r\n twenty miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"The necessity of
 protecting those suburbs from the incessant inroads of the
 barbarians engaged the younger Theodosius to surround his
 capital with an adequate and permanent enclosure of walls.
 (32)","('Theodosius', 'GPE')"
"The new
 wall of Constantine stretched from the port to the Propontis
 across the enlarged breadth of the triangle, at the distance
 of fifteen stadia from the ancient fortification, and with
 the city of Byzantium they enclosed five of the seven hills
 which, to the eyes of those who approach Constantinople,
 appear to rise above each other in beautiful order. (31)","('Constantine', 'GPE'), ('Propontis', 'FAC'), ('fifteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Byzantium', 'GPE'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The new castles of
 Europe and Asia are constructed, on either continent, upon
 the foundations of two celebrated temples, of Serapis and of
 Jupiter Urius.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Serapis', 'PRODUCT'), ('Jupiter Urius', 'LOC')"
"The nineteen years which
 preceded his final victory over Licinius had been a period
 of licence and intestine war.","('The nineteen years', 'DATE'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON')"
"The noble art, which had once been preserved
 as the sacred inheritance of the patricians, was fallen into
 the hands of freedmen and plebeians, (123) who, with cunning 
 rather than with skill, exercised a sordid and pernicious
 trade.","('123', 'CARDINAL')"
"The northern side of the city is bounded
 by the harbour, and the southern is washed by the Propontis
 or Sea of Marmora.","('the Propontis\r\n or Sea of Marmora', 'LOC')"
"The obscure
 millions of a great empire have much less to dread from the
 cruelty than from the avarice of their masters; and their
 humble happiness is principally affected by the grievance of
 excessive taxes, which, gently pressing on the wealthy,
 descend with accelerated weight on the meaner and more
 indigent classes of society.","('millions', 'CARDINAL')"
"The obtuse point, which advances towards the east
 and the shores of Asia, meets and repels the waves of the
 Thracian Bosphorus.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('the\r\n Thracian Bosphorus', 'LOC')"
"The old castles, a work of the Greek emperors
 command the narrowest part of the channel, in a place where
 the opposite banks advance within five hundred paces of each
 other.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('five hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The ordinary administration was conducted by those methods
 which extreme necessity can alone palliate; and the defects
 of evidence were diligently supplied by the use of torture.
  (162)","('162', 'CARDINAL')"
"The peculiar
 free gift of the senate of Rome was fixed by custom at
 sixteen hundred pounds of gold, or about sixty-four thousand
 pounds sterling.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('sixteen hundred pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('about sixty-four thousand\r\n pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"The ponderous
 volumes of the Codes and Pandects (114) would furnish ample 
 materials for a minute inquiry into the system of provincial
 government, as in the space of six centuries it was improved
 by the wisdom of the Roman statesmen and lawyers.","('Codes', 'PRODUCT'), ('114', 'CARDINAL'), ('six centuries', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The practice of Augustus was imitated by succeeding princes; the occasional commission was established as a permanent office; and the favoured quaestor, assuming a new and more illustrious character, alone survived the suppression of his ancient and useless colleagues. (149)","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('149', 'CARDINAL')"
The praefects of Rome and Constantinople.,"('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The preservation of the
 eastern provinces may, in some degree, be ascribed to the
 policy of Constantine, as the barbarians of the Euxine, who
 in the preceding age had poured their armaments into the
 heart of the Mediterranean, soon desisted from the exercise
 of piracy, and despaired of forcing this insurmountable
 barrier.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Euxine', 'NORP'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC')"
"The principal
 departments were relative to the command of a numerous
 watch, established as a safeguard against fires, robberies,
 and nocturnal disorders; the custody and distribution of the
 public allowance of corn and provisions; the care of the
 port, of the aqueducts, of the common sewers, and of the
 navigation and bed of the Tiber; the inspection of the
 markets, the theatres, and of the private as well as public
 works.","('Tiber', 'LOC')"
"The principal officers of the empire were saluted, even by the sovereign himself, with the deceitful titles of your Sincerity, your Gravity, your Excellency, your Eminence, your sublime and wonderful Magnitude, your illustrious and magnificent Highness. (75)","('Sincerity', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Highness', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"The procession 
 moved from the palace (87) to the Forum or principal square of 
 the city; where the consuls ascended their tribunal, and
 seated themselves in the curule chairs, which were framed
 after the fashion of ancient times.","('87', 'CARDINAL')"
"The proconsuls, vice-praefects, etc
 Those who in the Imperial hierarchy were distinguished by
 the title of Respectable formed an intermediate class
 between the illustrious praefects and the honourable
 magistrates of the provinces.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Respectable', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"The progress of zeal and flattery soon
 multiplied the number, and increased the size, of these
 popular donations; and the triumph of Caesar was enriched
 with two thousand eight hundred and twenty-two massy crowns,
 whose weight amounted to twenty thousand four hundred and
 fourteen pounds of gold.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('two thousand eight hundred and twenty-two', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty thousand four hundred and\r\n fourteen pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"The prospect of beauty, of safety, and of wealth, united in
 a single spot, was sufficient to justify the choice of
 Constantine.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The proudest and most perfect separation which can be found
 in any age or country between the nobles and the people is
 perhaps that of the Patricians and the Plebeians, as it was
 established in the first age of the Roman republic.","('Patricians', 'NORP'), ('Plebeians', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The public festival was continued during 
 several days in all the principal cities; in Rome, from
 custom; in Constantinople, from imitation; in Carthage,
 Antioch, and Alexandria, from the love of pleasure and the
 superfluity of wealth. (89)","('several days', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE')"
The public treasurer4.,"('4', 'CARDINAL')"
"The purity of  the Latin language was debased, by adopting, in the intercourse of pride and flattery, a profusion of epithets which Tully would scarcely have understood, and which Augustus would have rejected with indignation.","('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Tully', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"The rapacious ministers of Constantius
 had exhausted the wealth of Gaul, by exacting twenty-five
 pieces of gold for the annual tribute of every head.","('Constantius', 'ORG'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('twenty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('annual', 'DATE')"
"The remainder of
 their troops was distributed into several hundred cohorts of
 infantry, and squadrons of cavalry.","('several hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The remainder of the taxes, 
 according to the proportions determined by the annual
 indiction, was furnished in a manner still more direct, and
 still more oppressive.","('annual', 'DATE')"
"The resources of the
 Roman treasury were exhausted by the increase of pay, by the
 repetition of donatives, and by the invention of new
 emoluments and indulgences, which, in the opinion of the
 provincial youth, might compensate the hardships and dangers
 of a military life.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The revolution of
 three centuries had produced so remarkable a change in the
 prejudices of the people, that, with the public approbation,
 Constantine showed his successors the example of bestowing
 the honours of the consulship on the barbarians who, by
 their merit and services, had deserved to be ranked among
 the first of the Romans. (142)","('three centuries', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('142', 'CARDINAL')"
"The rights of mankind might derive some protection
 from religion and philosophy; and the name of freedom, which could no longer alarm, might sometimes admonish, the successors of Augustus, that they did not reign over a nation of Slaves or Barbarians. (194)","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Slaves', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('194', 'CARDINAL')"
"The rivals who contended for
 the possession of the Roman world had withdrawn the greatest
 part of their forces from the guard of the general frontier;
 and the principal cities which formed the boundary of their
 respective dominions were filled with soldiers, who
 considered their countrymen as their most implacable
 enemies.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The river Lycus,
 formed by the conflux of two little streams, pours into the
 harbour a perpetual supply of fresh water, which serves to
 cleanse the bottom and to invite the periodical shoals of
 fish to seek their retreat in that convenient recess.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The rudiments of this lucrative science were 
 taught in all the considerable cities of the East and West;
 but the most famous school was that of Berytus, (121) on the 
 coast of Phoenicia, which flourished above three centuries
 from the time of Alexander Severus, the author perhaps of an
 Institution so advantageous to his native country.","('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Berytus', 'GPE'), ('121', 'CARDINAL'), ('Phoenicia', 'GPE'), ('three centuries', 'DATE'), ('Alexander Severus', 'PERSON')"
"The same timid policy, of dividing whatever is united, of
 reducing whatever is eminent, of dreading every active
 power, and of expecting that the most feeble will prove the
 most obedient, seems to pervade the institutions of several
 princes, and particularly those of Constantine.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The seat of Turkish jealousy and despotism
 is erected on the foundations of a Grecian republic; but it
 may be supposed that the Byzantines were tempted by the
 conveniency of the harbour to extend their habitations on
 that side beyond the modern limits of the Seraglio.","('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('Byzantines', 'NORP'), ('Seraglio', 'NORP')"
"The space between the two metæ or goals was filled with statues and obelisks; and we may still remark a very singular fragment of antiquity, the bodies of three serpents twisted into one pillar of brass.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The spontaneous offering was at length 
 exacted as the debt of duty, and, instead of being confined
 to the occasion of a triumph, it was supposed to be granted
 by the several cities and provinces of the monarchy as often
 as the emperor condescended to announce his accession, his
 consulship, the birth of a son, the creation of a Caesar, a
 victory over the barbarians, or any other real or imaginary
 event which graced the annals of his reign.","('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"The straits of the Bosphorus are 
 terminated by the Cyanean rocks, which, according to the
 description of the poets, had once floated on the face of
 the waters, and were destined by the gods to protect the
 entrance of the Euxine against the eye of profane curiosity.","('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Cyanean', 'NORP'), ('Euxine', 'NORP')"
"The subjects of Constantine were incapable of discerning the decline of genius and manly virtue, which so far degraded them below the dignity of their ancestors; but they could feel and lament the rage of tyranny, the relaxation of discipline, and the increase of taxes.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The sum of
 forty-two pieces of gold, to which it was reduced,
 ascertains the exorbitant price of volunteers, and the
 reluctance with which the government admitted of this
 alternative. (138)","('forty-two', 'CARDINAL'), ('138', 'CARDINAL')"
"The supreme jurisdiction
 exercised by the Praetorian praefects over the armies of the
 empire was transferred to the two masters general whom he
 instituted, the one for the cavalry, the other for the
 infantry; and though each of these illustrious officers was
 more peculiarly responsible for the discipline of those
 troops which were under his immediate inspection, they both
 indifferently commanded in the field the several bodies,
 whether of horse or foot, which were united in the same
 army. (127)","('Praetorian', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('127', 'CARDINAL')"
"The testimony of Zosimus cannot indeed be
 justified from the charge of passion and prejudice; but,
 from the nature of this tribute, it seems reasonable to
 conclude that it was arbitrary in the distribution, and
 extremely rigorous in the mode of collecting.","('Zosimus', 'PERSON')"
"The threatening tempest of barbarians, which so soon subverted the foundations of Roman greatness, was still repelled, or suspended, on the frontiers.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The trophies of memorable wars, the objects of 
 religious veneration, the most finished statues of the gods
 and heroes, of the sages and poets of ancient times,
 contributed to the splendid triumph of Constantinople; and
 gave occasion to the remark of the historian Cedrenus, (43) 
 who observes, with some enthusiasm, that nothing seemed
 wanting except the souls of the illustrious men whom these
 admirable monuments were intended to represent.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Cedrenus', 'PERSON'), ('43', 'DATE')"
"The tutelar genius of the city, a venerable
 matron sinking under the weight of years and infirmities,
 was suddenly transformed into a blooming maid, whom his own
 hands adorned with all the symbols of Imperial greatness. (27)","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('27', 'CARDINAL')"
"The two opposite entrances formed triumphal arches;
 the porticoes, which enclosed it on every side, were filled
 with statues, and the centre of the Forum was occupied by a
 lofty column, of which a mutilated fragment is now degraded
 by the appellation of the burnt pillar.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Forum', 'ORG')"
"The value of a tributary head
 must have varied, according to many accidental, or at least
 fluctuating circumstances: but some knowledge has been
 preserved of a very curious fact, the more important since
 it relates to one of the richest provinces of the Roman
 empire, and which now flourishes as the most splendid of the
 European kingdoms.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('European', 'NORP')"
"The vanity of those who, from their rank and office, might
 claim a superior distinction above the rest of the
 senatorial order, was long afterwards indulged with the new
 appellation of Respectable: but the title of Illustrious
 was always reserved to some eminent personages who were
 obeyed or reverenced by the two subordinate classes.","('Illustrious', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The vast countries which the Roman conquerors had
 united under the same simple form of administration were
 imperceptibly crumbled into minute fragments, till at length
 the whole empire was distributed into one hundred and
 sixteen provinces, each of which supported an expensive and
 splendid establishment.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('one hundred and\r\n sixteen', 'CARDINAL')"
"The venerable parent still maintained the
 legal and acknowledged supremacy, which was due to her age,
 to her dignity, and to the remembrance of her former
 greatness. (63)
Dedication.","('63', 'CARDINAL')"
"The whole number consisted of three thousand and five hundred men, divided into seven schools, or troops, of five hundred each; and in the East this honourable service was almost entirely appropriated to the Armenians.","('three thousand and five hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('five hundred each', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Armenians', 'NORP')"
"The winding channel through which the waters of the Euxine
 flow with a rapid and incessant course towards the
 Mediterranean received the appellation of Bosphorus, a name
 not less celebrated in the history than in the fables of
 antiquity.","('Euxine', 'LOC'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC'), ('Bosphorus', 'LOC')"
"Their 
 solemn inauguration was performed at the place of the
 Imperial residence; and during a period of one hundred and
 twenty years Rome was constantly deprived of the presence of
 her ancient magistrates. (84)","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('one hundred and\r\n twenty years', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Their abilities (unless they were employed in more effective
 offices) were of little moment; and their names served only
 as the legal date of the year in which they had filled the
 chair of Marius and of Cicero.","('the year', 'DATE'), ('Marius', 'PERSON'), ('Cicero', 'PERSON')"
"Their arms, and titles,
 and ensigns were calculated to inspire terror, and to
 display the variety of nations who marched under the
 Imperial standard.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"Their courts were
 deserted; their number, which had once fluctuated between
 twelve and eighteen, (106) was gradually reduced to two or 
 three; and their important functions were confined to the
 expensive obligation (107) of exhibiting games for the 
