Sentence,Entities
(10),"('10', 'CARDINAL')"
"(15)
The huns invade Persia, A.D. 430-440.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('430-440', 'CARDINAL')"
"(31) The Huns might be 
 provoked to insult the misery of their slaves, over whom
 they exercised a despotic command;(32) but their manners were 
 not susceptible of a refined system of oppression, and the
 efforts of courage and diligence were often recompensed by
 the gift of freedom","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('32', 'CARDINAL')"
(51),"('51', 'CARDINAL')"
"(7) The religious arts of Attila 
 were not less skilfully adapted to the character of his age
 and country.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"A
 violent tempest of wind and rain, of thunder and lightning,
 overturned their tents, immersed their baggage and furniture
 in the water, and scattered their retinue, who wandered in
 the darkness of the night, uncertain of their road and
 apprehensive of some unknown danger, till they awakened by
 their cries the inhabitants of a neighbouring village, the
 property of the widow of Bleda.","('Bleda', 'PERSON')"
"A Moorish and a
 Scythian buffoon successively excited the mirth of the rude
 spectators, by their deformed figure, ridiculous dress,
 antic gestures, absurd speeches, and the strange
 unintelligible confusion of the Latin, the Gothic, and the
 Hunnic languages; and the hall resounded with loud and
 licentious peals of laughter.","('Moorish', 'NORP'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Hunnic', 'NORP')"
"A bright illumination, and,
 in a few moments, a comfortable fire of reeds, was kindled
 by their officious benevolence: the wants, and even the
 desires, of the Romans were liberally satisfied; and they
 seem to have been embarrassed by the singular politeness of
 Bleda's widow, who added to her other favours the gift, or
 at least the loan, of a sufficient number of beautiful and
 obsequious damsels.","('a few moments', 'TIME'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Bleda', 'PERSON')"
"A large proportion of the
 taxes extorted from the people was detained and intercepted
 in their passage through the foulest channels to the
 treasury of Constantinople.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"A personal contribution, rigorously but
 capriciously imposed on the members of the senatorian order,
 was the only expedient that could disarm without loss of
 time the impatient avarice of Attila: and the poverty of the
 nobles compelled them to adopt the scandalous resource of
 exposing to public auction the jewels of their wives and the
 hereditary ornaments of their palaces.(35) III.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('35', 'CARDINAL')"
"A separate house was assigned to each
 of the numerous wives of Attila; and, instead of the rigid
 and illiberal confinement imposed by Asiatic jealousy, they
 politely admitted the Roman ambassadors to their presence,
 their table, and even to the freedom of an innocent embrace.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"A solemn embassy, armed with full powers and magnificent gifts, was hastily sent to deprecate the wrath of Attila; and his pride was gratified by the choice of Nomius and Anatolius, two ministers of consular or patrician rank, of whom the one was great treasurer, and the other was master-general of the armies of the East.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Nomius', 'PERSON'), ('Anatolius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"A strict though fruitless inquiry
 was allowed; but the Huns were obliged to swear that they
 did not detain any prisoners belonging to the city before
 they could recover two surviving countrymen whom the
 Azimuntines had reserved as pledges for the safety of their
 lost companions.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Azimuntines', 'PERSON')"
"After passing a desert
 and a morass supposed by the Romans to be the lake Maeotis,
 they penetrated through the mountains, and arrived, at the
 end of fifteen days' march, on the confines of Media where
 they advanced as far as the unknown cities of Basic and
 Cursic.(17)","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Maeotis', 'LOC'), (""fifteen days'"", 'DATE'), ('Media', 'ORG'), ('Basic', 'ORG'), ('Cursic', 'LOC'), ('17', 'CARDINAL')"
"After passing through the guards who watched
 before the gate, the ambassadors were introduced into the
 private apartment of Cerca.","('Cerca', 'GPE')"
"After some previous conversation,
 and a mutual oath of secrecy, the eunuch, who had not, from
 his own feelings or experience, imbibed any exalted notions
 of ministerial virtue, ventured to propose the death of
 Attila, as an important service, by which Edecon might
 deserve a liberal share of the wealth and luxury which he
 admired.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Edecon', 'ORG')"
"After the Moguls had subdued the northern
 provinces of China, it was seriously proposed, not in the
 hour of victory and passion, but in calm deliberate council,
 to exterminate all the inhabitants of that populous country,
 that the vacant land might be converted to the pasture of
 cattle.","('Moguls', 'ORG'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('the\r\n hour', 'TIME')"
"After the conclusion of the treaty Attila still
 menaced the empire with implacable war, unless the
 Azimuntines were persuaded or compelled to comply with the
 conditions which their sovereign had accepted.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Azimuntines', 'PERSON')"
"After this entertainment
 they travelled about one hundred miles from Sardica to
 Naissus.","('about one hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Sardica', 'GPE'), ('Naissus', 'GPE')"
"An architect in the service of Onegesius, one of the
 favourites of Attila, was employed to construct a bath: but
 this work was a rare example of private luxury; and the
 trades of the smith, the carpenter, the armourer, were much
 more adapted to supply a wandering people with the useful
 instruments of peace and war.","('Onegesius', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"An enterprise had been
 concerted between the courts of Ravenna and Constantinople
 for the recovery of that valuable province; and the ports of
 Sicily were already filled with the military and naval
 forces of Theodosius.","('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE')"
"As far as we may ascertain the vague and obscure geography
 of Priscus, this capital appears to have been seated between
 the Danube, the Theiss, and the Carpathian hills, in the
 plains of Upper Hungary, and most probably in the
 neighbourhood of Jazberin, Agria, or Tokay.(44)","('Priscus', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Theiss', 'LOC'), ('the Carpathian hills', 'LOC'), ('Upper Hungary', 'LOC'), ('Jazberin', 'GPE'), ('Agria', 'GPE'), ('Tokay', 'GPE'), ('44', 'CARDINAL')"
"As he was
 riding or hunting in .the neighbourhood of Constantinople,
 he was thrown from his horse into the river Lycus: the spine
 of his back was injured by the fall; and he expired some
 days afterwards, in the fiftieth year of his age, and the
 forty-third of his reign.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Lycus', 'PERSON'), ('some\r\n days afterwards', 'DATE'), ('the fiftieth year', 'DATE'), ('forty-third', 'CARDINAL')"
"As soon as the monarch had graciously accepted
 her hospitable gift, his domestics lifted a small silver
 table to a convenient height, as he sat on horseback; and
 Attila, when he had touched the goblet with his lips, again
 saluted the wife of Onegesius, and continued his march.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Onegesius', 'PERSON')"
"As the Romans
 were pressed by a victorious enemy, they gradually, and
 unskilfully, retired towards the Chersonesus of Thrace; and
 that narrow peninsula, the last extremity of the land, was
 marked by their third and irreparable defeat.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Chersonesus', 'NORP'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('third', 'ORDINAL')"
"As the remains of Sardica were
 still included within the limits of the empire, it was
 incumbent on the Romans to exercise the duties of
 hospitality.","('Sardica', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"At his solicitation, and in the name of John the usurper, sixty thousand Huns advanced to the confines of Italy; their march and their retreat were alike expensive to the state; and the grateful policy of Aetius abandoned the possession of Pannonia to his faithful confederates.","('John', 'PERSON'), ('sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Pannonia', 'PERSON')"
"At length, by the intercession of
 Scotta, the brother of Onegesius, whose friendship had been
 purchased by a liberal gift, he was admitted to the royal
 presence; but, instead of obtaining a decisive answer, he
 was compelled to undertake a remote journey towards the
 North, that Attila might enjoy the proud satisfaction of
 receiving in the same camp the ambassadors of the Eastern
 and Western empires.","('Scotta', 'PERSON'), ('Onegesius', 'PERSON'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"Attila, on his side, was satisfied and
 deceived by their solemn asseveration that the rest of the
 captives had been put to the sword and that it was their
 constant practice immediately to dismiss the Romans and the
 deserters who had obtained the security of the public faith.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Azimus, or Azimuntium, a small city of Thrace on the
 Illyrian borders,(37) had been distinguished by the martial 
 spirit of its youth, the skill and reputation of the leaders
 whom they had chosen, and their daring exploits against the
 innumerable host of the barbarians.","('Azimus', 'GPE'), ('Azimuntium', 'GPE'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP'), ('37', 'CARDINAL')"
"Besides the
 freedom of a safe and plentiful market on the banks of the
 Danube, they required that the annual contribution should be
 augmented from three hundred and fifty to seven hundred
 pounds of gold; that a fine or ransom, of eight pieces of
 gold, should be paid for every Roman captive who had escaped
 from his barbarian master; that the emperor should renounce
 all treaties and engagements with the enemies of the Huns;
 and that all the fugitives who had taken refuge in the court
 or provinces of Theodosius should be delivered to the
 justice of their offended sovereign.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('three hundred and fifty to seven hundred\r\n pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE')"
"Besides the motive of pride and interest which might prompt
 the king of the Huns to continue this train of negotiation,
 he was influenced by the less honourable view of enriching
 his favourites at the expense of his enemies.","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"But
 the rashness of Vigilius will appear still more
 extraordinary, since he returned, conscious of his guilt and
 danger, to the royal camp accompanied by his son, and
 carrying with him a weighty purse of gold, which the
 favourite eunuch had furnished, to satisfy the demands of
 Edecon and to corrupt the fidelity of the guards.","('Vigilius', 'PERSON'), ('Edecon', 'PERSON')"
"But
 these slight obstacles were instantly swept away by the
 inundation of the Huns. (20)","('Huns.', 'NORP'), ('20', 'CARDINAL')"
"But he arrogantly declared that he
 apprehended only the disgrace of contending with his
 fugitive slaves; since he despised their impotent efforts to
 defend the provinces which Theodosius had intrusted to their
 arms:","('Theodosius', 'GPE')"
"But in the cities of Asia which yielded to the
 Moguls, the inhuman abuse of the rights of war was exercised
 with a regular form of discipline, which may, with equal
 reason though not with equal authority, be imputed to the
 victorious Huns.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Moguls', 'ORG'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"But the
 troops which had been sent against Genseric were hastily
 recalled from Sicily; the garrisons, on the side of Persia,
 were exhausted; and a military force was collected in
 Europe, formidable by their arms and numbers, if the
 generals had understood the science of command, and their
 soldiers the duty of obedience.","('Genseric', 'PERSON'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'LOC'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"But the
 wine still remained after the meat had been removed; and the
 Huns continued to indulge their intemperance long after the
 sober and decent ambassadors of the two empires had
 withdrawn themselves from the nocturnal banquet.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the Huns were obliged
 to retire before the numbers of the enemy.","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"But the behaviour of Marcian in a private life, and
 afterwards on the throne, may support a more rational belief
 that he was qualified to restore and invigorate an empire
 which had been almost dissolved by the successive weakness
 of two hereditary monarchs.","('Marcian', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the extent of his empire affords the only remaining evidence of the number and importance of his victories; and the Scythian monarch,
 however ignorant of the value of science and philosophy,
 might perhaps lament that his illiterate subjects were
 destitute of the art which could perpetuate the memory of
 his exploits.","('Scythian', 'NORP')"
"But the office of reproof was reserved for the superior
 dignity of his colleague Eslaw, who gravely addressed the
 emperor of the East in the following words:","('Eslaw', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"But the subtle Genseric, who spread
 his negotiations round the world, prevented their designs,
 by exciting the king of the Huns to invade the Eastern
 empire; and a trifling incident soon became the motive, or
 pretence, of a destructive war. (19)","('Genseric', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('19', 'CARDINAL')"
"But they were soon intimidated
 by the destruction of Viminiacum and the adjacent towns; and
 the people was persuaded to adopt the convenient maxim, that
 a private citizen, however innocent or respectable, may be
 justly sacrificed to the safety of his country.","('Viminiacum', 'GPE')"
"But this perfidious conspiracy was
 defeated by the dissimulation, or the repentance, of Edecon;
 and though he might exaggerate his inward abhorrence for the
 treason which he seemed to approve, he dexterously assumed
 the merit of an early and voluntary confession.","('Edecon', 'PERSON')"
"But this treaty was purchased at an expense which might have supported a vigorous and successful war; and the subjects of Theodosius were compelled to redeem the safety of a worthless favourite by oppressive taxes which they would more cheerfully have paid for his destruction.
 (50)","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"By the
 destruction of this army, Attila acquired the indisputable
 possession of the field.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"During his residence at the seat of empire his hours were
 not wasted in the recluse idleness of a seraglio; and the
 king of the Huns could maintain his superior dignity without
 concealing his person from the public view.","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"For these importunate
 and oppressive embassies Attila claimed a suitable return;
 he weighed with suspicious pride, the character and station
 of the Imperial envoys; but he condescended to promise that
 he would advance as far as Sardica to receive any minister
 who had been invested with the consular dignity.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Sardica', 'GPE')"
"Four dependent nations, among whom we may distinguish the Bavarians, disclaimed the sovereignty of the Huns; and their revolt was encouraged and protected by a Roman alliance; till the just claims and formidable power of Rugilas were effectually urged by the voice of Eslaw, his ambassador.","('Four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bavarians', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Rugilas', 'PERSON'), ('Eslaw', 'PERSON')"
"From the Hellespont to Thermopylae
 and the suburbs of Constantinople he ravaged, without
 resistance and without mercy, the provinces of Thrace and
 Macedonia.","('Hellespont', 'GPE'), ('Thermopylae', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Thrace', 'GPE'), ('Macedonia', 'GPE')"
"From the contiguous villages they received
 a plentiful and regular supply of provisions, mead instead
 of wine, millet in the place of bread, and a certain liquor
 named camus, which, according to the report of Priscus,
 was distilled from barley.(43) Such fare might appear coarse 
 and indelicate to men who had tasted the luxury of
 Constantinople; but, in their accidental distress, they were
 relieved by the gentleness and hospitality of the same
 barbarians, so terrible and so merciless in war.","('Priscus', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"From this principle he concluded, and the
 conclusions of Attila were irrevocable laws, that the Huns
 who had been taken prisoners in war should be released
 without delay and without ransom; that every Roman captive
 who had presumed to escape should purchase his right to
 freedom at the price of twelve pieces of gold; and that all
 the barbarians who had deserted the standard of Attila
 should be restored without any promise or stipulation of
 pardon.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"He
 boldly treated with the princes of the Huns; secured, by
 solemn oaths, his pardon and reward; posted a numerous
 detachment of barbarians, in silent ambush, on the banks of
 the Danube; and, at the appointed hour, opened, with his own
 hand, the gates of his episcopal city.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"He
 subdued the islands of the ocean, the kingdoms of
 Scandinavia, encompassed and divided by the waters of the
 Baltic; and the Huns might derive a tribute of furs from
 that northern region, which has been protected from all
 other conquerors by the severity of the climate and the
 courage of the natives.","('Scandinavia', 'LOC'), ('Baltic', 'LOC'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"He condescended to meet these ambassadors on the banks of the river Drenso; and though he at first affected a stern and haughty demeanour, his anger was insensibly mollified by their eloquence and liberality.","('Drenso', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"He condescended to pardon the emperor, the eunuch, and the interpreter; bound himself by an oath to observe the conditions of peace; released a great number of captives; abandoned the fugitives and deserters to their fate; and resigned a large territory, to the south of the Danube, which he had already exhausted of its wealth and inhabitants.","('Danube', 'LOC')"
"He delighted in war; but, after he had
 ascended the throne in a mature age, his head, rather than
 his hand, achieved the conquest of the North; and the fame
 of an adventurous soldier was usefully exchanged for that of
 a prudent and successful general.","('North', 'LOC')"
"He dismissed, however, the interpreter, who returned to Constantinople with his peremptory demand of more complete restitution, and a more splendid embassy.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"He frequently
 assembled his council, and gave audience to the ambassadors
 of the nations; and his people might appeal to the supreme
 tribunal, which he held at stated times, and, according to
 the Eastern custom, before the principal gate of his wooden
 palace.","('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"He passed nineteen years in the
 domestic and military service of Aspar and his son
 Ardaburius; followed those powerful generals to the Persian
 and African wars; and obtained, by their influence, the
 honourable rank of tribune and senator.","('nineteen years', 'DATE'), ('Aspar', 'PERSON'), ('Ardaburius', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('African', 'NORP')"
"He was born in Thrace, and
 educated to the profession of arms; but Marcian's youth had
 been severely exercised by poverty and misfortune, since his
 only resource, when he first arrived at Constantinople,
 consisted in two hundred pieces of gold which he had
 borrowed of a friend.","('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Marcian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('two hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"Heraclea and Hadrianople might, perhaps, escape
 this dreadful irruption of the Huns; but the words the most
 expressive of total extirpation and erasure are applied to
 the calamities which they inflicted on seventy cities of the
 Eastern empire.(21) Theodosius, his court, and the unwarlike 
 people, were protected by the walls of Constantinople; but
 those walls had been shaken by a recent earthquake, and the
 fall of fifty-eight towers had opened a large and tremendous
 breach.","('Heraclea', 'PERSON'), ('Hadrianople', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('seventy', 'CARDINAL'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('21', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('fifty-eight', 'CARDINAL')"
"His alliance with the Romans of the West was cemented by his personal friendship for the great Aetius, who was always secure of finding in the barbarian camp an hospitable reception and a powerful support.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON')"
"His ambassadors, Eslaw and Orestes, were
 immediately despatched to Constantinople with a peremptory
 instruction, which it was much safer for them to execute
 than to disobey.","('Eslaw', 'PERSON'), ('Orestes', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"His anger gradually subsided, and his domestic satisfaction in a marriage which he celebrated on the road with the daughter of Eslam might perhaps contribute to mollify the native fierceness of his temper.","('Eslam', 'PERSON')"
"His features,
 according to the observation of a Gothic historian, bore the
 stamp of his national origin; and the portrait of Attila
 exhibits the genuine deformity of a modern Calmuck;(6) a 
 large head, a swarthy complexion, small deep-seated eyes, a
 flat nose, a few hairs in the place of a beard, broad
 shoulders, and a short square body, of nervous strength,
 though of a disproportioned form.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Calmuck', 'NORP'), ('6', 'CARDINAL')"
"His figure and character; 
 Attila, the son of Mundzuk, deduced his noble, perhaps his
 regal, descent(5) from the ancient Huns, who had formerly 
 contended with the monarchs of China.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Mundzuk', 'PERSON'), ('5', 'CARDINAL'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('China', 'GPE')"
"His friend, the historian Priscus,(42) 
 embraced the opportunity of observing the barbarian hero in
 the peaceful and domestic scenes of life: but the secret of
 the embassy, a fatal and guilty secret, was intrusted only
 to the interpreter Vigilius.","('Priscus', 'PERSON'), ('42', 'DATE'), ('Vigilius', 'PERSON')"
"His mild disposition
 and useful talents, without alarming the jealousy,
 recommended Marcian to the esteem and favour of his patrons;
 he had seen, perhaps he had felt, the abuses of a venal and
 oppressive administration; and his own example gave weight
 and energy to the laws which he promulgated for the
 reformation of manners.(53)","('Marcian', 'PERSON')"
"His sister Pulcheria, whose 
 authority had been controlled both in civil and
 ecclesiastical affairs by the pernicious influence of the
 eunuchs, was unanimously proclaimed empress of the East; and
 the Romans, for the first time, submitted to a female reign.","('Pulcheria', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"His stern countenance, angry gestures, and impatient
 tone astonished the firmness of Maximin; but Vigilius had
 more reason to tremble, since he distinctly understood the
 menace, that if Attila did not respect the law of nations,
 he would nail the deceitful interpreter to a cross, and
 leave his body to the vultures.","('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Vigilius', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"His two nephews, Attila and Bleda, who succeeded to the
 throne of their uncle, consented to a personal interview
 with the ambassadors of Constantinople; but as they proudly
 refused to dismount, the business was transacted on
 horseback, in a spacious plain near the city of Margus, in
 the Upper Maesia.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Bleda', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Margus', 'GPE'), ('the Upper Maesia', 'LOC')"
"I. The emperor of the East
 resigned, by an express or tacit convention, an extensive
 and important territory which stretched along the southern
 banks of the Danube, from Singidunum, or Belgrade, as far as
 Novae, in the diocese of Thrace.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Singidunum', 'GPE'), ('Belgrade', 'GPE'), ('Novae', 'GPE'), ('Thrace', 'GPE')"
"If a line of separation were drawn between the civilised and
 the savage climates of the globe; between the inhabitants of
 cities, who cultivated the earth, and the hunters and
 shepherds, who dwelt in tents, Attila might aspire to the
 title of supreme and sole monarch of the barbarians.(13) He 
 alone, among the conquerors of ancient and modern times,
 united the two mighty kingdoms of Germany and Scythia; and
 those vague appellations, when they are applied to his
 reign, may be understood with an ample latitude.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'LOC')"
"If the rites of Scythia were practised on this solemn occasion, a lofty altar, or rather pile of faggots, three hundred yards in length and in breadth, was raised in a spacious plain;
 and the sword of Mars was placed erect on the summit of this
 rustic altar, which was annually consecrated by the blood of
 sheep, horses, and of the hundredth captive.","('Scythia', 'PERSON'), ('three hundred yards', 'QUANTITY'), ('Mars', 'LOC'), ('hundredth', 'CARDINAL')"
"If we now
 review the embassy of Maximin and the behaviour of Attila,
 we must applaud the barbarian, who respected the laws of
 hospitality, and generously entertained and dismissed the
 minister of a prince who had conspired against his life.","('Maximin', 'GPE'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"In all their invasions of the civilised empires of the
 South, the Scythian shepherds have been uniformly actuated
 by a savage and destructive spirit.","('South', 'LOC'), ('Scythian', 'NORP')"
"In its origin 
 it could be no more than an accidental camp, which, by the
 long and frequent residence of Attila, had insensibly
 swelled into a huge village, for the reception of his court,
 of the troops who followed his person, and of the various
 multitude of idle or industrious slaves and retainers.(45)","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('45', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the
 hands of a wise legislator such an industrious colony might
 have contributed to diffuse through the deserts of Scythia
 the rudiments of the useful and ornamental arts; but these
 captives, who had been taken in war, were accidentally
 dispersed among the hordes that obeyed the empire of Attila","('Scythia', 'LOC'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"In the execution of this cruel and ignominious
 treaty the Imperial officers were forced to massacre several
 loyal and noble deserters who refused to devote themselves
 to certain death; and the Romans forfeited all reasonable
 claims to the friendship of any Scythian people by this
 public confession that they were destitute either of faith
 or power to protect the suppliant who had embraced the
 throne of Theodosius.(36)
Spirit of Azimuntines","('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('36', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the free conversation of the
 Imperial ambassadors, who discussed, at the court of Attila,
 the character and designs of their formidable enemy, the
 ministers of Constantinople expressed their hope that his
 strength might be diverted and employed in a long and
 doubtful contest with the princes of the house of Sassan.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Sassan', 'PERSON')"
"In the midst of this
 intemperate riot, Attila alone, without a change of
 countenance, maintained his steadfast and inflexible
 gravity, which was never relaxed, except on the entrance of
 Irnac, the youngest of his sons: he embraced the boy with a
 smile of paternal tenderness, gently pinched him by the
 cheek, and betrayed a partial affection, which was justified
 by the assurance of his prophets that Irnac would be the
 future support of his family and empire.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Irnac', 'PERSON'), ('Irnac', 'PERSON')"
"In the proud review of the nations who
 acknowledged the sovereignty of Attila, and who never
 entertained, during his lifetime, the thought of a revolt,
 the Gepidae and the Ostrogoths were distinguished by their
 numbers, their bravery, and the personal merit of their
 chiefs.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Gepidae', 'PERSON'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP')"
"In the reign of ATTILA (1) the Huns again became the terrors of the world; and I shall now describe the character and actions of that formidable barbarian, who alternately insulted and invaded the East and the West and urged the rapid downfall of the Roman Empire.","('ATTILA', 'EVENT'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('the Roman Empire', 'GPE')"
"In the reign of his father Arcadius, a band of adventurous
 Huns had ravaged the provinces of the East, from whence they
 brought away rich spoils and innumerable captives.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"In the siege of Viminiacum he had lost,
 according to his own account, his fortune and liberty: he
 became the slave of Onegesius but his faithful services
 against the Romans and the Acatzires had gradually raised
 him to the rank of the native Huns, to whom he was attached
 by the domestic pledges of a new wife and several children.","('Viminiacum', 'GPE'), ('Onegesius', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Acatzires', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"In the tide of emigration which impetuously rolled from the confines of China to those of Germany, the most powerful and populous tribes may commonly be found on the verge of the Roman provinces.","('China', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In this advantageous situation, Rugilas, and his valiant brothers, who continually added to their power and reputation, commanded the alternative of peace or war with the two empires.","('Rugilas', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In time of peace, the dependent
 princes, with their national troops, attended the royal camp
 in regular succession; but when Attila collected his
 military force he was able to bring into the field an army
 of five, or, according to another account, of seven hundred
 thousand barbarians.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven hundred\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Instead of contenting himself with
 a moderate contribution and a military title, which equalled
 him only to the generals of Theodosius, Attila would proceed
 to impose a disgraceful and intolerable yoke on the necks of
 the prostrate and captive Romans, who would then be
 encompassed on all sides by the empire of the Huns.(18)","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('18', 'CARDINAL')"
"Instead of tamely
 expecting their approach, the Azimuntines attacked, in
 frequent and successful sallies, the troops of the Huns, who
 gradually declined the dangerous neighbourhood, rescued from
 their hands the spoil and the captives, and recruited their
 domestic force by the voluntary association of fugitives and
 deserters.","('Azimuntines', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"It may be affirmed with bolder assurance that the Huns
 depopulated the provinces of the empire by the number of
 Roman subjects whom they led away into captivity.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It was natural enough that the Scythians should
 adore, with peculiar devotion, the god of war; but as they
 were incapable of forming either an abstract idea or a
 corporeal representation, they worshipped their tutelar
 deity under the symbol of an iron cimeter.(8)","('Scythians', 'NORP')"
"It would have been strange, indeed, if Theodosius had
 purchased, by the loss of honour, a secure and solid
 tranquillity, or if his tameness had not invited the
 repetition of injuries.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Maximin and his colleagues
 were stopped on the threshold, till they had made a devout
 libation to the health and prosperity of the king of the
 Huns; and were conducted, after this ceremony, to their
 respective seats in a spacious hall.","('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"Maximin returned, by the same road, to Constantinople; and though he was involved in an accidental dispute with Beric, the new ambassador of Attila, he flattered himself that he had contributed, by the laborious journey to confirm the peace and alliance of the two nations.(48)
Conspiracy of the Romans against the life of Attila 
 But the Roman ambassador was ignorant of the treacherous
 design which had been concealed under the mask of the public
 faith.","('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Beric', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('48', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Maximin,(41) a respectable courtier, whose abilities 
 had been long exercised in civil and military employments,
 accepted with reluctance the troublesome, and perhaps
 dangerous, commission of reconciling the angry spirit of the
 king of the Huns.","('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('41', 'CARDINAL'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"No sooner had Maximin advanced about two miles from the
 Danube than he began to experience the fastidious insolence
 of the conqueror.","('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('about two miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"No sooner had Pulcheria ascended the throne than she
 indulged her own and the public resentment by an act of
 popular justice.","('Pulcheria', 'PERSON')"
"On his refusal to comply with such ignominious terms,
 the Imperial envoy was commanded instantly to depart; the
 order was recalled; it was again repeated; and the Huns
 renewed their ineffectual attempts to subdue the patient
 firmness of Maximin.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON')"
"On the third day the ambassadors were dismissed; the freedom of several captives was granted, for a moderate ransom to their pressing entreaties; and, besides the royal presents, they were permitted to accept from each of the Scythian nobles the honourable and useful gift of a horse.","('the third day', 'DATE'), ('Scythian', 'NORP')"
"One might imagine that such a
 demand, which scarcely equalled the measure of private
 wealth, would have been readily discharged by the opulent
 empire of the East; and the public distress affords a
 remarkable proof of the impoverished, or at least of the
 disorderly, state of the finances.","('East', 'LOC')"
"One of the 
 shepherds of the Huns perceived that a heifer, who was
 grazing, had wounded herself in the foot, and curiously
 followed the track of the blood, he discovers the sword of Mars, till he discovered, among
 the long grass, the point of an ancient sword which he dug
 out of the ground, and presented to Attila.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Mars', 'LOC'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
Peace was the unanimous wish of the senate: their decree was ratified by the emperor; and two ambassadors were named—,"('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Perhaps they might not understand the merit of a
 theologian profoundly skilled in the controversies of the
 Trinity and the Incarnation; yet they respected the
 ministers of every religion; and the active zeal of the
 Christian missionaries, without approaching the person or
 the palace of the monarch, successfully laboured in the
 propagation of the gospel.(28)","('Trinity', 'ORG'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('28', 'CARDINAL')"
"Plinthas, a general of Scythian extraction, but of consular rank; and the quaestor Epigenes, a wise and experienced statesman, who was recommended to
that office by his ambitious colleague.","('Plinthas', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Epigenes', 'PERSON')"
"Reign of Attila, A.D. 433-453","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 433-453', 'DATE')"
"She gave her hand to Marcian, a
 senator, about sixty years of age, and the nominal husband
 of Pullcheria was solemnly invested with the Imperial
 purple.","('Marcian', 'PERSON'), ('about sixty years of age', 'DATE'), ('Pullcheria', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"Some ecclesiastical historians have destroyed the barbarians with lightning and pestilence;(3) but Theodosius was reduced to the more humble expedient of stipulating an annual payment of three hundred and fifty pounds of gold, and of disguising this dishonourable tribute by the title of general, which the king of the Huns condescended to accept.","('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('three hundred and fifty pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"Some of the great
 vassals of the king of the Huns, who were themselves in the
 rank of powerful princes, had been sent to ratify an
 alliance and society of arms with the emperor, or rather
 with the general, of the West.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"Soon after this adventure they
 rejoined the march of Attila, from whom they had been
 separated about six days; and slowly proceeded to the
 capital of an empire which did not contain, in the space of
 several thousand miles, a single city.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('about six days', 'DATE'), ('several thousand miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"Such was the
 behaviour of the Moguls when they were not conscious of any
 extraordinary rigour.(24)","('Moguls', 'ORG')"
"That
 magnanimous, or rather that artful, prince accepted, with
 pious gratitude, this celestial favour; and, as the rightful
 possessor of the sword of Mars, asserted his divine and
 indefeasible claim to the dominion of the earth.","('Mars', 'LOC')"
"That Gallic 
 adventurer, who was recommended by Aetius to the king of the
 Huns, had engaged his service to the ministers of
 Constantinople for the stipulated reward of a wealthy and
 noble wife; and the daughter of Count Saturninus was chosen
 to discharge the obligations of her country.","('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Saturninus', 'PERSON')"
"That flourishing city, which had given birth to the
 great Constantine, was levelled with the ground; the
 inhabitants were destroyed or dispersed; and the appearance
 of some sick persons, who were still permitted to exist
 among the ruins of the churches, served only to increase the
 horror of the prospect.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The
 Scythian conquerors, Attila and Zingis, surpassed their rude
 countrymen in art, rather than in courage; and it may be
 observed that the monarchies, both of the Huns and of the
 Moguls, were erected by their founders on the basis of
 popular superstition.","('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Zingis', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Moguls', 'ORG')"
"The
 first class consisted of the soldiers of the garrison and
 the young men capable of bearing arms; and their fate was
 instantly decided: they were either enlisted among the
 Moguls, or they were massacred on the spot by the troops,
 who, with pointed spears and bended bows, had formed a
 circle round the captive multitude.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Moguls', 'NORP')"
"The
 greatness of the emperor and the empire was warmly
 maintained by their ministers; the Huns, with equal ardour,
 asserted the superiority of their victorious monarch: the
 dispute was inflamed by the rash and unseasonable flattery
 of Vigilius, who passionately rejected the comparison of a
 mere mortal with the divine Theodosius, and it was with
 extreme difficulty that Maximin and Priscus were able to
 divert the conversation or soothe the angry minds of the
 barbarians.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Vigilius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Priscus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 interpreter was instantly seized and dragged before the
 tribunal of Attila where he asserted his innocence with
 specious firmness; till the threat of inflicting instant
 death on his son extorted from him a sincere discovery of
 the criminal transaction.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The 
 perpetual intercourse of the Huns and the Goths had
 communicated the familiar knowledge of the two national
 dialects; and the barbarians were ambitious of conversing in
 Latin, the military idiom even of the Eastern empire.(30) But 
 they disdained the language and the sciences of the Greeks
 and the vain sophist or grave philosopher who had enjoyed
 the flattering applause of the schools, was mortified to
 find that his robust servant was a captive of more value and
 importance than himself.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"The Byzantine court was insulted by
 five or six successive embassies; (39) and the ministers of 
 Attila were uniformly instructed to press the tardy or
 imperfect execution of the last treaty; to produce the names
 of fugitives and deserters who were still protected by the
 empire; and to declare, with seeming moderation, that,
 unless their sovereign obtained complete and immediate
 satisfaction, it would be impossible for him, were it even
 his wish, to check the resentment of his warlike tribes.","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('five or six', 'CARDINAL'), ('39', 'CARDINAL'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The Character, Conquests, and Court of Attila, King of the Huns—Death of Theodosius the Younger—Elevation of Marcian to the Empire of the EastThe Huns, A.D. 376-433 
 THE WESTERN world was oppressed by the Goths and Vandals, who fled before the Huns; but the achievements of the Huns themselves were not adequate to their power and prosperity.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Death of Theodosius the Younger—Elevation of Marcian to the Empire of the EastThe Huns', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('376-433', 'CARDINAL'), ('WESTERN', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"The Hungarians, who ambitiously insert the name of Attila among their native kings, may affirm with truth that the hordes which were subject to his uncle Roas, or Rugilas, had formed their encampments within the limits of modern Hungary, (2) in a fertile country which liberally supplied the wants of a nation of hunters and shepherds.","('Hungarians', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Roas', 'PERSON'), ('Rugilas', 'PERSON'), ('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('2', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Huns
 justified this outrage as an act of reprisal; alleged that
 the bishop of Margus had entered their territories, to
 discover and steal a secret treasure of their kings; and
 sternly demanded the guilty prelate, the sacrilegious spoil,
 and the fugitive subjects, who had escaped from the justice
 of Attila.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Margus', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The Huns
 were ambitious of displaying those riches which were the
 fruit and evidence of their victories; the trappings of
 their horses, their swords, and even their shoes, were
 studded with gold and precious stones; and their tables were
 profusely spread with plates, and goblets, and vases of gold
 and silver, which had been fashioned by the labour of
 Grecian artists.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Grecian', 'NORP')"
"The Huns of Attila may without injustice be compared to the
 Moguls and Tartars before their primitive manners were
 changed by religion and luxury; and the evidence of Oriental
 history may reflect some light on the short and imperfect
 annals of Rome.","('The Huns of Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Moguls', 'NORP'), ('Tartars', 'NORP'), ('Oriental', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The Huns were masters of the great river: their
 navigation was performed in large canoes, hollowed out of
 the trunk of a single tree; the ministers of Theodosius were
 safely landed on the opposite bank; and their barbarian
 associates immediately hastened to the camp of Attila, which
 was equally prepared for the amusements of hunting or of
 war.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The Illyrian frontier was
 covered by a line of castles and fortresses; and though the
 greatest part of them consisted only of a single tower, with
 a small garrison, they were commonly sufficient to repel, or
 to intercept, the inroads of an enemy who was ignorant of
 the art, and impatient of the delay, of a regular siege.","('Illyrian', 'NORP')"
"The Imperial
 treasury was exhausted to procure the friendly offices of
 the ambassadors and their principal attendants, whose
 favourable report might conduce to the maintenance of peace.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The Romans of the East were not less apprehensive of the arms of Rugilas, which threatened the provinces, or even the capital.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Rugilas', 'GPE')"
"The Romans who traversed the plains
 of Hungary suppose that they passed several navigable
 rivers, either in canoes or portable boats; but there is
 reason to suspect that the winding stream of the Theiss, or
 Tibiscus, might present itself in different places under
 different names.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('Theiss', 'PRODUCT'), ('Tibiscus', 'ORG')"
"The Romans, both of the East and of the West, were
 twice invited to the banquets,The royal feast where Attila feasted with the princes and nobles of Scythia.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Scythia', 'PERSON')"
"The Scythian or Tartar, wars.","('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Tartar', 'NORP')"
"The ambassador of the Huns listened to the tempting
 offer; and professed, with apparent zeal, his ability, as
 well as readiness, to execute the bloody deed: the design
 was communicated to the master of the offices, and the
 devout Theodosius consented to the assassination of his
 invincible enemy.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The ambassadors of the Huns might awaken the attention of
 Theodosius, by reminding him that they were his neighbours
 both in Europe and Asia; since they touched the Danube on
 one hand, and reached with the other as far as the Tanais.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tanais', 'NORP')"
"The ambassadors, who were followed by a numerous train of
 men and horses, made their first halt at Sardica, at the
 distance of three hundred and fifty miles, or thirteen days'
 journey, from Constantinople.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Sardica', 'GPE'), ('three hundred and fifty miles', 'QUANTITY'), (""thirteen days'"", 'DATE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The armies of the Eastern
 empire were vanquished in three successive engagements; and
 the progress of Attila may be traced by the fields of
 battle.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The barbarian monarch was flattered by the liberal reception
 of his ministers; he computed with pleasure the value and
 splendour of their gifts, rigorously exacted the performance
 of every promise which would contribute to their private
 emolument, and treated as an important business of state the
 marriage of his secretary Constantius. (40)","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('40', 'CARDINAL')"
"The barbarians condescended,
 by producing an accurate list, to expose the bold falsehood
 of Vigilius, who had affirmed that no more than seventeen
 deserters could be found.","('Vigilius', 'PERSON'), ('no more than seventeen', 'CARDINAL')"
"The baths, constructed by Onegesius, were the only edifice
 of stone; the materials had been transported from Pannonia;
 and since the adjacent country was destitute even of large
 timber, it may be presumed that the meaner habitations of
 the royal village consisted of straw, of mud, or of canvas.","('Onegesius', 'FAC'), ('Pannonia', 'GPE')"
The behaviour of Attila to the Roman ambassadors.,"('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The bishop
 of Margus, who did not possess the spirit of a martyr,
 resolved to prevent the designs which he suspected.","('Margus', 'PERSON')"
"The breadth was defined by
 the vague computation of fifteen days' journey; but, from
 the proposal of Attila to remove the situation of the
 national market, it soon appeared that he comprehended the
 ruined city of Naissus within the limits of his dominions.","(""fifteen days'"", 'DATE'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Naissus', 'GPE')"
"The council
 of Theodosius eluded this proposal by representing the
 desolate and ruined condition of Sardica; and even ventured
 to insinuate that every officer of the army or household was
 qualified to treat with the most powerful princes of
 Scythia.","('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('Sardica', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'PERSON')"
"The crowd of vulgar kings, the leaders of so
 many martial tribes, who served under the standard of
 Attila, were ranged in the submissive order of guards and
 domestics round the person of their master.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The damage indeed was speedily repaired; but this
 accident was aggravated by a superstitious fear that Heaven
 itself had delivered the Imperial city to the shepherds of
 Scythia, who were strangers to the laws, the language, and
 the religion of the Romans.(22)","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Scythia', 'LOC'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('22', 'CARDINAL')"
The death of Rugilas suspended the progress of the treaty.,"('Rugilas', 'PERSON')"
"The dress of Attila, his arms, and the 
 furniture of his horse, were plain, without ornament, and of
 a single colour.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The embassy of Maximin to Attila, A.D. 448.","('Maximin', 'GPE'), ('Attila', 'GPE'), ('448', 'CARDINAL')"
"The emperor Theodosius did not long survive the most
 humiliating circumstance of an inglorious life.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"The entrance of Attila into the royal village was marked by a very
 singular ceremony.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The firmness of a Chinese mandarin, (23) who 
 insinuated some principles of rational policy into the mind
 of Zingis, diverted him from the execution of this horrid
 design.","('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('23', 'DATE'), ('Zingis', 'PERSON')"
"The freedman of Onegesius exposed, in true and lively
 colours, the vices of a declining empire of which he had so
 long been the victim; the cruel absurdity of the Roman
 princes, unable to protect their subjects against the public
 enemy, unwilling to trust them with arms for their own
 defence; the intolerable weight of taxes, rendered still
 more oppressive by the intricate or arbitrary modes of
 collection; the obscurity of numerous and contradictory
 laws; the tedious and expensive forms of judicial
 proceedings; the partial administration of justice; and the
 universal corruption which increased the influence of the
 rich and aggravated the misfortunes of the poor A sentiment
 of patriotic sympathy was at length revived in the breast of
 the fortunate exile, and he lamented with a flood of tears
 the guilt or weakness of those magistrates who had perverted
 the wisest and most salutary institutions.(33)
Treaty of peace between Attila and the Eastern empire, A.D. 446.","('Onegesius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('33)\r\nTreaty', 'LAW'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('446', 'CARDINAL')"
"The haughty step and
 demeanour of the king of the Huns expressed the
 consciousness of his superiority above the rest of mankind;
 and he had a custom of fiercely rolling his eyes, as if he
 wished to enjoy the terror which he inspired.","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"The historian Priscus, whose embassy is
 a source of curious instruction, was accosted in the camp of
 Attila by a stranger, who saluted him in the Greek language,
 but whose dress and figure displayed the appearance of a
 wealthy Scythian.","('Priscus', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Greek', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Scythian', 'PERSON')"
"The inhabitants who had submitted to their
 discretion were ordered to evacuate their houses and to
 assemble in some plain adjacent to the city, where a
 division was made of the vanquished into three parts.","('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"The king of the Huns appears to have established as a principle of
 national jurisprudence, that he could never lose the
 property which he had once acquired in the persons who had
 yielded either a voluntary or reluctant submission to his
 authority.","('Huns', 'PERSON')"
"The king of the Huns held a long and familiar
 conversation with Maximin; but his civility was interrupted
 by rude expressions and haughty reproaches; and he was
 provoked, by a motive of interest, to support, with
 unbecoming zeal, the private claims of his secretary
 Constantius.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The king of the Huns required and obtained that his
 tribute or subsidy should be augmented from seven hundred
 pounds of gold to the annual sum of two thousand one
 hundred; and he stipulated the immediate payment of six
 thousand pounds of gold to defray the expenses, or to
 expiate the guilt, of the war.","('The king of the Huns', 'PERSON'), ('seven hundred\r\n pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('two thousand one\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('six\r\n thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"The kings of the Huns assumed the solid
 benefits, as well as the vain honours, of the negotiation.","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"The laws of war, that
 restrain the exercise of national rapine and murder, are
 founded on two principles of substantial interest: the
 knowledge of the permanent benefits which may be obtained by
 a moderate use of conquest, and a just apprehension lest the
 desolation which we inflict on the enemy's country may be
 retaliated on our own.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The mechanic arts were encouraged
 and esteemed, as they tended to satisfy the wants of the
 Huns.","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"The memory of this invasion was still recent in
 the minds of the Orientals.","('Orientals', 'NORP')"
"The ministers
 of Theodosius confessed, with shame and with truth, that
 they no longer possessed any authority over a society of men
 who so bravely asserted their natural independence; and the
 king of the Huns condescended to negotiate an equal exchange
 with the citizens of Azimus.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Azimus', 'GPE')"
"The ministers of
 Attila pressed him to communicate the business and the
 instructions which he reserved for the ear of their
 sovereign.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The miraculous conception, which fraud
 and credulity ascribed to the virgin mother of Zingis,
 raised him above the level of human nature; and the naked
 prophet, who, in the name of the Deity, invested him with
 the empire of the earth, pointed the valour of the Moguls
 with irresistible enthusiasm.","('Zingis', 'PERSON'), ('Moguls', 'ORG')"
"The monarch alone assumed the superior
 pride of still adhering to the simplicity of his Scythian
 ancestors. (46)","('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('46', 'CARDINAL')"
"The more sagacious Italians admonished their Eastern
 brethren of the folly and danger of such a hope; and
 convinced them, that the Medes and Persians were incapable
 of resisting the arms of the Huns; and that the easy and
 important acquisition would exalt the pride, as well as
 power, of the conqueror.","('Italians', 'NORP'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Medes', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"The palace of
 Attila, which surpassed all other houses in his dominions,
 was built entirely of wood, and covered an ample space of
 ground.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The public
tranquillity was frequently interrupted by the fierce impatience of the barbarians and the perfidious intrigues of the Byzantine court.","('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"The public danger and distress could not, however, provoke
 Theodosius to interrupt his amusements and devotion or to
 appear in person at the head of the Roman legions.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The refusal of the Byzantine court was the signal
 of war; and the Maesians at first applauded the generous
 firmness of their sovereign.","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Maesians', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The reluctance
 of the victim, some domestic troubles, and the unjust
 confiscation of her fortune, cooled the ardour of her
 interested lover; but he still demanded, in the name of
 Attila, an equivalent alliance; and, after many ambiguous
 delays and excuses, the Byzantine court was compelled to
 sacrifice to this insolent stranger the widow of Armatius,
 whose birth, opulence, and beauty placed her in the most
 illustrious rank of the Roman matrons.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Armatius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The renowned Ardaric, king of the Gepidae, was the
 faithful and sagacious counsellor of the monarch, who
 esteemed his intrepid genius, whilst he loved the mild and
 discreet virtues of the noble Walamir, king of the
 Ostrogoths.","('Ardaric', 'PERSON'), ('Gepidae', 'PERSON'), ('Walamir', 'PERSON'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP')"
"The revenue was dissipated by
 Theodosius and his favourites in wasteful and profuse
 luxury, which was disguised by the names of imperial
 magnificence or Christian charity.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The royal table and
 couch, covered with carpets and fine linen, was raised by
 several steps in the midst of the hall; and a son, an uncle,
 or perhaps a favourite king, were admitted to share the
 simple and homely repast of Attila.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The royal table was served in wooden cups
 and platters; flesh was his only food; and the conqueror of
 the North never tasted the luxury of bread.","('North', 'LOC')"
"The second class,
 composed of the young and beautiful women, of the artificers
 of every rank and profession, and of the more wealthy or
 honourable citizens, from whom a private ransom might be
 expected, was distributed in equal or proportionable lots.","('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"The son of Arcadius, who was accustomed only to the voice of flattery, heard with astonishment the severe language of truth: he blushed and trembled; nor did he presume directly to refuse the head of Chrysaphius, which Eslaw and Orestes were instructed to demand.","('Arcadius', 'PERSON'), ('Chrysaphius', 'PRODUCT'), ('Eslaw', 'PERSON'), ('Orestes', 'PERSON')"
"The spoils of war had restored and improved his private
 property; he was admitted to the table of his former lord
 and the apostate Greek blessed the hour of his captivity,
 since it had been the introduction to a happy and
 independent state, which he held by the honourable tenure of
 military service.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('the hour', 'TIME')"
"The subjects of Attila might
 execute, with superior forces, the design which these
 adventurers had so boldly attempted; and it soon became the
 subject of anxious conjecture whether the tempest would fall
 on the dominions of Rome or of Persia.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"The sunshine of the succeeding day was
 dedicated to repose, to collect and dry the baggage, and to
 the refreshment of the men and horses; but, in the evening,
 before they pursued their journey, the ambassadors expressed
 their gratitude to the bounteous lady of the village by a
 very acceptable present of silver cups, red fleeces, dried
 fruits, and Indian pepper.","('the succeeding day', 'DATE'), ('Indian', 'NORP')"
"The surface of the country was
 covered with the bones of the slain; and the ambassadors,
 who directed their course to the north-west, were obliged to
 pass the hills of modern Servia before they descended into
 the flat and marshy grounds which are terminated by the
 Danube.","('Servia', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"The surprise and satisfaction of Edecon, when he
 contemplated the splendour of Constantinople had encouraged
 the interpreter Vigilius to procure for him a secret
 interview with the eunuch Chrysaphius,(49) who governed the 
 emperor and the empire.","('Edecon', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Vigilius', 'PERSON'), ('Chrysaphius', 'PERSON'), ('49', 'DATE')"
"The three great
 capitals of Khorasan, Maru, Neisabour, and Herat, were
 destroyed by the armies of Zingis; and the exact account
 which was taken of the slain amounted to four millions three
 hundred and forty-seven thousand persons. (25) Timur, or 
 Tamerlane, was educated in a less barbarous age and in the
 profession of the Mahometan religion; yet, if Attila
 equalled the hostile ravages of Tamerlane, (26) either the 
 Tartar or the Hun might deserve the epithet of the SCOURGE
 OF GOD.(27)","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Khorasan', 'GPE'), ('Maru', 'GPE'), ('Neisabour', 'GPE'), ('Herat', 'GPE'), ('Zingis', 'GPE'), ('four millions three\r\n hundred and forty-seven thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Timur', 'PERSON'), ('Tamerlane', 'PERSON'), ('Mahometan', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Tamerlane', 'GPE'), ('26', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tartar', 'NORP'), ('Hun', 'PERSON'), ('27', 'CARDINAL')"
"The timid or selfish policy of the Western Romans had
 abandoned the Eastern empire to the Huns.(34)","('the Western Romans', 'NORP'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('34', 'CARDINAL')"
"The two former, on the banks of the Utus, and under
 the walls of Marcianopolis, were fought in the extensive
 plains between the Danube and Mount Haemus.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Utus', 'FAC'), ('Marcianopolis', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Mount Haemus', 'LOC')"
"The two last ambassadors of the
 Huns, Orestes, a noble subject of the Pannonian province,
 and Edecon, a valiant chieftain of the tribe of the Scyrri,
 returned at the same time from Constantinople to the royal
 camp.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Orestes', 'PERSON'), ('Pannonian', 'NORP'), ('Edecon', 'PERSON'), ('Scyrri', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The whole breadth of Europe, as
 it extends above five hundred miles from the Euxine to the
 Hadriatic, was at once invaded, and occupied, and desolated,
 by the myriads of barbarians whom Attila led into the field.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('five hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Euxine', 'LOC'), ('Hadriatic', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The wife
 of his favourite Onegesius, with a train of female
 attendants, saluted Attila at the door of her own house, on
 his way to the palace; and offered, according to the custom
 of the country, her respectful homage, by entreating him to
 taste the wine and meat which she had prepared for his
 reception.","('Onegesius', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The wife of Attila received
 their visit sitting, or rather lying, on a soft couch; the
 floor was covered with a carpet; the domestics formed a
 circle round the queen; and her damsels, seated on the
 ground, were employed in working the variegated embroidery
 which adorned the dress of the barbaric warriors.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The wooden houses of the more illustrious Huns were built
 and adorned with rude magnificence, according to the rank,
 the fortune, or the taste of the proprietors.","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"The zeal which he displayed for the orthodox creed,
 as it was established by the council of Chalcedon, would
 alone have inspired the grateful eloquence of the catholics.","('Chalcedon', 'GPE')"
Their establishment in modern Hungary,"('Hungary', 'GPE')"
"Their obscure names were afterwards illustrated by the
 extraordinary fortune and the contrast of their sons: the
 two servants of Attila became the fathers of the last Roman
 emperor of the West, and of the first barbarian king of
 Italy.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Their victorious hordes had spread from the Volga to the
 Danube; but the public force was exhausted by the discord of independent chieftains; their valour was idly consumed in obscure and predatory excursions; and they often degraded their national dignity, by condescending, for the hopes of spoil, to enlist under the banners of their fugitive enemies.","('Volga', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"Theodosius might still affect the style as well as the title
 of Invincible Augustus, but he was reduced to solicit the
 clemency of Attila who imperiously dictated these harsh and
 humiliating conditions of peace.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Invincible Augustus', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"Theodosius the Younger dies, A.D. 450, July 28.","('Theodosius the Younger', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 450', 'DATE'), ('July 28', 'DATE')"
"They
 advanced, by a secret path, along the shores of the Caspian
 Sea; traversed the snowy mountains of Armenia; passed the
 Tigris, the Euphrates, and the Halys; recruited their weary
 cavalry with the generous breed of Cappadocian horses
 occupied the hilly country of Cilicia; and disturbed the
 festal songs and dances of the citizens of Antioch.(16) Egypt 
 trembled at their approach; and the monks and pilgrims of
 the Holy Land prepared to escape their fury by a speedy
 embarkation.","('the Caspian\r\n Sea', 'LOC'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Halys', 'NORP'), ('Cappadocian', 'NORP'), ('Cilicia', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('16', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('the Holy Land', 'GPE')"
"They ,destroyed, with fire and 
 sword, the populous cities of Sirmium and Singidunum, of
 Ratiaria and Marcianopolis, of Naissus and Sardica; where
 every circumstance in the discipline of the people and the
 construction of the buildings had been gradually adapted to
 the sole purpose of defence.","('Sirmium', 'GPE'), ('Singidunum', 'GPE'), ('Ratiaria', 'GPE'), ('Marcianopolis', 'GPE'), ('Naissus', 'GPE'), ('Sardica', 'GPE')"
"They attack the Eastern empire, A.D. 441, etc 
 While the powers of Europe and Asia were solicitous to avert
 the impending danger, the alliance of Attila maintained the
 Vandals in the possession of Africa.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 441', 'FAC'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Vandals', 'PRODUCT'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"They boldly entered :he Imperial presence
 with the fatal purse hanging down from the neck of Orestes,
 who interrogated the eunuch Chrysaphius, as he stood beside
 the throne, whether he recognised the evidence of his guilt.","('Orestes', 'PERSON'), ('Chrysaphius', 'PERSON')"
"They encountered the Persian army in the plains 
 of Media, and the air, according to their own expression,
 was darkened by a cloud of arrows.","('Persian', 'NORP')"
"They marched before him,
 distributed into long and regular files: the intervals
 between the files were filled by white veils of thin linen,
 which the women on either side bore aloft in their hands,
 and which formed a canopy for a chorus of young virgins, who
 chanted hymns and songs in the Scythian language.","('Scythian', 'LANGUAGE')"
"They provided, with the assistance of the
 provincials, a sufficient number of sheep and oxen, and
 invited the Huns to a splendid, or, at least, a plentiful
 supper.","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"They related, during their
 residence at Rome, the circumstances of an expedition which
 they had lately made into the East.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"They watched his
 nod; they trembled at his frown; and at the first signal of
 his will, they executed, without murmur or hesitation, his
 stern and absolute commands.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"They were crucified on the territories of the empire,
 by the command of Attila: and, as soon as the king of the
 Huns had impressed the Romans with the terror of his name,
 he indulged them in a short and arbitrary respite, whilst he
 subdued the rebellious or independent nations of Scythia and
 Germany.(4)","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Scythia', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('4', 'CARDINAL')"
"This prudent and officious dissimulation may be condemned or
 excused by the casuists as they incline to the rigid decree
 of St. Augustin, or the milder sentiment of St. Jerom and
 St. Chrysostom: but every soldier, every statesman, must
 acknowledge that, if the race of the Azimuntines had been
 encouraged and multiplied, the barbarians would have ceased
 to trample on the majesty of the empire.(38)
Embassies from Attila to Constantinople","('St. Augustin', 'GPE'), ('St. Jerom', 'LOC'), ('St. Chrysostom', 'GPE'), ('Azimuntines', 'NORP'), ('38', 'CARDINAL'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"This reflection naturally produced a
 dispute on the advantages and defects of the Roman
 government, which was severely arraigned by the apostate,
 and defended by Priscus in a prolix and feeble declamation.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Priscus', 'PERSON')"
"Thuringia,
 which stretched beyond its actual limits as far as the
 Danube, was in the number of his provinces; he interposed,
 with the weight of a powerful neighbour, in the domestic
 affairs of the Franks; and one of his lieutenants chastised,
 and almost exterminated, the Burgundians of the Rhine.","('Thuringia', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"Towards the East, it is difficult to
 circumscribe the dominion of Attila over the Scythian
 deserts; yet we may be assured that he reigned on the banks
 of the Volga; that the king of the Huns was dreaded, not
 only as a warrior, but as a magician;(14) that he insulted 
 and vanquished the khan of the formidable Geougen; and that
 he sent ambassadors to negotiate an equal alliance with the
 empire of China.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Volga', 'LOC'), ('Huns', 'PERSON'), ('14', 'DATE'), ('Geougen', 'PERSON'), ('China', 'GPE')"
"Two Scythians stood before the couch of Attila,
 and recited the verses which they had composed to celebrate
 his valour and his victories.","('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Scythians', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"Two days afterwards
 the ambassadors received a second invitation; and they had
 reason to praise the politeness, as well as the hospitality,
 of Attila.","('Two days afterwards', 'DATE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"Two lines of small
 tables, each of which contained three or four guests, were
 ranged in order on either hand; the right was esteemed the
 most honourable, but the Romans ingenuously confess that
 they were placed on the left; and that Beric, an unknown
 chieftain, most probably of the Gothic race, preceded the
 representatives of Theodosius and Valentinian.","('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Beric', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"Under the faith of the 
 treaty of Margus, a free market was held on the northern
 side of the Danube, which was protected by a Roman fortress
 surnamed Constantia.","('Margus', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Constantia', 'PRODUCT')"
"Under the name of ransom, or
 confiscation, the rapacious king of the Huns accepted two
 hundred pounds of gold for the life of a traitor whom he
 disdained to punish.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('two\r\n hundred pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"When Attila first gave audience to the Roman ambassadors on
 the banks of the Danube, his tent was encompassed with a
 formidable guard.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"When Maximin offered his presents to Cerca the principal
 queen, he admired the singular architecture of her mansion,
 the height of the round columns, the size and beauty of the
 wood, which was curiously shaped or turned, or polished or
 carved; and his attentive eye was able to discover some
 taste in the ornaments, and some regularity in the
 proportions.","('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Cerca', 'PERSON')"
"When Maximin temperately urged the contrary
 practice of nations, he was still more confounded to find
 that the resolutions of the Sacred Consistory, those secrets
 (says Priscus) which should not be revealed to the gods
 themselves, had been treacherously disclosed to the public
 enemy.","('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('the Sacred Consistory', 'ORG'), ('Priscus', 'PERSON')"
"When they rose from table the Imperial
 ambassador presented Edecon and Orestes with rich gifts of
 silk robes and Indian pearls, which they thankfully
 accepted.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Edecon', 'PERSON'), ('Orestes', 'PERSON'), ('Indian', 'NORP')"
"Whether human sacrifices formed any part of the worship of Attila, or whether he propitiated the god of war with the victims which he continually offered in the field of battle, the
 favourite of Mars soon acquired a sacred character, which
 rendered his conquests more easy and more permanent; and the
 barbarian princes confessed, in the language of devotion or
 flattery, that they could not presume to gaze, with a steady
 eye, on the divine majesty of the king of the Huns.(11) His brother Bleda, who reigned over a considerable part of the nation, was compelled to resign his sceptre and his life.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Mars', 'LOC'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Bleda', 'PERSON')"
"Without any legal trial, the eunuch
 Chrysaphius was executed before the gates of the city; and
 the immense riches which had been accumulated by the
 rapacious favourite served only to hasten and to justify his
 punishment.(52) Amidst the general acclamations of the clergy 
 and people, the empress did not forget the prejudice and
 disadvantage to which her sex was exposed; and she wisely
 resolved to prevent their murmurs by the choice of a
 colleague who would always respect the superior rank and
 virgin chastity of his wife.","('Chrysaphius', 'PERSON')"
"Yet Orestes could not forbear insinuating that he
 had not always been treated with such respect and
 liberality: and the offensive distinction which was implied
 between his civil office and the hereditary rank of his
 colleague seems to have made Edecon a doubtful friend and
 Orestes an irreconcilable enemy.","('Orestes', 'PERSON'), ('Edecon', 'PERSON'), ('Orestes', 'PERSON')"
"Yet even this cruel act was attributed to a supernatural
 impulse; and the vigour with which Attila wielded the sword
 of Mars convinced the world that it had been reserved alone
 for his invincible arm. (12)","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Mars', 'LOC')"
"Yet this
 savage hero was not inaccessible to pity; his suppliant
 enemies might confide in the assurance of peace or pardon;
 and Attila was considered by his subjects as a just and
 indulgent master.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
and acquires the empire of Scythia and Germany.,"('Scythia', 'ORG'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"and is succeeded by Marcian, August 25.","('Marcian', 'PERSON'), ('August 25', 'DATE')"
"and ravage Europe, as far as Constantinople","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
