Sentence,Entities
(19),"('19', 'CARDINAL')"
(31),"('31', 'CARDINAL')"
(37),"('37', 'CARDINAL')"
"(50)
more absolute over the property than over the person of the Germans","('Germans', 'NORP')"
(51),"('51', 'CARDINAL')"
(54),"('54', 'CARDINAL')"
"1. The great rivers which covered the Roman provinces, the Rhine and the Danube, were frequently frozen over, and capable of supporting the most enormous weights.","('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"2. The reindeer, that useful animal, from whom the savage of the North derives the best comforts of his dreary life, is of a constitution that supports, and even requires, the most intense cold.","('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('North', 'LOC')"
"A
 clime so profusely favoured by Nature could not long remain
 desert after the flood.","('Nature', 'ORG')"
"A multitude of darts, scattered  (72) 
 with incredible force, were an additional resource of the
 infantry.","('72', 'CARDINAL')"
"A ridge of hills, rising from the Danube, and
 called the Carpathian mountains, covered Germany on the side
 of Dacia or Hungary.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('the Carpathian mountains', 'LOC'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Dacia', 'GPE'), ('Hungary', 'GPE')"
"A small quantity of corn was the only produce
 exacted from the earth: the use of orchards or artificial
 meadows was unknown to the Germans; nor can we expect any
 improvements in agriculture from a people whose property
 every year experienced a general change by a new division of
 the arable lands, and who, in that strange operation,
 avoided disputes by suffering a great part of their
 territory to lie waste and without tillage.  (27)
and of the use of metals.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('every year', 'DATE'), ('27', 'CARDINAL')"
"A solemn
 procession was occasionally celebrated in the present
 countries of Mecklenburgh and Pomerania.","('Mecklenburgh', 'GPE'), ('Pomerania', 'LOC')"
"Almost the whole of modern Germany, Denmark, Norway, Sweden,
 Finland, Livonia, Prussia, and the greater part of Poland,
 were peopled by the various tribes of one great nation,
 whose complexion, manners, and language denoted a common
 origin and preserved a striking resemblance.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Denmark', 'GPE'), ('Norway', 'GPE'), ('Sweden', 'GPE'), ('Finland', 'GPE'), ('Livonia', 'GPE'), ('Prussia', 'GPE'), ('Poland', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"Although situated in the same
 parallel with the finest provinces of France and England,
 that country experiences the most rigorous cold.","('France', 'GPE'), ('England', 'GPE')"
"Although they were admitted in small numbers and with the
 strictest precaution, the example of Civilis was proper to
 convince the Romans that the danger was not imaginary, and
 that their precautions were not always sufficient.  (74)","('Civilis', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Among the nations who have adopted the
 Mosaic history of the world, the ark of Noah has been of the
 same use as was formerly to the Greeks and Romans the siege
 of Troy.","('Mosaic', 'NORP'), ('Noah', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Troy', 'PERSON')"
"And from
 facts thus exaggerated, an opinion was gradually
 established, and has been supported by writers of
 distinguished reputation, that, in the age of Caesar and
 Tacitus, the inhabitants of the North were far more numerous
 than they are in our days.  (38)","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('our days', 'DATE'), ('38', 'DATE')"
"And in the same manner
 the German auxiliaries, invited into France during the civil
 wars of the sixteenth century, were allured by the promise
 of plenteous quarters in the provinces of Champagne and
 Burgundy.  (35)","('German', 'NORP'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('the sixteenth century', 'DATE'), ('Champagne', 'GPE'), ('Burgundy', 'GPE'), ('35', 'CARDINAL')"
"And yet we find that, during more
 than two hundred and fifty years that elapsed from the
 defeat of Varus to the reign of Decius, these formidable
 barbarians made few considerable attempts, and not any
 material impression on the luxurious and enslaved provinces
 of the empire.","('more\r\n than two hundred and fifty years', 'DATE'), ('Varus', 'PERSON'), ('Decius', 'PERSON')"
"And yet, when in
 calm retirement we peruse the combats described by Homer or
 Tasso, we are insensibly seduced by the fiction, and feel a
 momentary glow of martial ardour.","('Homer', 'PERSON'), ('Tasso', 'PERSON')"
"Assemblies of the people
 Civil governments, in their first institutions, are
 voluntary associations for mutual defence.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Barbarians
 accustomed to place their freedom in gratifying the present
 passion, and their courage in overlooking all future
 consequences, turned away with indignant contempt from the
 remonstrance of justice and policy, and it was the practice
 to signify by a hollow murmur their dislike of such timid
 counsels.","('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"But
 Tacitus asserts, as a well-known fact, that the Germans, in
 his time, had no Cities;   (20) and that they affected to
 despise the works of Roman industry as places of confinement
 rather than of security.   (21)","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('20', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('21', 'CARDINAL')"
But I shall select two remarkable circumstances of a less equivocal nature.,"('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"But a state of freedom and barbarism, the season of civil
 commotions, or the situation of petty republics,  (87) raises
 almost every member of the community into action, and
 consequently into notice.","('87', 'CARDINAL')"
"But all this well-laboured system of German antiquities is
 annihilated by a single fact, too well attested to admit of
 any doubt, and of too decisive a nature to leave room for
 any reply.","('German', 'NORP')"
"But as the barbarians
 poured forth their whole souls on the first onset, they knew
 not how to rally or to retire.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But the Germans, who carried with them what they
 most valued, their arms, their cattle, and their women,
 cheerfully abandoned the vast silence of their woods for the
 unbounded hopes of plunder and conquest.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"But the rude tribes of Germany, alike
 destitute of both those valuable metals, were reduced slowly
 to acquire, by their unassisted strength, the possession of
 the one as well as the other.","('Germany', 'GPE')"
"But the warlike Germans, who first
 resisted, then invaded, and at length overturned, the
 western monarchy of Rome, will occupy a much more important
 place in this history, and possess a stronger, and, if we
 may use the expression, a more domestic, claim to our
 attention and regard.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But those who
 had tasted the rich wines of Italy, and afterwards of Gaul,
 sighed for that more delicious species of intoxication.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"Canada, at this day, is an exact
 picture of ancient Germany.","('Canada', 'GPE'), ('this day', 'DATE'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"Causes which checked the progress of the Germans
 Such was the situation, and such were the manners, of the
 ancient Germans.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"Civil dissentions of Germany
 II.","('Germany', 'GPE')"
"Conscious pride
 taught the German females to suppress every tender emotion
 that stood in competition with honour, and the first honour
 of the sex has ever been that of chastity.","('German', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
Distinction of the German tribes,"('German', 'NORP')"
"During
 the civil wars that followed the death of Nero, that artful
 and intrepid Batavian, whom his enemies condescended to
 compare with Hannibal and Sertorius,   (75) formed a great
 design of freedom and ambition.","('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Batavian', 'PERSON'), ('Hannibal', 'PERSON'), ('Sertorius', 'PERSON'), ('75', 'DATE')"
"During her
 progress the sound of war was hushed, quarrels were
 suspended, arms laid aside, and the restless Germans had an
 opportunity of tasting the blessings of peace and harmony.
   (65)","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('65', 'CARDINAL')"
"Eight Batavian cohorts,
 renowned in the wars of Britain and Italy, repaired to his
 standard.","('Eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('Batavian', 'NORP'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Every quarrel among the
 Germans was fomented by the intrigues of Rome; and every
 plan of union and public good was defeated by the stronger
 bias of private jealousy and interest.  (81)","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Extent of Germany
 Ancient Germany, excluding from its independent limits the
 province westward of the Rhine, which had submitted to the
 Roman yoke, extended itself over a third part of Europe.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"Fainting armies of Germans have
 more than once been driven back upon the enemy by the
 generous despair of the women who dreaded death much less
 than servitude.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"For the Germans always met in arms, and it
 was constantly to be dreaded lest an irregular multitude,
 inflamed with faction and strong liquors, should use those
 arms to enforce, as well as to declare, their furious
 resolves.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"From Sweden (which formed
 so considerable a part of ancient Germany) the Greeks
 themselves derived their alphabetical characters, their
 astronomy, and their religion.","('Sweden', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"Germany was divided into more than
 forty independent states; and even in each state the union
 of the several tribes was extremely loose and precarious.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('more than\r\n forty', 'CARDINAL')"
"Gold, silver, and iron were extremely scarce in Germany.","('Germany', 'GPE')"
"He fixed generals of ability in the several
 stations of attack, and assumed in person the conduct of the most important province on the Upper Danube.","('the Upper Danube', 'LOC')"
"He introduced an army of Germans into Gaul,
 prevailed on the powerful cities of Treves and Langres to
 embrace his cause, defeated the legions, destroyed their
 fortified camps, and employed against the Romans the
 military knowledge which he had acquired in their service.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Treves', 'LOC'), ('Langres', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"He is found on the rock of Spitzberg, within ten degrees of the Pole; he seems to delight in the snows of Lapland and Siberia; but at present he cannot subsist, much less multiply, in any country to the south of the Baltic.  (4)","('Spitzberg', 'LOC'), ('ten degrees', 'QUANTITY'), ('Pole', 'LOC'), ('Lapland', 'LOC'), ('Siberia', 'LOC'), ('Baltic', 'LOC'), ('4', 'CARDINAL')"
"If the day was irrecoverably lost, they well
 knew how to deliver themselves and their children, with
 their own hands, from an insulting victor  (61) .","('the day', 'DATE'), ('61', 'CARDINAL')"
"In
 their primitive state of simplicity and independence the
 Germans were surveyed by the discerning eye, and delineated
 by the masterly pencil, of Tacitus, the first of historians
 who applied the science of philosophy to the study of facts.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"In a much wider extent of country, the geographer
 Ptolemy could discover no more than ninety places, which he
 decorates with the name of cities;  (18) though according to
 our ideas, they would but ill deserve that splendid title.","('Ptolemy', 'PERSON'), ('no more than ninety', 'CARDINAL'), ('18', 'CARDINAL')"
"In great monarchies
 millions of obedient subjects pursue their useful
 occupations in peace and obscurity.","('millions', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the course of this introductory chapter, we have confined
 ourselves to the general outlines of the manners of Germany,
 without attempting to describe or to distinguish the various
 tribes which filled the great country in the time of Caesar,
 of Tacitus or of Ptolemy.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('Ptolemy', 'PERSON')"
"In the faith of soldiers (and
 such were the Germans) cowardice is the most unpardonable of
 sins.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"In the most
 inclement winter, the hardy German was satisfied with a
 scanty garment made of the skin of some animal .","('the most\r\n inclement winter', 'DATE'), ('German', 'NORP')"
"In the remote
 darkness of the north, the ancients imperfectly described a frozen ocean that lay beyond the Baltic Sea, and beyond the Peninsula, or islands,  (1) of Scandinavia.","('the Baltic Sea', 'LOC'), ('Peninsula', 'LOC'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Scandinavia', 'LOC')"
"In the time of Caesar, the reindeer, as well as the elk and the wild bull, was a native of the Hercynian forest, which then overshadowed a great part of Germany and Poland.   (5)","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Hercynian', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Poland', 'GPE'), ('5', 'CARDINAL')"
"It expired with
 the war, and in time of peace the German tribes acknowledged
 not any supreme chief.  (47)","('German', 'NORP')"
"It is difficult to ascertain, and easy to exaggerate, the
 influence of the climate of ancient Germany over the minds
 and bodies of the natives.","('Germany', 'GPE')"
"It is impossible for us to determine whether this hasty confederation was formed by necessity, by reason, or by passion; but we may rest assured
 that the barbarians were neither allured by the indolence, nor provoked by the ambition, of the Roman monarch.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It was in the hour of battle, or in the
 feast of victory, that the bards celebrated the glory of
 heroes of ancient days, the ancestors of those warlike
 chieftains who listened with transport to their artless but
 animated strains.","('the hour', 'TIME')"
"Its
 barbarous inhabitants wanted both skill and patience to
 investigate those rich veins of silver, which have so
 liberally rewarded the attention of the princes of Brunswick
 and Saxony.","('Brunswick', 'GPE'), ('Saxony', 'GPE')"
"Many writers have supposed, and
 most have allowed, though, as it should seem, without any
 adequate proof, that the rigorous cold of the North was
 favourable to long life and generative vigour, that the
 women were more fruitful, and the human species more
 prolific, than in warmer or more temperate climates.  (8)","('North', 'LOC'), ('8', 'CARDINAL')"
"Modern Germany
 is said to contain about two thousand three hundred walled
 towns.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('about two thousand three hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"Money, in a
 word, is the most universal incitement, iron the most
 powerful instrument, of human industry; and it is very
 difficult to conceive by what means a people, neither
 actuated by the one nor seconded by the other, could emerge
 from the grossest barbarism.  (29)","('29', 'CARDINAL')"
"Neither stone, nor brick, nor
 tiles, were employed in these slight habitations.  (23)","('23', 'CARDINAL')"
"Of that delightful region
 (for such it appeared to the eyes of a native) the Atlantis
 of Plato, the country of the Hyperboreans, the gardens of
 the Hesperides, the Fortunate Islands, and even the Elysian
 Fields, were all but faint and imperfect transcripts.","('Atlantis', 'LOC'), ('Plato', 'LOC'), ('Hyperboreans', 'NORP'), ('Hesperides', 'LOC'), ('the Fortunate Islands', 'LOC'), ('the Elysian\r\n Fields', 'LOC')"
"Of these
 judicious critics, one of the most entertaining was Olaus
 Rudbeck, professor in the University of Upsal.  (15)","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Olaus\r\n Rudbeck', 'PERSON'), ('the University of Upsal', 'ORG'), ('15', 'CARDINAL')"
"Of these arts, the ancient Germans were wretchedly
 destitute.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"On a narrow basis of acknowledged truth an immense
 but rude superstructure of fable has been erected, and the
 wild Irishman, (13)  as well as the wild Tartar, (14) could point out
 the individual son of Japhet, from whose loins his ancestors
 were lineally descended.","('Irishman', 'NORP'), ('13', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tartar', 'NORP'), ('14', 'DATE'), ('Japhet', 'PERSON')"
"On the frequent rebellions of the Quadi and Marcomanni, the irritated emperor resolved to reduce their country into the form of a province.","('Quadi', 'NORP'), ('Marcomanni', 'NORP')"
"On the west,
 ancient Germany was divided by the Rhine from the Gallic,
 and on the south by the Danube from the Illyrian, provinces
 of the empire.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Illyrian', 'LOC')"
"Princes were, however, appointed
 in the general assembly, to administer justice, or rather to
 compose differences,  (48) in their respective districts.","('48', 'CARDINAL')"
"Some applause has been hastily bestowed on the
 sublime notion, entertained by that people, of the Deity,
 whom they neither confined within the walls of a temple, nor
 represented by any human figure; but when we recollect that
 the Germans were unskilled in architecture, and totally
 unacquainted with the art of sculpture, we shall readily
 assign the true reason of a scruple which arose not so much
 from a superiority of reason as from a want of ingenuity.","('Deity', 'PERSON'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
Some ingenious writers  (2) have suspected that Europe was much colder formerly than it is at present; and the most ancient descriptions of the climate of Germany tend exceedingly to confirm their theory.,"('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"Some of these interpreters of fate, such as
 Velleda, in the Batavian war, governed, in the name of the
 deity, the fiercest nations of Germany.  (58)","('Velleda', 'PERSON'), ('the Batavian war', 'EVENT'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('58', 'CARDINAL')"
"Some tribes of the north seem to have embraced
 the doctrine of transmigration,   (69) others imagined a gross
 paradise of immortal drunkenness.  (70)","('69', 'CARDINAL'), ('70', 'CARDINAL')"
"Some tribes, however, on the coast of the Baltic, acknowledged the authority of kings, though without relinquishing the rights of men;  (43) but in the far greater
 part of Germany, the form of government was a democracy
 tempered indeed, and controlled, not so much by general and
 positive laws, as by the occasional ascendant of birth or
 valour, of eloquence or superstition.  (44)","('Baltic', 'LOC'), ('43', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"Sometimes, indeed, these important
 questions were previously considered and prepared in a more
 select council of the principal chieftains.   (45)","('45', 'CARDINAL')"
"Sweden, which now supplies Europe with iron, was
 equally ignorant of its own riches; and the appearance of
 the arms of the Germans furnished a sufficient proof how
 little iron they were able to bestow on what they must have
 deemed the noblest use of that metal.","('Sweden', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"THE government and religion of Persia have deserved some
 notice from their connection with the decline and fall of
 the Roman empire.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"That singular order of
 men has most deservedly attracted the notice of all who have
 attempted to investigate the antiquities of the Celts, the
 Scandinavians, and the Germans.","('Celts', 'NORP'), ('Scandinavians', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"The
 Germans treated their women with esteem and confidence,
 consulted them on every occasion of importance, and fondly
 believed that in their breasts resided a sanctity and wisdom
 more than human.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"The
 magistrates might deliberate and persuade, the people only
 could resolve and execute; and the resolutions of the
 Germans were for the most part hasty and violent.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"The
 reindeer are very numerous, the ground is covered with deep
 and lasting snow, and the great river of St. Laurence is
 regularly frozen, in a season when the waters of the Seine
 and the Thames are usually free from ice.  (7)","('St. Laurence', 'FAC'), ('a season', 'DATE'), ('Seine', 'LOC'), ('Thames', 'LOC')"
"The Batavians still
 continued to occupy the islands of the Rhine,  (76) the allies
 not the servants of the Roman monarchy.","('Batavians', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('76', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The German huts, open on
 every side to the eye of indiscretion or jealousy, were a
 better safeguard of conjugal fidelity than the walls, the
 bolts, and the eunuchs of a Persian harem.","('German', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The German or Swedish detachment (which marched, if
 I am not mistaken, under the command of Askenaz, the son of
 Gomer, the son of Japhet) distinguished itself by a more
 than common diligence in the prosecution of this great work.","('German', 'NORP'), ('Swedish', 'NORP'), ('Askenaz', 'PERSON'), ('Gomer', 'PERSON'), ('Japhet', 'PERSON')"
"The German priests, improving this favourable
 temper of their countrymen, had assumed a jurisdiction, even
 in temporal concerns, which the magistrate could not venture
 to exercise; and the haughty warrior patiently submitted to
 the lash of correction, when it was inflicted, not by any
 human power, but by the immediate order of the god of war.
   (64)","('German', 'NORP'), ('64', 'CARDINAL')"
"The German tribes were
 voluntary and fluctuating associations of soldiers, almost
 of savages.","('German', 'NORP')"
"The German tribes were contented with this
 rude but liberal outline of political society.","('German', 'NORP')"
"The Germans abandoned their immense forests to the
 exercise of hunting, employed in pasturage the most
 considerable part of their lands, bestowed on the small
 remainder a rude and careless cultivation, and then accused
 the scantiness and sterility of a country that refused to
 maintain the multitude of its inhabitants.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
The Germans ignorant of letters;,"('Germans', 'NORP')"
"The Germans respected only those duties which they imposed
 on themselves.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"The Germans were not possessed of their varied
 resources.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"The Germans, in the age of Tacitus, were
 unacquainted with the use of letters;   (16) and the use of
 letters is the principal circumstance that distinguishes a
 civilized people from a herd of savages incapable of
 knowledge or reflection.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('16', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Quadi and the Marcomanni,  (83) who had taken the lead in the war, were the most severely punished in its catastrophe.","('Quadi', 'PERSON'), ('Marcomanni', 'PERSON'), ('83', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Tuscan who betrayed his
 country to the Celtic nations attracted them into Italy by
 the prospect of the rich fruits and delicious wines, the
 productions of a happier climate.  (34)","('Tuscan', 'NORP'), ('Celtic', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('34', 'CARDINAL')"
"The assembly of the warriors of the tribe was
 convened at stated seasons or on sudden emergencies.","('seasons', 'DATE')"
"The awful distance preserved by
 their neighbours attested the terror of their arms, and in
 some measure defended them from the danger of unexpected
 incursions.  (77)
fomented by the policy of Rome  These sentiments, less worthy of the humanity than of the
 patriotism of Tacitus, express the invariable maxims of the
 policy of his countrymen.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"The barbarians, who often chose that severe season for their inroads, transported, without apprehension or danger, their numerous armies, their cavalry, and their heavy wagons, over a vast and solid bridge of ice.  (3) Modern ages have not presented an instance of a like phenomenon.","('that severe season', 'DATE'), ('3', 'CARDINAL')"
"The climate of ancient Germany had been mollified, and the
 soil fertilised, by the labour of ten centuries from the
 time of Charlemagne.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('ten centuries', 'DATE'), ('Charlemagne', 'PERSON')"
"The comparative view of the powers of the magistrates, in
 two remarkable instances, is alone sufficient to represent
 the whole system of German manners.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('German', 'NORP')"
"The consecrated standards, long revered in the groves of
 superstition, were placed in the front of the battle;  (67) and
 the hostile army was devoted with dire execrations to the
 gods of war and of thunder.  (68)","('67', 'CARDINAL'), ('68', 'CARDINAL')"
"The contest was too unequal, till the
 introduction of luxury had enervated the vigour, and a
 spirit of disobedience and sedition had relaxed the
 discipline, of the Roman armies.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The distinctions of the ferocious invaders
 were perpetually varied by themselves, and confounded by the
 astonished subjects of the Roman empire.  (86)
Numbers
 Wars, and the administration of public affairs are the
 principal subjects of history; but the number of persons
 interested in these busy scenes is very different according
 to the different condition of mankind.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('86', 'CARDINAL')"
"The eastern frontier was faintly marked
 by the mutual fears of the Germans and the Sarmatians, and
 was often confounded by the mixture of warring and
 confederating tribes of the two nations.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The face of a German army
 displayed their poverty of iron.","('German', 'NORP')"
"The former,
 by reading and reflection, multiplies his own experience,
 and lives in distant ages and remote countries; whilst the
 latter, rooted to a single spot, and confined to a few years
 of existence, surpasses, but very little, his fellow
 labourer the ox in the exercise of his mental faculties.","('a few years', 'DATE')"
"The game of various sorts, with which the forests
 of Germany were plentifully stocked, supplied its
 inhabitants with food and exercise.  (25)","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('25', 'CARDINAL')"
"The general complaints of intense frost, and eternal winter, are perhaps little to be regarded, since we have no method of reducing to the accurate standard of the thermometer the feelings or the expressions of an orator, born in the happier regions of Greece or Asia.","('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The general conspiracy which terrified the Romans under the
 reign of Marcus Antoninus comprehended almost all the
 nations of Germany, and even Sarmatia, from the mouth of the
 Rhine to that of the Danube.  (82)","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Marcus Antoninus', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Sarmatia', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('82', 'CARDINAL')"
"The honourable gifts, bestowed by the chief on his
 brave companions, have been supposed, by an ingenious
 writer, to contain the first rudiments of the fiefs,
 distributed, after the conquest of the Roman provinces by
 the barbarian lords among their vassals with a similar duty
 of homage and military service.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The introduction of
 barbarian auxiliaries into those armies was a measure
 attended with very obvious dangers, as it might gradually
 instruct the Germans in the arts of war and of policy.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"The irregular divisions, and the
 restless motions, of the people of Germany dazzle our
 imagination and seem to multiply their numbers.","('Germany', 'GPE')"
"The last century abounded with
 antiquarians of profound learning and easy faith, who by the
 dim light of legends and traditions, of conjectures and
 etymologies, conducted the great-grand-children of Noah from
 the tower of Babel to the extremities of the globe.","('The last century', 'DATE'), ('Noah', 'PERSON'), ('Babel', 'FAC')"
"The lazy warrior, destitute of
 every art that might employ his leisure hours, consumed his
 days and nights in the animal gratifications of sleep and
 food.","('days and nights', 'DATE')"
"The learned Rudbeck allows the
 family of Noah a few years to multiply from eight to about
 twenty thousand persons.","('Rudbeck', 'PRODUCT'), ('Noah', 'PERSON'), ('a few years', 'DATE'), ('eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('about\r\n twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The money and negotiations of Rome insinuated themselves
 into the heart of Germany; and every art of seduction was
 used with dignity to conciliate those nations whom their
 proximity to the Rhine or Danube might render the most
 useful friends as well as the most troublesome enemies.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"The most civilised nations of modern
 Europe issued from the woods of Germany, and in the rude
 institutions of those barbarians we may still distinguish
 the original principles of our present laws and manners.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"The most formidable states of Germany
 affected to encompass their territories with a wide frontier
 of solitude and devastation.","('Germany', 'GPE')"
"The nations
 who dwelt towards the North clothed themselves in furs; and
 the women manufactured for their own use a coarse kind of
 linen.  (24)","('North', 'LOC'), ('24', 'CARDINAL')"
"The northern hive cast its swarms over the greatest part of
 Europe, Africa, and Asia; and (to use the author's metaphor)
 the blood circulated from the extremities to the heart.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The only temples in Germany were dark and ancient groves,
 consecrated by the reverence of succeeding generations.","('Germany', 'GPE')"
"The religious system of the Germans (if the wild opinions of
 savages can deserve that name) was dictated by their wants,
 their fears, and their ignorance.  (62)","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"The same extent of ground which at
 present maintains, in ease and plenty, a million of
 husbandmen and artificers, was unable to supply an hundred
 thousand lazy warriors with the simple necessaries of life.
   (36)","('a million', 'CARDINAL'), ('an hundred\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('36', 'CARDINAL')"
"The severity of a winter
 campaign, that chilled the courage of the Roman troops, was
 scarcely felt by these hardy children of the North,  (10) who
 in their turn were unable to resist the summer heats, and
 dissolved away in languor and sickness under the beams of an
 Italian sun.  (11)
Origin of the Germans","('winter', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"The sound that
 summoned the German to arms was grateful to his ear.","('German', 'NORP')"
"The state of Germany till the invasion of the Barbarians, in the time of the emperor Decius.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Decius', 'PERSON')"
"The strength of ancient Germany appears formidable when
 we consider the effects that might have been produced by its
 united effort.","('Germany', 'GPE')"
"The truce of God, so often and so ineffectually
 proclaimed by the clergy of the eleventh century, was an
 obvious imitation of this ancient custom.  (66)
in war
 But the influence of religion was far more powerful to
 inflame than to moderate the fierce passions of the Germans.","('the eleventh century', 'DATE'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"The unknown symbol
 of the Earth, covered with a thick veil, was placed on a
 carriage drawn by cows; and in this manner the goddess,
 whose common residence was in the isle of Rugen, visited
 several adjacent tribes of her worshippers.","('Earth', 'LOC'), ('Rugen', 'PERSON')"
"The various
 transactions of peace and war had introduced some Roman
 coins (chiefly silver) among the borderers of the Rhine and
 Danube; but the more distant tribes were absolutely
 unacquainted with the use of money, carried on their
 confined traffic by the exchange of commodities, and prized
 their rude earthen vessels as of equal value with the silver
 vases, the presents of Rome to their princes and
 ambassadors.   (28)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('28', 'CARDINAL')"
"The view of arms and of danger heightened
 the effect of the military song; and the passions which it
 tended to excite, the desire of fame and the contempt of
 death, were the habitual sentiments of a German mind.  (71)","('German', 'NORP'), ('71', 'CARDINAL')"
"The wide extent of country might very
 possibly contain a million of warriors, as all who were of
 age to bear arms were of a temper to use them.","('million', 'CARDINAL')"
"Their edifices were not even
 contiguous, or formed into regular villages;   (22) each
 barbarian fixed his independent dwelling on the spot to
 which a plain, a wood or a stream of fresh water had induced
 him to give the preference.","('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"Their monstrous herds
 of cattle, less remarkable indeed for their beauty than for
 their utility,  (26) formed the principal object of their
 wealth.","('26', 'CARDINAL')"
"Their progress was checked by their want of
 arms and discipline, and their fury was diverted by the
 intestine divisions of ancient Germany.","('Germany', 'GPE')"
"Their secret gloom, the imagined residence of an invisible
 power, by presenting no distinct object of fear or worship,
 impressed the mind with a still deeper sense of religious
 horror;  (63) and the priests, rude and illiterate as they
 were, had been taught by experience the use of every
 artifice that could preserve and fortify impressions so well
 suited to their own interest.","('63', 'CARDINAL')"
"Their taste for strong liquors
 Strong beer, a liquor extracted with very little art from
 wheat or barley, and corrupted (as it is strongly expressed
 by Tacitus) into a certain semblance of wine, was sufficient
 for the gross purposes of German debauchery.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('German', 'NORP')"
"There is not anywhere upon the globe a large tract of
 country which we have discovered destitute of inhabitants,
 or whose first population can be fixed with any degree of
 historical certainty.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"These conditions are,
 however, very repugnant to the maxims of the ancient
 Germans, who delighted in mutual presents; but without
 either imposing, or accepting, the weight of obligations.  (55)
German chastity
""In the days of chivalry, or more properly of romance, all
 the men were brave, and all the women were chaste ;""  and notwithstanding the latter of these virtues is acquired and preserved with much more difficulty than the former, it is ascribed, almost without exception, to the wives of the ancient Germans.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"These immense woods have been gradually cleared, which intercepted from the earth the rays
 of the sun.   (6)","('6', 'CARDINAL')"
"They
 attempted not, however (as has since been executed with so
 much success), to naturalise the vine on the banks of the
 Rhine and Danube; nor did they endeavour to procure by
 industry the materials of an advantageous commerce.","('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"They adored the great
 visible objects and agents of nature, the Sun and the Moon,
 the Fire and the Earth; together with those imaginary
 deities, who were supposed to preside over the most
 important occupations of human life.","('Sun', 'LOC'), ('Moon', 'LOC'), ('Earth', 'LOC')"
"They delight in
 sloth, they detest tranquillity.   (30)","('30', 'CARDINAL')"
"They were commanded to retire five miles  (84) from their own banks of the Danube, and to deliver up the flower of the youth, who were immediately sent into Britain, a remote island, where they might be secure as hostages, and useful as soldiers.","('five miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('84', 'CARDINAL'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
This dangerous invasion required all the firmness and vigilance of Marcus.,"('Marcus', 'PERSON')"
"This formidable league, however, the only one that appears in the two first
 centuries of the Imperial history, was entirely dissipated, without leaving any traces behind in Germany.","('the two first\r\n centuries', 'DATE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"This institution, however it might accidentally weaken the several republics, invigorated the general character of the Germans, and even
 ripened amongst them all the virtues of which barbarians are
 susceptible; the faith and valour, the hospitality and the
 courtesy, so conspicuous long afterwards in the ages of
 chivalry.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
"Though the horses of Germany were neither
 beautiful, swift, nor practised in the skilful evolutions of
 the Roman manege, several of the nations obtained renown by
 their cavalry; but, in general, the principal strength of
 the Germans consisted in their infantry,  (73) which was drawn
 up in several deep columns, according to the distinction of
tribes and families.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('73', 'CARDINAL')"
"To
 solicit by labour what might be ravished by arms was
 esteemed unworthy of the German spirit.  (33)","('German', 'NORP'), ('33', 'CARDINAL')"
"To each was assigned, by the public, a
 guard and a council of an hundred persons and the first of
 the princes appears to have enjoyed a pre-eminence of rank
 and honour which sometimes tempted the Romans to compliment
 him with the regal title.","('an hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"To the names of Mariana and of
 Machiavel,  (39) we can oppose the equal names of Robertson and
 Hume.  (40)
German freedom
 A warlike nation like the Germans, without either cities,
 letters, arts, or money, found some compensation for this
 savage state in the enjoyment of liberty.","('Mariana', 'PERSON'), ('Machiavel', 'PERSON'), ('39', 'DATE'), ('Robertson', 'PERSON'), ('Hume', 'PERSON'), ('40', 'CARDINAL'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
Transient union against Marcus Antoninus,"('Marcus Antoninus', 'PERSON')"
"We
 may assert, with greater confidence, that the keen air of
 Germany formed the large and masculine limbs of the natives,
 who were, in general, of a more lofty stature than the
 people of the South,   (9) gave them a kind of strength better
 adapted to violent exertions than to patient labour, and
 inspired them with constitutional bravery, which is the
 result of nerves and spirits.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('South', 'LOC'), ('9', 'CARDINAL')"
"We are only
 at a loss to conceive by what means riches and despotism
 could penetrate into a remote corner of the North, and
 extinguish the generous flame that blazed with such
 fierceness on the frontier of the Roman provinces: or how
 the ancestors of those Danes and Norwegians, so
 distinguished in latter ages by their unconquered spirit,
 could thus tamely resign the great character of German
 liberty.  (42)","('North', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Danes', 'NORP'), ('Norwegians', 'NORP'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('42', 'CARDINAL')"
"We may allow with safety, and perhaps
 with truth, that ancient Germany was not originally peopled
 by any foreign colonies already formed into a political
 society;  (12) but that the name and nation received their
 existence from the gradual union of some wandering savages
 of the Hercynian woods.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hercynian', 'NORP')"
"We may easily discover that Tacitus indulges an honest pleasure in the contrast of barbarian virtue with the dissolute conduct of the Roman ladies; yet there are
 some striking circumstances that give an air of truth, or at
 least of probability, to the conjugal faith and chastity of
 the Germans.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
"We may recollect how often the diets of Poland
 have been polluted with blood, and the more numerous party
 has been compelled to yield to the more violent and
 seditious.  (46)","('Poland', 'GPE')"
"We shall occasionally mention the Scythian
 or Sarmatian tribes, which, with their arms and horses,
 their flocks and herbs, their wives and families wandered
 over the immense plains which spread themselves from the
 Caspian Sea to the Vistulay from the confines of Persia to
 those of Germany.","('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Sarmatian', 'NORP'), ('the\r\n Caspian Sea', 'LOC'), ('Vistulay', 'LOC'), ('Persia', 'LOC'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"We shall therefore
 content ourselves with observing, and indeed with repeating,
 some of the most important circumstances of climate, of
 manners, and of institutions, which rendered the wild
 barbarians of Germany such formidable enemies to the Roman
 power.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"When Tacitus considered the purity of
 the German blood, and the forbidding aspect of the country,
 he was disposed to pronounce those barbarians Indigenae, or
 natives of the soil.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('Indigenae', 'NORP')"
"When at length, after an obstinate struggle, he yielded to
 the power of the empire, Civilis secured himself and his
 country by an honourable treaty.","('Civilis', 'PERSON')"
"When the return
 of famine severely admonished them of the importance of the
 arts, the national distress was sometimes alleviated by the
 emigration of a third, perhaps, or a fourth part of their
 youth.","('a third', 'CARDINAL'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL')"
"When we recollect the complete armour of the Roman soldiers,
 their discipline, exercises, evolutions, fortified camps,
 and military engines, it appears a just matter of surprise
 how the naked and unassisted valour of the barbarians could
 dare to encounter in the field the strength of the legions,
 and the various troops of the auxiliaries which seconded
 their operations.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"and of discipline Impatient of fatigue or delay, these half-armed warriors rushed to battle with dissonant shouts and disordered ranks; and sometimes, by the effort of native valour, prevailed over the constrained and more artificial
 bravery of the Roman mercenaries.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
