Sentence,Entities
"""Wheresoever the Roman conquers, he inhabits,"" (30)  is a very just observation of Seneca, confirmed by history and experience.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('30', 'CARDINAL'), ('Seneca', 'PERSON')"
(14),"('14', 'CARDINAL')"
(16),"('16', 'CARDINAL')"
"(19)
Freedom of Rome.","('19', 'CARDINAL'), ('Freedom of Rome', 'ORG')"
"(3) Fear, 
 gratitude, and curiosity, a dream or an omen, a singular
 disorder, or a distant journey, perpetually disposed him to
 multiply the articles of his belief, and to enlarge the list
(5),"('5', 'CARDINAL')"
(53),"('53', 'CARDINAL')"
(55),"('55', 'CARDINAL')"
"1. Almost all the flowers, the Introduction of fruits etc. herbs, and the fruits, that grow in our European gardens, are of foreign extraction, which, in many cases, is betrayed even by their names: the apple was a native of Italy, and when the Romans had tasted the richer flavour of the apricot, the peach, the pomegranate, the citron, and the orange, they contented themselves with applying to all these new fruits the common denomination of apple, discriminating them from each other by the additional epithet of their
 country.","('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"2. In the time of Homer, the vine grew wild in the  The vine.","('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Homer', 'PERSON')"
"A freedman, under the reign 
 of Augustus, though his fortune had suffered great losses in
 the civil wars, left behind him three thousand six hundred
 yoke of oxen, two hundred and fifty thousand head of smaller
 cattle, and, what was almost included in the description of
 cattle, four thousand one hundred and sixteen slaves. (61)","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('three thousand six hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('two hundred and fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('four thousand one hundred and sixteen', 'CARDINAL')"
"A nation
 of Romans was gradually formed in the provinces, by the
 double expedient of introducing colonies, and of admitting
 the most faithful and deserving of the provincials to the
 freedom of Rome.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"A republic of gods of such opposite tempers and
 interest required, in every system, the moderating hand of a
 supreme magistrate, who, by the progress of knowledge and
 flattery, was gradually invested with the sublime
 perfections of an Eternal Parent, and an Omnipotent Monarch.
 (4)","('Omnipotent Monarch', 'ORG'), ('4', 'CARDINAL')"
"A thousand years afterwards, Italy could boast, that of the fourscore most generous and celebrated wines, more than two-thirds were produced from her soil.","('A thousand years afterwards', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('more than two-thirds', 'CARDINAL')"
"According to the rigour of law, the emperor might
 have asserted his claim, and the prudent Atticus prevented,
 by a rank confession, the officiousness of informers.","('Atticus', 'PERSON')"
"Against such internal enemies, whose desperate
 insurrections had more than once reduced the republic to the
 brink of destruction, (47) the most severe regulations, (48) and 
 the most cruel treatment, seemed almost justified by the
 great law of self-preservation.","('47', 'CARDINAL')"
"Against such unworthy adversaries, Cicero
 condescended to employ the arms of reason and eloquence; but
 the satire of Lucian was a much more adequate, as well as
 more efficacious weapon.","('Cicero', 'PERSON'), ('Lucian', 'PERSON')"
"All these cities were connected with each other, and with
 the capital, by the public highways, which issuing from the
 Forum of Rome, traversed Italy, pervaded the provinces, and
 were terminated only by the frontiers of the empire.","('the\r\n Forum of Rome', 'ORG'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Almost every 
 profession, either liberal (57) or mechanical, might be found 
 in the household of an opulent senator.","('57', 'CARDINAL')"
"Amber was
 brought over land from the shores of the Baltic to the
 Danube; and the barbarians were astonished at the price
 which they received in exchange for so useless a commodity.
 (101)","('Amber', 'PERSON'), ('Baltic', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"Among a crowd of these private
 benefactors, we may select Herodes Atticus, an Athenian
 citizen, who lived in the age of the Antonines.","('Herodes Atticus', 'PERSON'), ('Athenian', 'NORP'), ('Antonines', 'NORP')"
"Among the innumerable monuments of architecture constructed
 by the Romans, how many have escaped the notice of history,
 how few have resisted the ravages of time and barbarism!","('Romans', 'NORP')"
Ancient Italy is said to have contained eleven hundred and In Italy.,"('Italy', 'GPE'), ('eleven hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"And
 yet even the majestic ruins that are still scattered over
 Italy and the provinces, would be sufficient to prove that
 those countries were once the seat of a polite and powerful
 empire.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"And
 yet, if we compare the proportion between gold and silver,
 as it stood in the time of Pliny, and as it was fixed in the
 reign of Constantine, we shall discover within that period a
 very considerable increase. (108)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('108', 'CARDINAL')"
"As the natives of Arabia and India were
Gold and silver  contented with the productions and manufactures of their own
 country, silver, on the side of the Romans, was the
 principal, if not the only instrument of commerce.","('Arabia', 'GPE'), ('India', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Asia was covered with Greek cities, and the long reign of
 the Macedonian kings had introduced a silent revolution into
 Syria and Egypt.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Macedonian', 'NORP'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
At Rome.,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
"At a small distance from
 thence was situated the Forum of Trajan.","('the Forum of Trajan', 'FAC')"
"Augustus was accustomed to boast that he had
 found his capital of brick, and that he had left it of
 marble.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"Avarice and taste very frequently despoiled the vanquished nations of the elegant statues of their gods, and  the rich ornaments of their temples; (10) but, in the exercise of the religion which they derived from their ancestors,
 they uniformly experienced the indulgence, and even
 protection, of the Roman conquerors.","('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But
 the equitable Nerva, who then filled the throne, refused to
 accept any part of it, and commanded him to use, without
 scruple, the present of fortune.","('Nerva', 'ORG')"
"But if
 the emperors were the first, they were not the only
 architects of their dominions.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But in the execution
 of the work the charge amounted to more than double the
 estimate, and the officers of the revenue began to murmur,
 till the generous Atticus silenced their complaints, by
 requesting that he might be permitted to take upon himself
 the whole additional expense. (68)","('more than double', 'CARDINAL'), ('Atticus', 'PERSON')"
"But the elegant amusements
 of the Romans were not suffered to interfere with their
 sound maxims of policy.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
But the firm  edifice of Roman power was raised and preserved by the wisdom of ages.,"('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But the obedience of the Roman world
 was uniform, voluntary, and permanent.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But the priests 
 themselves, their gods and their altars, subsisted in
 peaceful obscurity till the final destruction of Paganism.
 (12)","('Paganism', 'NORP'), ('12', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the provincials of
 Rome, trained by a uniform artificial foreign education,
 were engaged in a very unequal competition with those bold
 ancients, who, by expressing their genuine feelings in their
 native tongue, had already occupied every place of honour.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But the same salutary maxims
 of government, which had secured the peace and obedience of
 Italy, were extended to the most distant conquests.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"But when the popular assemblies had been
 suppressed by the administration of the emperors, the
 conquerors were distinguished from the vanquished nations,
 only as the first and most honourable order of subjects; and
 their increase, however rapid, was no longer exposed to the
 same dangers.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But when the principal
 nations of Europe, Asia, and Africa, were united under the
 laws of one sovereign, the source of foreign supplies flowed
 with much less abundance, and the Romans were reduced to the
 milder but more tedious method of propagation.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"But, after weighing with attention every
 circumstance which could influence the balance, it seems
 probable that there existed, in the time of Claudius, about
 twice as many provincials as there were citizens, of either
 sex, and of every age; and that the slaves were at least
 equal in number to the free inhabitants of the Roman world.","('Claudius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"By the
 periodical assistance of the Monsoons, they traversed the
 ocean in about forty days.","('Monsoons', 'NORP'), ('about forty days', 'DATE')"
"Carthage itself rose with new splendour from its ashes; and that capital, as well as
 Capua and Corinth, soon recovered all the advantages which
 can be separated from independent sovereignty.","('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Capua', 'GPE'), ('Corinth', 'GPE')"
Degeneracy,"('Degeneracy', 'PERSON')"
Division of the Latin and Greek provinces.,"('Latin', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"Domestic peace and union were the natural consequences of
 the moderate and comprehensive policy embraced by the
 Romans.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"During 
 the most flourishing era of the Athenian commonwealth, the
 number of citizens gradually decreased from about thirty (21) 
 to twenty-one thousand. (22)","('Athenian', 'NORP'), ('about thirty (21', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty-one thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Eleven cities
 of Asia had once disputed the honour of dedicating a temple
 to Tiberius, and their respective merits were examined by
 the senate. (80)","('Eleven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Tiberius', 'GPE')"
"Every city in the 
 empire was justified in maintaining the purity of its
 ancient ceremonies; and the Roman senate, using the common
 privilege, sometimes interposed, to check this inundation of
 foreign rites.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Every year, about the time of the summer
 solstice, a fleet of a hundred and twenty vessels sailed
 from Myoshormos, a port of Egypt, on the Red Sea.","('summer', 'DATE'), ('a hundred and twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Myoshormos', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('the Red Sea', 'LOC')"
Example of Herodes Atticus.,"('Herodes Atticus', 'ORG')"
"Exhausted by the abuse of her
 strength, by America, and by superstition, her pride might
 possibly be confounded, if we required such a list of three
 hundred and sixty cities, as Pliny has exhibited under the
 reign of Vespasian. (77) III.","('America', 'GPE'), ('three\r\n hundred and sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pliny', 'PERSON'), ('Vespasian', 'PERSON'), ('77', 'CARDINAL')"
"Four of them were immediately rejected as unequal to the burden; and among these was Laodicea, whose
 splendour is still displayed in its ruins. (81)","('Four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Laodicea', 'ORG'), ('81', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the foot
 of the Alps to the extremity of Calabria, all the natives of
 Italy were born citizens of Rome.","('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Calabria', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"From this port, 
 which was only sixteen miles from the capital, a favourable
 breeze frequently carried vessels in seven days to the
 columns of Hercules.","('sixteen miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('seven days', 'DATE'), ('Hercules', 'PRODUCT')"
Gaul could Gaul and Spain.,"('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Spain', 'GPE')"
"General felicity 
 Notwithstanding the propensity of mankind to exalt the past  and to depreciate the present, the tranquil and prosperous state of the empire was warmly felt, and honestly confessed, by the provincials as well as Romans.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Had she always confined the distinction of Romans to
 the ancient families within the walls of the city, that
 immortal name would have been deprived of some of its
 noblest ornaments.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"He had obtained for his son Herod the prefecture of
 the free cities of Asia; and the young magistrate, observing
 that the town of Troas was indifferently supplied with
 water, obtained from the munificence of Hadrian three
 hundred myriads of drachms (about a hundred thousand pounds)
 for the construction of a new aqueduct.","('Herod', 'PERSON'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Troas', 'GPE'), ('three\r\n hundred myriads', 'QUANTITY'), ('about a hundred thousand pounds)', 'QUANTITY')"
"He was honoured with the consulship at Rome; but the
 greatest part of his life was spent in a philosophic
 retirement at Athens, and his adjacent villas; perpetually
 surrounded by sophists, who acknowledged, without
 reluctance, the superiority of a rich and generous rival. (69)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Athens', 'GPE')"
"Herod restored its ancient beauty and
 magnificence.","('Herod', 'PERSON')"
"His grandfather had suffered by the hands of justice,
 and Julius Atticus, his father, must have ended his life in
 poverty and contempt, had he not discovered an immense
 treasure buried under an old house, the last remains of his
 patrimony.","('Julius Atticus', 'PERSON')"
"Hope, the best comfort of our imperfect condition, was not
 denied to the Roman slave; and if he had any opportunity of
 rendering himself either useful or agreeable, he might very
 naturally expect that the diligence and fidelity of a few
 years would be rewarded with the inestimable gift of
 freedom.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('a few\r\n years', 'DATE')"
"Houses were everywhere erected at the distance only of five
 or six miles; each of them was constantly provided with
 forty horses, and by the help of these relays it was easy to
 travel an hundred miles in a day along the Roman roads. (89)","('five\r\n or six miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('forty', 'CARDINAL'), ('an hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"IT is not alone by the rapidity, or extent of conquest, that we should estimate the greatness of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"If such was the poverty of Laodicea, what must 
 have been the wealth of those cities, whose claim appeared
 preferable, and particularly of Pergamus, of Smyrna, and of
 Ephesus, who so long disputed with each other over the
 titular primacy of Asia. (83)","('Laodicea', 'GPE'), ('Pergamus', 'PERSON'), ('Smyrna', 'GPE'), ('Ephesus', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('83', 'CARDINAL')"
"If we
 carefully trace the distance from the wall of Antoninus to
 Rome, and from thence to Jerusalem, it will be found that
 the great chain of communication, from the north-west to the
 south-east point of the empire, was drawn out to the length
 of four thousand and eighty Roman miles. (85)","('Antoninus', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('four thousand and eighty Roman miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('85', 'CARDINAL')"
"If we turn our eyes towards the monarchies of Asia,
 we shall behold despotism in the centre, and weakness in the
 extremities; the collection of the revenue, or the
 administration of justice, enforced by the presence of an
 army - hostile barbarians established in the heart of the
 country, hereditary satraps usurping the dominion of the
 provinces, and subjects inclined to rebellion, though
 incapable of freedom.","('Asia', 'LOC')"
"If, on the contrary, we study the 
 growth of the Roman republic, we may discover, that,
 notwithstanding the incessant demands of wars and colonies,
 the citizens, who, in the first census of Servius Tullius,
 amounted to no more than eighty-three thousand, were
 multiplied, before the commencement of the social war, to
 the number of four hundred and sixty-three thousand men,
 able to bear arms in the service of their country. (23)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Servius Tullius', 'PERSON'), ('no more than eighty-three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('four hundred and sixty-three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('23', 'CARDINAL')"
"In Etruria, in Greece, (28) and in 
 Gaul, (29) it was the first care of the senate to dissolve 
 those dangerous confederacies, which taught mankind, that as
 the Roman arts prevailed by division, they might be resisted
 by union.","('Etruria', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('28', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('29', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the commonwealths of Athens and Rome, the modest
 simplicity of private houses announced the equal condition
 of freedom; whilst the sovereignty of the people was
 represented in the majestic edifices destined to the public
 use; (71) nor was this republican spirit totally extinguished 
 by the introduction of wealth and monarchy.","('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('71', 'CARDINAL'), ('republican', 'NORP')"
"In the more remote ages of
 antiquity, the world was unequally divided.","('the more remote ages of\r\n antiquity', 'DATE')"
"In the purest ages of the commonwealth, Cybele
 and Aesculapius had been invited by solemn embassies; (17) and 
 it was customary to tempt the protectors of besieged cities,
 by the promise of more distinguished honours than they
 possessed in their native country. (18)","('Cybele', 'PERSON'), ('Aesculapius', 'PERSON'), ('17', 'CARDINAL'), ('18', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the seventh summer after his passage of the Hellespont, Alexander erected the Macedonian trophies on the banks of the Hyphasis. (1) Within less than a century, the irresistible Zingis, and the Mogul princes of his race, spread their cruel devastations and transient empire from the sea of China to the confines of Egypt and Germany. (2)","('the seventh summer', 'DATE'), ('Hellespont', 'EVENT'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Macedonian', 'NORP'), ('Hyphasis', 'ORG'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('less than a century', 'DATE'), ('Zingis', 'PERSON'), ('Mogul', 'PERSON'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('2', 'CARDINAL')"
"In their manners and internal policy, the colonies formed a perfect representation of their great parent; and as they were soon endeared to the natives by the ties of friendship and alliances they effectually diffused a reverence for the Roman name, and a desire, which was seldom disappointed, of sharing, in due time, its honours and advantages. (32)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('32', 'CARDINAL')"
"In their pompous courts those princes
 united the elegance of Athens with the luxury of the East,
 and the example of the court was imitated, at an humble
 distance, by the higher ranks of their subjects.","('Athens', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"In this state of general security, the 
 leisure as well as opulence both of the prince and people
 were devoted to improve and to adorn the Roman empire.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It is a just though trite observation, that victorious Rome
 was herself subdued by the arts of Greece.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE')"
"It is natural to suppose that the greatest number, as well
 as the most considerable of the Roman edifices, were raised
 by the emperors who possessed so unbounded a command both of
 men and money.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It is not easy to conceive from what motives a spirit of
 persecution could introduce itself into the Roman councils.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It may not be unpleasing to
 collect a few scattered instances relative to that subject,
 without forgetting, however, that from the vanity of nations
 and the poverty of language, the vague appellation of city
 has been indifferently bestowed on Rome and upon Laurentum.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Laurentum', 'PERSON')"
"It was a
 complaint worthy of the gravity of the senate, that in the
 purchase of female ornaments, the wealth of the state was
 irrevocably given away to foreign and hostile nations. (106)","('106', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was by such institutions that the nations of the empire
 insensibly melted away into the Roman name and people.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It was diffused over the whole extent of their
 empire; the most northern tribes of Britons had acquired a
 taste for rhetoric; Homer as well as Virgil were transcribed
 and studied on the banks of the Rhine and Danube; and the
 most liberal rewards sought out the faintest glimmerings of
 literary merit. (110)","('Britons', 'NORP'), ('Homer', 'PERSON'), ('Virgil', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('110', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was discovered, on a very melancholy occasion,
 that four hundred slaves were maintained in a single palace
 of Rome. (59)","('four hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"It was indifferent to them what shape the
 folly of the multitude might choose to assume; and they
 approached, with the same inward contempt, and the same
 external reverence, the altars of the Libyan, the Olympian,
 or the Capitoline Jupiter. (8)","('Libyan', 'NORP'), ('Olympian', 'NORP'), ('the Capitoline Jupiter', 'PRODUCT'), ('8', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was six hundred feet in
 length, built entirely of white marble, capable of admitting
 the whole body of the people, and finished in four years,
 whilst Herod was president of the Athenian games.","('six hundred feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('four years', 'DATE'), ('Herod', 'PERSON'), ('Athenian', 'NORP')"
"It was surrounded
 with a lofty portico, in the form of a quadrangle, into
 which four triumphal arches opened a noble and spacious
 entrance: in the centre arose a column of marble, whose
 height, of one hundred and ten feet, denoted the elevation
 of the hill that had been cut away.","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred and ten feet', 'QUANTITY')"
"It was the duty of the Proconsul to supply their
 deficiencies, to direct their taste, and sometimes to
 moderate their emulation. (66)","('Proconsul', 'PRODUCT')"
"It would be
 almost impossible to enumerate all the articles, either of
 the animal or the vegetable reign, which were successively
 imported into Europe, from Asia and Egypt; (93) but it will not be unworthy of the dignity, and much less of the utility, of an historical work, slightly to touch on a few of the principal heads.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('93', 'CARDINAL')"
"Italy claimed the birth, or
 at least the residence, of the emperors and the senate. (26)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('26', 'CARDINAL')"
"Laodicea 
 collected a very considerable revenue from its flocks of
 sheep, celebrated for the fineness of their wool, and had
 received, a little before the contest, a legacy of above
 four hundred thousand pounds by the testament of a generous
 citizen. (82)","('Laodicea', 'ORG'), ('above\r\n four hundred thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"Many were the 
 cities of Gaul, Marseilles, Aries, Nismes, Narbonne,
 Thoulouse, Bourdeaux, Autun, Vienna, Lyons, Langres, and
 Treves, whose ancient condition might sustain an equal, and
 perhaps advantageous comparison with their present state.","('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Marseilles', 'GPE'), ('Aries', 'GPE'), ('Nismes', 'GPE'), ('Narbonne', 'GPE'), ('Thoulouse', 'GPE'), ('Bourdeaux', 'GPE'), ('Autun', 'GPE'), ('Vienna', 'GPE'), ('Lyons', 'GPE'), ('Langres', 'NORP'), ('Treves', 'NORP')"
"Many will be of opinion that Atticus 
 literally obeyed the emperor's last instructions; since he
 expended the greatest part of his fortune, which was much
 increased by an advantageous marriage, in the service of the
 Public.","('Atticus', 'PERSON'), ('Public', 'ORG')"
"Most of the Roman monuments for public use; temples, theatres aqueducts etc.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Mountains were perforated, and bold arches thrown over the
 broadest and most rapid streams. (86)","('86', 'CARDINAL')"
"Nor was the 
 influence of the Grecian language and sentiments confined to
 the narrow limits of that once celebrated country.","('Grecian', 'NORP')"
"Nor was the  Navigation  communication of the Roman empire less free and open by sea
 than it was by land.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Nor was the liberality of that illustrious
 citizen confined to the walls of Athens.","('Athens', 'GPE')"
"Notwithstanding the fashionable irreligion which prevailed
 in the age of the Antonines, both the interests of the
 priests and the credulity of the people were sufficiently
 respected.","('Antonines', 'PERSON')"
"Notwithstanding the repairs bestowed
 on that ancient edifice by a king of Cappadocia, it was
 again fallen to decay.","('Cappadocia', 'GPE')"
Of the Union and Internal Prosperity of the Roman Empire in the Age of the Antonines Principles of government.,"('Union', 'ORG'), ('the Roman Empire', 'GPE'), ('the Antonines Principles', 'LAW')"
"Of the four most celebrated schools, the Stoics and the Platonists endeavoured to reconcile the
 jarring interests of reason and piety.","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Stoics', 'PERSON'), ('Platonists', 'NORP')"
Populousness of the Roman empire.,"('Roman', 'NORP')"
Roman Roads.,"('Roman Roads', 'LOC')"
Roman monuments.,"('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Rome gradually became 
 the common temple of her subjects and the freedom of the
 city was bestowed on all the gods of mankind.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Rome, the capital of a great monarchy, was incessantly
 filled with subjects and strangers from every part of the
 world, (13) who all introduced and enjoyed the favourite 
 superstitions of their native country.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('13', 'CARDINAL')"
"Scarcely had
 the proud structure of the Coliseum been dedicated at Rome,
 before the edifices of a smaller scale indeed, but of the
 same design and materials, were erected for the use and at
 the expense, of the cities of Capua and Verona. (65)","('Coliseum', 'FAC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Capua', 'GPE'), ('Verona', 'GPE'), ('65', 'CARDINAL')"
"So sensible were the Romans of the influence of language
 over national manners, that it was their most serious care
 to extend, with the progress of their arms, the use of the
 Latin tongue. (37)","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('37', 'CARDINAL')"
"Still preserving
 the prejudices after they had lost the virtues of their
 ancestors, they affected to despise the unpolished manners
 of the Roman conquerors, whilst they were compelled to
 respect their superior wisdom and power. (41)","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Such was
 the general division of the Roman empire into the Latin and
 Greek languages.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Greek', 'LANGUAGE')"
"Such was the solid 
 construction of the Roman highways, whose firmness has not
 entirely yielded to the effort of fifteen centuries.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('fifteen centuries', 'DATE')"
"The
 coasts of Italy are, in general, destitute of safe harbours;
 but human industry had corrected the deficiencies of nature;
 and the artificial port of Ostia, in particular, situate at
 the mouth of the Tyber, and formed by the emperor Claudius,
 was a useful monument of Roman greatness. (91)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Ostia', 'GPE'), ('Tyber', 'NORP'), ('Claudius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('91', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 deities of a thousand groves and a thousand streams
 possessed, in peace, their local and respective influence;
 nor could the Roman who deprecated the wrath of the Tiber,
 deride the Egyptian who presented his offering to the
 beneficent genius of the Nile.","('a thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('a thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Tiber', 'PERSON'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP'), ('Nile', 'LOC')"
"The
 exiles returned, the proselytes multiplied, the temples were
 restored with increasing splendour, and Isis and Serapis at
 length assumed their place among the Roman deities.","('Isis', 'PERSON'), ('Serapis', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The
 forests of Scythia afforded some valuable furs.","('Scythia', 'GPE')"
"The
 golden palace of Nero excited a just indignation, but the
 vast extent of ground which had been usurped by his selfish
 luxury, was more nobly filled under the succeeding reigns by
 the Coliseum, the baths of Titus, the Claudian portico, and
 the temples dedicated to the goddess of Peace, and to the
 genius of Rome. (72)","('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('Coliseum', 'FAC'), ('Titus', 'PERSON'), ('Claudian', 'NORP'), ('Peace', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('72', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 labour and risk of the voyage was rewarded with almost
 incredible profit; but the profit was made upon Roman
 subjects, and a few individuals were enriched at the expense
 of the Public.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Public', 'ORG')"
"The
 patriot family of the Catos emerged from Tusculum; and the
 little town of Arpinum claimed the double honour of
 producing Marius and Cicero, the former of whom deserved,
 after Romulus and Camillus, to be styled the Third Founder
 of Rome; and the latter, after saving his country from the
 designs of Catiline, enabled her to contend with Athens for
 the palm of eloquence. (27)","('Catos', 'PERSON'), ('Tusculum', 'GPE'), ('Arpinum', 'GPE'), ('Marius', 'PERSON'), ('Cicero', 'PERSON'), ('Romulus', 'PERSON'), ('Camillus', 'PERSON'), ('Third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Catiline', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Athens', 'GPE')"
"The
 spirit of improvement had passed the Alps, and been felt
 even in the woods of Britain, which were gradually cleared
 away to open a free space for convenient and elegant
 habitations.","('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"The 
 cultivation of Flax was transported from Egypt to Gaul, and flax enriched the whole country, however it might impoverish the  particular lands on which it was sown. (99) 3. The use of artificial grasses artificial grasses became familiar to the farmers both of Italy and the provinces, particularly the Lucerne, which derived its name and origin from Media. (100)","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('99', 'CARDINAL'), ('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Lucerne', 'ORG'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"The 
 inscription of the stupendous bridge of Alcantara attests
 that it was thrown over the Tagus by the contribution of a
 few Lusitanian communities.","('Alcantara', 'PERSON'), ('Tagus', 'PRODUCT'), ('Lusitanian', 'NORP')"
"The  municipal cities insensibly equalled the rank and splendour of the colonies; and in the reign of Hadrian, it was disputed which was the preferable condition, of those
 societies which had issued from, or those which had been received into the bosom of Rome. (33)","('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
The Asia.,"('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The Egyptian superstition, of all the most
 contemptible and abject, was frequently prohibited; the
 temples of Serapis and Isis demolished and their worshippers
 banished from Rome and Italy. (15)","('Egyptian', 'NORP'), ('Serapis', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('15', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Greek, the
 Roman, and the Barbarian, as they met before their
 respective altars, easily persuaded themselves, that under
 various names, and with various ceremonies, they adored the
 same deities.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
"The Odeum, designed by Pericles for musical performances,
 and the rehearsal of new tragedies, had been a trophy of the
 victory of the arts over Barbaric greatness, as the timbers
 employed in the construction consisted chiefly of the masts
 of the Persian vessels.","('Odeum', 'PRODUCT'), ('Pericles', 'PERSON'), ('Barbaric', 'GPE'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The Olive in the western world, The olive, followed the progress of peace, of which it was considered as the symbol.","('The Olive', 'PERSON')"
"The Samnites and the Lucanians
 paid the severe penalty of their rashness; but the rest of
 the Italian states, as they successively returned to their
 duty, were admitted into the bosom of the republic, (24) and 
 soon contributed to the ruin of public freedom.","('Samnites', 'PERSON'), ('Lucanians', 'NORP'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('24', 'CARDINAL')"
"The ablest preceptors of Greece and Asia had been invited by
 liberal rewards to direct the education of young Herod.","('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Herod', 'PERSON')"
"The ancient dialects of Italy, the Sabine, 
 the Etruscan, and the Venetian, sunk into oblivion; but in
 the provinces, the east was less docile than the west, to
 the voice of its victorious preceptors.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Sabine', 'LOC'), ('Etruscan', 'NORP'), ('Venetian', 'NORP')"
"The annual loss is computed, by a writer of an inquisitive
 but censorious temper, at upwards of eight hundred thousand
 pounds sterling. (107)","('annual', 'DATE'), ('eight hundred thousand\r\n pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('107', 'CARDINAL')"
"The aqueducts of the capital claim a just
 pre-eminence; but the curious traveller, who, without the
 light of history, should examine those of Spoleto, of Metz,
 or of Segovia, would very naturally conclude that those
 provincial towns had formerly been the residence of some
 potent monarch.","('Spoleto', 'GPE'), ('Metz', 'PERSON'), ('Segovia', 'GPE')"
"The aspiring genius of Rome sacrificed vanity to ambition,
 and deemed it more prudent, as well as honourable, to adopt
 virtue and merit for her own wheresoever they were found,
 among slaves or strangers, enemies or barbarians. (20)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('20', 'CARDINAL')"
"The assured 
 supply of wholesome and plentiful food for the cattle during winter multiplied the number of the flocks and herds, which in their turn contributed to the fertility of the soil.","('winter', 'DATE')"
"The authority of Plato and Aristotle,
 of Zeno and Epicurus, still reigned in the schools; and
 their systems, transmitted with blind deference from one
 generation of disciples to another, precluded every generous
 attempt to exercise the powers, or enlarge the limits, of
 the human mind.","('Plato', 'PERSON'), ('Aristotle', 'PERSON'), ('Zeno', 'GPE'), ('Epicurus', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The beauties of the poets and orators,
 instead of kindling a fire like their own, inspired only
 cold and servile imitations: or if any ventured to deviate
 from those models, they deviated at the same time from good
 sense and propriety on the revival of letters, the youthful
 vigour of the imagination, after a long repose, national
 emulation, a new religion, new languages, and a new world,
 called forth the genius of Europe.","('Europe', 'LOC')"
"The benevolence of the master was so frequently
 prompted by the meaner suggestions of vanity and avarice,
 that the laws found it more necessary to restrain than to
 encourage a profuse and undistinguishing liberality, which
 might degenerate into a very dangerous abuse (51).","('51', 'CARDINAL')"
"The blessing was soon communicated to the Narbonnese province of Gaul; but so
 intense was the cold to the north of the Cevennes, that, in the time of Strabo, it was thought impossible to ripen the grapes in those parts of Gaul. (96)","('Narbonnese', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Cevennes', 'LOC'), ('Strabo', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('96', 'CARDINAL')"
"The boldness of the enterprise, the solidity of the
 execution, and the uses to which they were subservient, rank
 the aqueducts among the noblest monuments of Roman genius
 and power.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The bulk of the people acquired, with that title, the benefit of the Roman laws, particularly in the interesting articles of marriage, testaments, and inheritances; and the road of fortune was
 open to those whose pretensions were seconded by favour or merit.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The capitals of Syria and Egypt 
 held a still superior rank in the empire: Antioch and
 Alexandria looked down with disdain on a crowd of dependent
 cities, (84) and yielded, with reluctance, to the majesty of 
 Rome itself.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The cautious Athenian still
 insisted that the treasure was too considerable for a
 subject, and that he knew not how to use it.","('Athenian', 'NORP')"
"The coast of Malabar, or the
 island of Ceylon, (102) was the usual term of their 
 navigation, and it was in those markets that the merchants
 from the more remote countries of Asia expected their
 arrival.","('Malabar', 'GPE'), ('Ceylon', 'GPE'), ('102', 'CARDINAL'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The consequences of this maxim would have
 prostituted the privileges of the Roman city to a mean and
 promiscuous multitude.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The elegant mythology of Homer gave a
 beautiful, and almost a regular form, to the polytheism of
 the ancient world.","('Homer', 'PERSON')"
"The elegant treatise of Columella describes the advanced state of the Spanish husbandry, under the reign of Tiberius; and it may be observed, that those famines which so frequently afflicted General plenty the infant republic, were seldom or never experienced by the extensive empire of Rome.","('Columella', 'PERSON'), ('Spanish', 'NORP'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The established authority of the emperors
 pervaded without an effort the wide extent of their
 dominions, and was exercised with the same facility on the
 banks of the Thames, or of the Nile, as on those of the
 Tiber.","('Thames', 'LOC'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Tiber', 'FAC')"
"The estates of the Italians were exempt from taxes, their
 persons from the arbitrary jurisdiction of governors.","('Italians', 'NORP')"
"The family of Herod, at least after it had been favoured by
 fortune, was lineally descended from Cimon and Miltiades,
 Theseus and Cecrops, Leacus and Jupiter.","('Herod', 'PERSON'), ('Cimon and Miltiades,\r\n Theseus', 'ORG'), ('Cecrops', 'PRODUCT'), ('Leacus', 'ORG'), ('Jupiter', 'LOC')"
"The free states and cities which had
 embraced the cause of Rome, were rewarded with a nominal
 alliance, and insensibly sunk into real servitude.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The grandsons of the Gauls, who had besieged Julius Caesar in Alesia, commanded legions, governed provinces, and were admitted into the senate of Rome. (36)","('Gauls', 'NORP'), ('Julius Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Alesia', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The language of Virgil and Cicero, though with
 some inevitable mixture of corruption, was so universally
 adopted in Africa, Spain, Gaul, Britain, and Pannonia, (38) 
 that the faint traces of the Punic or Celtic idioms were
 preserved only in the mountains, or among the peasants. (39) 
 Education and study insensibly inspired the natives of those
 countries with the sentiments of Romans; and Italy gave
 fashions as well as laws to her Latin provincials.","('Virgil', 'PERSON'), ('Cicero', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Pannonia', 'NORP'), ('38', 'DATE'), ('Punic', 'NORP'), ('Celtic', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"The love of letters, almost inseparable from peace and
 refinement, was fashionable among the subjects of Hadrian
 and the Antonines, who were themselves men of learning and
 curiosity.","('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('Antonines', 'PERSON')"
"The magistrates could not be actuated by a blind, though
 honest bigotry, since the magistrates were themselves
 philosophers; and the schools of Athens had given laws to
 the senate.","('Athens', 'GPE')"
"The magistrates only, at the expiration of their office, assumed the quality of Roman citizens; but as those offices were annual, in a few years
 they circulated round the principal families.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('annual', 'DATE'), ('a few years', 'DATE')"
"The monuments of his genius have perished; some considerable
 ruins still preserve the fame of his taste and munificence:
 modern travellers have measured the remains of the stadium
 which he constructed at Athens.","('Athens', 'GPE')"
"The most remote countries of the ancient world
 were ransacked to supply the pomp and delicacy of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The most splendid
 ornaments bestowed on the temple of Neptune in the Isthmus,
 a theatre at Corinth, a stadium at Delphi, a bath at
 Thermopylae, and an aqueduct at Canusium in Italy, were
 insufficient to exhaust his treasures.","('Neptune', 'LOC'), ('Isthmus', 'LOC'), ('Corinth', 'GPE'), ('Delphi', 'GPE'), ('Thermopylae', 'FAC'), ('Canusium', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The name of Poet was almost forgotten; that of Orator was
 usurped by the sophists.","('Poet', 'PERSON'), ('Orator', 'PERSON')"
"The narrow policy of preserving, without any foreign
 mixture, the pure blood of the ancient citizens, had checked
 the fortune, and hastened the ruin, of Athens and Sparta.","('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Sparta', 'GPE')"
"The natives of Europe were brave and robust, Spain, Gaul,
 Britain, and Illyricum supplied the legions with excellent
 soldiers, and constituted the real strength of the monarchy.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Illyricum', 'GPE')"
"The natives of Italy, allured by pleasure or by interest, hastened to enjoy the advantages of victory; and we may remark, that about forty years after the reduction of Asia, eighty thousand Romans were massacred in one day, by the cruel orders of Mithridates. (31)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('about forty years', 'DATE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('eighty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('one day', 'DATE'), ('Mithridates', 'NORP'), ('31', 'CARDINAL')"
"The number of subjects who acknowledged the laws of Rome, of
 citizens, of provincials, and of slaves, cannot now be fixed
 with such a degree of accuracy, as the importance of the
 object would deserve.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
The obedient provinces of Trajan and the Antonines were united by laws and adorned by arts.,"('Trajan', 'GPE'), ('Antonines', 'GPE')"
"The objects of oriental traffic were 
 splendid and trifling; silk, a pound of which was esteemed
 not inferior in value to a pound of gold; (104) precious 
 stones, among which the pearl claimed the first rank after
 the diamond; (105) and a variety of aromatics, that were 
 consumed in religious worship and the pomp of funerals.","('104', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('105', 'CARDINAL')"
"The opinions of
 the Academics and Epicureans were of a less religious cast; 
 but whilst the modest science of the former induced them to
 doubt, the positive ignorance of the latter urged them to
 deny, the providence of a Supreme Ruler.","('Academics', 'ORG'), ('Epicureans', 'ORG'), ('a Supreme Ruler', 'ORG')"
"The opulent senators of Rome 
 and the provinces esteemed it an honour, and almost an
 obligation, to adorn the splendour of their age and country;
 and the influence of fashion very frequently supplied the
 want of taste or generosity.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The people of Epirus,
 Thessaly, Eubcea, Boeotia, and Peloponnesus, experienced his
 favours; and many inscriptions of the cities of Greece and
 Asia gratefully style Herodes Atticus their patron and
 benefactor. (70)","('Epirus', 'GPE'), ('Thessaly', 'GPE'), ('Eubcea', 'GPE'), ('Boeotia', 'GPE'), ('Peloponnesus', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Herodes Atticus', 'PERSON')"
"The perfect settlement of
 the Roman empire was preceded by ages of violence and Their treatment.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The petty states of
 Latium were contained within the metropolis of the empire,
 by whose superior influence they had been attracted.","('Latium', 'GPE')"
"The philosophers of Greece deduced their morals from the
 nature of man, rather than from that of God.","('Greece', 'GPE')"
"The pontiffs were chosen among the
 most illustrious of the senators; and the office of Supreme
 Pontiff was constantly exercised by the emperors themselves.","('Supreme\r\n Pontiff', 'ORG')"
"The progress of manners was accelerated by the
 virtue or policy of the emperors; and by the edicts of
 Hadrian and the Antonines, the protection of the laws was
 extended to the most abject part of mankind.","('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('Antonines', 'PERSON')"
"The province of Gaul
 seems, and indeed only seems, an exception to this universal
 toleration.","('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The provinces surrounded and enclosed
 the Mediterranean; and Italy in the shape of an immense
 promontory, advanced into the midst of that great lake.","('Mediterranean', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The provinces would soon have
 been exhausted of their wealth, if the manufactures and
 commerce of luxury had not insensibly restored to the
 industrious subjects the sums which were exacted from them
 by the arms and authority of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The public monuments with which Hadrian adorned
 every province of the empire, were executed not only by his
 orders, but under his immediate inspection.","('Hadrian', 'PERSON')"
"The public roads 
 were accurately divided by mile-stones, and ran in a direct
 line from one city to another, with very little respect for
 the obstacles either of nature or private property.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The return of the fleet of Egypt was fixed to the
 months of December or January; and as soon as their rich
 cargo had been transported on the backs of camels, from the
 Red Sea to the Nile, and had descended that river as far as
 Alexandria, it was poured, without delay, into the capital
 of the empire. (103)","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('the\r\n months of December or January', 'DATE'), ('the\r\n Red Sea', 'LOC'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('103', 'CARDINAL')"
"The right of Latium, as it was called, conferred on the cities to which it had been granted a more partial favour.","('Latium', 'PRODUCT')"
"The ruins of antiquity
 scattered over uncultivated fields, and ascribed, by
 ignorance, to the power of magic, scarcely afford a shelter
 to the oppressed peasant or wandering Arab.","('Arab', 'NORP')"
"The same number of four hundred belonged to an 
 estate which an African widow, of a very private condition,
 resigned to her son, whilst she reserved for herself a much
 larger share of her property. (60)","('four hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('African', 'NORP')"
"The sciences of physic and astronomy 
 were successfully cultivated by the Greeks; the observations
 of Ptolemy and the writings of Galen are studied by those
 who have improved their discoveries and corrected their
 errors; but if we except the inimitable Lucian, this age of
 indolence passed away without having produced a single
 writer of original genius, or who excelled in the arts of
 elegant composition.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Ptolemy', 'PERSON'), ('Galen', 'PERSON'), ('Lucian', 'PERSON')"
"The situation of the
 Greeks was very different from that of the Barbarians.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"The slaves consisted, for the most part, of  barbarian captives, taken in thousands by the chance of war, purchased at a vile price, (46) accustomed to a life of 
 independence, and impatient to break and to revenge their
 fetters.","('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('46', 'CARDINAL')"
"The solitudes of Asia and Africa were once
 covered with flourishing cities, whose populousness, and
 even whose existence, was derived from such artificial
 supplies of a perennial stream of fresh water. (73)","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
The sovereign of the Russian deserts commands a larger portion of the globe.,"('Russian', 'NORP')"
"The spirit of
 inquiry, prompted by emulation, and supported by freedom,
 had divided the public teachers of philosophy into a variety
 of contending sects; but the ingenuous youth who, from every
 part, resorted to Athens, and the other seats of learning in
 the Roman empire, were alike instructed in every school to
 reject and to despise the religion of the multitude.","('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The splendour
 of Verona may be traced in its remains: yet Verona was less
 celebrated than Aquileia or Padua, Milan or Ravenna.","('Verona', 'GPE'), ('Verona', 'GPE'), ('Aquileia', 'PERSON'), ('Padua', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"The strict economy of Vespasian was the source of 
 his magnificence.","('Vespasian', 'GPE')"
"The sublime Longinus, who in somewhat a later period, and in
 the court of a Syrian queen, preserved the spirit of ancient
 Athens, observes and laments this degeneracy of his
 contemporaries, which debased their sentiments, enervated
 their courage, and depressed their talents.","('Longinus', 'PERSON'), ('Syrian', 'NORP'), ('Athens', 'GPE')"
"The thin texture of the Pagan mythology
 was interwoven with various but not discordant materials.","('Pagan', 'NORP')"
"The total amount of this imperfect calculation would rise to
 about one hundred and twenty millions of persons; a degree
 of population which possibly exceeds that of modern Europe,
 (62) and forms the most numerous society that has ever been 
 united under the same system of government.","('about one hundred and twenty millions', 'CARDINAL'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('62', 'CARDINAL')"
"The two languages exercised at the 
 same time their separate jurisdiction throughout the empire:
 the former as the natural idiom of science; the later as the
 legal dialect of public transactions.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The use of the posts was allowed to those who claimed it by
 an Imperial mandate; but though originally intended for the
 public service, it was sometimes indulged to the business or
 conveniency of private citizens. (90)","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The vanquished
 nations, blended into one great people, resigned the hope,
 nay even the wish, of resuming their independence, and
 scarcely considered their own existence as distinct from the
 existence of Rome.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The various modes of worship, which
 prevailed in the Roman world, were all considered by the
 people, as equally true; by the philosopher, as equally
 false; and by the magistrate, as equally useful.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The works of Trajan bear the stamp of his
 genius.","('Trajan', 'PERSON')"
"Their
 empire, by the progress of colonies and conquest, had been
 diffused from the Hadriatic to the Euphrates and the Nile.","('Hadriatic', 'NORP'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Nile', 'LOC')"
"Their greatness alone, or their beauty, might
 deserve our attention; but they are rendered more
 interesting by two important circumstances, which connect
 the agreeable history of the arts with the more useful
 history of human manners.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Their partial distinctions
 were obliterated, and they insensibly coalesced into one
 great nation, united by language, manners, and civil
 institutions, and equal to the weight of a powerful empire.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"Their pupil soon became a celebrated orator according to the
 useless rhetoric of that age, which, confining itself to the
 schools, disdained to visit either the Forum or the senate.","('Forum', 'ORG'), ('senate', 'ORG')"
"There is not the least 
 reason to suppose that gold was become more scarce; it is
 therefore evident that silver was grown more common; that
 whatever might be the amount of the Indian and Arabian
 exports, they were far from exhausting the wealth of the
 Roman world; and that the produce of the mines abundantly
 supplied the demands of commerce.","('Indian', 'NORP'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"There was a considerable demand for Babylonian carpets 
 and other manufactures of the East; but the most important
 and unpopular branch of foreign trade was carried on with
 Arabia and India.","('Babylonian', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Arabia', 'GPE'), ('India', 'GPE')"
"These monuments of architecture, the 
 property of the Roman people, were adorned with the most
 beautiful productions of Grecian painting and sculpture; and
 in the temple of Peace a very curious library was open to
 the curiosity of the learned.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Grecian', 'NORP'), ('Peace', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"They
 restored a manly spirit of freedom; and after the revolution
 of ten centuries, freedom became the happy parent of taste
 and science.","('ten centuries', 'DATE')"
"They
 solicited with more ardour, and obtained with more facility,
 the freedom and honours of the state; supported the national
 dignity in letters (40) and in arms; and, at length, in the 
 person of Trajan, produced an emperor whom the Scipios would
 not have disowned for their countryman.","('40', 'CARDINAL'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Scipios', 'PERSON')"
"They have left us the
 most sublime proofs of the existence and perfections of the
 first cause; but, as it was impossible for them to conceive
 the creation of matter, the workman in the Stoic philosophy
 was not sufficiently distinguished from the work; whilst, on
 the contrary, the spiritual God of Plato and his disciples
 resembled an idea rather than a substance.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Stoic', 'NORP'), ('Plato', 'PERSON')"
"They meditated,
 however, on the Divine Nature, as a very curious and
 important speculation; and in the profound inquiry, they
 displayed the strength and weakness of the human
 understanding (6).","('6', 'CARDINAL')"
"They were encouraged by the Antonines,
 as they contributed to the happiness of the people.","('Antonines', 'PERSON')"
"This column, which still
 subsists in its ancient beauty, exhibited an exact
 representation of the Dacian victories of its founder.","('Dacian', 'NORP')"
"This difficulty, however, was gradually vanquished; and there is some reason to
 believe, that the vineyards of Burgundy are as old as the
 age of the Antonines. (97)","('Burgundy', 'GPE'), ('Antonines', 'PERSON'), ('97', 'CARDINAL')"
"This diminutive  stature of mankind, if we pursue the metaphor, was daily
 sinking below the old standard, and the Roman world was
 indeed peopled by a race of pygmies; when the fierce giants
 of the north broke in, and mended the puny breed.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"This long peace, and the uniform government of the Romans, introduced a slow and secret poison into the vitals of the empire.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"This obvious
 difference marked the two portions of the empire with a
 distinction of colours, which, though it was in some degree
 concealed during the meridian splendour of prosperity,
 became gradually more visible as the shades of night
 descended upon the Roman world.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"This operation, the particular effects of which
 are felt in every society, acted with much more diffusive
 energy in the Roman world.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Those
 parts of Italy which have so long languished under the lazy
 tyranny of priests and viceroys, had been afflicted only by
 the more tolerable calamities of war; and the first symptoms
 of decay which they experienced were amply compensated by
 the rapid improvements of the Cisalpine Gaul.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the Cisalpine Gaul', 'GPE')"
"Those 
 nations had submitted to the Roman power, but they seldom
 desired or deserved the freedom of the city; and it was
 remarked that more than two hundred and thirty years elapsed
 after the ruin of the Ptolemies before an Egyptian was
 admitted into the senate of Rome. (44)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('more than two hundred and thirty years', 'DATE'), ('Ptolemies', 'NORP'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('44', 'CARDINAL')"
"Those immortal
 writers who still command the admiration of modern Europe,
 soon became the favourite object of study and imitation in
 Italy and the western provinces.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Those of  the provincials who were permitted to bear arms in the legions; (35) those who exercised any civil employment; all, in a word, who performed any public service, or displayed
 any personal talents, were rewarded with a present, whose value was continually diminished by the increasing liberality of the emperors.","('35', 'CARDINAL')"
"Those who united
 letters with business were equally conversant with both; and
 it was almost impossible, in any province, to find a Roman
 subject of a liberal education, who was at once a stranger
 to the Greek and to the Latin language.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE')"
Three hundred African cities had Africa.,"('Three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('African', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"Till the privileges of Romans had been progressively
 extended to all the inhabitants of the empire, an important
 distinction was preserved between Italy and the provinces.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"To the
 memory of his wife Regina he dedicated a theatre, scarcely
 to be paralleled in the empire; no wood except cedar, very
 curiously carved, was employed in any part of the building.","('Regina', 'PERSON')"
"To these we may add a third distinction for
 the body of the natives in Syria, and especially in Egypt.","('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"Two centuries after the foundation of Rome, both Italy and Africa were strangers to that useful plant;
 it was naturalised in those countries; and at length carried
 into the heart of Spain and Gaul.","('Two centuries', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"Under a
 democratical government, the citizens exercise the powers of
 sovereignty; and those powers will be first abused, and
 afterwards lost, if they are committed to an unwieldy
 multitude.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Under the
 Roman empire, the labour of an industrious and ingenious
 people was variously, but incessantly employed, in the
 service of the rich.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Under the protection of an established government,
 the productions of happier climates, and the industry of
 more civilised nations, were gradually introduced into the
 western countries of Europe; and the natives were
 encouraged, by an open and profitable commerce, to multiply
 the former, as well as to improve the latter.","('Europe', 'LOC')"
"Under the reign
 of the Caesars, the proper Asia alone contained five hundred
 populous cities, (79) enriched with all the gifts of nature, and adorned with all the refinements of art.","('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('five hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"Under the specious pretext of abolishing human
 sacrifices, the emperors Tiberius and Claudius suppressed
 the dangerous power of the Druids, (11)","('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('Claudius', 'PERSON'), ('Druids', 'PRODUCT'), ('11', 'CARDINAL')"
"Viewing, with a smile of pity and
 indulgence, the various errors of the vulgar, they
 diligently practised the ceremonies of their fathers,
 devoutly frequented the temples of the gods; and sometimes
 condescending to act a part on the theatre of superstition,
 they concealed the sentiments of an Atheist under the
 sacerdotal robes.","('Atheist', 'NORP')"
"Virgil was a native of Mantua; Horace was
 inclined to doubt whether he should call himself an Apulian
 or a Lucanian: it was in Padua that an historian was found
 worthy to record the majestic series of Roman victories.","('Virgil', 'PERSON'), ('Mantua', 'GPE'), ('Horace', 'PERSON'), ('Apulian', 'NORP'), ('Lucanian', 'NORP'), ('Padua', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"We are informed that when the emperor
 Claudius exercised the office of censor, he took an account
 of six millions nine hundred and forty-five thousand Roman
 citizens, who, with the proportion of women and children,
 must have amounted to about twenty millions of souls.","('Claudius', 'PERSON'), ('six millions nine hundred and forty-five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('about twenty millions', 'CARDINAL')"
"We have computed the inhabitants and contemplated the public
 works of the Roman empire.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Whatever
 might be the merit or fortune of their sons, they likewise,
 were esteemed unworthy of a seat in the senate; nor were the
 traces of a servile origin allowed to be completely
 obliterated till the third or fourth generation. (52)","('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('52', 'CARDINAL')"
"Whatever evils either reason or declamation have imputed to
 extensive empire, the power of Rome was attended with some
 beneficial consequences to mankind; and the same freedom of
 intercourse which extended the vices, diffused likewise the
 improvements of social life.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"When 
 the allies of Rome claimed an equal share of honours and
 privileges, the senate indeed preferred the chance of arms
 to an ignominious concession.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"When Pliny was intrusted with
 the government of Bithynia and Pontus, provinces by no means
 the richest or most considerable of the empire, he found the
 cities within his jurisdiction striving with each other in
 every useful and ornamental work, that might deserve the
 curiosity of strangers, or the gratitude of their citizens.","('Pliny', 'PERSON'), ('Bithynia', 'GPE'), ('Pontus', 'GPE')"
"Whilst they acknowledged the charms
 of the Greek, they asserted the dignity of the Latin tongue,
 and the exclusive use of the latter was inflexibly
 maintained in the administration of civil as well as
 military government.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP')"
"With regard to Spain, that country flourished as a province,
 and has declined as a kingdom.","('Spain', 'GPE')"
"Without interpreting, in their utmost 
 strictness, the liberal appellations of legions and myriads,
 (54) we may venture to pronounce, that the proportion of 
 slaves, who were valued as property, was more considerable
 than that of servants, who can be computed only as an
 expense.","('54', 'CARDINAL')"
"Yet even, in the age of the Antonines, when the freedom of the city had been bestowed on
 the greater number of their subjects, it was still accompanied with very solid advantages.","('Antonines', 'PERSON')"
"Yet the wisest princes, who adopted the maxims
 of Augustus, guarded with the strictest care the dignity of
 the Roman name, and diffused the freedom of the city with a
 prudent liberality. (25)
Italy.","('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"York was the seat of government; London was
 already enriched by commerce; and Bath was celebrated for
 the salutary effects of its medicinal waters.","('York', 'GPE'), ('London', 'GPE'), ('Bath', 'GPE')"
"and in nine or ten, to Alexandria in
 Egypt. (92)","('nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('92', 'CARDINAL')"
"boast of her twelve hundred cities; (75) and though, in the northern parts, many of them, without excepting Paris
 itself, were little more than the rude and imperfect
 townships of a rising people, the southern provinces
 imitated the wealth and elegance of Italy. (76)","('twelve hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('75', 'CARDINAL'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"island of Sicily, and most probably in the adjacent continent; but it was not improved by the skill, nor did it
 afford a liquor grateful to the taste, of the savage inhabitants. (94)","('Sicily', 'LOC'), ('94', 'CARDINAL')"
"ninety-seven cities; and for whatsoever era of antiquity the expression might be intended, (74) there is not any reason to 
 believe the country less populous in the age of the
 Antonines than in that of Romulus.","('ninety-seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antonines', 'NORP'), ('Romulus', 'GPE')"
"once acknowledged the authority of Carthage, (78) nor is it likely that their numbers diminished under the administration of the emperors:","('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('78', 'CARDINAL')"
provinces of the east present the contrast of Roman magnificence with Turkish barbarism.,"('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Turkish', 'NORP')"
