Sentence,Entities
"""I believe in one
 God, and Mahomet the apostle of God,"" is the simple and
 invariable profession of Islam.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Islam', 'ORG')"
"""We are only two,""  said the trembling Abubeker.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Abubeker', 'PERSON')"
"(1)
Description of Arabia","('Arabia', 'GPE')"
"(11)
 Arabia, in the opinion of the naturalist, is the genuine and
 original country of the horse; the climate most propitious, not indeed to the size, but to the spirit and swiftness, of
(179),"('179', 'CARDINAL')"
(37),"('37', 'CARDINAL')"
(75),"('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 paper copy, in a volume of silk and gems, was brought down
 to the lowest heaven by the angel Gabriel, who, under the
 Jewish economy, had indeed been despatched on the most
 important errands; and this trusty messenger successively
 revealed the chapters and verses to the Arabian prophet.","('Gabriel', 'PERSON'), ('Jewish', 'NORP'), ('Arabian', 'NORP')"
"A cloud of
 shame and sorrow hung on the retreat of the Mussulmans, and
 their disappointment might justly accuse the failure of a
 prophet who had so often appealed to the evidence of
 success.","('Mussulmans', 'NORP')"
"A dispute had arisen,
 who, among the citizens of Mecca, was entitled to the prize
 of generosity; and a successive application was made to the
 three who were deemed most worthy of the trial.","('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"A doubtful truce
 restored the appearances of concord till the death of Abu
 Taleb abandoned Mahomet to the power of his enemies, at the
 moment when he was deprived of his domestic comforts by the
 loss of his faithful and generous Cadijah.","('Abu\r\n Taleb', 'PERSON'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Cadijah', 'NORP')"
"A familiar story is related of the benevolence of one of the
 sons of Ali.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ali', 'PERSON')"
"A family of three hundred
 persons, the pure and orthodox branch of the caliph Hassan,
 is preserved without taint or suspicion in the holy cities
 of Mecca and Medina, and still retains, after the
 revolutions of twelve centuries, the custody of the temple,
 and the sovereignty of their native land.","('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hassan', 'PERSON'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('twelve centuries', 'DATE')"
"A fine or compensation for murder
 is familiar to the Barbarians of every age: but in Arabia
 the kinsmen of the dead are at liberty to accept the
 atonement, or to exercise with their own hands the law of
 retaliation.","('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Arabia', 'GPE')"
"A friendly tribe, instructed (I know
 not how) in the art of sieges, supplied him with a train of
 battering-rams and military engines, with a body of five
 hundred artificers.","('five\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"A fundamental article of faith was
 inculcated by the consent of the learned strangers; the
 existence of one supreme God who is exalted above the powers
 of heaven and earth, but who has often revealed himself to
 mankind by the ministry of his angels and prophets, and
 whose grace or justice has interrupted, by seasonable
 miracles, the order of nature.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"A life of prayer and contemplation had not chilled the
 martial activity of Ali; but in a mature age, after a long
 experience of mankind, he still betrayed in his conduct the
 rashness and indiscretion of youth.","('Ali', 'PERSON')"
"A list was
 secretly transmitted from Cufa to Medina, of one hundred and
 forty thousand Moslems, who professed their attachment to
 his cause, and who were eager to draw their swords so soon
 as he should appear on the banks of the Euphrates.","('Cufa', 'GPE'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('one hundred and\r\n forty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moslems', 'NORP'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"A more serious and
 decent excuse may be drawn from his fidelity to Cadijah.","('Cadijah', 'PERSON')"
"A mysterious animal, the
 Borak, conveyed him from the temple of Mecca to that of
 Jerusalem: with his companion Gabriel he successively
 ascended the seven heavens, and received and repaid the
 salutations of the patriarchs, the prophets, and the angels,
 in their respective mansions.","('Borak', 'PERSON'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Gabriel', 'PERSON'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"A parent who drags his son to the altar, exhibits the most
 painful and sublime effort of fanaticism: the deed, or the
 intention, was sanctified by the example of saints and
 heroes; and the father of Mahomet himself was devoted by a
 rash vow, and hardly ransomed for the equivalent of a
 hundred camels.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('a\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"A part of their time and industry
 was still devoted to the management of their cattle: they
 mingled, in peace and war, with their brethren of the
 desert; and the Bedoweens derived from their useful
 intercourse some supply of their wants, and some rudiments
 of art and knowledge.","('Bedoweens', 'NORP')"
"A philosophic theist might subscribe the popular
 creed of the Mahometans; (79) a creed too sublime, perhaps,
 for our present faculties.","('Mahometans', 'NORP'), ('79', 'CARDINAL')"
"A shady grove, a green pasture, a stream of fresh water, are sufficient to attract a colony of sedentary Arabs to the fortunate spots which can afford food and refreshment to themselves and their cattle, and which encourage their industry in the cultivation of the palmtree and the vine.","('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"A small portion of ground, the
 patrimony of two orphans, was acquired by gift or purchase;
 (121) on that chosen spot he built a house and a mosch, more
 venerable in their rude simplicity than the palaces and
 temples of the Assyrian caliphs.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('121', 'CARDINAL'), ('Assyrian', 'NORP')"
"A spacious portico
 encloses the quadrangle of the Caaba; a square chapel,
 twenty-four cubits long, twenty-three broad, and
 twenty-seven high: a door and a window admit the light; the
 double roof is supported by three pillars of wood; a spout
 (now of gold) discharges the rain-water, and the well Zemzen
 is protected by a dome from accidental pollution.","('Caaba', 'FAC'), ('twenty-four cubits', 'QUANTITY'), ('twenty-three', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty-seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Zemzen', 'GPE')"
"A special revelation dispensed him
 from the laws which he had imposed on his nation: the female
 sex, without reserve, was abandoned to his desires; and this
 singular prerogative excited the envy, rather than the
 scandal, the veneration, rather than the envy, of the devout
 Mussulmans.","('Mussulmans', 'NORP')"
"A tempest of wind, rain, and hail, overturned their tents:
 their private quarrels were fomented by an insidious
 adversary; and the Koreish, deserted by their allies, no
 longer hoped to subvert the throne, or to check the
 conquests, of their invincible exile. (134)","('Koreish', 'NORP'), ('134', 'CARDINAL')"
"A tent, or a cavern, might
 suffice for the worship of the savages, but an edifice of
 stone and clay has been erected in its place; and the art
 and power of the monarchs of the East have been confined to
 the simplicity of the original model. (47)","('East', 'LOC'), ('47', 'CARDINAL')"
"A treaty was proposed; and, in the first
 audience, the grandfather of Mahomet demanded the
 restitution of his cattle.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"A tumultuous anarchy
 of five days was appeased by the inauguration of Ali: his
 refusal would have provoked a general massacre.","('five days', 'DATE'), ('Ali', 'PERSON')"
"A venerable elder, to whose judgment they appealed, pronounced the sentence of their death; seven hundred Jews were dragged in chains to the market-place of the city; they descended alive into the grave prepared for their execution and burial; and the apostle beheld with an inflexible eye the slaughter of his helpless enemies.","('seven hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jews', 'NORP')"
"A zealous votary of
 the idols, a mortal foe of the line of Hashem, he convened
 an assembly of the Koreishites and their allies, to decide
 the fate of the apostle.","('Hashem', 'PERSON'), ('Koreishites', 'NORP')"
"Abdallah,
 the son of Abbas, had undertaken a distant journey, and his
 foot was in the stirrup when he heard the voice of a
 suppliant,   He instantly dismounted to present the pilgrim with his camel, her rich caparison, and a purse of four thousand pieces of gold, excepting only the
 sword, either for its intrinsic value, or as the gift of an
 honoured kinsman.","('Abdallah', 'PERSON'), ('Abbas', 'PERSON'), ('four thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"About half this length may be allowed for the middle breadth, from east to west, from Bassora to Suez, from the Persian Gulf to the Red Sea. (4)","('About half', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bassora', 'GPE'), ('Suez', 'GPE'), ('the Persian Gulf', 'LOC'), ('the Red Sea', 'LOC'), ('4', 'CARDINAL')"
"Abu Sophian himself, with only thirty or forty
 followers, conducted a wealthy caravan of a thousand camels;
 the fortune or dexterity of his march escaped the vigilance
 of Mahomet; but the chief of the Koreish was informed that
 the holy robbers were placed in ambush to await his return.","('Abu Sophian', 'PERSON'), ('only thirty or forty', 'CARDINAL'), ('a thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Koreish', 'PERSON')"
"Abu Sophian, the
 chief of the branch of Ommiyah, succeeded to the
 principality of the republic of Mecca.","('Abu Sophian', 'PERSON'), ('Ommiyah', 'GPE'), ('Mecca', 'GPE')"
"According as the shares of guilt or virtue shall
 preponderate, the sentence will be pronounced, and all,
 without distinction, will pass over the sharp and perilous
 bridge of the abyss; but the innocent, treading in the
 footsteps of Mahomet, will gloriously enter the gates of
 paradise, while the guilty will fall into the first and
 mildest of the seven hells.","('Mahomet', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"According to another legend, the apostle confounded in a
 national assembly the malicious challenge of the Koreish.","('Koreish', 'NORP')"
"According to the remark of Pliny, the
 Arabian tribes are equally addicted to theft and
 merchandise; the caravans that traverse the desert are
 ransomed or pillaged; and their neighbours, since the remote
 times of Job and Sesostris, (35) have been the victims of
 their rapacious spirit.","('Pliny', 'PERSON'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('Job', 'EVENT'), ('Sesostris', 'PERSON'), ('35', 'CARDINAL')"
"According to the tradition of his companions, Mahomet (69) was distinguished by the beauty of his person, an outward gift which is seldom despised, except by those to whom it
 has been refused.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('69', 'DATE')"
"After a perilous and rapid journey along the sea-coast, he halted at
 Koba, two miles from the city, and made his public entry
 into Medina, sixteen days after his flight from Mecca.","('Koba', 'GPE'), ('two miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('sixteen days', 'DATE'), ('Mecca', 'GPE')"
"After a reign of six years, fifteen hundred
 Moslems, in arms and in the field, renewed their oath of
 allegiance; and their chief repeated the assurance of
 protection till the death of the last member, or the final dissolution of the party.","('six years', 'DATE'), ('fifteen hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moslems', 'NORP')"
"After a reign of two years, the aged caliph was
 summoned by the angel of death.","('two years', 'DATE')"
"After a resistance of twenty-five days, they surrendered at discretion.","('twenty-five days', 'DATE')"
"After a siege of twenty-days, the prophet
 sounded a retreat; but he retreated with a song of devout
 triumph, and affected to pray for the repentance and safety
 of the unbelieving city.","('twenty-days', 'DATE')"
"After her death, he placed her in
 the rank of the four perfect women, with the sister of
 Moses, the mother of Jesus, and Fatima, the best beloved of
 his daughters.","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moses', 'PERSON'), ('Jesus', 'PERSON'), ('Fatima', 'PERSON')"
"After passing through the ranks to animate the
 troops, Ayesha had chosen her post amidst the dangers of the
 field.","('Ayesha', 'PERSON')"
"After pursuing above six hundred years the fleeting Caesars of Constantinople and Germany, I now descend, in the reign of Heraclius, on the eastern borders of the Greek monarchy.","('six hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Caesars', 'LOC'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Heraclius', 'GPE'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"After the conquest of Mecca, the sovereign of Arabia affected to prevent the hostile preparations of Heraclius; and solemnly proclaimed war against the Romans, without attempting to disguise the hardships and dangers of
 the enterprise. (147)","('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Arabia', 'GPE'), ('Heraclius', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('147', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the reduction of the castles, the town of Chaibar submitted to the yoke.","('Chaibar', 'GPE')"
"After the reign of three caliphs, the throne was transported
 from Medina to the valley of Damascus and the banks of the
 Tigris; the holy cities were violated by impious war; Arabia
 was ruled by the rod of a subject, perhaps of a stranger;
 and the Bedoweens of the desert, awakening from their dream
 of dominion, resumed their old and solitary independence.
 (187)","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Arabia', 'GPE'), ('Bedoweens', 'NORP'), ('187', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the ruin of the temple, the faith
 of the Hebrew exiles was purified, fixed, and enlightened,
 by the spiritual devotion of the synagogue; and the
 authority of Mahomet will not justify his perpetual
 reproach, that the Jews of Mecca or Medina adored Ezra as
 the son of God. (74)","('Hebrew', 'NORP'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('Ezra', 'PERSON'), ('74', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the simple inauguration of Abubeker, he
 was obeyed in Medina, Mecca, and the provinces of Arabia:
 the Hashemites alone declined the oath of fidelity; and
 their chief, in his own house, maintained, above six months,
 a sullen and independent reserve; without listening to the
 threats of Omar, who attempted to consume with fire the
 habitation of the daughter of the apostle.","('Abubeker', 'PERSON'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Arabia', 'GPE'), ('Hashemites', 'NORP'), ('six months', 'DATE'), ('Omar', 'PERSON')"
"After they
 had trampled on his body, they carried his head to the
 castle of Cufa, and the inhuman Obeidollah struck him on the
 mouth with a cane:","('Cufa', 'GPE'), ('Obeidollah', 'PERSON')"
"After this familiar, though
 important conversation, he again descended to Jerusalem,
 remounted the Borak, returned to Mecca, and performed in the
 tenth part of a night the journey of many thousand years.
 (98)","('Jerusalem', 'GPE'), ('Borak', 'NORP'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('tenth', 'ORDINAL'), ('many thousand years', 'DATE'), ('98', 'DATE')"
"After this victory, which was styled the Day of the
 Camel, Ali marched against a more formidable adversary;
 against Moawiyah, the son of Abu Sophian, who had assumed
 the title of caliph, and whose claim was supported by the
 forces of Syria and the interest of the house of Ommiyah.","('the Day of the\r\n Camel', 'EVENT'), ('Ali', 'PERSON'), ('Moawiyah', 'PERSON'), ('Abu Sophian', 'PERSON'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Ommiyah', 'GPE')"
"Alive or dead, almost every
 part of the camel is serviceable to man: her milk is
 plentiful and nutritious: the young and tender flesh has the
 taste of veal: (13) a valuable salt is extracted from the urine: the dung supplies the deficiency of fuel; and the long hair, which falls each year and is renewed, is coarsely
 manufactured into the garments, the furniture, and the tents
 of the Bedoweens.","('13', 'CARDINAL'), ('each year', 'DATE'), ('Bedoweens', 'PRODUCT')"
"Along the shores of the Persian Gulf,
 of the ocean, and even of the Red Sea, the Icthyophagi, (9) or fish eaters, continued to wander in quest of their precarious food.","('the Persian Gulf', 'LOC'), ('the Red Sea', 'LOC'), ('Icthyophagi', 'PRODUCT'), ('9', 'CARDINAL')"
"Among the forty-two cities of Arabia,
 (14) enumerated by Abulfeda, the most ancient and populous
 were situate in the happy Yemen: the towers of Saana, (15)
 and the marvellous reservoir of Merab, (16) were constructed
 by the kings of the Homerites; but their profane lustre was
 eclipsed by the prophetic glories of MEDINA (17) and MECCA, (18) near the Red Sea, and at the distance from each other of two hundred and seventy miles.","('forty-two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabia', 'GPE'), ('14', 'CARDINAL'), ('Abulfeda', 'PERSON'), ('Yemen', 'GPE'), ('Saana', 'GPE'), ('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('Merab', 'LOC'), ('16', 'CARDINAL'), ('Homerites', 'NORP'), ('17', 'CARDINAL'), ('MECCA', 'ORG'), ('18', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Red Sea', 'LOC'), ('two hundred and seventy miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"Amrou, the
 conqueror of Egypt, himself an army, was the first who
 saluted the new monarch, and divulged the dangerous secret,
 that the Arabian caliphs might be created elsewhere than in
 the city of the prophet.","('Amrou', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Arabian', 'NORP')"
"An angel or a spy revealed their
 conspiracy; and flight was the only resource of Mahomet.
 (117)","('Mahomet', 'ORG'), ('117', 'CARDINAL')"
"An annual festival of two, perhaps
 of four, months, was observed by the Arabs before the time
 of Mahomet, during which their swords were religiously
 sheathed both in foreign and domestic hostility; and this
 partial truce is more strongly expressive of the habits of
 anarchy and warfare. (38)","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('38', 'CARDINAL')"
"An expedition for the conquest of Syria was stopped by this mournful event; the
 army halted at the gates of Medina; the chiefs were assembled round their dying master.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Medina', 'GPE')"
"An historian who balances the
 four caliphs with a hand unshaken by superstition, will
 calmly pronounce that their manners were alike pure and
 exemplary; that their zeal was fervent, and probably
 sincere; and that, in the midst of riches and power, their
 lives were devoted to the practice of moral and religious
 duties.","('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"And, during the short respite of a night,  he prepared with calm and solemn resignation to encounter his fate.","('a night', 'TIME')"
Annual truce,"('Annual', 'DATE')"
"Arabia is destitute of navigable rivers, which
 fertilize the soil, and convey its produce to the adjacent regions: the torrents that fall from the hills are imbibed by the thirsty earth: the rare and hardy plants, the tamarind or the acacia, that strike their roots into the
 clefts of the rocks, are nourished by the dews of the night: a scanty supply of rain is collected in cisterns and aqueducts: the wells and springs are the secret treasure of the desert; and the pilgrim of Mecca, (5) after many a dry and sultry march, is disgusted by the taste of the waters which have rolled over a bed of sulphur or salt.","('Arabia', 'GPE'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('5', 'CARDINAL')"
"Arabia was free: the adjacent kingdoms were shaken by the
 storms of conquest and tyranny, and the persecuted sects
 fled to the happy land where they might profess what they
 thought, and practise what they professed.","('Arabia', 'GPE')"
"As
 he tasted a drop of water, he was pierced in the mouth with
 a dart; and his son and nephew, two beautiful youths, were
 killed in his arms.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"As a distinction
 from the Jews and Christians, the Friday in each week is set
 apart for the useful institution of public worship: the
 people is assembled in the mosch; and the imam, some
 respectable elder, ascends the pulpit, to begin the prayer
 and pronounce the sermon.","('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('the Friday in each week', 'DATE')"
"As he was still supported by his family, the rest of the tribe of Koreish engaged themselves to renounce all intercourse with the children of Hashem, neither to buy nor sell, neither to marry not to give in marriage, but to pursue them with implacable enmity, till they should deliver the person of Mahomet to the justice of the gods.","('Koreish', 'PERSON'), ('Hashem', 'PERSON'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"As often as
 he is pressed by the demands of the Koreish, he involves
 himself in the obscure boast of vision and prophecy, appeals
 to the internal proofs of his doctrine, and shields himself
 behind the providence of God, who refuses those signs and
 wonders that would depreciate the merit of faith, and
 aggravate the guilt of infidelity","('Koreish', 'PERSON')"
"As often as he smote a rebel, he shouted the Allah
 Acbar, ""God is victorious!""  and in the tumult of a nocturnal battle, he was heard to repeat four hundred times that
 tremendous exclamation.","('the Allah\r\n Acbar', 'PERSON'), ('four hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"At
 home and abroad, in peace and war, Abu Taleb, the most
 respectable of his uncles, was the guide and guardian of his
 youth; in his twenty-fifth year, he entered into the service
 of Cadijah, a rich and noble widow of Mecca, who soon
 rewarded his fidelity with the gift of her hand and fortune.","('Abu Taleb', 'PERSON'), ('twenty-fifth year', 'DATE'), ('Cadijah', 'NORP'), ('Mecca', 'GPE')"
"At a moment when his faculties
 were visibly impaired, he called for pen and ink to write,
 or, more properly, to dictate, a divine book, the sum and
 accomplishment of all his revelations: a dispute arose in
 the chamber, whether he should be allowed to supersede the
 authority of the Koran; and the prophet was forced to
 reprove the indecent vehemence of his disciples.","('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"At an awful distance they cast away their
 garments: seven times, with hasty steps, they encircled the
 Caaba, and kissed the black stone: seven times they visited
 and adored the adjacent mountains; seven times they threw
 stones into the valley of Mina; and the pilgrimage was
 achieved, as at the present hour, by a sacrifice of sheep
 and camels, and the burial of their hair and nails in the
 consecrated ground.","('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caaba', 'NORP'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mina', 'GPE'), ('the present hour', 'TIME')"
"At the conclusion of the life of Mahomet, it may perhaps be
 expected, that I should balance his faults and virtues, that
 I should decide whether the title of enthusiast or impostor
 more properly belongs to that extraordinary man.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"At the dead of night, accompanied by his friend
 Abubeker, he silently escaped from his house: the assassins
 watched at the door; but they were deceived by the figure of
 Ali, who reposed on the bed, and was covered with the green
 vestment of the apostle.","('night', 'TIME'), ('Abubeker', 'PERSON'), ('Ali', 'PERSON')"
"At the end of
 fifteen months the prophet wept over his grave; but he
 sustained with firmness the raillery of his enemies, and
 checked the adulation or credulity of the Moslems, by the
 assurance that an eclipse of the sun was not occasioned by
 the death of the infant.","('the end of\r\n fifteen months', 'DATE'), ('Moslems', 'NORP')"
"At the end of two hundred years, the Sonna, or
 oral law, was fixed and consecrated by the labours of Al
 Bochari, who discriminated seven thousand two hundred and
 seventy-five genuine traditions, from a mass of three
 hundred thousand reports, of a more doubtful or spurious
 character.","('the end of two hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Sonna', 'PERSON'), ('Al\r\n Bochari', 'PERSON'), ('seven thousand two hundred and\r\n seventy-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('three\r\n hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the head
 of twenty thousand of his loyal Arabs, and nine thousand
 valiant auxiliaries of Cufa, the caliph encountered and
 defeated the superior numbers of the rebels under the walls
 of Bassora.","('twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('nine thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Cufa', 'ORG'), ('Bassora', 'GPE')"
"At the hour of
 prayer, he repaired to the mosch of Medina, clothed in a
 thin cotton gown, a coarse turban on his head, his slippers
 in one hand, and his bow in the other, instead of a
 walking-staff.","('the hour', 'TIME'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the house of Zeid, his freedman and
 adopted son, he beheld, in a loose undress, the beauty of
 Zeineb, and burst forth into an ejaculation of devotion and
 desire.","('Zeid', 'PERSON'), ('Zeineb', 'GPE')"
"At these words he placed himself, with Abubeker, on a throne or pulpit, (130) and
 instantly demanded the succour of Gabriel and three thousand
 angels.","('Abubeker', 'PERSON'), ('Gabriel', 'PERSON'), ('three thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Battle of Beder, A.D. 623.","('Beder', 'PERSON'), ('623', 'CARDINAL')"
"Beyond that place Mahomet
 declined the prosecution of the war: he declared himself
 satisfied with the peaceful intentions, he was more probably
 daunted by the martial array, of the emperor of the East.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"Beyond the seventh heaven,
 Mahomet alone was permitted to proceed; he passed the veil
 of unity, approached within two bow-shots of the throne, and
 felt a cold that pierced him to the heart, when his shoulder
 was touched by the hand of God.","('the seventh', 'DATE'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Birth and education of Mahomet, A.D. 569-609.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('569-609', 'CARDINAL')"
"Both
 parties forgot their engagements; and Gabriel again
 descended with a chapter of the Koran, to absolve him from
 his oath, and to exhort him freely to enjoy his captives and
 concubines, without listening to the clamours of his wives.","('Gabriel', 'PERSON'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"But
 their simple freedom was of a very different cast from the
 nice and artificial machinery of the Greek and Roman
 republics, in which each member possessed an undivided share
 of the civil and political rights of the community.","('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But Mahomet was
 content with a character, more humble, yet more sublime, of
 a simple editor; the substance of the Koran, (91) according
 to himself or his disciples, is uncreated and eternal;
 subsisting in the essence of the Deity, and inscribed with a
 pen of light on the table of his everlasting decrees.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('91', 'CARDINAL')"
"But Yezid
 preferred the councils of mercy; and the mourning family was
 honourably dismissed to mingle their tears with their kindred
 at Medina.","('Yezid', 'PERSON'), ('Medina', 'PERSON')"
"But as the filial relation had excited some
 doubt and scandal, the angel Gabriel descended from heaven
 to ratify the deed, to annul the adoption, and gently to
 reprove the apostle for distrusting the indulgence of his
 God.","('Gabriel', 'PERSON')"
"But in an early period
 of antiquity the great body of the Arabs had emerged from
 this scene of misery; and as the naked wilderness could not
 maintain a people of hunters, they rose at once to the more
 secure and plentiful condition of the pastoral life.","('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"But in the dreary waste of Arabia, a boundless level of sand is intersected by sharp and naked mountains; and the face of the desert, without shade or shelter, is scorched by the direct and intense rays of a tropical sun.","('Arabia', 'GPE')"
"But it was in vain that he offered
 freedom to the slaves of Tayef; that he violated his own
 laws by the extirpation of the fruit-trees; that the ground
 was opened by the miners; that the breach was assaulted by
 the troops.","('Tayef', 'PERSON')"
"But it was in vain that the camels of Abu
 Sophian explored a new road through the desert and along the
 Euphrates: they were overtaken by the diligence of the
 Mussulmans; and wealthy must have been the prize, if twenty
 thousand drams could be set apart for the fifth of the
 apostle.","('Abu\r\n Sophian', 'PERSON'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Mussulmans', 'NORP'), ('twenty\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifth', 'ORDINAL')"
"But no sooner did
 Mahomet descend into the plain, within a day's journey of
 the city, than he exclaimed,  the numbers and resolution of the Koreish opposed his progress; and the roving Arabs of the desert might desert or betray a leader whom they had
 followed for the hopes of spoil.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('day', 'DATE'), ('Koreish', 'PERSON'), ('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"But so loose was the policy of Mecca, that the
 leaders of the Koreish, instead of accusing a criminal, were
 compelled to employ the measures of persuasion or violence.","('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Koreish', 'PERSON')"
"But the
 commands of the caliph, or his lieutenant, were stern and
 absolute; and Hosein was informed that he must either submit
 as a captive and a criminal to the commander of the
 faithful, or expect the consequences of his rebellion.","('Hosein', 'PERSON')"
"But the Mahometan religion is
 destitute of priesthood or sacrifice; and the independent
 spirit of fanaticism looks down with contempt on the
 ministers and the slaves of superstition.","('Mahometan', 'NORP')"
"But the Turkish dome of St. Sophia, with an
 increase of splendour and size, represents the humble
 tabernacle erected at Medina by the hands of Mahomet.","('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('St. Sophia', 'GPE'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"But the active and intrepid Caled spread around the terror
 of his name; and the prophet received the submission of the
 tribes and cities, from the Euphrates to Ailah, at the head
 of the Red Sea.","('Caled', 'PERSON'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Ailah', 'GPE'), ('the Red Sea', 'LOC')"
"But the attempt is partial and unavailing;
 and it is with a more philosophic spirit that Mahomet relies
 on the omnipotence of the Creator, whose word can reanimate
 the breathless clay, and collect the innumerable atoms, that
 no longer retain their form or substance. (107)","('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"But the children of Israel had ceased to
 be a people; and the religions of the world were guilty, at
 least in the eyes of the prophet, of giving sons, or
 daughters, or companions, to the supreme God.","('Israel', 'GPE')"
"But the flexible genius of their faith
 was always ready either to teach or to learn: in the
 tradition of the creation, the deluge, and the patriarchs,
 they held a singular agreement with their Jewish captives;
 they appealed to the secret books of Adam, Seth, and Enoch;
 and a slight infusion of the gospel has transformed the last
 remnant of the Polytheists into the Christians of St. John,
 in the territory of Bassora. (58)","('Jewish', 'NORP'), ('Adam', 'PERSON'), ('Seth', 'PERSON'), ('Enoch', 'PERSON'), ('Polytheists', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('St. John', 'GPE'), ('Bassora', 'GPE'), ('58', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the friendship of Heraclius and Mahomet
 was of short continuance: the new religion had inflamed
 rather than assuaged the rapacious spirit of the Saracens,
 and the murder of an envoy afforded a decent pretence for
 invading, with three thousand soldiers, the territory of
 Palestine, that extends to the eastward of the Jordan.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Palestine', 'GPE'), ('Jordan', 'GPE')"
"But the mild tenor of the evangelic style
 may explain an ambiguous text, that Jesus did not bring
 peace on the earth, but a sword: his patient and humble
 virtues should not be confounded with the intolerant zeal of
 princes and bishops, who have disgraced the name of his
 disciples.","('Jesus', 'PERSON')"
"But the modest or angry
 tone of his apologies betrays his weakness and vexation; and
 these passages of scandal established, beyond suspicion, the
 integrity of the Koran. (96)","('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('96', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the precepts of Mahomet himself inculcates a
 more simple and rational piety: prayer, fasting, and alms,
 are the religious duties of a Mussulman; and he is
 encouraged to hope, that prayer will carry him half way to
 God, fasting will bring him to the door of his palace, and
 alms will gain him admittance. (101)","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Mussulman', 'NORP'), ('half', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the public virtues of Abubeker and Omar, the
 prudence of the first, the severity of the second,
 maintained the peace and prosperity of their reigns.","('Abubeker', 'PERSON'), ('Omar', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"But the religious discord of the
 friends and enemies of Ali has been renewed in every age of
 the Hegira, and is still maintained in the immortal hatred
 of the Persians and Turks. (171)","('Ali', 'PERSON'), ('Hegira', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('171', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the sounder and more consistent party
 adhere without shame, to the literal interpretation of the
 Koran: useless would be the resurrection of the body, unless
 it were restored to the possession and exercise of its
 worthiest faculties; and the union of sensual and
 intellectual enjoyment is requisite to complete the
 happiness of the double animal, the perfect man.","('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"But the three hundred and sixty idols of the Caaba were ignominiously broken: the house of God was purified and adorned: as an example to future times, the apostle again fulfilled the duties of a pilgrim; and a perpetual law was enacted that no unbeliever should dare to set his foot on the territory of the holy city. (141)
Conquest of Arabia, A.D. 629-632.","('three hundred and sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caaba', 'NORP'), ('141', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabia', 'GPE'), ('629-632', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the unsuspecting
 hero confided in himself: the jealousy of empire, and
 perhaps the fear of opposition, might suspend the
 resolutions of Mahomet; and the bed of sickness was besieged
 by the artful Ayesha, the daughter of Abubeker, and the
 enemy of Ali. 
Reign of Abubeker; A.D. 632, June 7.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Ayesha', 'PERSON'), ('Abubeker', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 632', 'DATE'), ('June 7', 'DATE')"
"But their
 adverse fortune, and the wide extent of the Mussulman
 empire, allowed an ample scope for every bold and artful
 imposture, who claimed affinity with the holy seed: the
 sceptre of the Almohades, in Spain and Africa; of the
 Fatimites, in Egypt and Syria; (184) of the Sultans of Yemen;
 and of the Sophis of Persia; (185) has been consecrated by
 this vague and ambiguous title.","('Mussulman', 'NORP'), ('Almohades', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Fatimites', 'NORP'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('184', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sultans', 'NORP'), ('Yemen', 'GPE'), ('185', 'CARDINAL')"
"But their riches were confiscated, their arms became more effectual in the hands of the Mussulmans; and a wretched colony of seven hundred exiles was driven, with their wives
 and children, to implore a refuge on the confines of Syria.","('Mussulmans', 'NORP'), ('seven hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Syria', 'GPE')"
"But they assign the last and
 most humble place to the husband of Fatima, in the
 persuasion that the order of succession was determined by
 the decrees of sanctity.","('Fatima', 'PERSON')"
"But this statue was a
 monument of Syrian arts: the devotion of the ruder ages was
 content with a pillar or a tablet; and the rocks of the
 desert were hewn into gods or altars, in imitation of the
 black stone (49) of Mecca, Sacrifices and rites.","('Syrian', 'NORP'), ('49', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mecca', 'LOC')"
"By
 the advice of Moses, he applied for an alleviation of this
 intolerable burden; the number was gradually reduced to
 five; without any dispensation of business or pleasure, or
 time or place: the devotion of the faithful is repeated at
 daybreak, at noon, in the afternoon, in the evening, and at
 the first watch of the night; and in the present decay of
 religious fervour, our travellers are edified by the profound
 humility and attention of the Turks and Persians.","('Moses', 'PERSON'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('noon', 'TIME'), ('the afternoon', 'TIME'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the night', 'TIME'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"By his intolerant
 adversaries he is upbraided for extending, even to
 themselves, the hope of salvation, for asserting the
 blackest heresy, that every man who believes in God, and
 accomplishes good works, may expect in the last day a
 favourable sentence.","('the last day', 'DATE')"
"By his persuasion, ten of
 the most respectable citizens of Mecca were introduced to
 the private lessons of Islam; they yielded to the voice of
 reason and enthusiasm; they repeated the fundamental creed,  and their faith, even in this life, was rewarded with riches and honours, with the command of armies and the government of kingdoms.","('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Islam', 'ORG')"
"By the repetition of such
 acts, the character of Mahomet must have been gradually
 stained; and the influence of such pernicious habits would
 be poorly compensated by the practice of the personal and
 social virtues which are necessary to maintain the
 reputation of a prophet among his sectaries and friends.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"By the seaport of Gedda, at the distance only of forty miles, they maintained an easy correspondence with Abyssinia; and that
 Christian kingdom afforded the first refuge to the disciples
 of Mahomet.","('Gedda', 'GPE'), ('forty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Abyssinia', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"By this alliance, the son of Abdallah was restored to the station of his ancestors; and the judicious matron was content with his domestic virtues, till, in the fortieth year of his age, (68) he assumed the title of a prophet, and proclaimed the religion of the Koran.","('Abdallah', 'PERSON'), ('the fortieth year', 'DATE'), ('68', 'DATE'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Cadijah had likewise given him
 four daughters, who were married to the most faithful of his
 disciples: the three eldest died before their father; but
 Fatima, who possessed his confidence and love, became the
 wife of her cousin Ali, and the mother of an illustrious
 progeny.","('Cadijah', 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Fatima', 'PERSON'), ('Ali', 'PERSON')"
"Charity may
 believe that the original motives of Mahomet were those of
 pure and genuine benevolence; but a human missionary is
 incapable of cherishing the obstinate unbelievers who reject
 his claims despise his arguments, and persecute his life; he
 might forgive his personal adversaries, he may lawfully hate
 the enemies of God; the stern passions of pride and revenge
 were kindled in the bosom of Mahomet, and he sighed, like
 the prophet of Nineveh, for the destruction of the rebels
 whom he had condemned.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Nineveh', 'GPE')"
Cities of Arabia:,"('Arabia', 'GPE')"
"Cleanliness is the key of prayer: the frequent lustration of
 the hands, the face, and the body, which was practised of
 old by the Arabs, is solemnly enjoined by the Koran; and a
 permission is formally granted to supply with sand the
 scarcity of water.","('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Conscious of his reason and of his weakness, he asserted the liberty of conscience, and disclaimed the use of religious violence: (114) but he called the Arabs to
 repentance, and conjured them to remember the ancient
 idolaters of Ad and Thamud, whom the divine justice had
 swept away from the face of the earth.","('114', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Ad', 'PERSON'), ('Thamud', 'NORP')"
"Death of Hosein, A.D. 680, October 10.","('Death of Hosein', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 680', 'DATE'), ('October 10', 'DATE')"
"Death of Mahomet, A.D. 632, June 7.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 632', 'DATE'), ('June 7', 'DATE')"
Description of Arabia and Its Inhabitants.,"('Arabia', 'GPE')"
Discord of the Turks and Persians.,"('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"Disdaining the penance and merit of a
 hermit, he observed, without effort or vanity, the
 abstemious diet of an Arab and a soldier.","('Arab', 'NORP')"
"Division of the sandy, the stony, and the happy, Arabia This
 division of the sandy, the stony, and the happy, so familiar to the Greeks and Latins, is unknown to the Arabians
 themselves; and it is singular enough, that a country, whose
 language and inhabitants have ever been the same, should
 scarcely retain a vestige of its ancient geography.","('Arabia', 'LOC'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('Arabians', 'NORP')"
"During four
 years, the health of the prophet declined; his infirmities
 increased; but his mortal disease was a fever of fourteen
 days, which deprived him by intervals of the use of reason.","('four\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('fourteen\r\n days', 'DATE')"
"During six
 hundred years the gospel was the way of truth and salvation;
 but the Christians insensibly forgot both the laws and
 example of their founder; and Mahomet was instructed by the
 Gnostics to accuse the church, as well as the synagogue, of
 corrupting the integrity of the sacred text. (89)","('six\r\n hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Gnostics', 'NORP'), ('89', 'CARDINAL')"
"During that period, some rays of prophetic light had been imparted to one hundred and twenty-four thousand of the elect, discriminated by their
 respective measure of virtue and grace; three hundred and
 thirteen apostles were sent with a special commission to
 recall their country from idolatry and vice; one hundred and
 four volumes have been dictated by the Holy Spirit; and six
 legislators of transcendent brightness have announced to
 mankind the six successive revelations of various rites, but
 of one immutable religion.","('one hundred and twenty-four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('three hundred and\r\n thirteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred and\r\n four', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Holy Spirit', 'ORG'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"During the month of Ramadan,
 from the rising to the setting of the sun, the Mussulman
 abstains from eating, and drinking, and women, and baths,
 and perfumes; from all nourishment that can restore his
 strength, from all pleasure that can gratify his senses.","('the month of Ramadan', 'DATE'), ('Mussulman', 'NORP')"
"During the twenty-four years of their marriage, her youthful
 husband abstained from the right of polygamy, and the pride
 or tenderness of the venerable matron was never insulted by
 the society of a rival.","('the twenty-four years', 'DATE')"
"Each
 tribe, each family, each independent warrior, created and
 changed the rites and the object of his fantastic worship;
 but the nation, in every age, has bowed to the religion, as
 well as to the language, of Mecca.","('Mecca', 'GPE')"
"Each day the pious author prayed in the temple
 of Mecca, and performed his ablutions with the water of
 Zemzem: the pages were successively deposited on the pulpit
 and the sepulchre of the apostle; and the work has been
 approved by the four orthodox sects of the Sonnites. (95)
Miracles","('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Zemzem', 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sonnites', 'ORG')"
"Each tribe either found or introduced
 in the Caaba their domestic worship: the temple was adorned,
 or defiled, with three hundred and sixty idols of men,
 eagles, lions, and antelopes; and most conspicuous was the
 statue of Hebal, of red agate, holding in his hand seven
 arrows, without heads or feathers, the instruments and
 symbols of profane divination.","('Caaba', 'NORP'), ('three hundred and sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hebal', 'PERSON'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"Enthusiasm and discipline impelled the march, and preserved
 the secret till the blaze of ten thousand fires proclaimed
 to the astonished Koreish the design, the approach, and the
 irresistible force of the enemy.","('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Koreish', 'NORP')"
"Even a female of sense and spirit has been
 permitted to command the countrymen of Zenobia. (31)","('Zenobia', 'PERSON'), ('31', 'CARDINAL')"
"Even in a conqueror or a priest, I can
 surprise a word or action of unaffected humanity; and the
 decree of Mahomet, that, in the sale of captives, the
 mothers should never be separated from their children, may
 suspend, or moderate, the censure of the historian. (157)","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('157', 'CARDINAL')"
"Even the wilds of
 Tartary are decked, by the hand of nature, with lofty trees and luxuriant herbage; and the lonesome traveller derives a sort of comfort and society from the presence of vegetable life.","('Tartary', 'LOC')"
"First war of the Mahometans against the Roman empire, A.D. 629, 630.","('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Mahometans', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('A.D. 629', 'FAC'), ('630', 'CARDINAL')"
"Five
 hundred of the citizens advanced to meet him; he was hailed
 with acclamations of loyalty and devotion; Mahomet was
 mounted on a she-camel, an umbrella shaded his head, and a
 turban was unfurled before him to supply the deficiency of a
 standard.","('Five\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"Five times each day the eyes of Mahomet were turned towards
 Mecca, (138) and he was urged by the most sacred and powerful motives to revisit, as a conqueror, the city and the temple
 from whence he had been driven as an exile.","('Five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('138', 'CARDINAL')"
Flies to Medina.,"('Medina', 'GPE')"
"For the author of Christianity,
 the Mahometans are taught by the prophet to entertain a high
 and mysterious reverence. (84) Jesus","('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Mahometans', 'NORP')"
"Forsaken by those who had abused his
 simplicity, the hopeless and venerable caliph expected the
 approach of death: the brother of Ayesha marched at the head
 of the assassins; Death of Othman, A.D. 655, June 18.  and Othman, with the Koran in his lap, was
 pierced with a multitude of wounds.","('Ayesha', 'PERSON'), ('Death of Othman', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 655', 'DATE'), ('June 18', 'DATE'), ('Othman', 'PERSON'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Four thousand Pagans advanced with secrecy and speed to surprise the conqueror: they pitied and despised
 the supine negligence of the Koreish, but they depended on
 the wishes, and perhaps the aid, of a people who had so
 lately renounced their gods, and bowed beneath the yoke of
 their enemy.","('Four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pagans', 'NORP'), ('Koreish', 'NORP')"
"From Cufa,
 from Bassora, from Egypt, from the tribes of the desert,
 they rose in arms, encamped about a league from Medina, and
 despatched a haughty mandate to their sovereign, requiring
 him to execute justice, or to descend from the throne.","('Cufa', 'PERSON'), ('Bassora', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Medina', 'GPE')"
"From Japan to Peru, the
 use of sacrifice has universally prevailed; and the votary
 has expressed his gratitude, or fear, by destroying or
 consuming, in honour of the gods, the dearest and most
 precious of their gifts.","('Japan', 'GPE'), ('Peru', 'GPE')"
"From Mecca to the Euphrates, the Arabian tribes (29)
 were confounded by the Greeks and Latins, under the general
 appellation of SARACENS, (30) a name which every Christian mouth has been taught to pronounce with terror and abhorrence.","('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('29', 'CARDINAL'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Latins', 'NORP'), ('30', 'CARDINAL'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"From all sides the roving Arabs
 were allured to the standard of religion and plunder: the
 apostle sanctified the license of embracing the female
 captives as their wives or concubines, and the enjoyment of
 wealth and beauty was a feeble type of the joys of paradise
 prepared for the valiant martyrs of the faith.","('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"From enthusiasm to
 imposture, the step is perilous and slippery: the daemon of
 Socrates (155) affords a memorable instance, how a wise man may deceive himself, how a good man may deceive others, how
 the conscience may slumber in a mixed and middle state
 between self-illusion and voluntary fraud.","('Socrates', 'PERSON'), ('155', 'CARDINAL')"
"From every
 region of that solitary world, the pilgrims of Mecca were
 annually assembled, by the calls of devotion and commerce:
 in the free concourse of multitudes, a simple citizen, in
 his native tongue, might study the political state and
 character of the tribes, the theory and practice of the Jews
 and Christians.","('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"From his earliest youth Mahomet was addicted to religious
 contemplation; each year, during the month of Ramadan, he
 withdrew from the world, and from the arms of Cadijah: in
 the cave of Hera, three miles from Mecca, (73) he consulted
 the spirit of fraud or enthusiasm, whose abode is not in the
 heavens, but in the mind of the prophet.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('the month of Ramadan', 'DATE'), ('Cadijah', 'PERSON'), ('Hera', 'PERSON'), ('three miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('73', 'DATE')"
"From his establishment at Medina, Mahomet assumed the
 exercise of the regal and sacerdotal office; and it was
 impious to appeal from a judge whose decrees were inspired
 by the divine wisdom.","('Medina', 'GPE'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"From the
 Atlantic to the Ganges, the Koran is acknowledged as the
 fundamental code, not only of theology, but of civil and
 criminal jurisprudence; and the laws which regulate the
 actions and the property of mankind are guarded by the
 infallible and immutable sanction of the will of God.","('Atlantic', 'LOC'), ('Ganges', 'LOC'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"From the field of Honain, he
 marched without delay to the siege of Tayef, sixty miles to
 the south- east of Mecca, a fortress of strength, whose
 fertile lands produce the fruits of Syria in the midst of
 the Arabian desert.","('Honain', 'GPE'), ('Tayef', 'GPE'), ('sixty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Arabian', 'NORP')"
"From the first hour of his mission to the last rites
 of his funeral, the apostle was never forsaken by a generous
 friend, whom he delighted to name his brother, his
 vicegerent, and the faithful Aaron of a second Moses.","('the first hour', 'TIME'), ('Aaron', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Moses', 'PERSON')"
"From the northern point of Beles (3) on the Euphrates, a line of fifteen hundred miles is terminated by the Straits of Bebelmandel and the land of frankincense.","('Beles', 'GPE'), ('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('fifteen hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('the Straits of Bebelmandel', 'LOC')"
"From the observations of two thousand years, the
 priests and astronomers of Babylon (56) deduced the eternal
 laws of nature and providence.","('two thousand years', 'DATE'), ('Babylon', 'GPE'), ('56', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the passage of Thapsacus, the plain of Siffin (174)
 extends along the western bank of the Euphrates.","('Thapsacus', 'GPE'), ('Siffin', 'GPE'), ('174', 'CARDINAL'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"Had I been
 intimately conversant with the son of Abdallah, the task
 would still be difficult, and the success uncertain: at the
 distance of twelve centuries, I darkly contemplate his shade
 through a cloud of religious incense; and could I truly
 delineate the portrait of an hour, the fleeting resemblance
 would not equally apply to the solitary of Mount Hera, to
 the preacher of Mecca, and to the conqueror of Arabia.","('Abdallah', 'PERSON'), ('twelve centuries', 'DATE'), ('an hour', 'TIME'), ('Mount Hera', 'LOC'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Arabia', 'GPE')"
"Had the
 impulse been less powerful, Arabia, free at home and
 formidable abroad, might have flourished under a succession
 of her native monarchs.","('Arabia', 'LOC')"
"He
 checked the lamentations of his sister Fatima, who deplored
 the impending ruin of his house.","('Fatima', 'PERSON')"
"He
 traversed the desert of Arabia with a timorous retinue of
 women and children; but as he approached the confines of
 Irak he was alarmed by the solitary or hostile face of the
 country, and suspected either the defection or ruin of his
 party.","('Arabia', 'LOC'), ('Irak', 'PERSON')"
He Preaches at Mecca.,"('Mecca', 'GPE')"
"He beheld with temperate firmness the approach of death; enfranchised his slaves (seventeen men, as they are named, and eleven women;) minutely directed the order of his funeral, and moderated the lamentations of his
 weeping friends, on whom he bestowed the benediction of
 peace.","('seventeen', 'CARDINAL'), ('eleven', 'CARDINAL')"
"He besieged their castle, three miles from Medina; but their resolute defence obtained an honourable capitulation; and the
 garrison, sounding their trumpets and beating their drums, was permitted to depart with the honours of war.","('three miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Medina', 'GPE')"
"He compares the nations and the regions of
 the earth; discovers the weakness of the Persian and Roman
 monarchies; beholds, with pity and indignation, the
 degeneracy of the times; and resolves to unite under one God
 and one king the invincible spirit and primitive virtues of
 the Arabs.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"He concealed himself in a cavern near
 Bagdad: the time and place of his death are unknown; and his
 votaries pretend that he still lives, and will appear before
 the day of judgment to overthrow the tyranny of Dejal, or
 the Antichrist. (182)","('Bagdad', 'GPE'), ('Dejal', 'PERSON'), ('Antichrist', 'PERSON'), ('182', 'CARDINAL')"
"He despatched a messenger to his brethren of Mecca, and they
 were roused, by the fear of losing their merchandise and
 their provisions, unless they hastened to his relief with
 the military force of the city.","('Mecca', 'GPE')"
"He disdained to compel their service: but on his return he admonished the most guilty, by an excommunication of fifty days.","('fifty days', 'DATE')"
"He expired in the
 sixty-third year of his age, and mercifully recommended to
 his children, that they would despatch the murderer by a
 single stroke.","('the\r\n sixty-third year', 'DATE')"
"He generously proposed to
 save the blood of the Moslems by a single combat; but his
 trembling rival declined the challenge as a sentence of
 inevitable death.","('Moslems', 'NORP')"
"He has never been accused of prompting
 the assassin of Omar; though Persia indiscreetly celebrates
 the festival of that holy martyr.","('Omar', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"He might have
 obtained their suffrage, had he deigned to promise a strict
 and servile conformity, not only to the Koran and tradition,
 but likewise to the determinations of two seniors. of Othman, A.D. 644, November 6. (170)","('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Othman', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 644', 'DATE'), ('November 6', 'DATE'), ('170', 'CARDINAL')"
"He might still
 have escaped to a fortress in the desert, that had defied
 the power of Caesar and Chosroes, and confided in the
 fidelity of the tribe of Tai, which would have armed ten
 thousand warriors in his defence.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Chosroes', 'PERSON'), ('Tai', 'PERSON'), ('ten\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
He persevered ten years in the exercise of his mission; and the religion which has overspread the East and the West advanced with a slow and painful progress within the walls of Mecca.,"('ten years', 'DATE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Mecca', 'GPE')"
"He possessed the courage both of thought and
 action; and, although his designs might gradually expand
 with his success, the first idea which he entertained of his
 divine mission bears the stamp of an original and superior
 genius.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"He retreated
 with sorrow and indignation to Cufa; his party was
 discouraged; the distant provinces of Persia, of Yemen, and
 of Egypt, were subdued or seduced by his crafty rival; and
 the stroke of fanaticism, which was aimed against the three
 chiefs of the nation, was fatal only to the cousin of
 Mahomet.","('Cufa', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Yemen', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"He united the
 qualifications of a poet, a soldier, and a saint: his wisdom
 still breathes in a collection of moral and religious
 sayings; (167) and every antagonist, in the combats of the
 tongue or of the sword, was subdued by his eloquence and
 valour.","('167', 'CARDINAL')"
"He was followed by the deputies of Tayef, who dreaded the repetition of a
 siege.","('Tayef', 'PERSON')"
"He was indeed wounded in the face with a javelin: two of his
 teeth were shattered with a stone; yet, in the midst of
 tumult and dismay, he reproached the infidels with the
 murder of a prophet; and blessed the friendly hand that
 stanched his blood, and conveyed him to a place of safety.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"He was piously interred by the hands of his nearest kinsman, on the
 same spot on which he expired: (151) Medina has been
 sanctified by the death and burial of Mahomet; and the
 innumerable pilgrims of Mecca often turn aside from the way,
 to bow, in voluntary devotion, (152) before the simple tomb
 of the prophet.","('151', 'CARDINAL'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('152', 'CARDINAL')"
"Her behaviour had been ambiguous and
 indiscreet: in a nocturnal march she was accidentally left
 behind; and in the morning Ayesha returned to the camp with
 a man.","('Ayesha', 'PERSON')"
His Death and Successors.,"('Death and Successors', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
His beneficial or pernicious influence on the public happiness is the last consideration in the character of Mahomet.,"('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"His best beloved
 Abdallah was the most beautiful and modest of the Arabian
 youth; and in the first night, when he consummated his
 marriage with Amina,  of the noble race of the Zahrites, two hundred virgins are said to have expired of jealousy and
 despair.","('Abdallah', 'PERSON'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Amina', 'PERSON'), ('Zahrites', 'NORP'), ('two hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"His bravest disciples, who had been scattered by
 the storm, assembled round his person; and the equal, though
 various, merit of the Moslems was distinguished by the names
 of Mohagerians and Ansars, the fugitives of Mecca, and the
 auxiliaries of Medina.","('Moslems', 'NORP'), ('Mohagerians', 'NORP'), ('Ansars', 'NORP'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Medina', 'GPE')"
"His death was resolved; and they agreed
 that a sword from each tribe should be buried in his heart,
 to divide the guilt of his blood, and baffle the vengeance
 of the Hashemites.","('Hashemites', 'NORP')"
His defensive war against the Koreish of Mecca.,"('Koreish', 'NORP'), ('Mecca', 'GPE')"
"His descent from
 Ismael was a national privilege or fable; but if the first
 steps of the pedigree (64) are dark and doubtful, he could
 produce many generations of pure and genuine nobility: he
 sprung from the tribe of Koreish and the family of Hashem,
 the most illustrious of the Arabs, the princes of Mecca, and
 the hereditary guardians of the Caaba.","('Ismael', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('64', 'CARDINAL'), ('Koreish', 'NORP'), ('Hashem', 'PERSON'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Caaba', 'NORP')"
"His epileptic fits, an absurd calumny of the
 Greeks, would be an object of pity rather than abhorrence;
 (149) but he seriously believed that he was poisoned at
 Chaibar by the revenge of a Jewish female. (150)","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Chaibar', 'PERSON'), ('Jewish', 'NORP'), ('150', 'CARDINAL')"
"His eye was fixed on the field of battle: the
 Mussulmans fainted and were pressed: in that decisive moment
 the prophet started from his throne, mounted his horse, and
 cast a handful of sand into the air:  Both armies heard the thunder of his voice: their fancy beheld the angelic warriors: (131) the
 Koreish trembled and fled: seventy of the bravest were slain; and seventy captives adorned the first victory of the faithful.","('Mussulmans', 'NORP'), ('131', 'CARDINAL'), ('Koreish', 'NORP'), ('seventy', 'CARDINAL'), ('seventy', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"His fears were just: Obeidollah, the governor of
 Cufa, had extinguished the first sparks of an insurrection;
 and Hosein, in the plain of Kerbela, was encompassed by a
 body of five thousand horse, who intercepted his
 communication with the city and the river.","('Obeidollah', 'PERSON'), ('Cufa', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Hosein', 'PERSON'), ('Kerbela', 'GPE'), ('five thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"His imprisonment might provoke the
 despair of his enthusiasm; and the exile of an eloquent and
 popular fanatic would diffuse the mischief through the
 provinces of Arabia.","('Arabia', 'GPE')"
"His lieutenants, on the shores of the Red Sea, the Ocean, and the Gulf of Persia, were saluted by the acclamations of a faithful people; and the ambassadors, who knelt before the throne of Medina, were as numerous (says the Arabian proverb) as the dates that fall from the maturity of a palm-tree.","('the Red Sea', 'LOC'), ('Ocean', 'LOC'), ('the Gulf of Persia', 'LOC'), ('Medina', 'PERSON'), ('Arabian', 'NORP')"
"His march from Medina to
 Mecca displayed the peaceful and solemn pomp of a
 pilgrimage: seventy camels, chosen and bedecked for
 sacrifice, preceded the van; the sacred territory was
 respected; and the captives were dismissed without ransom to
 proclaim his clemency and devotion.","('Medina', 'GPE'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('seventy', 'CARDINAL')"
"His regal dignity, A.D. 622-632.","('622-632', 'CARDINAL')"
"His resistless word split asunder the orb of the moon: the
 obedient planet stooped from her station in the sky,
 accomplished the seven revolutions round the Caaba, saluted
 Mahomet in the Arabian tongue, and, suddenly contracting her
 dimensions, entered at the collar, and issued forth through
 the sleeve, of his shirt. (99)","('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caaba', 'NORP'), ('Mahomet', 'NORP'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('99', 'CARDINAL')"
"His seal of gold, or
 silver, was inscribed with the apostolic title; when he
 prayed and preached in the weekly assembly, he leaned
 against the trunk of a palm-tree; and it was long before he
 indulged himself in the use of a chair or pulpit of rough
 timber. (122)","('122', 'CARDINAL')"
"His troops were strictly enjoined to
 await the first onset of the enemy, to spare their flying
 brethren, and to respect the bodies of the dead, and the
 chastity of the female captives.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"His troops, in three divisions, marched
 into the city: eight-and-twenty of the inhabitants were
 slain by the sword of Caled; eleven men and six women were
 proscribed by the sentence of Mahomet; but he blamed the
 cruelty of his lieutenant; and several of the most obnoxious
 victims were indebted for their lives to his clemency or
 contempt.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('eight-and-twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caled', 'PERSON'), ('eleven', 'CARDINAL'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"His uncle Abbas, who, like the heroes of Homer, excelled in the
 loudness of his voice, made the valley resound with the recital of the gifts and promises of God: the flying Moslems returned from all sides to the holy standard; and Mahomet observed with pleasure that the furnace was again rekindled: his conduct and example restored the battle, and he animated
 his victorious troops to inflict a merciless revenge on the
 authors of their shame.","('Abbas', 'PERSON'), ('Homer', 'PERSON'), ('Moslems', 'NORP'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"His voice invited the Arabs to freedom and victory,
 to arms and rapine, to the indulgence of their darling
 passions in this world and the other: the restraints which
 he imposed were requisite to establish the credit of the
 prophet, and to exercise the obedience of the people; and
 the only objection to his success was his rational creed of
 the unity and perfections of God.","('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"I am ignorant, and I am
 careless, of the blind mythology of the Barbarians; of the
 local deities, of the stars, the air, and the earth, of
 their sex or titles, their attributes or subordination.","('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"I. According to the
 tradition of the nocturnal journey, the apostle, in his
 personal conference with the Deity, was commanded to impose
 on his disciples the daily obligation of fifty prayers.","('fifty', 'CARDINAL')"
"If
 the composition of the Koran exceed the faculties of a man
 to what superior intelligence should we ascribe the Iliad of
 Homer, or the Philippics of Demosthenes?","('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('the Iliad of\r\n Homer', 'PERSON'), ('Philippics', 'NORP')"
"If a Bedoween discovers from afar a
 solitary traveller, he rides furiously against him, crying,
 with a loud voice, ""Undress thyself, thy aunt (my wife) is without a garment.""","('Bedoween', 'PERSON')"
"If he falls by their hands, they are exposed, in
 their turn, to the danger of reprisals, the interest and
 principal of the bloody debt are accumulated: the
 individuals of either family lead a life of malice and
 suspicion, and fifty years may sometimes elapse before the
 account of vengeance be finally settled.","('fifty years', 'DATE')"
"If he retained any
 vestige of his native innocence, the sins of Mahomet may be
 allowed as an evidence of his sincerity.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"If the
 Christian apostles, St. Peter or St. Paul, could return to
 the Vatican, they might possibly inquire the name of the
 Deity who is worshipped with such mysterious rites in that
 magnificent temple: at Oxford or Geneva, they would
 experience less surprise; but it might still be incumbent on
 them to peruse the catechism of the church, and to study the
 orthodox commentators on their own writings and the words of
 their Master.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('St. Peter', 'PERSON'), ('St. Paul', 'GPE'), ('Vatican', 'FAC'), ('Oxford', 'GPE'), ('Geneva', 'GPE')"
"If the
 slightest credit may be afforded to the traditions of his
 wives and companions, he maintained, in the bosom of his
 family, and to the last moments of his life, the dignity 
 of an apostle, and the faith of an enthusiast; described the
 visits of Gabriel, who bade an everlasting farewell to the
 earth, and expressed his lively confidence, not only of the
 mercy, but of the favour, of the Supreme Being.","('Gabriel', 'PERSON')"
"If the Arabian princes abuse their power,
 they are quickly punished by the desertion of their
 subjects, who had been accustomed to a mild and parental
 jurisdiction.","('Arabian', 'NORP')"
"If they professed the creed of Islam, they were
 admitted to all the temporal and spiritual benefits of his
 primitive disciples, and marched under the same banner to
 extend the religion which they had embraced.","('Islam', 'ORG')"
"If we remember the seven hundred wives and three hundred concubines of the wise Solomon, we shall
 applaud the modesty of the Arabian, who espoused no more
 than seventeen or fifteen wives; eleven are enumerated who
 occupied at Medina their separate apartments round the house
 of the apostle, and enjoyed in their turns the favour of his
 conjugal society.","('seven hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Solomon', 'PERSON'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('no more\r\n than seventeen or fifteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('eleven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Medina', 'GPE')"
"In
 Arabia, as well as in Greece, the perfection of language
 outstripped the refinement of manners; and her speech could
 diversify the fourscore names of honey, the two hundred of a
 serpent, the five hundred of a lion, the thousand of a
 sword, at a time when this copious dictionary was entrusted
 to the memory of an illiterate people.","('Arabia', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('two hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('five hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"In
 the revolution of the lunar year, the Ramadan coincides, by
 turns, with the winter cold and the summer heat; and the
 patient martyr, without assuaging his thirst with a drop of
 water, must expect the close of a tedious and sultry day.","('the lunar year', 'EVENT'), ('winter', 'DATE')"
"In
 these hasty and superficial excursions, the eye of genius
 might discern some objects invisible to his grosser
 companions; some seeds of knowledge might be cast upon a
 fruitful soil; but his ignorance of the Syriac language must
 have checked his curiosity; and I cannot perceive, in the
 life or writings of Mahomet, that his prospect was far
 extended beyond the limits of the Arabian world.","('Syriac', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Arabian', 'NORP')"
"In a
 remote period of antiquity, Sabianism was diffused over Asia
 by the science of the Chaldaeans (55) and the arms of the
 Assyrians.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Chaldaeans', 'PERSON'), ('55', 'CARDINAL'), ('Assyrians', 'NORP')"
"In a conference with the
 chief of the enemy, he proposed the option of three
 honourable conditions: that he should be allowed to return to
 Medina, or be stationed in a frontier garrison against the
 Turks, or safely conducted to the presence of Yezid.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Yezid', 'PERSON')"
"In a distant age and climate, the tragic scene of the death of
 Hosein will awaken the sympathy of the coldest reader.","('Hosein', 'PERSON')"
"In a more serious tone, the father of Ali advised his nephew to relinquish his impracticable design.","('Ali', 'PERSON')"
"In a solitary retreat of thirty days, he labored, alone with
 Mary, to fulfil the commands of the angel.","('thirty days', 'DATE'), ('Mary', 'PERSON')"
"In a transport of despair his sister
 issued from the tent, and adjured the general of the
 Cufians, that he would not suffer Hosein to be murdered
 before his eyes: a tear trickled down his venerable beard;
 and the boldest of his soldiers fell back on every side as
 the dying hero threw himself among them.","('Cufians', 'PERSON'), ('Hosein', 'PERSON')"
"In all religions,
 the life of the founder supplies the silence of his written
 revelation: the sayings of Mahomet were so many lessons of
 truth; his actions so many examples of virtue; and the
 public and private memorials were preserved by his wives and
 companions.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"In every close
 onset, or single combat, the despair of the Fatimites was
 invincible; but the surrounding multitudes galled them from
 a distance with a cloud of arrows, and the horses and men
 were successively slain; a truce was allowed on both sides
 for the hour of prayer; and the battle at length expired by
 the death of the last companions of Hosein.","('Fatimites', 'NORP'), ('the hour', 'TIME'), ('Hosein', 'PERSON')"
"In his
 adventures with Zeineb, the wife of Zeid, and with Mary, an
 Egyptian captive, the amorous prophet forgot the interest of
 his reputation.","('Zeineb', 'PERSON'), ('Zeid', 'PERSON'), ('Mary', 'PERSON'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP')"
"In his early infancy, he was deprived of his father, his mother, and his
 grandfather; his uncles were strong and numerous; and, in
 the division of the inheritance, the orphan's share was
 reduced to five camels and an Aethiopian maid-servant.","('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aethiopian', 'NORP')"
"In his testament, with the
 tacit approbation of his companions, he bequeathed the
 sceptre to the firm and intrepid virtue of Omar.","('Omar', 'PERSON')"
"In serving at table, a slave had inadvertently
 dropped a dish of scalding broth on his master: the heedless
 wretch fell prostrate, to deprecate his punishment, and
 repeated a verse of the Koran:   With an equal measure of piety, Hosein, the younger brother of Hassan,
 inherited a remnant of his father's spirit, and served with
 honour against the Christians in the siege of Constantinople.","('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Hosein', 'PERSON'), ('Hassan', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"In the
 more simple state of the Arabs, the nation is free, because
 each of her sons disdains a base submission to the will of a
 master.","('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"In the Ottoman empire they
 are distinguished by a green turban; receive a stipend from
 the treasury; are judged only by their chief; and, however
 debased by fortune or character, still assert the proud
 preeminence of their birth.","('Ottoman', 'NORP')"
"In the constitution of Europe, the right of
 peace and war is now confined to a small, and the actual
 exercise to a much smaller, list of respectable potentates;
 but each Arab, with impunity and renown, might point his
 javelin against the life of his countrymen.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Arab', 'NORP')"
"In the course of
 ninety actions or skirmishes, the loss of Ali was estimated
 at twenty-five, that of Moawiyah at forty-five, thousand
 soldiers; and the list of the slain was dignified with the
 names of five-and-twenty veterans who had fought at Beder
 under the standard of Mahomet.","('ninety', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ali', 'PERSON'), ('twenty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moawiyah', 'GPE'), ('forty-five, thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('five-and-twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Beder', 'ORG'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"In the familiar offices of life he scrupulously adhered to
 the grave and ceremonious politeness of his country: his
 respectful attention to the rich and powerful was dignified
 by his condescension and affability to the poorest citizens
 of Mecca: the frankness of his manner concealed the artifice
 of his views; and the habits of courtesy were imputed to
 personal friendship or universal benevolence.","('Mecca', 'GPE')"
"In the fertile and famous vale of Beder,
 (129) three stations from Medina, he was informed by his scouts of the caravan that approached on one side; of the Koreish, one hundred horse, eight hundred and fifty foot, who advanced on the other.","('Beder', 'PRODUCT'), ('129', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Koreish', 'NORP'), ('one hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('eight hundred and fifty foot', 'QUANTITY')"
"In the first days of
 his reign, he neglected to secure, either by gifts or
 fetters, the doubtful allegiance of Telha and Zobeir, two of
 the most powerful of the Arabian chiefs.","('the first days', 'DATE'), ('Telha', 'PERSON'), ('Zobeir', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabian', 'NORP')"
"In the first months of
 his reign he practised the lessons of holy warfare, and
 displayed his white banner before the gates of Medina: the
 martial apostle fought in person at nine battles or sieges;
 (125) and fifty enterprises of war were achieved in ten years
 by himself or his lieutenants.","('the first months', 'DATE'), ('Medina', 'PERSON'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('125', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten years', 'DATE')"
"In the first, ten Charegites and two Awsites united
 in faith and love, protested, in the name of their wives,
 their children, and their absent brethren, that they would
 forever profess the creed, and observe the precepts, of the
 Koran.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Charegites', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Awsites', 'NORP'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"In the free society of the Arabs, the duties
 of subject and citizen imposed a feeble restraint; and
 Mahomet, in the exercise of a peaceful and benevolent
 mission, had been despoiled and banished by the injustice of
 his countrymen.","('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"In the heat of the action, seventy men, who held the
 bridle of her camel, were successively killed or wounded;
 and the cage or litter, in which she sat, was stuck with
 javelins and darts like the quills of a porcupine.","('seventy', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the idiom of the Koran,
 (108) the belief of God is inseparable from that of Mahomet:
 the good works are those which he has enjoined, and the two
 qualifications imply the profession of Islam, to which all
 nations and all sects are equally invited.","('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('108', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Islam', 'ORG')"
"In the lapse of two or three centuries,
 the posterity of Abbas, the uncle of Mahomet, had multiplied
 to the number of thirty-three thousand: (183) the race of Ali
 might be equally prolific: the meanest individual was above
 the first and greatest of princes; and the most eminent were
 supposed to excel the perfection of angels.","('two or three centuries', 'DATE'), ('Abbas', 'PERSON'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('thirty-three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('183', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ali', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"In the markets of
 Saana and Merab, in the harbours of Oman and Aden, the camels
 of the Koreishites were laden with a precious cargo of
 aromatics; a supply of corn and manufactures was purchased
 in the fairs of Bostra and Damascus; the lucrative exchange
 diffused plenty and riches in the streets of Mecca; and the
 noblest of her sons united the love of arms with the
 profession of merchandise. (20)
National independence of the Arabs.","('Saana', 'GPE'), ('Merab', 'GPE'), ('Oman', 'GPE'), ('Aden', 'GPE'), ('Koreishites', 'PRODUCT'), ('Bostra', 'GPE'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('20', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"In the mid-way, ten days' journey from Medina and Damascus, they reposed near
 the grove and fountain of Tabuc.","(""ten days'"", 'DATE'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Tabuc', 'GPE')"
"In the moving picture of the dynasties of
 the East, a hundred fortunate usurpers have arisen from a
 baser origin, surmounted more formidable obstacles, and
 filled a larger scope of empire and conquest.","('East', 'LOC'), ('hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the nocturnal council of the camp he was chosen to command: his skilful evolutions of the ensuing day secured either the victory or the retreat of the Saracens; and Caled is renowned among his brethren and his enemies by the glorious appellation of the
 Sword of God.","('the ensuing day', 'DATE'), ('Saracens', 'NORP'), ('Caled', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n Sword of God', 'PERSON')"
"In the prosecution of religious war, Mahomet
 might appeal with more propriety to the example of Moses, of
 the Judges, and the kings of Israel.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Moses', 'PERSON'), ('Israel', 'GPE')"
"In the pulpit, Mahomet described, with
 prophetic rapture, the crowns of the blessed martyrs; but in
 private he betrayed the feelings of human nature: he was
 surprised as he wept over the daughter of Zeid: ""What do I see?""  said the astonished votary.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Zeid', 'PERSON')"
"In the rainy seasons, they consume the
 rare and insufficient herbage of the desert: during the
 heats of summer and the scarcity of winter, they remove
 their encampments to the sea-coast, the hills of Yemen, or
 the neighbourhood of the Euphrates, and have often extorted
 the dangerous license of visiting the banks of the Nile, and
 the villages of Syria and Palestine.","('the rainy seasons', 'DATE'), ('winter', 'DATE'), ('Yemen', 'GPE'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Palestine', 'GPE')"
"In the rude
 idolatry of the Arabs, the crime is manifest and audacious:
 the Sabians are poorly excused by the preeminence of the
 first planet, or intelligence, in their celestial hierarchy;
 and in the Magian system the conflict of the two principles
 betrays the imperfection of the conqueror.","('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Sabians', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Magian', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the sands
 of Africa and Arabia, the camel is a sacred and precious gift.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Arabia', 'LOC')"
"In the spirit of
 enthusiasm or vanity, the prophet rests the truth of his
 mission on the merit of his book; audaciously challenges
 both men and angels to imitate the beauties of a single
 page; and presumes to assert that God alone could dictate
 this incomparable performance. (92)","('92', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the story of the Hebrew
 patriarchs, the Arabs were pleased to discover the fathers
 of their nation.","('Hebrew', 'NORP'), ('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"In the temple of Mecca, three Charegites or
 enthusiasts discoursed of the disorders of the church and
 state: they soon agreed, that the deaths of Ali, of
 Moawiyah, and of his friend Amrou, the viceroy of Egypt,
 would restore the peace and unity of religion.","('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Charegites', 'NORP'), ('Ali', 'PERSON'), ('Moawiyah', 'GPE'), ('Amrou', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"In the time of ignorance, the Arabs, like
 the Jews and Egyptians, abstained from the taste of swine's
 flesh; (53) they circumcised (54) their children at the age of
 puberty: the same customs, without the censure or the
 precept of the Koran, have been silently transmitted to
 their posterity and proselytes.","('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Egyptians', 'NORP'), ('53', 'CARDINAL'), ('54', 'CARDINAL'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"In the twelfth
 year of his reign, Omar received a mortal wound from the
 hand of an assassin: he rejected with equal impartiality the
 names of his son and of Ali, refused to load his conscience
 with the sins of his successor, and devolved on six of the
 most respectable companions the arduous task of electing a
 commander of the faithful.","('the twelfth\r\n year', 'DATE'), ('Omar', 'PERSON'), ('Ali', 'PERSON'), ('six', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the vacant space between Persia, Syria, Egypt, and Aethiopia, the Arabian peninsula (2) may be conceived as a triangle of spacious but irregular dimensions.","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Aethiopia', 'GPE'), ('Arabian', 'NORP'), ('2', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the various conditions of princes, or doctors, or nobles, or merchants,
 or beggars, a swarm of the genuine or fictitious descendants
 of Mahomet and Ali is honoured with the appellation of
 sheiks, or sherifs, or emirs.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Ali', 'PERSON')"
"In their
 obvious sense, they introduce three equal deities, and
 transform the man Jesus into the substance of the Son of
 God: (76) an orthodox commentary will satisfy only a
 believing mind: intemperate curiosity and zeal had torn the
 veil of the sanctuary; and each of the Oriental sects was
 eager to confess that all, except themselves, deserved the
 reproach of idolatry and polytheism.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jesus', 'PERSON'), ('the Son of\r\n God', 'PERSON'), ('76', 'CARDINAL'), ('Oriental', 'NORP')"
"In their nocturnal
 marches, they steered by the guidance of the stars: their
 names, and order, and daily station, were familiar to the
 curiosity and devotion of the Bedoween; and he was taught by
 experience to divide, in twenty-eight parts, the zodiac of
 the moon, and to bless the constellations who refreshed,
 with salutary rains, the thirst of the desert.","('Bedoween', 'NORP'), ('twenty-eight', 'CARDINAL')"
"In their private converse, in their public worship,
 they bitterly execrate the three usurpers who intercepted
 his indefeasible right to the dignity of Imam and Caliph;
 and the name of Omar expresses in their tongue the perfect
 accomplishment of wickedness and impiety. (172)","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imam', 'PERSON'), ('Caliph', 'PERSON'), ('Omar', 'PERSON'), ('172', 'CARDINAL')"
"In this
 painful situation he supported the becoming pride of the
 chief of the Hashemites; declared that he had rather serve
 than reign; rebuked the presumption of the strangers; and
 required the formal, if not the voluntary, assent of the
 chiefs of the nation.","('Hashemites', 'NORP')"
"In this eventful moment, the lance of an Arab might have changed the history of the world.","('Arab', 'NORP')"
"Indifference for rites and opinions
 still marks the character of the Bedoweens; and they might
 accept, as loosely as they hold, the doctrine of the Koran.","('Bedoweens', 'NORP'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Instead of a perpetual and perfect measure of the divine
 will, the fragments of the Koran were produced at the
 discretion of Mahomet; each revelation is suited to the
 emergencies of his policy or passion; and all contradiction
 is removed by the saving maxim, that any text of Scripture
 is abrogated or modified by any subsequent passage.","('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Scripture', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Instead of chastising the disaffection
 of the Koreish, he endeavoured to cut out their tongues, (his
 own expression,) and to secure their attachment by a
 superior measure of liberality: Abu Sophian alone was
 presented with three hundred camels and twenty ounces of
 silver; and Mecca was sincerely converted to the profitable
 religion of the Koran.","('Koreish', 'NORP'), ('Abu Sophian', 'PERSON'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty ounces', 'QUANTITY'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Instead of indulging their passions and his own,
 (139) the victorious exile forgave the guilt, and united the
 factions, of Mecca.","('139', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mecca', 'GPE')"
Introduction of the Sabians.,"('Sabians', 'NORP')"
"Is opposed by the Koreish, A.D. 613-622.","('Koreish', 'PERSON'), ('622', 'CARDINAL')"
"It
 was attacked the ensuing year by an army of ten thousand
 enemies; and this third expedition is variously named from
 the nations, which marched under the banner of Abu Sophian,
 from the ditch which was drawn before the city, and a camp
 of three thousand Mussulmans.","('the ensuing year', 'DATE'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Abu Sophian', 'PERSON'), ('three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mussulmans', 'NORP')"
"It is more simple to
 believe that he adhered to the habits and opinions of his
 youth, without foreseeing that a practice congenial to the
 climate of Mecca might become useless or inconvenient on the
 banks of the Danube or the Volga.","('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Volga', 'LOC')"
"It is natural
 enough that an Arabian prophet should dwell with rapture on
 the groves, the fountains, and the rivers of paradise; but
 instead of inspiring the blessed inhabitants with a liberal
 taste for harmony and science, conversation and friendship,
 he idly celebrates the pearls and diamonds, the robes of
 silk, palaces of marble, dishes of gold, rich wines,
 artificial dainties, numerous attendants, and the whole
 train of sensual and costly luxury, which becomes insipid to
 the owner, even in the short period of this mortal life.","('Arabian', 'NORP')"
"It is not the
 propagation, but the permanency, of his religion, that
 deserves our wonder: the same pure and perfect impression
 which he engraved at Mecca and Medina, is preserved, after
 the revolutions of twelve centuries, by the Indian, the
 African, and the Turkish proselytes of the Koran.","('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('twelve centuries', 'DATE'), ('Indian', 'NORP'), ('African', 'NORP'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"It is the boast of the Jewish apologists, that while the
 learned nations of antiquity were deluded by the fables of
 polytheism, their simple ancestors of Palestine preserved
 the knowledge and worship of the true God.","('Jewish', 'NORP'), ('Palestine', 'GPE')"
"It was for this earthly paradise that Nature had
 reserved her choicest favours and her most curious
 workmanship: the incompatible blessings of luxury and
 innocence were ascribed to the natives: the soil was
 impregnated with gold (7) and gems, and both the land and sea
 were taught to exhale the odours of aromatic sweets.","('7', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was in the same camp that the deputy of Mecca was astonished by the attention of the faithful to the words and looks of the prophet, by the eagerness with which they collected his spittle, a hair that dropped on the ground, the refuse water of his lustrations, as if they participated in some degree of the prophetic virtue.","('Mecca', 'GPE')"
"It was the interest of the
 caliphs, the successors of the prophet and commanders of the
 faithful, to repress and discourage all religious
 innovations: the order, the discipline, the temporal and
 spiritual ambition of the clergy, are unknown to the
 Moslems; and the sages of the law are the guides of their
 conscience and the oracles of their faith.","('Moslems', 'NORP')"
"Mahomet accepted his offer with transport, and Abu Taled was ironically exhorted to respect the superior dignity of his son.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Abu Taled', 'PERSON')"
"Mahomet heard the complaint, satisfied the demand, and thanked his
 creditor for accusing him in this world rather than at the day of judgment.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"Mahomet subdues the Jews of Arabia, A.D. 623-627.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Arabia', 'GPE'), ('623-627', 'CARDINAL')"
"Mahomet was
 alike instructed to preach and to fight; and the union of
 these opposite qualities, while it enhanced his merit,
 contributed to his success: the operation of force and
 persuasion, of enthusiasm and fear, continually acted on
 each other, till every barrier yielded to their irresistible
 power.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"Mahomet was, perhaps, incapable of
 dictating a moral and political system for the use of his
 countrymen: but he breathed among the faithful a spirit of
 charity and friendship; recommended the practice of the
 social virtues; and checked, by his laws and precepts, the
 thirst of revenge, and the oppression of widows and orphans.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"Mahomet, or more properly Mohammed, the only son
 of Abdallah and Amina, was born at Mecca, four years after
 the death of Justinian, and two months after the defeat of
 the Abyssinians, (66) whose victory would have introduced into the Caaba the religion of the Christians.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Mohammed', 'PERSON'), ('Abdallah', 'PERSON'), ('Amina', 'PERSON'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('four years', 'DATE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('two months', 'DATE'), ('Abyssinians', 'NORP'), ('66', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caaba', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Mahomet, perhaps, is the only lawgiver who has
 defined the precise measure of charity: the standard may
 vary with the degree and nature of property, as it consists
 either in money, in corn or cattle, in fruits or
 merchandise; but the Mussulman does not accomplish the law,
 unless he bestows a tenth of his revenue; and if his
 conscience accuses him of fraud or extortion, the tenth,
 under the idea of restitution, is enlarged to a fifth. (105)","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Mussulman', 'PERSON'), ('a tenth', 'CARDINAL'), ('the tenth', 'DATE'), ('a fifth', 'CARDINAL'), ('105', 'CARDINAL')"
"Mahomet, the apostle of God, and the last of the prophets.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"Many ages before Mahomet, (26) their
 intrepid valour had been severely felt by their neighbours in
 offensive and defensive war.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('26', 'DATE')"
"Many thousands of the Shiites
 repose in holy ground at the feet of the vicar of God; and
 the desert is vivified by the numerous and annual visits of
 the Persians, who esteem their devotion not less meritorious
 than the pilgrimage of Mecca.","('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('Shiites', 'NORP'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Mecca', 'GPE')"
"Mary, his Egyptian concubine, was
 endeared to him by the birth of Ibrahim.","('Mary', 'PERSON'), ('Egyptian', 'NORP'), ('Ibrahim', 'PERSON')"
"Mecca is placed almost at an equal distance, a
 month's journey, between Yemen on the right, and Syria on
 the left hand.","('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('month', 'DATE'), ('Yemen', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE')"
"Mecca, which had been fed by the
 liberality of the father, was saved by the courage of the
 son.","('Mecca', 'GPE')"
"Medina, or the city, known under the name
 of Yathreb, before it was sanctified by the throne of the
 prophet, was divided between the tribes of the Charegites
 and the Awsites, whose hereditary feud was rekindled by the
 slightest provocations: two colonies of Jews, who boasted a
 sacerdotal race, were their humble allies, and without
 converting the Arabs, they introduced the taste of science
 and religion, which distinguished Medina as the city of the
 Book.","('Medina', 'GPE'), ('Yathreb', 'PERSON'), ('Charegites', 'NORP'), ('Awsites', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jews', 'NORP'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('Medina', 'PERSON')"
"Moawiyah, the son of Abu Sophian, and of the cruel Henda,
 was dignified, in his early youth, with the office or title
 of secretary of the prophet: the judgment of Omar entrusted
 him with the government of Syria; and he administered that
 important province above forty years, either in a
 subordinate or supreme rank.","('Moawiyah', 'PERSON'), ('Abu Sophian', 'PERSON'), ('Henda', 'PERSON'), ('Omar', 'PERSON'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('forty years', 'DATE')"
"Moses   the seven precepts of Noah were observed by an inferior and imperfect class of the
 proselytes of the synagogue; (82) and the memory of Abraham was obscurely revered by the Sabians in his native land of
 Chaldaea: of the myriads of prophets, Moses and Christ alone
 lived and reigned; and the remnant of the inspired writings
 was comprised in the books of the Old and the New Testament.","('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Noah', 'PERSON'), ('82', 'CARDINAL'), ('Abraham', 'PERSON'), ('Sabians', 'NORP'), ('Chaldaea', 'LOC'), ('Moses', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON'), ('the Old and the New Testament', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"No answer was returned, till the silence of astonishment, and doubt, and
 contempt, was at length broken by the impatient courage of Ali, a youth in the fourteenth year of his age.","('Ali', 'PERSON'), ('the fourteenth year of his age', 'DATE')"
"No sooner was the pursuit abated than the two fugitives issued from the rock, and mounted their camels: on the road to Medina, they were overtaken by the emissaries of the Koreish; they redeemed themselves with prayers and promises from their hands.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('Koreish', 'NORP')"
"Nor was the charity of Mahomet confined to the tribe of Koreish,
 or the precincts of Mecca: on solemn festivals, in the days of pilgrimage, he frequented the Caaba, accosted the strangers of every tribe, and urged, both in private converse and public discourse, the belief and worship of a
 sole Deity.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Koreish', 'NORP'), ('Mecca', 'GPE'), ('Caaba', 'NORP')"
"Notwithstanding a vulgar prejudice, the gates of heaven will
 be open to both sexes; but Mahomet has not specified the
 male companions of the female elect, lest he should either
 alarm the jealousy of their former husbands, or disturb
 their felicity, by the suspicion of an everlasting marriage.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON')"
"Of
 his last years, ambition was the ruling passion; and a
 politician will suspect, that he secretly smiled (the
 victorious impostor!) at the enthusiasm of his youth, and
 the credulity of his proselytes. (156)","('his last years', 'DATE'), ('156', 'CARDINAL')"
"Of the time of ignorance
 which preceded Mahomet, seventeen hundred battles (36) are recorded by tradition: hostility was embittered with the rancour of civil faction; and the recital, in prose or verse, of an obsolete feud, was sufficient to rekindle the same
 passions among the descendants of the hostile tribes.","('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('seventeen hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('36', 'CARDINAL')"
"On
 solemn occasions they convened the assembly of the people;
 and, since mankind must be either compelled or persuaded to
 obey, the use and reputation of oratory among the ancient
 Arabs is the clearest evidence of public freedom. (33)","('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"On
 these occasions, the Cadhi respectfully places on his head
 the holy volume, and substitutes a dexterous interpretation
 more apposite to the principles of equity, and the manners
 and policy of the times.","('Cadhi', 'PERSON')"
"On solemn
 occasions he feasted his companions with rustic and
 hospitable plenty; but in his domestic life, many weeks
 would elapse without a fire being kindled on the hearth of
 the prophet.","('many weeks', 'DATE')"
"On the annual festival of his martyrdom, in the devout pilgrimage to his sepulchre, his Persian votaries abandon
 their souls to the religious frenzy of sorrow and indignation. (180)
Posterity of Mahomet and Ali.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('180', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mahomet', 'PERSON'), ('Ali', 'PERSON')"
"On the event of his decease, Jaafar and
 Abdallah were successively substituted to the command; and
 if the three should perish in the war, the troops were
 authorized to elect their general.","('Jaafar', 'PERSON'), ('Abdallah', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"On the morning of the fatal day, he mounted on
 horseback, with his sword in one hand and the Koran in the
 other: his generous band of martyrs consisted only of
 thirty-two horse and forty foot; but their flanks and rear
 were secured by the tent-ropes, and by a deep trench which
 they had filled with lighted fagots, according to the
 practice of the Arabs.","('the morning of the fatal day', 'TIME'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Koran', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('thirty-two', 'CARDINAL'), ('forty foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('Arabs', 'NORP')"
"On this
 spacious and level theatre, the two competitors waged a
 desultory war of one hundred and ten days.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred and ten days', 'DATE')"
"On this foundation the zeal of the
 Arabians has supposed the secret conversion of the Christian
 emperor: the vanity of the Greeks has feigned a personal
 visit of the prince of Medina, who accepted from the royal
 bounty a rich domain, and a secure retreat, in the province
 of Syria. (145)","('Arabians', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Medina', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('145', 'CARDINAL')"
"On this occasion, Ali was again
 blamed by his friends (169) for submitting his right to the judgment of men, for recognizing their jurisdiction by accepting a place among the six electors.","('Ali', 'PERSON'), ('169', 'CARDINAL'), ('six', 'CARDINAL')"
"Once only the concord was slightly ruffled by an
 accidental quarrel: a patriot of Medina arraigned the
 insolence of the strangers, but the hint of their expulsion
 was heard with abhorrence; and his own son most eagerly
 offered to lay at the apostle's feet the head of his father.","('Medina', 'PERSON')"
One God.,"('One', 'CARDINAL')"
"One of his wives, Hafna, the daughter of Omar,
 surprised him on her own bed, in the embraces of his
 Egyptian captive: she promised secrecy and forgiveness, he
