Sentence,Entities
(14),"('14', 'CARDINAL')"
(15),"('15', 'CARDINAL')"
(19),"('19', 'CARDINAL')"
"(4)
Embassy of the Avars, A.D. 566.","('4', 'CARDINAL'), ('Embassy of the Avars', 'ORG'), ('566', 'CARDINAL')"
(41),"('41', 'CARDINAL')"
(44),"('44', 'CARDINAL')"
(45),"('45', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 faithful chieftain, and a select band, were stationed at
 Forum Julii, the modern Friuli, to guard the passes of the
 mountains.","('Forum Julii', 'ORG'), ('Friuli', 'GPE')"
"A
 pestilential disease arose from the stagnation of the
 deluge, and so rapid was the contagion, that fourscore
 persons expired in an hour in the midst of a solemn
 procession, which implored the mercy of Heaven. (59)","('an hour', 'TIME')"
"A
 society in which marriage is encouraged and industry
 prevails soon repairs the accidental losses of pestilence
 and war: but, as the far greater part of the Romans was
 condemned to hopeless indigence and celibacy, the
 depopulation was constant and visible, and the gloomy
 enthusiasts might expect the approaching failure of the
 human race. (60)","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('60', 'CARDINAL')"
"A Lombard
 was born the soldier of his king and his duke; and the civil
 assemblies of the nation displayed the banners, and assumed
 the appellation, of a regular army.","('Lombard', 'PERSON')"
"A fortunate soldier, whom he instantly promoted to the rank of tribune, encircled his neck with a military collar; four robust youths exalted him on a shield; he stood firm and erect to receive the adoration of his subjects; and their choice was sanctified by the benediction of the patriarch, Reign of Justin II, A.D. 565, Nov. 15-A.D. 574, December.","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Justin II', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 565', 'DATE'), ('Nov. 15-A.D. 574', 'DATE'), ('December', 'DATE')"
"A nation, less sensible of
 danger than of fatigue and delay, soon murmured against the
 folly of their twenty commanders; and the hot vapors of an
 Italian sun infected with disease those tramontane bodies
 which had already suffered the vicissitudes of intemperance
 and famine.","('twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
"A new exarch, Longinus, was appointed to
 supersede the conqueror of Italy, and the base motives of
 his recall were revealed in the insulting mandate of the
 empress Sophia,  is said to have been the reply  which indignation and conscious virtue extorted from the hero.","('Longinus', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Sophia', 'PERSON')"
"A numerous army
 constitutes but a small nation, and the powers of the
 Lombards were soon diminished by the retreat of twenty
 thousand Saxons, who scorned a dependent situation, and
 returned, after many bold and perilous adventures, to their
 native country. (39)","('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('twenty\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saxons', 'NORP')"
"A vague tradition was embraced, that
 two Jewish teachers, a tent-maker and a fisherman, had
 formerly been executed in the circus of Nero, and at the end
 of five hundred years, their genuine or fictitious relics
 were adored as the Palladium of Christian Rome.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jewish', 'NORP'), ('Nero', 'PERSON'), ('the end\r\n of five hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"About fourscore years after the conquest of Italy, Laws, A.D. 643, etc. their traditional customs were transcribed in Teutonic Latin, (53) and ratified by the consent of the prince and people: some new regulations were introduced, more suitable to their present condition; the example of Rotharis was imitated by
 the wisest of his successors; and the laws of the Lombards have been esteemed the least imperfect of the Barbaric codes. (54)","('About fourscore years', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 643', 'DATE'), ('Teutonic', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('53', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rotharis', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Barbaric', 'NORP'), ('54', 'CARDINAL')"
"According to the strange jurisprudence of the times, the guilt of blood might be redeemed by a fine; yet the high price of nine hundred pieces of gold declares a just sense of the value of a simple citizen.","('nine hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"According to this standard, it
 will appear, that the Lombards of Italy, and the Visigoths
 of Spain, were less numerous than the Franks or Burgundians;
 and the conquerors of Gaul must yield, in their turn, to the
 multitude of Saxons and Angles who almost eradicated the
 idioms of Britain.","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Angles', 'NORP'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"After composing his countenance to surprise, sorrow, and decent modesty, Justin, by the advice of his wife Sophia, submitted to the authority of the senate.","('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Sophia', 'PERSON')"
"After draining many capacious
 bowls of Rhaetian or Falernian wine, he called for the skull
 of Cunimund, the noblest and most precious ornament of his
 sideboard.","('Rhaetian', 'NORP'), ('Falernian', 'NORP'), ('Cunimund', 'NORP')"
"After recording the vice or folly
 of so many Roman princes, it is pleasing to repose, for a
 moment, on a character conspicuous by the qualities of
 humanity, justice, temperance, and fortitude; to contemplate
 a sovereign affable in his palace, pious in the church,
 impartial on the seat of judgment, and victorious, at least
 by his generals, in the Persian war.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('the Persian war', 'EVENT')"
"After the loss of his
 promised bride, a Merovingian princess, he sought in
 marriage the daughter of the king of Bavaria; and Garribald
 accepted the alliance of the Italian monarch.","('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('Bavaria', 'GPE'), ('Garribald', 'PERSON'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
"After two doubtful battles, he consented to retire, and the Austrasian king relieve the distress of his camp with an immediate supply of
 corn and cattle.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Austrasian', 'NORP')"
"Against the proposal of the murder, he could no longer urge the scruples of fidelity or gratitude; but Helmichis trembled when he revolved the danger as well as the guilt, when he recollected the matchless strength and intrepidity of a warrior whom he had so often attended in the field of battle.","('Helmichis', 'PERSON')"
"Alboin bowed with reverence to the institutions of his country, selected forty companions, and boldly visited the court of Turisund, king of the Gepidae, who embraced and entertained, according to the laws of hospitality, the murderer of his son.","('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('forty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Turisund', 'PERSON'), ('Gepidae', 'PERSON')"
"Alboin is murdered by his wife Rosamond, A.D. 573, June 28.","('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('Rosamond', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 573', 'DATE'), ('June 28', 'DATE')"
"Alboin returned in triumph; and the Lombards, who celebrated his matchless intrepidity, were compelled to praise the virtues of an enemy. (8)","('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('8', 'CARDINAL')"
"Alboin undertakes the conquest of Italy, A.D. 567.","('Alboin', 'ORG'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('567', 'CARDINAL')"
"Alboin, king of the Lombards— his valour, love and revenge.","('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"Along the maritime coast, the
 courage of the inhabitants was supported by the facility of
 supply, the hopes of relief, and the power of escape; but
 from the Trentine hills to the gates of Ravenna and Rome the
 inland regions of Italy became, without a battle or a siege,
 the lasting patrimony of the Lombards.","('Trentine', 'GPE'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"Amidst the arms of the Lombards, and under the despotism of
 the Greeks, we again inquire into the fate of Rome, (58)
 which had reached, about the close of the sixth century, the
 lowest period of her depression.","('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('58', 'CARDINAL'), ('the sixth century', 'DATE')"
"Among the virtues of Tiberius, (28) his beauty (he was one of
 the tallest and most comely of the Romans) might introduce
 him to the favor of Sophia; and the widow of Justin was
 persuaded, that she should preserve her station and
 influence under the reign of a second and more youthful
 husband.","('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('28', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Sophia', 'PERSON'), ('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"And, as the offer of marriage was rejected with contempt, Alboin was compelled to relinquish his prey, and to partake of the disgrace which he had inflicted on the house of Cunimund.","('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('Cunimund', 'PERSON')"
"As a Christian bishop, he preferred the salutary offices of peace; his mediation appeased the tumult of arms: but he was too conscious of the arts of the Greeks, and the passions of the
 Lombards, to engage his sacred promise for the observance of the truce.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Lombards', 'NORP')"
"As soon as he
 had received the character of deacon, Gregory was sent to
 reside at the Byzantine court, the nuncio or minister of the
 apostolic see; and he boldly assumed, in the name of St.
 Peter, a tone of independent dignity, which would have been
 criminal and dangerous in the most illustrious layman of the
 empire.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('St.\r\n Peter', 'LOC')"
"As soon as they
 were apprehensive of a just retaliation, they renounced
 their feeble and disorderly independence: the advantages of
 real government, union, secrecy, and vigor, were unanimously
 confessed; Autharis, king of the Lombards, A.D. 584-590.","('Autharis', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 584-590', 'DATE')"
"Association of Tiberius, A.D. 574, December.","('Association of Tiberius', 'ORG'), ('A.D. 574', 'DATE'), ('December', 'DATE')"
"At length he signified
 the ultimate price of his alliance, that the Lombards should
 immediately present him with a tithe of their cattle; that
 the spoils and captives should be equally divided; but that
 the lands of the Gepidae should become the sole patrimony of
 the Avars.","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Gepidae', 'NORP'), ('Avars', 'NORP')"
"At the banquet, whilst Alboin occupied the seat of the youth whom he had slain, a tender remembrance arose in the mind of Turisund.","('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('Turisund', 'PERSON')"
"At the end of one year, it was dissolved by the death of Autharis: but the virtues of Theudelinda (51) had endeared her to the nation, and she was permitted to bestow, with her hand, the sceptre of the Italian kingdom.","('the end of one year', 'DATE'), ('Autharis', 'PERSON'), ('Theudelinda', 'PERSON'), ('51', 'DATE'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
"At the extreme
 point of the Calabria, he touched with his spear a column on
 the sea-shore of Rhegium, (32) proclaiming that ancient
 landmark to stand the immovable boundary of his kingdom. (33)","('Calabria', 'LOC'), ('Rhegium', 'PERSON'), ('32', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the foot of the Rhaetian Alps, he
 subdued the resistance, and rifled the hidden treasures, of
 a sequestered island in the Lake of Comum.","('the Rhaetian Alps', 'LOC'), ('the Lake of Comum', 'LOC')"
"At the hour of midnight, his domestics were awakened by an importunate crowd, who thundered at his door, and obtained admittance by revealing themselves to be the principal members of the senate.","('the hour of midnight', 'TIME')"
"At the public audience, the
 unknown stranger advanced to the throne, and informed
 Garribald that the ambassador was indeed the minister of
 state, but that he alone was the friend of Autharis, who had
 trusted him with the delicate commission of making a
 faithful report of the charms of his spouse.","('Garribald', 'PERSON'), ('Autharis', 'PERSON')"
"Before the end of eighteen months, the throne was
 polluted by a second murder: Clepho was stabbed by the hand of a domestic; the regal office was suspended above ten years during the minority of his son Autharis; and Italy was divided and oppressed by a ducal aristocracy of thirty
 tyrants. (22)","('the end of eighteen months', 'DATE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Clepho', 'PERSON'), ('ten years', 'DATE'), ('Autharis', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('thirty', 'CARDINAL'), ('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"Before the end of three years, his example was imitated and surpassed by the empress Sophia, who delivered many indigent citizens from the weight of debt and usury: an act of benevolence the best entitled to gratitude, since it relieves the most intolerable distress; but in which the bounty of a prince is the most liable to be abused by the
 claims of prodigality and fraud.","('the end of three years', 'DATE'), ('Sophia', 'PERSON')"
"Before the throne of Justinian they
 boldly declared, that their Gothic servitude had been more
 tolerable than the despotism of a Greek eunuch; and that,
 unless their tyrant were instantly removed, they would
 consult their own happiness in the choice of a master.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Greek', 'NORP')"
"But Naples soon acquired the privilege of electing
 her own dukes: (36) the independence of Amalphi was the fruit
 of commerce; and the voluntary attachment of Venice was
 finally ennobled by an equal alliance with the Eastern
 empire.","('Naples', 'GPE'), ('36', 'CARDINAL'), ('Amalphi', 'GPE'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"But his ambition was yet unsatisfied; and the conqueror
 of the Gepidae turned his eyes from the Danube to the richer
 banks of the Po, and the Tyber.","('Gepidae', 'PERSON'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Po', 'LOC'), ('Tyber', 'PRODUCT')"
"But in less than four years after the death of
 Justin, his worthy successor sunk into a mortal disease,
 which left him only sufficient time to restore the diadem,
 according to the tenure by which he held it, to the most
 deserving of his fellow-citizens.","('less than four years', 'DATE'), ('Justin', 'PERSON')"
"But the Lombard chiefs, who fled in the first
 moments of consternation and disorder, had resumed their
 courage and collected their powers; and the nation, instead
 of submitting to her reign, demanded, with unanimous cries,
 that justice should be executed on the guilty spouse and the
 murderers of their king.","('Lombard', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But the courage of the Gepidae could secure them no
 more than an honorable death.","('Gepidae', 'PERSON')"
"But the evidence
 of his destructive rage is doubtful and recent: the Temple
 of Peace, or the theatre of Marcellus, have been demolished
 by the slow operation of ages, and a formal proscription
 would have multiplied the copies of Virgil and Livy in the
 countries which were not subject to the ecclesiastical
 dictator. (62)","('the Temple\r\n of Peace', 'FAC'), ('Marcellus', 'GPE'), ('Virgil and Livy', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"But the martial
 spirit of the pope was checked by the scruples of humanity
 and religion: the imposition of tribute, though it was
 employed in the Italian war, he freely condemned as odious
 and oppressive; whilst he protected, against the Imperial
 edicts, the pious cowardice of the soldiers who deserted a
 military for a monastic life","('the Italian war', 'EVENT'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"But the occupations of a pastoral life were more
 pleasing to the idleness of the Barbarian.","('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
"But the passions of the people
 are furious and changeable, and the Romans soon recollected the merits, or dreaded the resentment, of their victorious general.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"But the power as well as virtue of
 the apostles resided with living energy in the breast of
 their successors; Birth and profession of Gregory the Roman. and the chair of St. Peter was filled
 under the reign of Maurice by the first and greatest of the
 name of Gregory. (64)","('Gregory the Roman', 'PERSON'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('64', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the relief was accidental, the danger was perpetual and pressing; and the clergy and senate, collecting the remains of their ancient opulence, a sum of three thousand pounds of gold, despatched the patrician Pamphronius to lay their gifts and their complaints at the foot of the Byzantine throne.","('three thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('Pamphronius', 'NORP'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"But the services of Justinian were
 not considered by that excellent prince as an aggravation of
 his offences: after a mild reproof, his treason and
 ingratitude were forgiven; and it was commonly believed,
 that the emperor entertained some thoughts of contracting a
 double alliance with the rival of his throne.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"But the succession of their kings is
 marked with virtue and ability; the troubled series of their annals is adorned with fair intervals of peace, order, and domestic happiness; and the Italians enjoyed a milder and more equitable government, than any of the other kingdoms which had been founded on the ruins of the Western empire.
 (57)
Misery of Rome.","('Italians', 'NORP'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('57', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But the weakness
 of the Byzantine court was subservient to the Barbarian
 cause; and it was for the ruin of Italy, that the emperor
 once listened to the complaints of his subjects.","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"But, if they hesitated or delayed to
 prevent the malice of the Romans, the same spirit which had
 insulted would pursue the Avars to the extremity of the
 earth.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Avars', 'NORP')"
"By the command of her father she obeyed:
 Autharis received the cup in his turn, and, in restoring it
 to the princess, he secretly touched her hand, and drew his
 own finger over his face and lips.","('Autharis', 'PERSON')"
"By the free
 suffrage of the nation, in the assembly of Pavia, Clepho, king of the Lombards, A.D. 573 August.","('Pavia', 'GPE'), ('Clepho', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 573 August', 'DATE')"
"By the hands of the proper officers he was invested with the Imperial garments, the red buskins, white tunic, and purple robe.","('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"By the mediation of the pope, who undertook a special pilgrimage to Naples, their repentance was accepted; and Narses, assuming a milder aspect and a more dutiful language, consented to fix his residence in the Capitol.","('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Capitol', 'FAC')"
"Childebert, the great-grandson of Clovis, was persuaded to
 invade Italy by the payment of fifty thousand pieces; but,
 as he had viewed with delight some Byzantine coin of the
 weight of one pound of gold, the king of Austrasia might
 stipulate, that the gift should be rendered more worthy of
 his acceptance, by a proper mixture of these respectable
 medals.","('Childebert', 'PERSON'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('fifty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('one pound', 'QUANTITY'), ('Austrasia', 'ORG')"
"Clepho,  one of their noblest chiefs, was elected as the successor of Alboin.","('Clepho', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alboin', 'ORG')"
"Conquest of a great part of Italy by the Lombards, A.D. 568-570.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('568-570', 'CARDINAL')"
"Constantinople believed that the emperor
 had discovered a treasure: but his genuine treasure
 consisted in the practice of liberal economy, and the
 contempt of all vain and superfluous expense.","('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Delighted with the
 situation of a city which was endeared to his pride by the
 difficulty of the purchase, the prince of the Lombards
 disdained the ancient glories of Milan; and Pavia, during
 some ages, was respected as the capital of the kingdom of
 Italy. (20)","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Pavia', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('20', 'CARDINAL')"
Disaffection and death of Narses.,"('Narses', 'PERSON')"
Distress of Italy.,"('Italy', 'GPE')"
"During a period of two hundred years, Italy was unequally
 divided between the kingdom of the Lombards and the
 exarchate of Ravenna.","('two hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Lombards', 'LOC'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"During the last years of Justinian, his infirm mind was devoted to heavenly contemplation, and he neglected the business of the lower world.","('the last years of Justinian', 'DATE')"
"Either the Roman landlord was expelled by his
 strong and insolent guest, or the annual payment, a third of
 the produce, was exchanged by a more equitable transaction
 for an adequate proportion of landed property.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('a third', 'CARDINAL')"
"Even the existence, the union, or the
 translation of episcopal seats was decided by his absolute
 discretion: and his successful inroads into the provinces of
 Greece, of Spain, and of Gaul, might countenance the more
 lofty pretensions of succeeding popes.","('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"Fifteen years had not
 elapsed, since his subjects, the confederates of Narses, had
 visited the pleasant climate of Italy: the mountains, the
 rivers, the highways, were familiar to their memory: the
 report of their success, perhaps the view of their spoils,
 had kindled in the rising generation the flame of emulation
 and enterprise.","('Fifteen years', 'DATE'), ('Narses', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"For their
 relief, as often as they had suffered by natural or hostile
 calamities, he was impatient to remit the arrears of the
 past, or the demands of future taxes: he sternly rejected
 the servile offerings of his ministers, which were
 compensated by tenfold oppression; and the wise and
 equitable laws of Tiberius excited the praise and regret of
 succeeding times.","('Tiberius', 'PERSON')"
"From Capua to
 Tarentum, they reigned near five hundred years over the
 greatest part of the present kingdom of Naples. (37)","('Capua', 'GPE'), ('Tarentum', 'GPE'), ('five hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('37', 'CARDINAL')"
"From Italy the emperors were incessantly tormented by tales
 of misery and demands of succour, which extorted the
 humiliating confession of their own weakness.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"From the pomp and honors which she
 had abused, Sophia was reduced to a modest allowance:
 Tiberius dismissed her train, intercepted her
 correspondence, and committed to a faithful guard the
 custody of her person.","('Sophia', 'PERSON'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON')"
"From this fact, as well as from similar events, (52) it is certain that the Lombards possessed freedom to elect their sovereign, and sense to decline the frequent use of that dangerous privilege.","('52', 'DATE'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"Gregory awakened the emperor from a long slumber; exposed
 the guilt or incapacity of the exarch and his inferior
 ministers; complained that the veterans were withdrawn from
 Rome for the defence of Spoleto; encouraged the Italians to
 guard their cities and altars; and condescended, in the
 crisis of danger, to name the tribunes, and to direct the
 operations, of the provincial troops.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Spoleto', 'GPE'), ('Italians', 'NORP')"
"Gregory might justly be styled
 the Father of his Country; and such was the extreme
 sensibility of his conscience, that, for the death of a
 beggar who had perished in the streets, he interdicted
 himself during several days from the exercise of sacerdotal
 functions.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('the Father of his Country', 'PERSON'), ('several days', 'DATE')"
"He
 extolled, by the tongue of his interpreter, the greatness of
 the chagan, by whose clemency the kingdoms of the South were
 permitted to exist, whose victorious subjects had traversed
 the frozen rivers of Scythia, and who now covered the banks
 of the Danube with innumerable tents.","('South', 'LOC'), ('Scythia', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"He
 frequently ascended the pulpit, and kindled, by his rude,
 though pathetic, eloquence, the congenial passions of his
 audience: the language of the Jewish prophets was
 interpreted and applied; and the minds of a people,
 depressed by their present calamities, were directed to the
 hopes and fears of the invisible world.","('Jewish', 'NORP')"
"He alone resisted, or seemed to resist, his
 own elevation; and his humble petition, that Maurice would
 be pleased to reject the choice of the Romans, could only
 serve to exalt his character in the eyes of the emperor and
 the public.","('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"He ascended the Julian Alps, and looked down with contempt
 and desire on the fruitful plains to which his victory
 communicated the perpetual appellation of LOMBARDY.","('the Julian Alps', 'LOC')"
"He expired in his palace, after a reign of thirty-eight years; and the decisive opportunity was embraced by the friends of Justin, the son of Vigilantia. (2)","('thirty-eight years', 'DATE'), ('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Vigilantia', 'NORP'), ('2', 'CARDINAL')"
"He pressed and obtained, that one of the bravest champions of the Lombards should be associated to the enterprise; but no more than a promise of secrecy could be drawn from the gallant Peredeus, and the mode of seduction employed by Rosamond betrays her shameless insensibility both to honor and love.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Peredeus', 'PERSON'), ('Rosamond', 'PERSON')"
"He returned to Rome with a just increase of
 reputation, and, after a short exercise of the monastic
 virtues, he was dragged from the cloister to the papal
 throne, by the unanimous voice of the clergy, the senate,
 and the people.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"He selected Maurice from
 the crowd, a judgment more precious than the purple itself:
 the patriarch and senate were summoned to the bed of the
 dying prince: he bestowed his daughter and the empire; and
 his last advice was solemnly delivered by the voice of the
 quaestor.","('Maurice', 'PERSON')"
"He was
 informed that the Avars had entered his confines; but, on
 the strong assurance that, after the defeat of the Lombards,
 these foreign invaders would easily be repelled, he rushed
 forwards to encounter the implacable enemy of his name and
 family.","('Avars', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"Her name was Rosamond, an appellation expressive of female beauty, and which our own history or romance has consecrated to amorous tales.","('Rosamond', 'PERSON')"
"His ample patrimony was
 dedicated to the foundation of seven monasteries, (67) one in
 Rome, (68) and six in Sicily; and it was the wish of Gregory
 that he might be unknown in this life, and glorious only in
 the next.","('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('67', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('68', 'CARDINAL'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON')"
"His artful patroness had chosen the
 month of the vintage, while the emperor, in a rural
 solitude, was permitted to enjoy the pleasures of a subject.","('the\r\n month of the vintage', 'DATE')"
"His death, (16) though in the extreme period of old age, was unseasonable and premature, since his genius alone could have repaired the last and fatal error of his life.","('16', 'DATE')"
"His faithless spouse was anxious for his health and repose: the gates of the palace were shut, the arms removed, the attendants dismissed, and Rosamond, after lulling him to rest by her tender caresses, unbolted the chamber door, and urged the reluctant conspirators to the instant execution of the deed.","('Rosamond', 'PERSON')"
"His government was oppressive or unpopular, and
 the general discontent was expressed with freedom by the
 deputies of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"His grandfather Felix had himself been
 pope, and as the bishops were already bound by the laws of
 celibacy, his consecration must have been preceded by the
 death of his wife.","('Felix', 'PERSON')"
"His grief exasperated the national resentment of the Gepidae; and Cunimund, his surviving son, was provoked by wine, or fraternal affection, to the desire of vengeance.","('Gepidae', 'NORP'), ('Cunimund', 'PERSON')"
"His precepts and
 example defined the model of the Roman liturgy; (69) the
 distribution of the parishes, the calendar of the festivals,
 the order of processions, the service of the priests and
 deacons, the variety and change of sacerdotal garments.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('69', 'CARDINAL')"
"His spiritual office, and the ecclesiastical jurisdiction of
 Gregory was confined to the triple character of Bishop of
 Rome, Primate of Italy, and Apostle of the West.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Apostle', 'PERSON')"
"Honoratus,
 who filled the chair of St. Ambrose, had credulously
 accepted the faithless offers of a capitulation; and the
 archbishop, with the clergy and nobles of Milan, were driven
 by the perfidy of Alboin to seek a refuge in the less
 accessible ramparts of Genoa.","('Honoratus', 'PERSON'), ('St. Ambrose', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('Genoa', 'GPE')"
"I
 should not be apprehensive of deviating from my subject, if
 it were in my power to delineate the private life of the
 conquerors of Italy; and I shall relate with pleasure the
 adventurous gallantry of Autharis, which breathes the true
 spirit of chivalry and romance. (50)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Autharis', 'GPE'), ('50', 'CARDINAL')"
"I. The church of Rome, as
 it has been formerly observed, was endowed with ample
 possessions in Italy, Sicily, and the more distant
 provinces; and her agents, who were commonly sub-deacons,
 his estates.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE')"
"If the forces of the Avars and the Lombards should
 unite in this glorious quarrel, the victory was secure, and
 the reward inestimable: the Danube, the Hebrus, Italy, and
 Constantinople, would be exposed, without a barrier, to
 their invincible arms.","('Avars', 'NORP'), ('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Hebrus', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"If the junction of the
 Merovingian and Imperial forces had been effected in the
 neighborhood of Milan, perhaps they might have subverted the
 throne of the Lombards; but the Franks expected six days the
 signal of a flaming village, and the arms of the Greeks were
 idly employed in the reduction of Modena and Parma, which
 were torn from them after the retreat of their transalpine
 allies.","('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('six days', 'DATE'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Modena', 'GPE'), ('Parma', 'GPE')"
"If we may credit his own
 declarations, it would have been easy for Gregory to
 exterminate the Lombards by their domestic factions, without
 leaving a king, a duke, or a count, to save that unfortunate
 nation from the vengeance of their foes","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"Impatient for revenge, they
 returned a third time with accumulated force, and Autharis
 yielded to the fury of the torrent.","('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Autharis', 'PERSON')"
"Impatient of
 the slow progress of negotiation, the ardent lover escaped
 from his palace, and visited the court of Bavaria in the
 train of his own embassy.","('Bavaria', 'GPE')"
"Implacable in her enmity, or inconstant in her love, the queen of Italy had stooped from the throne to the arms of a subject, and Helmichis, the king's armor-bearer, was the secret minister of her pleasure and revenge.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Helmichis', 'PERSON')"
"In
 Sardinia, the savage mountaineers preserved the liberty and
 religion of their ancestors; and the husbandmen of Sicily
 were chained to their rich and cultivated soil.","('Sardinia', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'LOC')"
"In
 his rival, the patriarch of Constantinople, he condemned the
 anti-Christian title of universal bishop, which the
 successor of St. Peter was too haughty to concede, and too
 feeble to assume;","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE')"
"In a
 palace near Verona, which had not been erected for the
 Barbarians, he feasted the companions of his arms;
 intoxication was the reward of valor, and the king himself
 was tempted by appetite, or vanity, to exceed the ordinary
 measure of his intemperance.","('Verona', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"In a season of excessive rains, the
 Tyber swelled above its banks, and rushed with irresistible
 violence into the valleys of the seven hills.","('a season', 'DATE'), ('Tyber', 'GPE'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"In an agony of grief and rage, Rosamond had strength to utter, ""Let the will of my lord be obeyed!""  and, touching it with her lips, pronounced a silent imprecation, that the insult should be washed away in the blood of Alboin.","('Rosamond', 'PERSON'), ('Alboin', 'PERSON')"
"In less than two years, he could announce to the
 archbishop of Alexandria, that they had baptized the king of
 Kent with ten thousand of his Anglo-Saxons, and that the
 Roman missionaries, like those of the primitive church, were
 armed only with spiritual and supernatural powers.","('less than two years', 'DATE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Kent', 'GPE'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Anglo-Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the
 second they were vanquished in a bloody battle, with more
 loss and dishonour than they had sustained since the
 foundation of their monarchy.","('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"In the West, the Roman empire was afflicted
 by the loss of Italy, the desolation of Africa, and the
 conquests of the Persians.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Persians', 'NORP')"
"In the attack of the Gepidae, he had been
 prompted by the just desire of extirpating a people whom
 their alliance with the Roman empire had rendered the common
 enemies of the nations, and the personal adversaries of the
 chagan.","('Gepidae', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the days of Charlemagne, the Bavarians, the
 Saxons, and the other tribes of the Teutonic language, still
 repeated the songs which described the heroic virtues, the
 valor, liberality, and fortune of the king of the Lombards.
 (12)","('Charlemagne', 'PERSON'), ('Bavarians', 'NORP'), ('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Teutonic', 'NORP'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('12', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the evening,
 Theudelinda imparted to her nurse the indiscreet familiarity
 of the stranger, and was comforted by the assurance, that such boldness could proceed only from the king her husband, who, by his beauty and courage, appeared worthy of her love.","('Theudelinda', 'PERSON')"
"In the first emotions of surprise, they submitted
 to the servile adoration of the Byzantine court; but as soon
 as they rose from the ground, Targetius, the chief of the
 embassy, expressed the freedom and pride of a Barbarian.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Targetius', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
"In the language of
 modern geography, it is now represented by the Terra Firma
 of the Venetian republic, Tyrol, the Milanese, Piedmont, the
 coast of Genoa, Mantua, Parma, and Modena, the grand duchy
 of Tuscany, and a large portion of the ecclesiastical state
 from Perugia to the Adriatic.","('the Terra Firma', 'ORG'), ('Venetian', 'NORP'), ('Tyrol', 'GPE'), ('Milanese', 'NORP'), ('Piedmont', 'GPE'), ('Genoa', 'GPE'), ('Mantua', 'GPE'), ('Parma', 'GPE'), ('Modena', 'GPE'), ('Tuscany', 'GPE'), ('Perugia', 'GPE'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC')"
"In the preceding years Italy had been desolated by pestilence and famine, and a disaffected people ascribed the calamities of nature to the guilt or folly of their rulers. (17)","('the preceding years', 'DATE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"In the progress
 of conquest, the same option could not be granted to the
 dukes of Brescia or Bergamo, ot Pavia or Turin, of Spoleto
 or Beneventum; but each of these, and each of their
 colleagues, settled in his appointed district with a band of
 followers who resorted to his standard in war and his
 tribunal in peace.","('Brescia', 'GPE'), ('Bergamo', 'GPE'), ('Pavia', 'GPE'), ('Turin', 'GPE'), ('Spoleto', 'GPE'), ('Beneventum', 'GPE')"
"In the rich
 meadows of Venetia, they restored and improved the breed of
 horses, for which that province had once been illustrious;
 (43) and the Italians beheld with astonishment a foreign race
 of oxen or buffaloes.","('Venetia', 'GPE'), ('43', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italians', 'NORP')"
"In the speeches which Justin addressed to the senate and people, he promised to correct the abuses which had disgraced the age of his predecessor, displayed the maxims of a just and beneficent government, and declared that, on the approaching calends of January, (3) His consulship, A.D. 566, January 1. he would revive in his own person the name and liberty of a Roman consul.","('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('January', 'DATE'), ('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('A.D. 566', 'DATE'), ('January 1', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In this alternative he chose rather to be the accomplice than the victim of Rosamond, (21) whose undaunted spirit was incapable of fear or remorse.","('Rosamond', 'PERSON'), ('21', 'DATE')"
"In this extraordinary visit he had probably seen the daughter of Cunimund, who soon after ascended the
 throne of the Gepidae.","('Cunimund', 'PERSON'), ('Gepidae', 'PERSON')"
"Instead of attending, a slave and a victim, at the
 gate of the Byzantine palace, he retired to Naples, from whence (if any credit is due to the belief of the times)","('Byzantine', 'NORP'), ('Naples', 'GPE')"
"Instead of executing his threats against the Eastern empire, he marched into the poor and savage countries of Germany, which were subject to the dominion of the Franks.","('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"Instead of six legions, forty monks were embarked for that
 distant island, and the pontiff lamented the austere duties
 which forbade him to partake the perils of their spiritual
 warfare.","('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('forty', 'CARDINAL')"
"It is commonly believed, that
 Pope Gregory the First attacked the temples and mutilated
 the statues of the city; that, by the command of the
 Barbarian, the Palatine library was reduced to ashes, and
 that the history of Livy was the peculiar mark of his absurd
 and mischievous fanaticism.","('Pope Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('Palatine', 'PERSON'), ('Livy', 'PERSON')"
"Justin collected the remaining
 strength of his mind and body; but the popular belief that
 his speech was inspired by the Deity betrays a very humble
 opinion both of the man and of the times. (26)","('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Deity', 'PERSON'), ('26', 'CARDINAL')"
"Justinian
 received a free pardon, and the command of the eastern army.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
Language and manners of the Lombards.,"('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"Like Thebes, or Babylon, or Carthage, the names of Rome
 might have been erased from the earth, if the city had not
 been animated by a vital principle, which again restored her
 to honor and dominion.","('Thebes', 'GPE'), ('Babylon', 'GPE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Longinus beheld with delight the charms and the treasures of the widow of Alboin: her situation and her past conduct might justify the most licentious proposals; and she readily listened to the passion of a minister, who, even in the decline of the empire, was respected as the equal of kings.","('Longinus', 'PERSON'), ('Alboin', 'PERSON')"
"Many of the most wealthy Italians were slain or
 banished; the remainder were divided among the strangers,
 and a tributary obligation was imposed (under the name of
 hospitality) of paying to the Lombards a third part of the
 fruits of the earth.","('Italians', 'NORP'), ('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('third', 'ORDINAL')"
"Maurice ascended the throne at
 the mature age of forty-three years; and he reigned above
 twenty years over the East and over himself; (30) expelling
 from his mind the wild democracy of passions, and
 establishing (according to the quaint expression of
 Evagrius) a perfect aristocracy of reason and virtue.","('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('the mature age of forty-three years', 'DATE'), ('twenty years', 'DATE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('30', 'CARDINAL'), ('Evagrius', 'PERSON')"
"Maurice gave audience to a second deputation of priests and senators: the duties and the menaces of religion were forcibly urged in the letters of the Roman pontiff; and his nuncio, the deacon Gregory, was alike qualified to solicit the powers either of heaven or of the earth.","('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON')"
"Maurice was endowed with sense
 and courage to promote that happiness, and his
 administration was directed by the principles and example of
 Tiberius.","('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON')"
Narses invited the Lombards to chastise the ingratitude of the prince and people.,"('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"No sooner had he erected his
 standard, than the native strength of the Lombard was
 multiplied by the adventurous youth of Germany and Scythia.","('Lombard', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'GPE')"
"Notwithstanding this weak invention, Italy was still afflicted, Rome was again besieged, and the suburb of Classe, only three miles from Ravenna, was pillaged and occupied by the troops of a simple duke of Spoleto.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Classe', 'GPE'), ('only three miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Spoleto', 'GPE')"
"Of the Saxons, the old
 allies of the Lombards, twenty thousand warriors, with their
 wives and children, accepted the invitation of Alboin.","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alboin', 'PERSON')"
"Of this army, the pay
 and the rewards were drawn from the conquered provinces; and
 the distribution, which was not effected till after the
 death of Alboin, is disgraced by the foul marks of injustice
 and rapine.","('Alboin', 'PERSON')"
"On the approach of a French army, Garribald and his daughter took refuge in the dominions of their ally; and the marriage was consummated in the palace of Verona.","('French', 'NORP'), ('Garribald', 'PERSON'), ('Verona', 'GPE')"
"On the first alarm, the warrior started from his couch: his sword, which he attempted to draw, had been fastened to the scabbard by the hand of Rosamond; and a small stool, his only weapon, could not long protect him from the spears of the assassins.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rosamond', 'PERSON')"
"On the first day of every month, he
 distributed to the poor, according to the season, their
 stated portion of corn, wine, cheese, vegetables, oil, fish,
 fresh provisions, clothes, and money; and his treasurers
 were continually summoned to satisfy, in his name, the
 extraordinary demands of indigence and merit.","('the first day of every month', 'DATE'), ('season', 'DATE')"
"On the first intelligence of her designs, he returned to
 Constantinople, and the conspiracy was suppressed by his
 presence and firmness.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"On the four great festivals, he divided their quarterly allowance to the clergy, to his domestics, to the monasteries, the churches, the places of
 burial, the almshouses, and the hospitals of Rome, and the
 rest of the diocese.","('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('quarterly', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"On the map of Italy, the measure of the exarchate
 occupies a very inadequate space, but it included an ample
 proportion of wealth, industry, and population.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"On the report of his ambassadors, the  chagan was awed by the apparent firmness of a Roman emperor of whose character and resources he was ignorant.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"On the seventh day of his reign, Justin gave audience to the
 ambassadors of the Avars, and the scene was decorated to
 impress the Barbarians with astonishment, veneration, and
 terror.","('the seventh day', 'DATE'), ('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Avars', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"One
 city, which had been diligently fortified by the Goths,
 resisted the arms of a new invader; and while Italy was
 subdued by the flying detachments of the Lombards, the royal
 camp was fixed above three years before the western gate of
 Ticinum, or Pavia.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('three years', 'DATE'), ('Ticinum', 'GPE'), ('Pavia', 'GPE')"
"One moiety of the spoil introduced into the camp
 of Alboin more wealth than a Barbarian could readily
 compute.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP')"
"One of his attendants was prompted by
 compassion, or piety, to interpret this miraculous sign of
 the wrath of Heaven: the conqueror paused and relented; he
 sheathed his sword, and peacefully reposing himself in the
 palace of Theodoric, proclaimed to the trembling multitude
 that they should live and obey.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON')"
"Paulinus, the
 patriarch of Aquileia, removed his treasures, sacred and
 profane, to the Isle of Grado, (18) and his successors were
 adopted by the infant republic of Venice, which was
 continually enriched by the public calamities.","('Paulinus', 'PERSON'), ('Aquileia', 'GPE'), ('the Isle of Grado', 'GPE'), ('18', 'CARDINAL'), ('Venice', 'GPE')"
"Pontificate of Gregory the Great, or First, A.D. 590, February 8 - A.D. 604, March 12.","('Gregory the Great', 'PERSON'), ('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('590', 'CARDINAL'), ('February 8 - A.D. 604', 'DATE'), ('March 12', 'DATE')"
"Reign of Tiberius II, A.D. 578, Sept. 26 - A.D. 582, August 14.","('A.D. 578', 'DATE'), ('Sept. 26 - A.D. 582', 'DATE'), ('August 14', 'DATE')"
"Reign of the Younger Justin —  Embassy of the Avars — Their Settlement on the Danube — Conquests of Italy by the Lombards — Adoption and Reign of Tiberius — Of Maurice — State of Italy under the Lombards and the Exarchs of Ravenna — Distress of Rome — Character and Pontificate of Gregory the FirstDeath of Justinian, A.D. 565, Nov. 14.","('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Embassy of the Avars — Their Settlement on the Danube — Conquests of Italy by the Lombards — Adoption and Reign of Tiberius', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Maurice — State of Italy under the Lombards and the Exarchs of Ravenna — Distress of Rome', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Character and Pontificate of Gregory the FirstDeath of Justinian', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('A.D. 565', 'DATE'), ('Nov. 14', 'DATE')"
"Rome was
 oppressed by the iron sceptre of the exarchs, and a Greek,
 perhaps a eunuch, insulted with impunity the ruins of the
 Capitol.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Capitol', 'FAC')"
"Seven nephews (1) of the childless monarch, the sons or grandsons of his brother and sister, had been educated in the splendor of a princely fortune; they had been shown in high commands to the provinces and armies; their characters were known, their followers were zealous, and, as the jealousy of age postponed the declaration of a successor, they might expect with equal hopes the inheritance of their uncle.","('Seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('1', 'CARDINAL')"
"She expected and soon found a favorable moment, when the king, oppressed with wine, had retired from the table to his afternoon slumbers.","('afternoon', 'TIME')"
"She supplied the place of one of her female attendants who was beloved by Peredeus, and contrived some excuse for darkness and silence, till she could inform her companion that he had enjoyed the queen of the Lombards, and that his own death, or the death of Alboin, must be the consequence of such treasonable adultery.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Peredeus', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Alboin', 'PERSON')"
"So rapid was the influence of climate and example, that the
 Lombards of the fourth generation surveyed with curiosity
 and affright the portraits of their savage forefathers. (49)","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('49', 'CARDINAL')"
"Some
 suspicion will degrade the testimony of a subject, though he
 protests that his secret praise should never reach the ear
 of his sovereign, (31) and some failings seem to place the
 character of Maurice below the purer merit of his
 predecessor.","('31', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maurice', 'PERSON')"
"Such
 incessant alarms must annihilate the pleasures and interrupt
 the labors of a rural life; and the Campagna of Rome was
 speedily reduced to the state of a dreary wilderness, in
 which the land is barren, the waters are impure, and the air
 is infectious.","('Campagna', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Such hard conditions were eagerly accepted by the
 passions of Alboin; and, as the Romans were dissatisfied
 with the ingratitude and perfidy of the Gepidae, Justin
 abandoned that incorrigible people to their fate, and
 remained the tranquil spectator of this unequal conflict.","('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Gepidae', 'NORP'), ('Justin', 'PERSON')"
"Such repeated disappointments had chilled the spirit of the Avars, and their power would have dissolved away in the Sarmatian desert, if the alliance of Alboin, king of the Lombards, had not given a new object to their arms, and a lasting settlement to their wearied fortunes.","('Avars', 'NORP'), ('the Sarmatian desert', 'LOC'), ('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"Terror preceded his march: he found every where,
 or he left, a dreary solitude; and the pusillanimous
 Italians presumed, without a trial, that the stranger was
 invincible.","('Italians', 'NORP')"
"That marvellous art which
 teaches the birds of the air to acknowledge the voice, and
 execute the commands, of their master, had been unknown to
 the ingenuity of the Greeks and Romans. (46) Scandinavia and Scythia produce the boldest and most tractable falcons: (47)
 they were tamed and educated by the roving inhabitants,
 always on horseback and in the field.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('46', 'CARDINAL'), ('Scandinavia', 'LOC'), ('Scythia', 'LOC'), ('47', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 apprehension of a revolt was urged by the voice of envy and
 detraction, which had so recently triumphed over the merit
 of Belisarius.","('Belisarius', 'PERSON')"
"The
 attention of the court, and the forces of the East, were diverted by the Persian war: but the justice of Tiberius applied the subsidy to the defence of the city; and he dismissed the patrician with his best advice, either to bribe the Lombard chiefs, or to purchase the aid of the kings of France.","('East', 'LOC'), ('the Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('Lombard', 'PERSON'), ('France', 'GPE')"
"The
 credulity or the prudence of Gregory was always disposed to
 confirm the truths of religion by the evidence of ghosts,
 miracles, and resurrections; (72) and posterity has paid to
 his memory the same tribute which he freely granted to the
 virtue of his own or the preceding generation.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('72', 'DATE')"
"The
 fair countries of Walachia, Moldavia, Transylvania, and the
 other parts of Hungary beyond the Danube, were occupied,
 without resistance, by a new colony of Scythians; and the
 Dacian empire of the chagans subsisted with splendor above
 two hundred and thirty years.","('Walachia', 'GPE'), ('Moldavia', 'GPE'), ('Transylvania', 'GPE'), ('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Scythians', 'NORP'), ('Dacian', 'NORP'), ('two hundred and thirty years', 'DATE')"
"The
 ministers of command, and the messengers of victory, no
 longer met on the Appian or Flaminian way; and the hostile
 approach of the Lombards was often felt, and continually
 feared.","('Appian', 'NORP'), ('Flaminian', 'NORP'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"The
 misery of the times had reduced the nobles and matrons of
 Rome to accept, without a blush, the benevolence of the
 church: three thousand virgins received their food and
 raiment from the hand of their benefactor; and many bishops
 of Italy escaped from the Barbarians to the hospitable
 threshold of the Vatican.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Vatican', 'FAC')"
"The
 numerous islands from Grado to Chiozza composed the infant
 dominion of Venice: but the more accessible towns on the
 Continent were overthrown by the Lombards, who beheld with
 impotent fury a new capital rising from the waves.","('Grado', 'LOC'), ('Chiozza', 'GPE'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('Continent', 'LOC'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"The
 pilgrims of the East and West resorted to the holy
 threshold; but the shrines of the apostles were guarded by
 miracles and invisible terrors; and it was not without fear
 that the pious Catholic approached the object of his
 worship.","('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"The
 virtues of Narses were stained with avarice; and, in his
 provincial reign of fifteen years, he accumulated a treasure
 of gold and silver which surpassed the modesty of a private
 fortune.","('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('fifteen years', 'DATE')"
"The
 voluminous account of his receipts and disbursements was
 kept above three hundred years in the Lateran, as the model
 of Christian economy.","('three hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Lateran', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The
 youth of Maurice was spent in the profession of arms:
 Tiberius promoted him to the command of a new and favorite
 legion of twelve thousand confederates; his valor and
 conduct were signalized in the Persian war; and he returned
 to Constantinople to accept, as his just reward, the
 inheritance of the empire.","('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('twelve thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The Gepidae, a nation of warriors, started from their seats, and the fearless Alboin, with his forty companions, laid their hands on their swords.","('Gepidae', 'PERSON'), ('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('forty', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Lombards and Avars destroy the king and kingdom of the Gepidae, A.D. 566.","('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('Avars', 'NORP'), ('Gepidae', 'PRODUCT'), ('566', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Lombards respected the strength of Pavia,
 and listened to the prayers of the Trevisans: their slow and
 heavy multitudes proceeded to occupy the palace and city of
 Verona; and Milan, now rising from her ashes, was invested
 by the powers of Alboin five months after his departure from
 Pannonia.","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Pavia', 'GPE'), ('Trevisans', 'NORP'), ('Verona', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('five months', 'DATE'), ('Pannonia', 'ORG')"
"The Lombards, and their confederates,
 were united by their common attachment to a chief, who
 excelled in all the virtues and vices of a savage hero; and
 the vigilance of Alboin provided an ample magazine of
 offensive and defensive arms for the use of the expedition.","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Alboin', 'PERSON')"
"The Lombards, who applauded
 such early prowess, requested his father, with unanimous
 acclamations, that the heroic youth, who had shared the
 dangers of the field, might be admitted to the feast of
 victory.","('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"The Persian monarch fled before his arms; and the
 acclamations which accompanied his triumph declared him
 worthy of the purple.","('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The Romans of
 the East would have been happy, if the best gift of Heaven,
 a patriot king, had been confirmed as a proper and permanent
 blessing.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The aid of famine at length enabled
 him to execute his bloody vow; but, as Alboin entered the
 gate, his horse stumbled, fell, and could not be raised from
 the ground.","('Alboin', 'PERSON')"
"The ambassadors were dismissed: no sooner did they reach the confines of Italy than Autharis, raising himself on his horse, darted his battle-axe against a tree with incomparable strength and dexterity.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Autharis', 'PERSON')"
"The ambitious Rosamond aspired to reign in the name of her
 lover; the city and palace of Verona were awed by her power;
 and a faithful band of her native Gepidae was prepared to
 applaud the revenge, and to second the wishes, of their
 sovereign.","('Rosamond', 'PERSON'), ('Verona', 'GPE'), ('Gepidae', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"The annals of
 the second Justin (23) are marked with disgrace abroad and
 misery at home.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('23', 'CARDINAL')"
"The assembly, in silence and in tears, applauded the counsels, and sympathized with the repentance, of their prince the patriarch rehearsed the prayers of the church; Tiberius received the diadem on his knees; and Justin, who in his abdication appeared most worthy to reign, addressed the new monarch in the following words:  Death of Justin II, A.D. 578, October 5.","('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Justin II', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 578', 'DATE'), ('October 5', 'DATE')"
"The bishops of Italy and the adjacent islands
 acknowledged the Roman pontiff as their special
 metropolitan.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The bravest of the nation fell
 in the field of battle; the king of the Lombards
 contemplated with delight the head of Cunimund; and his
 skull was fashioned into a cup to satiate the hatred of the
 conqueror, or, perhaps, to comply with the savage custom of
 his country.","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Cunimund', 'PERSON')"
"The camp of Alboin was of formidable
 extent, but the extent of a camp would be easily
 circumscribed within the limits of a city; and its martial
 in habitants must be thinly scattered over the face of a
 large country.","('Alboin', 'PERSON')"
"The celestial
 honors have been liberally bestowed by the authority of the
 popes, but Gregory is the last of their own order whom they
 have presumed to inscribe in the calendar of saints.","('Gregory', 'PERSON')"
"The ceremony of his
 elevation to the rank of Caesar, or Augustus, was performed
 in the portico of the palace, in the presence of the
 patriarch and the senate.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"The cup of victory was accepted with horrid
 applause by the circle of the Lombard chiefs.","('Lombard', 'PERSON')"
"The daughter of Alboin and Rosamond, with the richest spoils of the Lombards, was embarked for Constantinople: the surprising strength of Peredeus amused and terrified the Imperial court:  his blindness and revenge exhibited an imperfect copy of the adventures of Samson.","('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('Rosamond', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Peredeus', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Samson', 'PERSON')"
The daughter of Cunimund smiled in his fall: his body was buried under the staircase of the palace; and the grateful posterity of the Lombards revered the tomb and the memory of their victorious leader.,"('Cunimund', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"The death of a jealous lover was an easy and grateful sacrifice; and, as Helmichis issued from the bath, he received the deadly potion from the hand of his mistress.","('Helmichis', 'PERSON')"
"The depopulation of Lombardy, and the increase of forests, afforded an ample range for the
 pleasures of the chase.","('Lombardy', 'GPE')"
"The design and coloring of
 this picture afford an honorable testimony that the art of
 painting was cultivated by the Italians of the sixth
 century; but the most abject ideas must be entertained of
 their taste and learning, since the epistles of Gregory, his
 sermons, and his dialogues, are the work of a man who was
 second in erudition to none of his contemporaries: (66) his
 birth and abilities had raised him to the office of praefect
 of the city, and he enjoyed the merit of renouncing the
 pomps and vanities of this world.","('Italians', 'NORP'), ('the sixth\r\n century', 'DATE'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('66', 'CARDINAL')"
The despair of Cunimund was active and dangerous.,"('Cunimund', 'GPE')"
"The destruction of a mighty kingdom established the fame of
 Alboin.","('Alboin', 'PERSON')"
"The duchy of
 Rome appears to have included the Tuscan, Sabine, and Latin
 conquests, of the first four hundred years of the city, and
 the limits may be distinctly traced along the coast, from
 Civita Vecchia to Terracina, and with the course of the
 Tyber from Ameria and Narni to the port of Ostia.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Tuscan', 'NORP'), ('Sabine', 'NORP'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('the first four hundred years', 'DATE'), ('Civita Vecchia', 'LOC'), ('Terracina', 'GPE'), ('Tyber', 'GPE'), ('Ameria', 'GPE'), ('Narni', 'GPE'), ('Ostia', 'GPE')"
"The dukes of the Lombards had provoked by frequent
 inroads their powerful neighbors of Gaul.","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The dukes, and at length the
 princes, of Beneventum, survived the monarchy, and
 propagated the name of the Lombards.","('Beneventum', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"The edifices of Rome were
 exposed to the same ruin and decay: the mouldering fabrics
 were easily overthrown by inundations, tempests, and
 earthquakes: and the monks, who had occupied the most
 advantageous stations, exulted in their base triumph over
 the ruins of antiquity.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The emperor Maurice derived his origin from ancient Rome; (29)
 but his immediate parents were settled at Arabissus in
 Cappadocia, and their singular felicity preserved them alive
 to behold and partake the fortune of their august son.","('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('29', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arabissus', 'LOC'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE')"
"The emperor adopted, with stronger effect, the measures of his predecessor: some formidable chiefs were persuaded to
 embrace the friendship of the Romans; and one of them, a mild and faithful Barbarian, lived and died in the service of the exarchs: the passes of the Alps were delivered to the Franks; and the pope encouraged them to violate, without scruple, their oaths and engagements to the misbelievers.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
The exarchate of Ravenna.,"('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"The expiring
 dignity of Rome was only marked by the freedom and energy of
 her complaints: Tiberius forgave the reproach, and relieved the distress: a supply of corn was transported from Egypt to the Tyber; and the Roman people, invoking the name, not of Camillus, but of St. Peter repulsed the Barbarians from their walls.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Tyber', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Camillus', 'PERSON'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"The factions
 of the hippodrome demanded, with some impatience, the name
 of their new empress: both the people and Sophia were
 astonished by the proclamation of Anastasia, the secret,
 though lawful, wife of the emperor Tiberius.","('Sophia', 'PERSON'), ('Anastasia', 'PERSON'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON')"
"The fair Rosamond was persuaded, or compelled, to
 acknowledge the rights of her victorious lover; and the
 daughter of Cunimund appeared to forgive those crimes which
 might be imputed to her own irresistible charms.","('Rosamond', 'PERSON'), ('Cunimund', 'PERSON')"
"The first expedition was defeated
 by the jealous animosity of the Franks and Alemanni.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON')"
The four last years of the emperor Justin were passed in tranquil obscurity: his conscience was no longer tormented by the remembrance of those duties which he was incapable of discharging; and his choice was justified by the filial reverence and gratitude of Tiberius.,"('four last years', 'DATE'), ('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON')"
"The ignorance of the Lombards in the state of Paganism or Christianity gave implicit credit to the malice and mischief of witchcraft, but the judges of the seventeenth century might have been instructed and confounded by the wisdom of Rotharis, who derides the absurd superstition, and protects the wretched victims of popular or judicial cruelty. (55)","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Paganism', 'NORP'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('the seventeenth century', 'DATE'), ('Rotharis', 'PERSON')"
"The immediate discharge of his uncle's debts exhibited a solid pledge of his faith and generosity: a train of porters, laden with bags of gold, advanced into the
 midst of the hippodrome, and the hopeless creditors of Justinian accepted this equitable payment as a voluntary gift.","('Justinian', 'ORG')"
"The inhabitants of a potent and peaceful capital,
 who visit without an anxious thought the garden of the
 adjacent country, will faintly picture in their fancy the
 distress of the Romans: they shut or opened their gates with
 a trembling hand, beheld from the walls the flames of their
 houses, and heard the lamentations of their brethren, who
 were coupled together like dogs, and dragged away into
 distant slavery beyond the sea and the mountains.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The instant
 distress of the sick and helpless, of strangers and
 pilgrims, was relieved by the bounty of each day, and of
 every hour; nor would the pontiff indulge himself in a
 frugal repast, till he had sent the dishes from his own
 table to some objects deserving of his compassion.","('every hour', 'TIME')"
"The king of Italy convened the national assemblies in the palace, or more probably in the fields, of Pavia: his great
 council was composed of the persons most eminent by their birth and dignities; but the validity, as well as the execution, of their decrees depended on the approbation of the faithful people, the fortunate army of the Lombards.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Pavia', 'GPE'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"The king of the
 Lombards had been educated in the Arian heresy; but the
 Catholics, in their public worship, were allowed to pray for
 his conversion; while the more stubborn Barbarians
 sacrificed a she-goat, or perhaps a captive, to the gods of
 their fathers.","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Catholics', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"The king of the Lombards (the father of Alboin no longer lived) was contracted to the granddaughter of Clovis; but the restraints of faith and policy soon yielded to the hope of possessing the fair Rosamond, and of insulting her family and nation.","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON'), ('Rosamond', 'PERSON')"
The kingdom of the Lombards.,"('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"The late emperor had cultivated, with annual and costly gifts, the friendship of
 a grateful monarch, and the enemies of Rome had respected
 the allies of the Avars.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Avars', 'NORP')"
"The merits of Gregory were treated by the Byzantine court with reproach and insult; but in the attachment of a grateful people, he found the purest reward of a citizen, and the best right of a sovereign. (75)","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantine', 'NORP')"
"The misfortunes of Rome involved the
 apostolical pastor in the business of peace and war; and it
 might be doubtful to himself, whether piety or ambition
 prompted him to supply the place of his absent sovereign.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The modern Italian has been insensibly
 formed by the mixture of nations: the awkwardness of the
 Barbarians in the nice management of declensions and
 conjugations reduced them to the use of articles and
 auxiliary verbs; and many new ideas have been expressed by
 Teutonic appellations.","('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Teutonic', 'NORP')"
"The most
 faithful and valuable subjects escaped from the Barbarian
 yoke; and the banners of Pavia and Verona, of Milan and
 Padua, were displayed in their respective quarters by the
 new inhabitants of Ravenna.","('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('Pavia', 'GPE'), ('Verona', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Padua', 'GPE'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"The most glorious
 trophy of his victory consisted in a multitude of captives,
 whom Tiberius entertained, redeemed, and dismissed to their
 native homes with the charitable spirit of a Christian hero.","('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The nation of the Gepidae was
 dissolved; but, in the distribution of the captives, the
 slaves of the Avars were less fortunate than the companions
 of the Lombards, whose generosity adopted a valiant foe, and
 whose freedom was incompatible with cool and deliberate
 tyranny.","('Gepidae', 'GPE'), ('Avars', 'NORP'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON')"
"The offices and professions, which
 the jealousy of Constantine had separated, were united by
 the indulgence of Justinian; and eighteen successive exarchs
 were invested, in the decline of the empire, with the full
 remains of civil, of military, and even of ecclesiastical,
 power.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('eighteen', 'CARDINAL')"
"The only son of Justin and Sophia died
 in his infancy; their daughter Arabia was the wife of
 Baduarius, (24) superintendent of the palace, and afterwards
 commander of the Italian armies, who vainly aspired to
 confirm the rights of marriage by those of adoption.","('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Sophia', 'PERSON'), ('Arabia', 'PERSON'), ('Baduarius', 'PERSON'), ('24', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
"The parents of Gregory, Sylvia, and
 Gordian, were the noblest of the senate, and the most pious
 of the church of Rome; his female relations were numbered
 among the saints and virgins; and his own figure, with those
 of his father and mother, were represented near three
 hundred years in a family portrait, (65) which he offered to
 the monastery of St. Andrew.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Sylvia', 'PERSON'), ('Gordian', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('three\r\n hundred years', 'DATE'), ('65', 'DATE'), ('St. Andrew', 'GPE')"
"The pontificate of Gregory the Great, which lasted thirteen
 years, six months, and ten days, is one of the most edifying
 periods of the history of the church.","('Gregory the Great', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('thirteen\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('six months', 'DATE'), ('ten days', 'DATE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The portable wealth of the Lombards attended the march:
 their lands they cheerfully relinquished to the Avars, on
 the solemn promise, which was made and accepted without a
 smile, that if they failed in the conquest of Italy, these
 voluntary exiles should be reinstated in their former
 possessions.","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Avars', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The posterity of the first conquerors struck
 a deeper root into the soil, which, by every motive of
 interest and honor, they were bound to defend.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The power
 of the dukes of Naples was circumscribed by the bay and the
 adjacent isles, by the hostile territory of Capua, and by
 the Roman colony of Amalphi, (35) whose industrious citizens,
 by the invention of the mariner's compass, have unveiled the
 face of the globe.","('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Capua', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Amalphi', 'GPE'), ('35', 'CARDINAL')"
"The pride of the reigning
 house supported, with reluctance, the dominion of a
 stranger: the youth was deservedly popular; his name, after
 the death of Justin, had been mentioned by a tumultuous
 faction; and his own submissive offer of his head with a
 treasure of sixty thousand pounds, might be interpreted as
 an evidence of guilt, or at least of fear.","('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('sixty thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"The pusillanimity of the Greeks had introduced so
 complete a separation between the offices of king and of
 general, that a private soldier, who had deserved and
 obtained the purple, seldom or never appeared at the head of
 his armies.","('Greeks', 'NORP')"
"The reality, or the suspicion, of a conspiracy disarmed and disunited the Italians.","('Italians', 'NORP')"
"The reign of Maurice, A.D. 582, August 13 - A.D. 602, Nov. 27.","('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 582', 'DATE'), ('August 13 - A.D. 602', 'DATE'), ('Nov. 27', 'DATE')"
"The reign of the founder was splendid and transient; and,
 before he could regulate his new conquests, Alboin fell a
 sacrifice to domestic treason and female revenge.","('Alboin', 'PERSON')"
"The remainder of Italy was
 possessed by the Lombards; and from Pavia, the royal seat,
 their kingdom was extended to the east, the north, and the
 west, as far as the confines of the Avars, the Bavarians,
 and the Franks of Austrasia and Burgundy.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('Pavia', 'GPE'), ('Avars', 'LOC'), ('Bavarians', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Austrasia', 'GPE'), ('Burgundy', 'GPE')"
"The rent or the produce of these estates was transported to the mouth of the Tyber, at the risk and expense of the pope: in the use of wealth he acted like a faithful steward of the
 church and the poor, and liberally applied to their wants
 the inexhaustible resources of abstinence and order.","('Tyber', 'LOC')"
"The reply of the emperor was delivered in
 the same strain of haughty defiance, and he derived his
 confidence from the God of the Christians, the ancient glory
 of Rome, and the recent triumphs of Justinian.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"The robust peasantry of Noricum and Pannonia had resumed the
 manners of Barbarians; and the names of the Gepidae,
 Bulgarians, Sarmatians, and Bavarians, may be distinctly
 traced in the provinces of Italy.","('Noricum', 'GPE'), ('Pannonia', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Gepidae', 'NORP'), ('Bulgarians', 'NORP'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Bavarians', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The same prudence would instruct
 the nephew of Justinian to imitate the liberality of his
 uncle, and to purchase the blessings of peace from an
 invincible people, who delighted and excelled in the
 exercise of war.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"The same spirit of a legislator, superior to his age and country, may be ascribed to Luitprand, who condemns, while
 he tolerates, the impious and inveterate abuse of duels, (56) observing, from his own experience, that the juster cause had often been oppressed by successful violence.","('Luitprand', 'PERSON')"
The saviour of Rome.,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The strength of
 Alboin had been found unequal to the gratification of his
 love, ambition, and revenge: he condescended to implore the
 formidable aid of the chagan; and the arguments that he
 employed are expressive of the art and policy of the
 Barbarians.","('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"The submission of
 the people invited the Barbarian to assume the character of
 a lawful sovereign, and the helpless exarch was confined to
 the office of announcing to the emperor Justin the rapid and
 irretrievable loss of his provinces and cities.","('Barbarian', 'NORP'), ('Justin', 'PERSON')"
"The successor of St. Peter administered his patrimony with the temper of a vigilant and moderate landlord; (73) and the epistles of Gregory are
 filled with salutary instructions to abstain from doubtful
 or vexatious lawsuits; to preserve the integrity of weights
 and measures; to grant every reasonable delay; and to reduce
 the capitation of the slaves of the glebe, who purchased the
 right of marriage by the payment of an arbitrary fine.","('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON')"
"The sword of the enemy was suspended over Rome; it was averted by the mild eloquence and seasonable gifts of the pontiff, who commanded the respect of heretics and Barbarians.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP')"
"The talents of Gregory, and the
 splendor which accompanied his retreat, rendered him dear
 and useful to the church; and implicit obedience has always
 been inculcated as the first duty of a monk.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The taste of the liquor, its speedy operation, and his experience of the character of Rosamond, convinced him that he was poisoned: he pointed his dagger to her breast, compelled her to drain the remainder of the cup, and expired in a few minutes, with the consolation that she could not survive to enjoy the fruits of her wickedness.","('Rosamond', 'PERSON'), ('a few minutes', 'TIME')"
"The three islands of Sardinia, Corsica,
 and Sicily, still adhered to the empire; and the acquisition
 of the farther Calabria removed the landmark of Autharis
 from the shore of Rhegium to the Isthmus of Consentia.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sardinia', 'GPE'), ('Corsica', 'GPE'), ('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Calabria', 'LOC'), ('Autharis', 'GPE'), ('Rhegium', 'GPE'), ('the Isthmus of Consentia', 'LOC')"
"The troops and treasures
 of the Lombards were distributed in the walled towns between
 the Alps and the Apennine.","('Lombards', 'LOC'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Apennine', 'LOC')"
The tumult was appeased by the venerable interposition of Turisund.,"('Turisund', 'PERSON')"
"The unreasonable request of an empress, who wished to
 deprive the Romans of their sacred treasure, the head of St.
 Paul, was rejected with the deepest abhorrence; and the pope
 asserted, most probably with truth, that a linen which had
 been sanctified in the neighborhood of his body, or the
 filings of his chain, which it was sometimes easy and
 sometimes impossible to obtain, possessed an equal degree of
 miraculous virtue. (63)","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('St.\r\n Paul', 'GPE')"
"The vices
 of the Lombards were the effect of passion, of ignorance, of
 intoxication; their virtues are the more laudable, as they
 were not affected by the hypocrisy of social manners, nor
 imposed by the rigid constraint of laws and education.","('Lombards', 'NORP')"
"The victorious Autharis asserted his claim to the
 dominion of Italy.","('Autharis', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The voice of
 an angel (such a fable was propagated) might reveal to the
 emperor, that he should always triumph over his domestic
 foes; but Tiberius derived a firmer assurance from the
 innocence and generosity of his own mind.","('Tiberius', 'PERSON')"
"The writings of Gregory himself
 reveal his implacable aversion to the monuments of classic
 genius; and he points his severest censure against the
 profane learning of a bishop, who taught the art of grammar,
 studied the Latin poets, and pronounced with the same voice
 the praises of Jupiter and those of Christ.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Jupiter', 'LOC'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')"
"Their dress consisted of
 loose linen garments, after the fashion of the Anglo-Saxons,
 which were decorated, in their opinion, with broad stripes
 or variegated colors.","('Anglo-Saxons', 'NORP')"
"Their hopes were encouraged by the spirit
 and eloquence of Alboin: and it is affirmed, that he spoke
 to their senses, by producing at the royal feast, the
 fairest and most exquisite fruits that grew spontaneously in
 the garden of the world.","('Alboin', 'PERSON')"
"Their immediate jurisdiction, which was afterwards
 consecrated as the patrimony of St. Peter, extended over the
 modern Romagna, the marshes or valleys of Ferrara and
 Commachio, (34) five maritime cities from Rimini to Ancona,
 and a second inland Pentapolis, between the Adriatic coast
 and the hills of the Apennine.","('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('Romagna', 'GPE'), ('Ferrara', 'GPE'), ('Commachio', 'GPE'), ('34', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rimini', 'GPE'), ('Ancona', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Pentapolis', 'GPE'), ('Adriatic', 'LOC'), ('Apennine', 'LOC')"
"Their temporal power insensibly arose from the calamities of
 the times: and the Roman bishops, who have deluged Europe
 and Asia with blood, were compelled to reign as the
 ministers of charity and peace.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"These specious reasons were heard by the chagan with
 coldness and disdain: he detained the Lombard ambassadors in
 his camp, protracted the negotiation, and by turns alleged
 his want of inclination, or his want of ability, to
 undertake this important enterprise.","('Lombard', 'PERSON')"
"These welcome deputies announced the recent and momentous secret of the emperor's decease; reported, or perhaps invented, his dying choice of the best beloved and most deserving of his nephews, and conjured Justin to prevent the disorders of the multitude, if they should perceive, with the return of light, that they were left without a master.","('Justin', 'PERSON')"
"Theudelinda was
 summoned to undergo this important examination; and, after a
 pause of silent rapture, he hailed her as the queen of
 Italy, and humbly requested that, according to the custom of
 the nation, she would present a cup of wine to the first of
 her new subjects.","('Theudelinda', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"They might have failed, if Narses had been the antagonist of
 the Lombards; and the veteran warriors, the associates of
 his Gothic victory, would have encountered with reluctance
 an enemy whom they dreaded and esteemed.","('Narses', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
They were ignorant of their new exarch; and Longinus was himself ignorant of the state of the army and the province.,"('Longinus', 'PERSON')"
"This domestic animosity was refined into a
 generous resolution of seeking a successor, not in his
 family, but in the republic; and the artful Sophia
 recommended Tiberius, (25) his faithful captain of the
 guards, whose virtues and fortune the emperor might cherish
 as the fruit of his judicious choice.","('Sophia', 'PERSON'), ('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('25', 'CARDINAL')"
"This favorite
 amusement of our ancestors was introduced by the Barbarians
 into the Roman provinces; and the laws of Italy esteemed the
 sword and the hawk as of equal dignity and importance in the
 hands of a noble Lombard. (48)","('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Lombard', 'PERSON')"
"Three subordinate provinces,
 of Rome, of Venice, and of Naples, which were divided by
 hostile lands from the palace of Ravenna, acknowledged, both
 in peace and war, the supremacy of the exarch.","('Three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('Naples', 'GPE'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"Tiberius expressed his hope that the virtues of
 his son and successor would erect the noblest mausoleum to
 his memory.","('Tiberius', 'PERSON')"
"Till the last days of his life, he officiated in the canon
 of the mass, which continued above three hours: the
 Gregorian chant (70) has preserved the vocal and instrumental
 music of the theatre, and the rough voices of the Barbarians
 attempted to imitate the melody of the Roman school. (71)","('the last days', 'DATE'), ('above three hours', 'TIME'), ('Gregorian', 'NORP'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('71', 'CARDINAL')"
"Under
 the standard of their new king, the conquerors of Italy
 withstood three successive invasions, one of which was led
 by Childebert himself, the last of the Merovingian race who
 descended from the Alps.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Childebert', 'PERSON'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('Alps', 'LOC')"
"Under his reign, the
 Arians of Italy and Spain were reconciled to the Catholic
 church, and the conquest of Britain reflects less glory on
 the name of Caesar, than on that of Gregory the First.","('Arians', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Catholic', 'NORP'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('First', 'ORDINAL')"
"War was the consequence which he foresaw and solicited; but the Lombards could not long withstand the furious assault of the Gepidae, who were sustained by a Roman army.","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Gepidae', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
Weakness of the emperor Justin.,"('Justin', 'PERSON')"
"Whatever
 merit may be discovered in the laws of the Lombards, they are the genuine fruit of the reason of the Barbarians, who never admitted the bishops of Italy to a seat in their legislative councils.","('Lombards', 'PERSON'), ('Barbarians', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Whatever could
 alleviate the disappointment of Sophia, Imperial honors, a
 stately palace, a numerous household, was liberally bestowed
 by the piety of her adopted son; on solemn occasions he
 attended and consulted the widow of his benefactor; but her
 ambition disdained the vain semblance of royalty, and the
 respectful appellation of mother served to exasperate,
 rather than appease, the rage of an injured woman.","('Sophia', 'PERSON')"
"Whatever might be the grounds of his security, Alboin
 neither expected nor encountered a Roman army in the field.","('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"When Alboin descended from the Alps, he
 invested his nephew, the first duke of Friuli, with the
 command of the province and the people: but the prudent
 Gisulf would have declined the dangerous office, unless he
 had been permitted to choose, among the nobles of the
 Lombards, a sufficient number of families (40) to form a
 perpetual colony of soldiers and subjects.","('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Friuli', 'PERSON'), ('Gisulf', 'PERSON'), ('Lombards', 'NORP'), ('40', 'CARDINAL')"
"When the fatal mandate was proclaimed, Gregory
 solicited the aid of some friendly merchants to convey him
 in a basket beyond the gates of Rome, and modestly concealed
 himself some days among the woods and mountains, till his
 retreat was discovered, as it is said, by a celestial light.","('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('some days', 'DATE')"
"When the independent dukes agreed that Autharis should ascend the throne of his father, they endowed the regal office with a
 fair moiety of their respective domains.","('Autharis', 'PERSON')"
"When the nephew of Justinian ascended the throne, he
 proclaimed a new aera of happiness and glory.","('Justinian', 'PERSON')"
"When the veil of the sanctuary was
 withdrawn, the ambassadors beheld the emperor of the East on
 his throne, beneath a canopy, or dome, which was supported
 by four columns, and crowned with a winged figure of
 Victory.","('East', 'LOC'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Victory', 'PRODUCT')"
"While
 she accepted, and repaid with a courtly smile, the fair
 expressions of regard and confidence, a secret alliance was
 concluded between the dowager empress and her ancient
 enemies; and Justinian, the son of Germanus, was employed as
 the instrument of her revenge.","('Justinian', 'PERSON'), ('Germanus', 'PERSON')"
"While
 the empire appeared an object of desire, Justin was
 accustomed to behold with jealousy and hatred his brothers
 and cousins, the rivals of his hopes; nor could he depend on
 the gratitude of those who would accept the purple as a
 restitution, rather than a gift.","('Justin', 'PERSON')"
"While Alboin served under his father's standard, he
 encountered in battle, and transpierced with his lance, the
 rival prince of the Gepidae.","('Alboin', 'PERSON'), ('Gepidae', 'PERSON')"
"With her daughter, the heiress of the Lombard throne, her two lovers, her trusty Gepidae, and the spoils of the palace of Verona, Rosamond descended the Adige and the Po, and was transported by a Greek vessel to the safe harbor of Ravenna.","('Lombard', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gepidae', 'PERSON'), ('Verona', 'GPE'), ('Rosamond', 'PERSON'), ('Adige', 'PRODUCT'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"With the odious name of Tiberius, he assumed the more
 popular appellation of Constantine, and imitated the purer
 virtues of the Antonines.","('Tiberius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Antonines', 'PERSON')"
"Within less than seventy years, this
 artificial system was abolished by a more simple and solid
 tenure. (42)","('less than seventy years', 'DATE')"
"Yet a candid suspicion will arise, that
 the sentiments of Justin were pure and benevolent, and that
 he might have filled his station without reproach, if the
 faculties of his mind had not been impaired by disease,
 which deprived the emperor of the use of his feet, and
 confined him to the palace, a stranger to the complaints of
 the people and the vices of the government.","('Justin', 'PERSON')"
"Yet the emperor Maurice enjoyed the glory of
 restoring the Persian monarch to his throne; his lieutenants
 waged a doubtful war against the Avars of the Danube; and he
 cast an eye of pity, of ineffectual pity, on the abject and
 distressful state of his Italian provinces.","('Maurice', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Avars', 'NORP'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
"Yet the number of citizens still exceeded
 the measure of subsistence: their precarious food was
 supplied from the harvests of Sicily or Egypt; and the
 frequent repetition of famine betrays the inattention of the
 emperor to a distant province.","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"Yet the principal stock of technical
 and familiar words is found to be of Latin derivation; (38)
 and, if we were sufficiently conversant with the obsolete,
 the rustic, and the municipal dialects of ancient Italy, we
 should trace the origin of many terms which might, perhaps,
 be rejected by the classic purity of Rome.","('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('38', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"and Autharis, the son of Clepho, had already
 attained the strength and reputation of a warrior.","('Autharis', 'PERSON'), ('Clepho', 'PERSON')"
