Sentence,Entities
"""Attila, my lord, and thy lord, commands thee to provide a palace for his immediate reception.""  (2)","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('2', 'CARDINAL')"
(14),"('14', 'CARDINAL')"
(18),"('18', 'CARDINAL')"
"(19) 
 Clodion, the first of their long-haired kings whose name and
 actions are mentioned in authentic history, held his
 residence at Dispargum, (20) a village or fortress, whose 
 place may be assigned between Louvain and Brussels.","('19', 'CARDINAL'), ('Clodion', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Dispargum', 'ORG'), ('20', 'CARDINAL'), ('Louvain', 'GPE'), ('Brussels', 'GPE')"
(43),"('43', 'CARDINAL')"
"(9) Strangers to the emperor or the republic, the 
 Alani of Gaul were devoted to the ambition of Aetius; and
 though he might suspect that, in a contest with Attila
 himself, they would revolt to the standard of their national
 king, the patrician laboured to restrain, rather than to
 excite, their zeal and resentment against the Goths, the
 Burgundians, and the Franks.","('Alani', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"A
 republican spirit was insensibly revived in the senate, as
 their authority, and even their supplies, became necessary
 for the support of his feeble government.","('republican', 'NORP')"
"A native of Gaul and a contemporary, the learned and
 eloquent Sidonius, who was afterwards bishop of Clermont,
 had made a promise to one of his friends that he would
 compose a regular history of the war of Attila.","('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Sidonius', 'PERSON'), ('Clermont', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"A people whose habitations might be
 doubtfully assigned to the earth or water soon became alike
 familiar with the two elements; and the demands of avarice
 succeeded to those of necessity.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"A seasonable treaty
 which he concluded with Genseric protected Italy from the
 depredations of the Vandals; the independent Britons
 implored and acknowledged his salutary aid; the Imperial
 authority was restored and maintained in Gaul and Spain; and
 he compelled the Franks and the Suevi, whom he had
 vanquished in the field, to become the useful confederates
 of the republic.","('Genseric', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Britons', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Suevi', 'PERSON')"
"A troop of light barbarians who roamed in quest of
 plunder might choose the winter for the convenience of
 passing the river on the ice, but the innumerable cavalry of
 the Huns required such plenty of forage and provisions as
 could be procured only in a milder season; the Hercynian
 forest supplied materials for a bridge of boats, and the
 hostile myriads were poured with resistless violence into
 the Belgic provinces. (33)","('the winter', 'DATE'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('a milder season', 'DATE'), ('Hercynian', 'NORP'), ('Belgic', 'NORP'), ('33', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 435-439.,"('435-439', 'CARDINAL')"
"Aetius assumed the command of the left, and Theodoric of the
 right wing; while Torismond still continued to occupy the
 heights which appear to have stretched on the flank, and
 perhaps the rear, of the Scythian army.","('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Torismond', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'NORP')"
"Aetius himself, supported by the consciousness
 of his merit, his services, and perhaps his innocence, seems
 to have maintained a haughty and indiscreet behaviour.","('Aetius', 'PERSON')"
"Aetius was the sole
 guardian of the public safety; but his wisest measures were
 embarrassed by a faction which, since the death of Placidia,
 infested the Imperial palace: the youth of Italy trembled at
 the sound of the trumpet; and the barbarians, who from fear
 or affection were inclined to the cause of Attila, awaited
 with doubtful and venal faith the event of the war.","('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Placidia', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"After an obstinate siege the walls
 were shaken by the battering rams; the Huns had already
 occupied the suburbs, and the people who were incapable of
 bearing arms lay prostrate in prayer.","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"After his death
 the boldest chieftains aspired to the rank of kings; the
 most powerful kings refused to acknowledge a superior; and
 the numerous sons whom so many various mothers bore to the
 deceased monarch divided and disputed like a private
 inheritance the sovereign command of the nations of Germany
 and Scythia.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'GPE')"
"After the death of Wallia, the Gothic sceptre
 devolved to Theodoric, the son of the great Alaric;(10) and 
 his prosperous reign of more than thirty years over a
 turbulent people may be allowed to prove that his prudence
 was supported by uncommon vigour, both of mind and body.","('Wallia', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('more than thirty years', 'DATE')"
"After the death of his rival Boniface, Aetius had prudently
 retired to the tents of the Huns; and he was indebted to
 their alliance for his safety and his restoration.","('Boniface', 'PERSON'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"After the departure of the Goths, and the 
 separation of the allied army, Attila was surprised at the
 vast silence that reigned over the plains of Chalons: the
 suspicion of some hostile stratagem detained him several
 days within the circle of his waggons, and his retreat
 beyond the Rhine confessed the last victory which was
 achieved in the name of the Western empire.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Chalons', 'NORP'), ('several\r\n days', 'DATE'), ('Rhine', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"After the mutual and repeated discharge of missile weapons, in which the archers of Scythia might signalise their superior dexterity, the cavalry and infantry of the two armies were furiously mingled in closer combat.","('Scythia', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"After this dreadful chastisement, Attila 
 pursued his march; and as he passed, the cities of Altinumn
 Concordia, and Padua were reduced into heaps of stones and
 ashes.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Altinumn\r\n Concordia', 'GPE'), ('Padua', 'GPE')"
Alliance of the Romans and Visigoths.,"('Alliance of the Romans', 'ORG'), ('Visigoths', 'ORG')"
"Amidst the general consternation, Aetius alone was incapable
 of fear; but it was impossible that he should achieve alone
 and unassisted any military exploits worthy of his former
 renown.","('Aetius', 'PERSON')"
"An artery had suddenly burst: and as Attila lay in a supine
 posture, he was suffocated by a torrent of blood, which,
 instead of finding a passage through the nostrils,
 regurgitated into the lungs and stomach.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"Anianus, who anxiously counted the days and hours!","('Anianus', 'PERSON')"
"Aquileia was at that period one of the richest, the
 most Populous, and the strongest of the maritime cities of
 the Hadriatic coast.","('Aquileia', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Populous', 'NORP'), ('the Hadriatic coast', 'LOC')"
"Aquileia, Padua, and the
 adjacent towns, who fled from the sword of the Huns, found a
 safe, though obscure, refuge in the neighbouring islands.(55)","('Aquileia', 'GPE'), ('Padua', 'GPE'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('55', 'CARDINAL')"
"As Theodoric rode along the ranks to animate his troops, he received a mortal stroke from the javelin of Andaires, a noble Ostrogoth, and immediately fell from his horse.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Andaires', 'NORP'), ('Ostrogoth', 'NORP')"
"As early as the time of Cicero and Varro it was the opinion of the Roman augurs that the twelve vultures which Romulus had seen, represented the twelve centuries assigned for the fatal period of his city(75)","('Cicero', 'PERSON'), ('Varro', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romulus', 'PERSON'), ('the twelve centuries', 'DATE'), ('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"At
 the head of his brave and faithful Huns, he occupied in
 person the centre of the line.","('Huns', 'PERSON')"
"At the extremity of the Gulf, where the Hadriatic feebly
 imitates the tides of the ocean, near an hundred small
 islands are separated by shallow water from the continent,
 and protected from the waves by several long slips of land,
 which admit the entrance of vessels through some secret and
 narrow channels.(56)","('Gulf', 'LOC'), ('Hadriatic', 'GPE'), ('hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('56', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the head of
 an army of Huns, he rashly advanced to the gates of
 Toulouse, full of careless contempt for an enemy whom his
 misfortunes had rendered prudent, and his situation made
 desperate.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Toulouse', 'GPE')"
"Attila
 had fondly or superstitiously believed that Irnac, the
 youngest of his sons, was destined to perpetuate the glories
 of his race.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Irnac', 'PERSON')"
"Attila already exulted in the confidence of victory, when the valiant Torismond descended from the hills, and verified the remainder of the prediction.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Torismond', 'PERSON')"
"Attila threatens both empires, and prepares to invade Gaul, A.D. 450.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('450', 'CARDINAL')"
Battle of Chalons.,"('Battle of Chalons', 'ORG')"
"Before the irruption of the barbarians,
 fifty Venetian cities flourished in peace and prosperity:
 Aquileia was placed in the most conspicuous station: but the
 ancient dignity of Padua was supported by agriculture and
 manufactures; and the property of five hundred citizens, who
 were entitled to the equestrian rank, must have amounted, at
 the strictest computation, to one million seven hundred
 thousand pounds.","('fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Venetian', 'NORP'), ('Aquileia', 'PERSON'), ('Padua', 'GPE'), ('five hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('one million seven hundred\r\n thousand pounds', 'QUANTITY')"
"Before the king of the Huns evacuated Italy, he threatened
 to return more dreadful, and more implacable, if his bride,
 the princess Honoria, were not delivered to his ambassadors
 within the term stipulated by the treaty.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Honoria', 'PERSON')"
"Boethius, the
 Praetorian praefect, was killed at the same moment; and
 before the event could be divulged, the principal friends of
 the patrician were summoned to the palace and separately
 murdered.","('Boethius', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP')"
"But as he rode round the walls, pensive, angry, and
 disappointed, he observed a stork preparing to leave her
 nest in one of the towers, and to fly with her infant family
 towards the country.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"But as the
 greatest part of the Gallic cities were alike destitute of
 saints and soldiers, they were besieged and stormed by the
 Huns, who practised, in the example of Metz, (35) their 
 customary maxims of war.","('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Metz', 'PERSON'), ('35', 'CARDINAL')"
"But as the barbarian despised, or affected to despise, the Romans of the East, whom he had so often vanquished, he soon declared his resolution of suspending the easy conquest till he had achieved a more glorious and important enterprise.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"But his enemies had passed the night in equal disorder and
 anxiety.","('the night', 'TIME')"
"But in the
 absence of the patrician, who was hastily summoned to Italy
 by some public or private interest, Count Litorius succeeded
 to the command; and his presumption soon discovered that far
 different talents are required to lead a wing of cavalry, or
 to direct the operations of an important war.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Litorius', 'PERSON')"
"But in this tumultuary retreat the
 vanguard of the Romans and their allies continually pressed,
 and sometimes engaged, the troops whom Attila had posted in
 the rear; the hostile columns, in the darkness of the night
 and the perplexity of the roads, might encounter each other without design; and the bloody conflict of the Franks and Gepidae, in which fifteen thousand(40) 
 barbarians were slain, was a prelude to a more general and
 decisive action.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Gepidae', 'PERSON'), ('fifteen thousand(40', 'CARDINAL')"
"But its fall was announced by a clearer omen than the flight of vultures: the Roman government appeared every day less formidable to its enemies, more odious and oppressive to its subjects.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('every day', 'DATE')"
"But on his arrival at Arles or Lyons he was confounded by 
 the intelligence that the Visigoths, refusing to embrace the
 defence of Gaul, had determined to expect within their own
 territories the formidable invader whom they professed to
 despise.","('Arles', 'GPE'), ('Lyons', 'PERSON'), ('Visigoths', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"But the battle of Chalons can only excite our
 curiosity by the magnitude of the object; since it was
 decided by the blind impetuosity of barbarians, and has been
 related by partial writers, whose civil and ecclesiastical
 profession secluded them from the knowledge of military
 affairs.","('Chalons', 'GPE')"
"But the emperor of the West, the feeble and
 dissolute Valentinian, who had reached his thirty-fifth year
 without attaining the age of reason or courage, abused this
 apparent security to undermine the foundations of his own
 throne by the murder of the patrician Aetius.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('thirty-fifth year', 'DATE'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON')"
"But the fair Honoria had no sooner
 attained the sixteenth year of her age than she detested the
 importunate greatness which must for ever exclude her from
 the comforts of honourable love: in the midst of vain and
 unsatisfactory pomp Honoria sighed, yielded to the impulse
 of nature, and threw herself into the arms of her
 chamberlain Eugenius.","('Honoria', 'PERSON'), ('the sixteenth year', 'DATE'), ('Honoria', 'PERSON'), ('Eugenius', 'PERSON')"
"But the impatience of the barbarians soon disdained
 these cautious and dilatory measures: and the mature policy
 of Aetius was apprehensive that, after the extirpation of
 the Huns, the republic would be oppressed by the pride and
 power of the Gothic nation.","('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"But the labour of many
 thousand provincials and captives, whose lives were
 sacrificed without pity, might execute the most painful and
 dangerous work.","('many\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the manners of the Venetian fugitives, their arts
 and their government, were gradually formed by their new situation; and one of the
 epistles of Cassiodorus, (57) which describes their condition 
 about seventy years afterwards, may be considered as the
 primitive monument of the republic.","('Venetian', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Cassiodorus', 'PERSON'), ('57', 'DATE'), ('about seventy years afterwards', 'DATE')"
"But the timid grandson of Theodosius,
 instead of sharing the dangers, escaped from the sound, of
 war; and his hasty retreat from Ravenna to Rome, from an
 impregnable fortress to an open capital, betrayed his secret
 intention of abandoning Italy as soon as the danger should
 approach his Imperial person.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"But the unusual
 despondency which seemed to prevail among the Huns engaged
 Attila to use the expedient, so familiar to the generals of
 antiquity, of animating his troops by a military oration;
 and his language was that of a king who had often fought and
 conquered at their head.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"But this treacherous
 conspiracy was detected and disappointed: Orleans had been
 strengthened with recent fortifications, and the assaults of
 the Huns were vigorously repelled by the faithful valour of
 the soldiers or citizens who defended the place.","('Orleans', 'GPE'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"By the ministry
 of a faithful eunuch she transmitted to Attila a ring, the
 pledge of her affection, and earnestly conjured him to claim
 her as a lawful spouse to whom he had been secretly
 betrothed.","('the ministry\r\n of a faithful', 'ORG'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"By the specious professions of
 gratitude and voluntary attachment, the patrician might
 disguise his apprehensions of the Scythian conqueror, who
 pressed the two empires with his innumerable armies.","('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Cassiodorus, however, had familiarly conversed with
 many Gothic warriors who served in that memorable
 engagement;","('Cassiodorus', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"Death of Valentinian, A.D. 455, March 16.","('Valentinian', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 455', 'DATE'), ('March 16', 'DATE')"
"Deep gaming was one of the
 vices of the court; the emperor, who, by chance or
 contrivance, had gained from Maximus a considerable sum,
 uncourteously exacted his ring as a security for the debt,
 and sent it by a trusty messenger to his wife, with an order
 in her husband's name that she should immediately attend the
 empress Eudoxia.","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Eudoxia', 'PERSON')"
"During his absence his elder brother had solicited
 with equal ardour the formidable aid of Attila; and the king
 of the Huns embraced an alliance which facilitated the
 passage of the Rhine, and justified by a specious and
 honourable pretence the invasion of Gaul.(27)","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('27', 'CARDINAL')"
"Ellac, the
 eldest on of Attila, lost his life and crown in the
 memorable battle of Netad; his early valour had raised him
 to the throne of the Acatzires, a Scyhlan people, whom he
 subdued; and his father, who loved the superior merit, would
 have envied the death, of Ellac.(70)","('Ellac', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Netad', 'PERSON'), ('Acatzires', 'NORP'), ('Scyhlan', 'NORP'), ('Ellac', 'PERSON')"
"From a principle of interest, as well as gratitude, Aetius
 assiduously cultivated the alliance of the Huns.","('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"From the
 instinct of a base and jealous mind, he hated the man who
 was universally celebrated as the terror of the barbarians
 and the support of the republic; and his new favourite, the
 eunuch Heraclius, awakened the emperor from the supine
 lethargy which might be disguised during the life of
 Placidia(72) by the excuse of filial piety.","('Heraclius', 'PERSON'), ('Placidia', 'PERSON'), ('72', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the
 report of his spies the king of the Franks was informed that
 the defenceless state of the second Belgic must yield, on
 the slightest attack, to the valour of his subjects.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Belgic', 'GPE')"
"From the Rhine and the
 Moselle, Attila advanced into the heart of Gaul, crossed the
 Seine at Auxerre, and after a long and laborious march fixed
 his camp under the walls of Orleans.","('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Moselle', 'FAC'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Seine', 'LOC'), ('Auxerre', 'LOC'), ('Orleans', 'GPE')"
"From the royal village in the
 plains of Hungary his standard moved towards the West and
 after a march of seven or eight hundred miles he reached the
 conflux of the Rhine and the Neckar, where he was joined by
 the Franks who adhered to his ally, the elder of the sons of
 Clodion.","('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('seven or eight hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Neckar', 'LOC'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Clodion', 'PERSON')"
"He
 boldly penetrated through the thickets and morasses of the
 Carbonarian forest,(21) occupied Tournay and Cambray, the 
 only cities which existed in the fifth century; and extended
 his conquests as far as the river Somme, over a desolate
 country whose cultivation and populousness are the effects
 of more recent industry. (22)","('Carbonarian', 'NORP'), ('21', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tournay', 'LOC'), ('Cambray', 'LOC'), ('the fifth century', 'DATE'), ('Somme', 'LOC'), ('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"He
 represented to Theodoric that an ambitious conqueror who
 aspired to the dominion of the earth could be resisted only
 by the firm and unanimous alliance of the powers whom he
 laboured to oppress.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON')"
He Is Repulsed by Aetius and the Visigoths. —  Attila Invades and Evacuates Italy. —,"('Aetius', 'ORG'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Attila Invades', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"He commanded a
 painter to reverse the figures and the attitudes; and the
 emperors were delineated on the same canvas approaching in a
 suppliant posture to empty their bags of tributary gold
 before the throne of the Scythian monarch.(52)","('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('52', 'CARDINAL')"
"He faithfully imitated the hereditary weakness of his cousin and his two uncles, without inheriting the gentleness, the purity, the innocence, which alleviate in their characters the want of spirit and ability.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"He had exposed his person with the rashness of a private soldier, but the intrepid troops of the centre had pushed forwards beyond the rest of the line; their attack was faintly supported; their flanks were unguarded; and the conquerors of Scythia and Germany were saved by the approach of the night from a total defeat.","('Scythia', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('the night', 'TIME')"
He returned twice without any intelligence that could inspire hope or comfort; but in his third report he mentioned a small cloud which he had faintly descried at the extremity of the horizon.,"('third', 'ORDINAL')"
"He strenuously urged that it was the duty of every
 Christian to save from sacrilegious violation the churches
 of God and the relics of the saints; that it was the
 interest of every barbarian who had acquired a settlement in
 Gaul to defend the fields and vineyards, which were
 cultivated for his use, against the desolation of the
 Scythian shepherds.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Scythian', 'NORP')"
"He threatened to chastise the rash successor of 
 Theodosius; but he hesitated, whether he should first direct his invincible arms against the Eastern or the Western empire.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"He was desirous of
 securing his conquests by the possession of an advantageous
 post which commanded the passage of the Loire; and he
 depended on the secret invitation of Sangiban, king of the
 Alani, who had promised to betray the city and to revolt
 from the service of the empire.","('Loire', 'LOC'), ('Sangiban', 'PERSON'), ('Alani', 'PERSON')"
"Her guilt and shame (such is the
 absurd language of imperious man) were soon betrayed by the
 appearances of pregnancy: but the disgrace of the royal
 family was published to the world by the imprudence of the
 empress Placidia, who dismissed her daughter, after a strict
 and shameful confinement, to a remote exile at
 Constantinople.","('Placidia', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"Her tears when she
 returned home, her deep affliction, and the bitter
 reproaches against a husband whom she considered as the
 accomplice of his own shame, excited Maximus to a just
 revenge; the desire of revenge was stimulated by ambition;
 and he might reasonably aspire, by the free suffrage of the
 Roman senate, to the throne of a detested and despicable
 rival.","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"His
 soldiers, animated with martial and religious enthusiasm,
 assaulted the camp of Litorius.","('Litorius', 'PERSON')"
"His
 throne was surrounded by six valiant sons, who were educated
 with equal care in the exercises of the barbarian camp, and
 in those of the Gallic schools: from the study of the Roman
 jurisprudence they acquired the theory, at least, of law and
 justice; and the harmonious sense of Virgil contributed to
 soften the asperity of their native manners.","('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Virgil', 'PERSON')"
"His attendants continued to respect his pleasures or his
 repose the greatest part of the ensuing day, till the
 unusual silence alarmed their fears and suspicions; and,
 after attempting to awaken Attila by loud and repeated
 cries, they at length broke into the royal apartment.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"His body was
 solemnly exposed in the midst of the plain, under a silken
 pavilion; and the chosen squadrons of the Huns, wheeling
 round in measured evolutions, chanted a funeral song to the
 memory of a hero, glorious in his life, invincible in his
 death, the father of his people, the scourge of his enemies,
 and the terror of the world.","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"His brother Dengisich, 
 with an army of Huns still formidable in their flight and
 ruin, maintained his ground above fifteen years on the banks
 of the Danube.","('Dengisich', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('fifteen years', 'DATE'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
His connection with the Huns and Alani.,"('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Alani', 'PERSON')"
"His predecessors, the
 ancient Tanjous, had often addressed in the same hostile and
 peremptory manner the daughters of China; and the
 pretensions of Attila were not less offensive to the majesty
 of Rome.","('Tanjous', 'NORP'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"His prudence, rather than his virtue, engaged him
 to leave the grandson of Theodosius in the possession of the
 purple; and Valentinian was permitted to enjoy the peace and
 luxury of Italy, while the patrician appeared in the
 glorious light of a hero and a patriot, who supported near
 twenty years the ruins of the Western empire.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('near\r\n twenty years', 'DATE'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"His public declarations were
 skilfully mitigated by his private assurances; he
 alternately soothed and threatened the Romans and the Goths;
 and the courts of Ravenna and Toulouse, mutually suspicious
 of each other's intentions, beheld with supine indifference
 the approach of their common enemy.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Toulouse', 'GPE')"
"His rich gifts and
 pressing solicitations inflamed the ambition of Attila; and
 the designs of Aetius and Theodoric were prevented by the
 invasion of Gaul.(15)
The Franks in Gaul, under the Merovingian kings, A.D. 420-451.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Aetius', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Theodoric', 'ORG'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('The Franks in Gaul', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Merovingian', 'NORP'), ('420-451', 'CARDINAL')"
"IT was the opinion of Marcian, that war should be avoided as
 long as it is possible to preserve a secure and honourable
 peace; but it was likewise his opinion that peace cannot be
 honourable or secure, if the sovereign betrays a
 pusillanimous aversion to war.","('Marcian', 'PERSON')"
"If all the barbarian conquerors had been annihilated in the same hour, their total destruction would not have restored the empire of the West: and if Rome still survived, she survived the loss of freedom, of virtue, and of honour.","('the same hour', 'TIME'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"If the
 modesty of Sidonius had not discouraged him from the
 prosecution of this interesting work,(31) the historian could 
 have related with the simplicity of truth those memorable
 events to which the poet, in vague and doubtful metaphors,
 has concisely alluded. (32)","('Sidonius', 'PERSON'), ('31', 'CARDINAL'), ('32', 'CARDINAL')"
"If the 
 mind of Valentinian had been susceptible of any generous
 sentiments, he would have chosen such a general for his
 example and his guide.","('Valentinian', 'ORG')"
"Impatient of his narrow limits, Theodoric aspired to the
 possession of Arles, the wealthy seat of government and
 commerce; but the city was saved by the timely approach of
 Aetius; and the Gothic king, who had raised the siege with
 some loss and disgrace, was persuaded, for an adequate
 subsidy, to divert the martial valour of his subjects in a
 Spanish war.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Arles', 'PERSON'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('a\r\n Spanish war', 'EVENT')"
"In a bloody and decisive
 conflict on the banks of the river Netad in Pannonia, the
 lance of the Gepidae, the sword of the Goths, the arrows of
 the Huns, the Suevic infantry, the light arms of the Heruli,
 and the heavy weapons of the Alani, encountered or supported
 each other; and the victory of Ardaric was accompanied with
 the slaughter of thirty thousand of his enemies.","('Netad', 'GPE'), ('Pannonia', 'GPE'), ('Gepidae', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Suevic', 'NORP'), ('Heruli', 'PRODUCT'), ('Alani', 'NORP'), ('Ardaric', 'PERSON'), ('thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the confusion of a nocturnal combat he was thrown from
 his horse; and the Gothic prince must have perished like his
 father, if his youthful strength and the intrepid zeal of
 his companions had not rescued him from this dangerous
 situation.","('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"In the ensuing spring he repeated his demand of
 the princess Honoria and her patrimonial treasures.","('the ensuing spring', 'DATE'), ('Honoria', 'PERSON')"
"In the memorable invasions of Gaul and Italy, the Huns were naturally attracted by the wealth and fertility of those provinces; but the particular motives and provocations of Attila can only be explained by the state of the Western empire under the reign of Valentinian, or, to speak more correctly, under the administration of Aetius. (3)
Character and administration of Aetius, A.D. 433-454.","('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Aetius', 'ORG'), ('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aetius', 'ORG'), ('433-454', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the pursuit of
 love, or rather of revenge, the daughter of Placidia
 sacrificed every duty and every prejudice, and offered to
 deliver her person into the arms of a barbarian of whose
 language she was ignorant, whose figure was scarcely human,
 and whose religion and manners she abhorred.","('Placidia', 'PERSON')"
"In the same manner, but on the left of the line,
 Aetius himself, separated from his allies, ignorant of their
 victory, and anxious for their fate, encountered and escaped
 the hostile troops that were scattered over the plains of
 Chalons; and at length reached the camp of the Goths, which
 he could only fortify with a slight rampart of shields till
 the dawn of day.","('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Chalons', 'LOC'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('the dawn of day', 'DATE')"
"Instead
 of the suppliant language of a guilty exile, he solicited
 his pardon at the head of sixty thousand barbarians; and the
 empress Placidia confessed, by a feeble resistance, that the
 condescension which might have been ascribed to clemency was
 the effect of weakness or fear.","('sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Placidia', 'PERSON')"
Invasion of Gaul by Attila. —,"('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"It is a saying worthy of the ferocious pride of Attila, that
 the grass never grew on the spot where his horse had trod.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"It was determined in a
 general council of war to besiege the king of the Huns in
 his camp, to intercept his provisions, and to reduce him to
 the alternative of a disgraceful treaty or an unequal
 combat.","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"It was reported at Constantinople that, on the fortunate
 night in which he expired, Marcian beheld in a dream the bow
 of Attila broken asunder: and the report may be allowed to
 prove how seldom the image of that formidable barbarian was
 absent from the mind of a Roman emperor.(69)
Destruction of his empire.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('the fortunate\r\n night', 'TIME'), ('Marcian', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('69', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was reported that, after scrutinising the
 entrails of victims and scraping their bones, they revealed,
 in mysterious language, his own defeat, with the death of
 his principal adversary; and that the barbarian, by
 accepting the equivalent, expressed his involuntary esteem
 for the superior merit of Aetius.","('Aetius', 'PERSON')"
"Meroveus and his
 Franks, observing a prudent distance, and magnifying the
 opinion of their strength by the numerous fires which they
 kindled every night, continued to follow the rear of the
 Huns till they reached the confines of Thuringia.","('Meroveus', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('every night', 'TIME'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Thuringia', 'GPE')"
"Meroveus, the younger, (26) was persuaded to implore the 
 protection of Rome; he was received at the Imperial court as
 the ally of Valentinian and the adopted son of the patrician
 Aetius, and dismissed to his native country with splendid
 gifts and the strongest assurances of friendship and
 support.","('Meroveus', 'PERSON'), ('26', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON')"
"Milan and
 Pavia submitted, without resistance, to the loss of their
 wealth; and applauded the unusual clemency which preserved
 from the flames the public as well as private buildings, and
 spared the lives of the captive multitude.","('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Pavia', 'GPE')"
"Neither the spirit, nor the forces, nor the reputation of
 Attila were impaired by the failure of the Gallic
 expedition.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP')"
"On every side, the activity of Aetius  and his Scythian cavalry opposed a firm and successful resistance.","('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'NORP')"
"On the discovery of her 
 connection with the king of the Huns, the guilty princess
 had been sent away, as an object of horror, from
 Constantinople to Italy: her life was spared, but the
 ceremony of her marriage was performed with some obscure and
 nominal husband before she was immured in a perpetual
 prison, to bewail those crimes and misfortunes which Honoria
 might have escaped had she not been born the daughter of an
 emperor.(30)
Attila invades Gaul, and besieges Orleans, A.D. 4501.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Honoria', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('4501', 'CARDINAL')"
"On their approach the king of the Huns immediately raised
 the siege, and sounded a retreat to recall the foremost of
 his troops from the pillage of a city which they had already
 entered.(39)","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"Petronius
 Maximus, a wealthy senator of the Anician family, who had
 been twice consul was possessed of a chaste and beautiful
 wife; her obstinate resistance served only to irritate the
 desires of Valentinian, and he resolved to accomplish them
 either by stratagem or force.","('Petronius\r\n Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Anician', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"Sangiban, the faithless king of the Alani, was
 placed in the centre: where his motions might be strictly
 watched, and his treachery might be instantly punished.","('Sangiban', 'PERSON'), ('Alani', 'PERSON')"
"She delivered herself, her
 son Valentinian, and the Western empire, into the hands of
 an insolent subject; nor could Placidia protect the
 son-in-law of Boniface, the virtuous and faithful Sebastian,
 (4) from the implacable persecution which urged him from one 
 kingdom to another, till he miserably perished in the
 service of the Vandals.","('Valentinian', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('Placidia', 'PERSON'), ('Boniface', 'PERSON'), ('Sebastian', 'PERSON'), ('4', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Vandals', 'PRODUCT')"
"Since Aetius, at the head
 of his domestic troops, still maintained the field, and
 harassed or retarded the march of Attila, he never showed
 himself more truly great than at the time when his conduct
 was blamed by an ignorant and ungrateful people.(59)","('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"Such
 sentiments seldom pervade the walls of a palace; yet the
 emperor was confounded by the honest reply of a Roman whose
 approbation he had not disdained to solicit. and ravishes the wife of Maximus.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"Such an event might contribute to the safety of the Eastern
 empire under the reign of a prince who conciliated the
 friendship, without forfeiting the esteem, of the
 barbarians.","('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"Such was the fate of Valentinian the Third, (74) the last Roman emperor of the family of Theodosius.","('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Third', 'ORDINAL'), ('74', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"Such was the various army which, under the conduct of Aetius
 and Theodoric, advanced by rapid marches to relieve Orleans,
 and to give battle to the innumerable host of Attila.(38)
Attila retires to the plains of Champagne.","('Aetius', 'GPE'), ('Theodoric', 'GPE'), ('Orleans', 'GPE'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Champagne', 'LOC')"
"Such were
 those savage ancestors whose imaginary virtues have
 sometimes excited the praise and envy of civilised ages !(47)
Invasion of Italy by Attila, A.D. 452.","('47', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('452', 'CARDINAL')"
"Surrounded and
 oppressed by the multitude of his father's slaves, the
 kingdom of Dengisich was confined to the circle of his
 waggons; his desperate courage urged him to invade the
 Eastern empire: he fell in battle, and his head,
 ignominiously exposed in the Hippodrome, exhibited a
 grateful spectacle to the people of Constantinople.","('Dengisich', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP'), ('Hippodrome', 'FAC'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"The
 Thuringians served in the army of Attila: they traversed,
 both in their march and in their return, the territories of
 the Franks; and it was perhaps in this war that they
 exercised the cruelties which, about four-score years
 afterwards, were revenged by the son of Clovis.","('Thuringians', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('about four-score years\r\n afterwards', 'DATE'), ('Clovis', 'PERSON')"
"The
 demand was again rejected or eluded; and the indignant lover
 immediately took the field, passed the Alps, invaded Italy,
 and besieged Aquileia with an innumerable host of
 barbarians.","('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Aquileia', 'PERSON')"
"The
 distress of Cologne was prolonged by the perpetual dominion
 of the same barbarians who evacuated the ruins of Treves,
 and Treves, which in the space of forty years had been four
 times besieged and pillaged, was disposed to lose the memory
 of her afflictions in the vain amusements of the circus.(25)","('Cologne', 'GPE'), ('Treves', 'LOC'), ('Treves', 'LOC'), ('the space of forty years', 'DATE'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('25', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 pastoral diligence of Anianus, a bishop of primitive
 sanctity and consummate prudence, exhausted every art of
 religious policy to support their courage till the arrival
 of the expected succours.","('Anianus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 patrician offended his sovereign by an hostile declaration;
 he aggravated the offence by compelling him to ratify with a
 solemn oath a treaty of reconciliation and alliance; he
 proclaimed his suspicions, he neglected his safety; and from
 a vain confidence that the enemy whom he despised was
 incapable even of a manly crime, he rashly ventured his
 person in the palace of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The
 patrician passed the Alps at the head of some troops whose
 strength and numbers scarcely deserved the name of an army.
 (36)","('Alps', 'LOC')"
"The
 young and valiant Torismond first occupied the summit; the
 Goths rushed with irresistible weight on the Huns, who
 laboured to ascend from the opposite side: and the
 possession of this advantageous post inspired both the
 troops and their leaders with a fair assurance of victory.","('Torismond', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"The 
 barbarian monarch listened with favourable, and even
 respectful, attention; and the deliverance of Italy was
 purchased by the immense ransom or dowry of the princess
 Honoria.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Honoria', 'PERSON')"
"The Armorican provinces of Gaul and the greatest part of Spain were thrown into a state of disorderly independence by the confederations of the Bagaudae, and the Imperial ministers pursued with proscriptive laws and ineffectual arms the rebels whom they had made.","('Armorican', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Bagaudae', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"The Catalaunian fields(41) spread themselves 
 round Chalons, and extend, according to the vague
 measurement of Jornandes, to the length of one hundred and
 fifty, and the breadth of one hundred miles, over the whole
 province, which is entitled to the appellation of a
 'champaign' country. (42)","('Catalaunian', 'NORP'), ('41', 'CARDINAL'), ('Chalons', 'GPE'), ('Jornandes', 'GPE'), ('one hundred and\r\n fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('42', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Deaths of Attila, Aetius, and Valentinian the Third.","('The Deaths of Attila', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Third', 'ORDINAL')"
"The Franks, whose monarchy was still confined to the
 neighbourhood of the Lower Rhine, had wisely established the
 right of hereditary succession in the noble family of the
 Merovingians.(16)","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('the Lower Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Merovingians', 'NORP'), ('16', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Geougen, or Avares,
 whose residence is assigned by the Greek writers to the
 shores of the ocean, impelled the adjacent tribes; till at
 length the Igours of the North, issuing from the cold
 Siberian regions which produce the most valuable furs,
 spread themselves over the desert as far as the Borysthenes
 and the Caspian gates, and finally extinguished the empire
 of the Huns.(71)
Valentinian murders the patrician Aetius, A.D. 454.","('Geougen', 'PERSON'), ('Avares', 'PERSON'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Igours', 'PERSON'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('Siberian', 'NORP'), ('Borysthenes', 'LOC'), ('Caspian', 'LOC'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('71', 'CARDINAL'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 454', 'DATE')"
"The Gothic
 historian ingenuously confesses that Aetius was born for the
 salvation of the Roman republic; (5) and the following 
 portrait, though it is drawn in the fairest colours, must be
 allowed to contain a much larger proportion of truth than of
 flattery.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('5', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Gothic auxiliaries, who appear to
 have served under their native princes, Alaric and Antala,
 communicated their intrepid spirit; and the citizens still
 remembered the glorious and successful resistance which
 their ancestors had opposed to a fierce, inexorable
 barbarian, who disgraced the majesty of the Roman purple.","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON'), ('Antala', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Goths besieged Narbonne, while the Belgic  provinces were invaded by the Burgundians; and the public  safety was threatened on every side by the apparent union of  the enemies of Rome.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Narbonne', 'GPE'), ('Belgic', 'NORP'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The Goths, clashing their arms,
 elevated on a buckler his eldest son Torismond, to whom they
 justly ascribed the glory of their success; and the new king
 accepted the obligation of revenge as a sacred portion of
 his paternal inheritance.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Torismond', 'PERSON')"
"The Huns, who fought under the eyes of their king, pierced through the feeble and doubtful centre of the allies, separated their wings from each other, and wheeling, with a rapid effort, to the left, directed their whole force against the Visigoths.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP')"
"The Imperial general was soon satisfied of
 the defeat of Attila, who still remained inactive within his
 entrenchments; and when he contemplated the bloody scene, he
 observed, with secret satisfaction, that the loss had
 principally fallen on the barbarians.","('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The Imperial ministers, who
 always cherished the discord of the barbarians, would have
 supplied the Goths with arms, and ships, and treasures, for
 the African war; and the cruelty of Genseric might have been
 fatal to himself, if the artful Vandal had not armed, in his
 cause, the formidable power of the Huns.","('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('the African war', 'EVENT'), ('Genseric', 'EVENT'), ('Vandal', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"The Italians, who had long since renounced the exercise of
 arms, were surprised, after forty years' peace, by the
 approach of a formidable barbarian, whom they abhorred as
 the enemy of their religion as well as of their republic.","('Italians', 'NORP'), (""forty years'"", 'DATE')"
"The Pannonian conquests, from Vienna to
 Sirmium, were occupied by the Ostrogoths; and the
 settlements of the tribes who had so bravely asserted their
 native freedom were irregularly distributed according to the
 measure of their respective strength.","('Pannonian', 'NORP'), ('Vienna', 'GPE'), ('Sirmium', 'GPE'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP')"
"The Roman ambassadors were
 introduced to the tent of Attila, as he lay encamped at the
 place where the slow-winding Mincius is lost in the foaming
 waves of the lake Benacus, (62) and trampled, with his 
 Scythian cavalry, the farms of Catullus and Virgil.(63)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Mincius', 'GPE'), ('Benacus', 'LOC'), ('62', 'CARDINAL'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Catullus', 'GPE'), ('Virgil', 'PERSON'), ('63', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Roman general, after a total
 defeat, which could be imputed only to his unskilful
 rashness, was actually led through the streets of Toulouse,
 not in his own, but in an hostile triumph; and the misery
 which he experienced, in a long and ignominious captivity,
 excited the compassion of the barbarians themselves.(12) Such 
 a loss, in a country whose spirit and finances were long
 since exhausted, could not easily be repaired; and the
 Goths, assuming, in their turn, the sentiments of ambition
 and revenge, would have planted their victorious standards
 on the banks of the Rhone, if the presence of Aetius had not
 restored strength and discipline to the Romans.(13) The two 
 armies expected the signal of a decisive action; but the
 generals, who were conscious of each other's force, and
 doubtful of their own superiority, prudently sheathed their
 swords in the field of battle; and their reconciliation was
 permanent and sincere.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Toulouse', 'GPE'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Rhone', 'LOC'), ('Aetius', 'ORG'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('13', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Visigoths alone were the strength
 and nerves of the opposite army, and the Huns might securely
 trample on the degenerate Romans, whose close and compact
 order betrayed their apprehensions, and who were equally
 incapable of supporting the dangers or the fatigues of a day
 of battle.","('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('a day', 'DATE')"
"The Visigoths in Gaul under the reign of Theoderic, A.D. 419-451.","('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Theoderic', 'PERSON'), ('419-451', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Visigoths, who at that time were in the mature vigour of their fame and
 power, obeyed with alacrity the signal of war, prepared
 their arms and horses, and assembled under the standard of
 their aged king, who was resolved, with his two eldest sons,
 Torismond and Theodoric, to command in person his numerous
 and valiant people.","('Visigoths', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Torismond', 'PERSON'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON')"
"The Visigoths, who had been thrown into confusion by the flight, or defection, of the Alani, gradually restored their order of battle; and the Huns were undoubtedly vanquished, since Attila was compelled to retreat.","('Visigoths', 'PERSON'), ('Alani', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The Western emperor,
 with the senate and people of Rome, embraced the more
 salutary resolution of deprecating, by a solemn and
 suppliant embassy, the wrath of Attila.","('Western', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
The adventures of the princess Honoria.,"('Honoria', 'PERSON')"
"The ambiguous office of these
 magistrates is explained by the tradition, that, in the
 twelve principal islands, twelve tribunes, or judges, were
 created by an annual and popular election.","('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('annual', 'DATE')"
"The ambitious designs, of which he was secretly
 accused, excited the fears as well as the resentment of
 Valentinian.","('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"The anxiety of Attila prompted him to consult his priests
 and haruspices.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The apparition of the two apostles of St. Peter
 and St. Paul, who menaced the barbarian with instant death
 if he rejected the prayer of their successor, is one of the
 noblest legends of ecclesiastical tradition.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('St. Peter', 'GPE'), ('St. Paul', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The attentive
 study of the military operations of Xenophon, or Caesar, or
 Frederic, when they are described by the same genius which
 conceived and executed them, may tend to improve (if such
 improvement can be wished) the art of destroying the human
 species.","('Xenophon', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Frederic', 'PERSON')"
"The barbarians who had defended Gaul refused to march to the
 relief of Italy; and the succours promised by the Eastern
 emperor were distant and doubtful.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"The barbarians, who had seated themselves in the Western provinces, were insensibly taught to respect the faith and valour of the patrician Aetius.","('Western', 'NORP'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON')"
"The birth of the empress Eudoxia
 was equal to his own, and her charms and tender affection
 deserved those testimonies of love which her inconstant
 husband dissipated in vague and unlawful amours.","('Eudoxia', 'PERSON')"
"The body of Theodoric,
 pierced with honourable wounds, was discovered under a heap
 of the slain: his subjects bewailed the death of their king
 and father; but their tears were mingled with songs and
 acclamations, and his funeral rites were performed in the
 face of a vanquished enemy.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON')"
"The bold Ardaric felt and represented the
 disgrace of this servile partition and his subjects, the
 warlike Gepidae, with the Ostrogoths, under the conduct of
 three valiant brothers, encouraged their allies to vindicate
 the rights of freedom and royalty.","('Ardaric', 'PERSON'), ('Gepidae', 'PERSON'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"The celebrated
 name of Venice, or Venetia,(54) was formerly diffused over a 
 larger and fertile province of Italy, from the confines of
 Pannonia to the river Addua, and from the Po to the Rhaetian
 and the Julian Alps.","('Venice', 'GPE'), ('Venetia', 'GPE'), ('54', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Pannonia', 'GPE'), ('Addua', 'LOC'), ('Po', 'LOC'), ('Rhaetian', 'LOC'), ('the Julian Alps', 'LOC')"
"The character of that prince, who attempted to
 moderate the rashness of his brother Dengisich, was more
 suitable to the declining condition of the Huns; and Irnac,
 with his subject hordes, retired into the heart of the
 Lesser Scythia.","('Dengisich', 'PERSON'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Irnac', 'PERSON')"
"The consternation of Gaul was 
 universal, and the various fortunes of its cities have been
 adorned by tradition with martyrdoms and miracles.(34) Troyes 
 was saved by the merits of St. Lupus; St. Servatius was
 removed from the world that he might not behold the ruin of
 Tongres; and the prayers of St. Genevieve diverted the march
 of Attila from the neighbourhood of Paris.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Troyes', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('St. Lupus', 'LOC'), ('St. Servatius', 'GPE'), ('Tongres', 'GPE'), ('St. Genevieve', 'GPE'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Paris', 'GPE')"
"The cruel Genseric suspected that his son's wife had
 conspired to poison him; the supposed crime was punished by
 the amputation of her nose and ears; and the unhappy
 daughter of Theodoric was ignominiously returned to the
 court of Toulouse in that deformed and mutilated condition.","('Genseric', 'PERSON'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Toulouse', 'GPE')"
"The death of Attila, A.D. 453.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('453', 'CARDINAL')"
"The death of Clodion, after a reign of twenty years, exposed
 his kingdom to the discord and ambition of his two sons.","('Clodion', 'PERSON'), ('twenty years', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The discipline and tactics of the Greeks and Romans form an
 interesting part of their national manners.","('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The doctrine of predestination, so favourable to
 martial virtue, was carefully inculcated by the king of the
 Huns; who assured his subjects that the warriors, protected
 by Heaven, were safe and invulnerable amidst the darts of
 the enemy; but that the unerring Fates would strike their
 victims in the bosom of inglorious peace.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Fates', 'PERSON')"
"The emperor
 signified to the barbarians that they must no longer insult
 the majesty of Rome by the mention of a tribute; that he was
 disposed to reward, with becoming liberality, the faithful
 friendship of his allies; but that, if they presumed to
 violate the public peace, they should feel that he possessed
 troops, and arms, and resolution, to repel their attacks.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The epistle of
 Cassiodorus, the Praetorian praefect, is addressed to the
 maritime tribunes; and he exhorts them, in a mild tone of
 authority, to animate the zeal of their countrymen for the
 public service, which required their assistance to transport
 the magazines of wine and oil from the province of Istria to
 the royal city of Ravenna.","('Cassiodorus', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Istria', 'GPE'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
The event was doubtful but Attila had secured a last and honourable resource.,"('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The example of the Goths determined
 several tribes or nations that seemed to fluctuate between
 the Huns and the Romans.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The existence of
 the Venetian republic under the Gothic kingdom of Italy is
 attested by the same authentic record which annihilates
 their lofty claim of original and perpetual independence.(58)
Attila gives peace to the Romans.","('Venetian', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The facility with which Attila had penetrated into the heart
 of Gaul may be ascribed to his insidious policy as well as
 to the terror of his arms.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The fame of 
 Aetius, his wealth and dignity, the numerous and martial
 train of barbarian followers, his powerful dependents who
 filled the civil offices of the state, and the hopes of his
 son Gaudentius, who was already contracted to Eudoxia, the
 emperor's daughter, had raised him above the rank of a
 subject.","('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Gaudentius', 'PERSON'), ('Eudoxia', 'PERSON')"
"The favourable omen inspired 
 an assurance of victory; the siege was renewed, and
 prosecuted with fresh vigour; a large breach was made in the
 part of the wall from whence the stork had taken her flight;
 the Huns mounted to the assault with irresistible fury; and
 the succeeding generation could scarcely discover the ruins
 of Aquileia.(50)","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Aquileia', 'PERSON'), ('50', 'CARDINAL')"
"The fortunate Aetius, who was
 immediately promoted to the rank of patrician, and thrice
 invested with the honours of the consulship, assumed, with
 the title of master of the cavalry and infantry, the whole
 military power of the state; and he is sometimes styled, by
 contemporary writers, the duke, or general, of the Romans of
 the West.","('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"The genius of Leo(61) was exercised 
 and displayed in the public misfortunes; and he has deserved
 the appellation of Great by the successful zeal with which
 he laboured to establish his opinions and his authority,
 under the venerable names of orthodox faith and
 ecclesiastical discipline.","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('61', 'DATE')"
"The inconsiderate courage of Torismond was tempted
 to urge the pursuit, till he unexpectedly found himself,
 with a few followers, in the midst of the Scythian waggons.","('Torismond', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'NORP')"
"The indefatigable diligence of the
 patrician gradually collected the troops of Gaul and
 Germany, who had formerly acknowledged themselves the
 subjects or soldiers of the republic, but who now claimed
 the rewards of voluntary service and the rank of independent
 allies; the Laeti, the Armoricans, the Breones, the Saxons,
 the Burgundians, the Sarmatians or Alani, the Ripuarians,
 and the Franks who followed Meroveus as their lawful prince.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Laeti', 'NORP'), ('Armoricans', 'NORP'), ('Breones', 'NORP'), ('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Alani', 'PERSON'), ('Ripuarians', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Meroveus', 'PERSON')"
"The inland towns, Vicenza, Verona, and Bergamo, were
 exposed to the rapacious cruelty of the Huns.","('Vicenza', 'GPE'), ('Verona', 'GPE'), ('Bergamo', 'GPE'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"The invasion of Gaul was preceded and justified by
 a formal demand of the princess Honoria, with a just and
 equal share of the Imperial patrimony.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Honoria', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"The islanders, who, from
 Grado to Chiozza, were intimately connected with each other,
 penetrated into the heart of Italy, by the secure, though
 laborious, navigation of the rivers and inland canals.","('Grado', 'LOC'), ('Chiozza', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The king of the Goths
 exhibited in his distress the edifying contrast of Christian
 piety and moderation; nor did he lay aside his sackcloth and
 ashes till he was prepared to arm for the combat.","('The king of the Goths', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The kingdom established by the Visigoths in the southern
 provinces of Gaul had gradually acquired strength and
 maturity; and the conduct of those ambitious barbarians,
 either in peace or war, engaged the perpetual vigilance of
 Aetius.","('Visigoths', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Aetius', 'ORG')"
"The kings and nations of Germany 
 and Scythia, from the Volga perhaps to the Danube, obeyed
 the warlike summons of Attila.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'GPE'), ('Volga', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The kings and nations who might
 have deserted his standard in the hour of distress were made
 sensible that the displeasure of their monarch was the most
 imminent and inevitable danger.","('the hour', 'TIME')"
"The lively eloquence of Avitus inflamed
 the Gothic warriors by the description of the injuries which
 their ancestors had suffered from the Huns, whose implacable
 fury still pursued them from the Dawe to the foot of the
 Pyrenees.","('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Dawe', 'PRODUCT'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC')"
"The lofty 
 stature of the Franks and their blue eyes denoted a Germanic
 origin; their close apparel accurately expressed the figure
 of their limbs; a weighty sword was suspended from a broad
 belt; their bodies were protected by a large shield: and
 these warlike barbarians were trained from their earliest
 youth to run, to leap, to swim; to dart the javelin or
 battle-axe with unerring aim; to advance without hesitation
 against a superior enemy; and to maintain, either in life or
 death, the invincible reputation of their ancestors.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Germanic', 'NORP')"
"The luxury of Rome seems to have attracted the long and
 frequent visits of Valentinian, who was consequently more
 despised at Rome than in any other part of his dominions.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The minister of
 Theodoric compares them, in his quaint declamatory style, to
 waterfowl, who had fixed their nests on the bosom of the
 waves; and though he allows that the Venetian provinces had
 formerly contained many noble families, he insinuates that
 they were now reduced by misfortune to the same level of
 humble poverty.","('The minister of\r\n Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Venetian', 'NORP')"
"The name of
 Attila was familiar and formidable at Constantinople, and
 his frequent embassies entertained a perpetual intercourse
 between his camp and the Imperial palace.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"The nations from the
 Volga to the Atlantic were assembled on the plain of
 Chalons; but many of these nations had been divided by
 faction, or conquest, or emigration; and the appearance of
 similar arms and ensigns, which threatened each other,
 presented the image of a civil war.","('Volga', 'LOC'), ('Atlantic', 'LOC'), ('Chalons', 'LOC')"
"The nations subject to his
 empire, the Rugians, the Heruli, the Thuringians, the
 Franks, the Burgundians, were extended, on either hand, over
 the ample space of the Catalaunian fields; the right wing
 was commanded by Ardaric, king of the Gepidae; and the three
 valiant brothers who reigned over the Ostrogoths were posted
 on the left to oppose the kindred tribes of the Visigoths.","('Rugians', 'NORP'), ('Heruli', 'NORP'), ('Thuringians', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Catalaunian', 'NORP'), ('Ardaric', 'PERSON'), ('Gepidae', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ostrogoths', 'NORP'), ('Visigoths', 'NORP')"
"The nations who were strangers or enemies to Aetius
 generously deplored the unworthy fate of a hero; the
 barbarians who had been attached to his service dissembled
 their grief and resentment; and the public contempt which
 had been so long entertained for Valentinian was at once
 converted into deep and universal abhorrence.","('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'PERSON')"
"The number of the slain amounted to one hundred and sixty-two thousand, or, according to another account, three hundred thousand persons; (44) and these incredible exaggerations suppose a real and effective loss, sufficient to justify the historian's remark that whole generations may be swept away by the madness of kings in the space of a single hour.","('one hundred and sixty-two thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('three hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('a single hour', 'TIME')"
"The palace of Attila, with the old country of
 Daciab from the Carpathian hills to the Euxine, became the
 seat of a new power which was erected by Ardaric, king of
 the Gepidae.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Daciab', 'GPE'), ('the Carpathian hills', 'LOC'), ('Euxine', 'LOC'), ('Ardaric', 'PERSON'), ('Gepidae', 'PERSON')"
"The patrician exerted the
 superior ascendant of authority and reason to calm the
 passions which the son of Theodoric considered as a duty;
 represented, with seeming affection and real truth, the
 dangers of absence and delay; and persuaded Torismond to
 disappoint, by his speedy return, the ambitious designs of
 his brothers, who might occupy the throne and treasures of
 Toulouse.(46)","('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Torismond', 'PERSON'), ('Toulouse', 'GPE'), ('46', 'CARDINAL')"
"The popular
 traditions of Comum, Turin, or Modena may justly be
 respected; yet they concur with more authentic evidence to
 prove that Attila spread his ravages over the rich plains of
 modern Lombardy, which are divided by the Po, and bounded by
 the Alps and Apennine. (51)","('Comum', 'LOC'), ('Turin', 'GPE'), ('Modena', 'GPE'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Lombardy', 'GPE'), ('Po', 'NORP'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Apennine', 'PERSON'), ('51', 'CARDINAL')"
"The predictions of the augurs had inspired
 Litorius with the profane confidence that he should enter
 the Gothic capital in triumph; and the trust which he
 reposed in his Pagan allies encouraged him to reject the
 fair conditions of peace which were repeatedly proposed by
 the bishops in the name of Theodoric.","('Litorius', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('Theodoric', 'ORG')"
"The pressing eloquence 
 of Leo, his majestic aspect and sacerdotal robes, excited
 the veneration of Attila for the spiritual father of the
 Christians.","('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"The princess of the Vandals was
 the victim of a jealous tyrant, whom she called her father.","('Vandals', 'PERSON')"
"The queen of
 the Suevi bewailed the death of an husband, inhumanly
 massacred by her brother.","('Suevi', 'PERSON')"
"The remains of Attila were enclosed
 within three coffins of gold, of silver, and of iron, and
 privately buried in the night: the spoils of nations were
 thrown into his grave; the captives who had opened the
 ground were inhumanly massacred; and the same Huns, who had
 indulged such excessive grief, feasted, with dissolute and
 intemperate mirth, about the recent sepulchre of their king.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Huns', 'NORP')"
"The remote object, on which every eye was fixed, became each moment larger and more distinct; the Roman and Gothic banners were gradually perceived; and a favourable wind, blowing aside the dust, discovered.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Gothic', 'NORP')"
"The revenge which Attila inflicted on this monument of
 Roman vanity was harmless and ingenious.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The revolution which subverted the empire of the Huns
 established the fame of Attila, whose genius alone had
 sustained the huge and disjointed fabric.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The right of female succession, though it
 might derive a specious argument from the recent examples of
 Placidia and Pulcheria, was strenuously denied, and the
 indissoluble engagements of Honoria were opposed to the
 claims of her Scythian lover. (29)","('Placidia', 'ORG'), ('Pulcheria', 'PERSON'), ('Honoria', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('29', 'CARDINAL')"
"The saddles and rich furniture of the cavalry were collected by his order into a funeral pile; and the magnanimous barbarian had resolved, if his entrenchments should be forced, to rush headlong into the flames, and deprive his enemies of the glory which they might have acquired by the death or captivity of Attila. (45)
Retreat of Attila.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('45', 'CARDINAL'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The safety of
 Rome might deserve the interposition of celestial beings;
 and some indulgence is due to a fable which has been
 represented by the pencil of Raphael and the chisel of
 Algardi.(66)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Raphael', 'PERSON'), ('Algardi', 'PERSON'), ('66', 'CARDINAL')"
"The same fortune which opened the deserts and
 morasses of Scythia to their unarmed valour, which had laid
 so many warlike nations prostrate at their feet, had
 reserved the joys of this memorable field for the
 consummation of their victories.","('Scythia', 'ORG')"
"The same language, even in the camp of the Huns, was used by
 his ambassador Apollonius, whose bold refusal to deliver the
 presents, till he had been admitted to a personal interview,
 displayed a sense of dignity, and a contempt of danger,
 which Attila was not prepared to expect from the degenerate
 Romans.(1)","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Apollonius', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('1', 'CARDINAL')"
"The senator Avitus, who after the honourable
 exercise of the Praetorian praefecture had retired to his
 estate in Auvergne, was persuaded to accept the important
 embassy, which he executed with ability and success.","('Avitus', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Auvergne', 'GPE')"
"The severe inquisition, which confiscated their goods and tortured their persons, compelled the subjects of Valentinian to prefer the more simple tyranny of the barbarians, to fly to the woods and mountains, or to embrace the vile and abject condition of mercenary servants.","('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"The shepherds of
 the North, whose ordinary food consisted of milk and raw
 flesh, indulged themselves too freely in the use of bread,
 of wine, and of meat prepared and seasoned by the arts of
 cookery; and the progress of disease revenged in some
 measure the injuries of the Italians. (64)","('North', 'LOC'), ('Italians', 'NORP')"
"The siege was
 immediately raised; and the more decisive victory, which is
 ascribed to the personal conduct of Aetius himself, was
 marked with the blood of eight thousand Goths.","('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('eight thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The sister of Valentinian was educated in
 the palace of Ravenna; and as her marriage might be
 productive of some danger to the state, she was raised, by
 the title of Augusta, (28) above the hopes of the most 
 presumptuous subject.","('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Augusta', 'GPE'), ('28', 'DATE')"
"The skill of the Roman artists might be
 corrupted to the destruction of their country.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The specious and artful character of
 Avienus(60) was admirably qualified to conduct a negotiation 
 either of public or private interest: his colleague
 Trigetius had exercised the Praetorian praefecture of Italy;
 and Leo, bishop of Rome, consented to expose his life for
 the safety of his flock.","('Avienus', 'PERSON'), ('60', 'DATE'), ('Trigetius', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Leo', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The spectators 
 must have confessed the truth and propriety of the
 alteration; and were perhaps tempted to apply, on this
 singular occasion, the well-known fable of the dispute
 between the lion and the man.(53)
Foundation of the republic of Venice.","('53', 'CARDINAL'), ('Venice', 'GPE')"
"The spirit of the barbarians was rekindled by the presence, the voice and the example of their intrepid leader and Attila, yielding to
 their impatience, immediately formed his order of battle.","('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"The stately
 demeanour of an hereditary monarch offended their pride, and
 the pleasures of Valentinian were injurious to the peace and
 honour of noble families.","('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"The tables, which had been
 spread under the shelter of a hill along the banks of a
 pleasant stream, were rudely overturned; the Franks were
 oppressed before they could recover their arms or their
 ranks, and their unavailing valour was fatal only to
 themselves.","('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"The two 
 daughters of the Gothic king were given in marriage to the
 eldest sons of the kings of the Suevi and of the Vandals,
 who reigned in Spain and Africa; but these illustrious
 alliances were pregnant with guilt and discord.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Suevi', 'PERSON'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"The unhappy princess passed twelve or
 fourteen years in the irksome society of the sisters of
 Theodosius and their chosen virgins, to whose crown
 Honoria could no longer aspire, and whose monastic assiduity
 of prayer, fasting, and vigils she reluctantly imitated.","('twelve or\r\n fourteen years', 'DATE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Honoria', 'NORP')"
"The unsuspecting wife of Maximus was
 conveyed in her litter to the Imperial palace; the
 emissaries of her impatient lover conducted her to a remote
 and silent bedchamber; and Valentinian violated, without
 remorse, the laws of hospitality.","('Maximus', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"The valour of Attila was always guided by his 
 prudence; and as he foresaw the fatal consequences of a
 defeat in the heart of Gaul, he repassed the Seine, and
 expected the enemy in the plains of Chalons, whose smooth
 and level surface was adapted to the operations of his
 Scythian cavalry.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Seine', 'LOC'), ('Chalons', 'GPE'), ('Scythian', 'NORP')"
"The walls of
 Aquileia were assaulted by a formidable train of battering
 rams, movable turrets, and engines that threw stones, darts,
 and fire;(48) and the monarch of the Huns employed the 
 forcible impulse of hope, fear, emulation and interest, to
 subvert the only barrier which delayed the conquest of
 Italy.","('Aquileia', 'PRODUCT'), ('48', 'CARDINAL'), ('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Their
 flaxen locks, which they combed and dressed with singular
 care, hung down in flowing ringlets on their back and
 shoulders; while the rest of the nation were obliged, either
 by law or custom, to shave the hinder part of their head, to
 comb their hair over the forehead, and to content themselves
 with the ornament of two small whiskers.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Their
 vessels, which were continually increasing in size and
 number, visited all the harbours of the Gulf; and the
 marriage which Venice annually celebrates with the Hadriatic
 was contracted in her early infancy.","('Gulf', 'LOC'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('Hadriatic', 'PERSON')"
"Their marriage was celebrated with 
 barbaric pomp and festivity, at his wooden palace beyond the
 Danube; and the monarch, oppressed with wine and sleep,
 retired at a late hour from the banquet to the nuptial bed.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('a late hour', 'TIME')"
"Theodoric yielded to the evidence of
 truth, adopted the measure at once the most prudent and the
 most honourable, and declared that as the faithful ally of
 Aetius and the Romans he was ready to expose his life and
 kingdom for the common safety of Gaul.(37)","('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('37', 'CARDINAL')"
"Theodoric; king of the Visigoths,
 appears to have deserved the love of his subjects, the
 confidence of his allies, and the esteem of mankind.","('Visigoths', 'NORP')"
"These indecent advances were received, however,
 with coldness and disdain; and the king of the Huns
 continued to multiply the number of his wives till his love
 was awakened by the more forcible passions of ambition and
 avarice.","('Huns', 'NORP')"
"These princes were elevated on a buckler, 
 the symbol of military command;(17) and the royal fashion of 
 long hair was the ensign of their birth and dignity.","('17', 'CARDINAL')"
"These savage allies were not indeed less
 formidable to the subjects than to the enemies of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"They
 massacred their hostages, as well as their captives: two
 hundred young maidens were tortured with exquisite and
 unrelenting rage; their bodies were torn asunder by wild
 horses, or their bones were crushed under the weight of
 rolling waggons; and their unburied limbs were abandoned on
 the public roads as a prey to dogs and vultures.","('two\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"They abjured and abhorred the name of Roman citizens, which had formerly excited the ambition of mankind.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"They involved in a promiscuous
 massacre the priests who served at the altar and the infants
 who, in the hour of danger, had been providently baptised by
 the bishop; the flourishing city was delivered to the
 flames, and a solitary chapel of St. Stephen marked the
 place where it formerly stood.","('St. Stephen', 'FAC')"
"This advantage, which
 had been obtained by the skill and activity of Aetius, might
 reflect some disgrace on the military prudence of Clodion;
 but the king of the Franks soon regained his strength and
 reputation, and still maintained the possession of his
 Gallic kingdom from the Rhine to the Somme.(24)","('Aetius', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Clodion', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Somme', 'LOC'), ('24', 'CARDINAL')"
"This horrid act, which must seem incredible to a civilised
 age, drew tears from every spectator; but Theodoric was
 urged, by the feelings of a parent and a king, to revenge
 such irreparable injuries.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON')"
"This important
 commission was accepted by Avienus, who, from his birth and
 riches, his consular dignity, the numerous train of his
 clients, and his personal abilities, held the first rank in
 the Roman senate.","('Avienus', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"This prophecy, disregarded perhaps in the season of health and prosperity, inspired the people with gloomy apprehensions when the twelfth century, clouded with disgrace and misfortune, was almost elapsed;(76) and even posterity must acknowledge with some surprise that the arbitrary interpretation of an accidental or fabulous circumstance has been seriously verified in the downfall of the Western empire.","('the twelfth century', 'DATE'), ('76', 'DATE'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"This spacious plain was 
 distinguished, however, by some inequalities of ground; and
 the importance of an height which commanded the camp of
 Attila was understood and disputed by the two generals.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"This temperate courage
 dictated his reply to the demands of Attila, who insolently
 pressed the payment of the annual tribute.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('annual', 'DATE')"
"Three months were consumed without effect in the siege of
 Aquileia; till the want of provisions and the clamours of
 his army compelled Attila to relinquish the enterprise, and
 reluctantly to issue his orders that the troops should
 strike their tents the next morning, and begin their
 retreat.","('Three months', 'DATE'), ('Aquileia', 'GPE'), ('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('the next morning', 'TIME')"
"Till the middle of the fifth century 
 these remote and sequestered spots remained without
 cultivation, with few inhabitants, and almost without a
 name.","('the middle of the fifth century', 'DATE')"
"Twenty thousand Burgundians were slain in battle, and the remains of the nation humbly accepted a ependent seat in the mountains of Savoy.(11) The walls of Narbonne had been shaken by the battering engines, and the inhabitants had endured the last extremities of famine, when Count Litorius, approaching in silence, and directing each
 horseman to carry behind him two sacks of flour, cut his way
 through the entrenchments of the besiegers.","('Twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Savoy', 'GPE'), ('11', 'CARDINAL'), ('Narbonne', 'GPE'), ('Litorius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Two colonies of these barbarians were judiciously fixed in
 the territories of Valence and Orleans;(8) and their active 
 cavalry secured the important passages of the Rhine and of
 the Loire.","('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Valence', 'LOC'), ('Orleans', 'GPE'), ('8', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Loire', 'LOC')"
"Two of these, of barbarian race, were
 persuaded to execute a sacred and honourable duty by
 punishing with death the assassin of their patron, and their intrepid courage did not long expect a favourable moment.","('Two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Under his 
 reign, and most probably from the enterprising spirit of his
 subjects, the three Capitals, Mentzs Treves, and Cologne,
 experienced the effects of hostile cruelty and avarice.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Capitals', 'ORG'), ('Mentzs Treves', 'ORG'), ('Cologne', 'GPE')"
"Valentinian was less excusable, since he had passions without virtues: even his religion was questionable; and though he never deviated into the paths of heresy, he scandalised the pious Christians by his attachment to the profane arts of magic and divination.","('Valentinian', 'PERSON'), ('Christians', 'NORP')"
"Valentinian, who supposed that every human breast was
 devoid like his own of friendship and gratitude, had
 imprudently admitted among his guards several domestics and
 followers of Aetius.","('Valentinian', 'PERSON'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON')"
"When Attila 
 declared his resolution of carrying his victorious arms to
 the gates of Rome, he was admonished by his friends, as well
 as by his enemies, that Alaric had not long survived the
 conquest of the eternal city.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Alaric', 'PERSON')"
"When Attila declared his resolution of supporting the cause
 of his allies the Vandals and the Franks, at the same time,
 and almost in the spirit of romantic chivalry, the savage
 monarch professed himself the lover and the champion of the
 princess Honoria.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Vandals', 'NORP'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Honoria', 'PERSON')"
"When he claimed the spoils of
 a vanquished city, some vases of gold, which had been
 fraudulently embezzled, the civil and military governors of
 Noricum were immediately despatched to satisfy his
 complaints:(7) and it is evident, from their conversation 
 with Maximin and Priscus in the royal village, that the
 valour and prudence of Aetius had not saved the Western
 Romans from the common ignominy of tribute.","('Noricum', 'GPE'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Priscus', 'PERSON'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('the Western\r\n Romans', 'NORP')"
"When he took possession of the 
 royal palace of Milan, he was surprised and offended at the
 sight of a picture which represented the Caesars seated on
 their throne, and the princes of Scythia prostrate at their
 feet.","('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Caesars', 'PERSON'), ('Scythia', 'PERSON')"
"While Clodion lay encamped in 
 the plains of Artois, (23) and celebrated with vain and 
 ostentatious security the marriage perhaps of his son, the
 nuptial feast was interrupted by the unexpected and
 unwelcome presence of Aetius, who had passed the Somme at
 the head of his light cavalry.","('Clodion', 'PERSON'), ('Artois', 'GPE'), ('23', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Somme', 'LOC')"
"While he
 resided in their tents as an hostage or an exile, he had
 familiarly conversed with Attila himself, the nephew of his
 benefactor; and the two famous antagonists appear to have
 been connected by a personal and military friendship, which
 they afterwards confirmed by mutual gifts, frequent
 embassies, and the education of Carpilio, the son of Aetius,
 in the camp of Attila.","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Carpilio', 'PERSON'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"While mankind awaited his decision with awful suspense, he sent an equal defiance to the courts of Ravenna and Constantinople; and his ministers saluted the two emperors with the same haughty declaration.","('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Whilst Valentinian amused himself in the field of Mars with the spectacle of some military sports, they suddenly rushed upon him with drawn weapons, despatched the guilty Heraclius, and stabbed the emperor to the heart, without the least opposition from his numerous train, who seemed to rejoice in the tyrant's death.","('Valentinian', 'PERSON'), ('Mars', 'LOC'), ('Heraclius', 'PERSON')"
"Whilst he urged, perhaps with
 intemperate vehemence, the marriage of his son, Valentinian,
 drawing his sword - the first sword he had ever drawn -
 plunged it in the breast of a general who had saved his
 empire: his courtiers and eunuchs ambitiously struggled to
 imitate their master; and Aetius, pierced with an hundred
 wounds, fell dead in the royal presence.","('Valentinian', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"Yet Theodoric still watched, and eagerly
 seized, the favourable moment of renewing his hostile
 attempts.","('Theodoric', 'PERSON')"
"Yet his
 dexterous policy prolonged the advantages of a salutary
 peace; and a numerous army of Huns and Alani, whom he had
 attached to his person, was employed in the defence of Gaul.","('Huns', 'NORP'), ('Alani', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"Yet the Goths themselves were
 astonished by the fierce and undaunted aspect of their
 formidable antagonist; and their historian has compared
 Attila to a lion encompassed in his den and threatening his
 hunters with redoubled fury.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Attila', 'PERSON')"
"Yet the savage destroyer undesignedly laid the foundations
 of a republic which revived, in the feudal state of Europe,
 the art and spirit of a commercial industry.","('Europe', 'LOC')"
"Yet, in the
 meanwhile, Attila relieved his tender anxiety, by adding a
 beautiful maid, whose name was Ildico, to the list of his
 innumerable wives.(67)","('Attila', 'PERSON'), ('Ildico', 'PERSON')"
"in deep array, the impatient squadrons of Aetius and Theodoric, who pressed forwards to the relief of Orleans.","('Aetius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodoric', 'PERSON'), ('Orleans', 'GPE')"
