Sentence,Entities
"""Let him be beaten with clubs till he expires;"" (57) and his most favoured ministers soon understood that, by a rash attempt to dispute or suspend the execution of his sanguinary commands; they might involve themselves in the guilt and punishment of disobedience.","('57', 'DATE')"
(131),"('131', 'CARDINAL')"
(3),"('3', 'CARDINAL')"
(31),"('31', 'CARDINAL')"
"(5) As soon as he had gained the confidence and 
 secured the faith of the Christian emperor, he returned in
 triumph to his diocese, and continued, with mature counsels
 and undiminished vigour, to direct, ten years longer,(6) the 
 ecclesiastical government of Alexandria, Egypt, and the
 Catholic church.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('ten years longer', 'DATE'), ('6', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"1. The silence of 
 Valentinian may suggest a probable argument that the partial
 severities which were exercised in the name and provinces of
 his colleague amounted only to some obscure and
 inconsiderable deviations from the established system of
 religious toleration; and the judicious historian, who has
 praised the equal temper of the elder brother, has not
 thought himself obliged to contrast the tranquillity of the
 West with the cruel persecution of the East.(70)","('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('70', 'CARDINAL')"
"2. Whatever 
 credit may be allowed to vague and distant reports, the
 character, or at least the behaviour, of Valens may be most
 distinctly seen in his personal transactions with the
 eloquent Basil, archbishop of Gaesarea, who had succeeded
 Athanasius in the management of the Trinitarian cause.(71)","('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Basil', 'PERSON'), ('Gaesarea', 'PERSON'), ('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Trinitarian', 'NORP'), ('71', 'CARDINAL')"
"A
 dark conspiracy was detected by the penetration of
 Theodosius, and he satisfied, without much reluctance, the
 public indignation which he had secretly excited.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"A
 separate view of the five great theatres of war—","('five', 'CARDINAL')"
"A bloody sentence was pronounced, without hesitation, by the
 rash and headstrong cruelty of Valentinian.","('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"A bridge of boats was established upon
 the Danube, the presence of Valens animated his troops, and
 his ignorance of the art of war was compensated by personal
 bravery, and a wise deference to the advice of Victor and
 Arintheus, his masters-general of the cavalry and infantry.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Victor', 'PERSON'), ('Arintheus', 'PERSON')"
"A chain of posts and fortifications,
 skilfully disposed by Valens, or the generals of Valens,
 resisted their march, prevented their retreat, and
 intercepted their subsistence.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"A dark and
 almost impervious path securely conveyed the Armenian troops
 through the thicket; and Para had left behind him the count
 and the tribune, while they patiently expected his approach
 along the public highways.","('Armenian', 'NORP'), ('Para', 'PERSON')"
"A detachment
 of cavalry and infantry, consisting of three thousand men, marched from Alexandria into the adjacent desert of Nitria, (75) which was peopled by five thousand monks.","('three thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Nitria', 'GPE'), ('75', 'CARDINAL'), ('five thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"A legion was
 ordered to pursue the royal fugitive; but the pursuit of
 infantry could not be very alarming to a body of light
 cavalry; and upon the first cloud of arrows that was
 discharged into the air, they retreated with precipitation
 to the gates of Tarsus.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Tarsus', 'GPE')"
"A military
 confederation was gradually moulded into a national body by
 the gentle operation of marriage and consanguinity; and the
 adjacent tribes, who solicited the alliance, accepted the
 name and laws of the Saxons.","('Saxons', 'NORP')"
"A numerous and active party acknowledged
 Para, the son of Tiranus, as the lawful sovereign of
 Armenia, and his title to the throne was deeply rooted in
 the hereditary succession of five hundred years.","('Para', 'PERSON'), ('Tiranus', 'PERSON'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('five hundred years', 'DATE')"
"A powerful army, under
 the command of Count Trajan, and of Vadomair king of the
 Alemanni, fixed their camp on the confines of Armenia.","('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Vadomair', 'PERSON'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"A robust and desperate barbarian instantly rushed on the
 king of Armenia, and though he bravely defended his life
 with the first weapon that chance offered to  A.D. 374.his hand, the
 table of the Imperial general was stained with the royal
 blood of a guest and an ally.","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('A.D. 374.his', 'DATE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"A.D. 363, October","('A.D. 363', 'DATE'), ('October', 'DATE')"
A.D. 364-375.,"('364-375', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 364.,"('A.D. 364', 'DATE')"
A.D. 365.,"('A.D. 365', 'DATE')"
A.D. 366-384.,"('A.D. 366-384', 'DATE')"
A.D. 366.,"('A.D. 366', 'DATE')"
A.D. 367-378.,"('A.D. 367-378', 'DATE')"
A.D. 370.,"('370', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 371,"('A.D. 371', 'DATE')"
A.D. 372,"('A.D. 372', 'DATE')"
"A.D. 373 that the great Theodosius, with a small band of
 veterans, had landed near Igilgilis, or Gigeri, on the
 African coast, and the timid usurper sunk under the
 ascendant of virtue and military genius.","('A.D. 373', 'DATE'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('Igilgilis', 'GPE'), ('Gigeri', 'GPE'), ('African', 'NORP')"
A.D. 380,"('A.D. 380', 'DATE')"
"About
 the same time the restorer of Britain and Africa, on a vague
 suspicion that his name and services were superior to the
 rank of a subject, was ignominiously beheaded at Carthage.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"About the
 middle of the fourth century, the countries, perhaps of
 Lusace and Thuringia, on either side of the Elbe, were
 occupied by the vague dominion of the BURGUNDIANS, a warlike
 and numerous people of the Vandal race,(96) whose obscure 
 name insensibly swelled into a powerful kingdom, and has
 finally settled on a flourishing province.","('About the\r\n middle of the fourth century', 'DATE'), ('Lusace', 'GPE'), ('Thuringia', 'GPE'), ('Elbe', 'LOC'), ('BURGUNDIANS', 'NORP'), ('Vandal', 'NORP'), ('96', 'CARDINAL')"
"According
 to others, he was suffocated in his sleep by the vapour of
 charcoal, which extracted from the walls of the apartment
 the unwholesome moisture of the fresh plaster.(16) But the 
 want of a regular inquiry into the death of a prince whose
 reign and person were soon forgotten appears to have been
 the only circumstance which countenanced the malicious
 whispers of poison and domestic guilt.(17)","('17', 'CARDINAL')"
Africa IV.,"('Africa', 'LOC')"
"After
 his return to his native kingdom, Para still continued to
 profess himself the friend and ally of the Romans: but the
 Romans had injured him too deeply ever to forgive, and the
 secret sentence of his death was signed in the council of
 Valens.","('Para', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"After an honourable defence the city and
 island of Cyzicus yielded to his power, the renowned legions
 of the Jovians and Herculians embraced the cause of the
 usurper whom they were ordered to crush, and, as the
 veterans were continually augmented with new levies, he soon
 appeared at the head of an army whose valour, as well as
 numbers, were not unequal to the greatness of the contest.","('Cyzicus', 'GPE'), ('Jovians', 'NORP'), ('Herculians', 'NORP')"
"After an incessant march of two days
 and two nights, Para and his Armenians reached the banks of
 the Euphrates; but the passage of the river, which they were
 obliged to swim, was attended with some delay and some loss.","('two days', 'DATE'), ('two nights', 'DATE'), ('Para', 'PERSON'), ('Armenians', 'NORP'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC')"
"After indulging himself with a plentiful, perhaps an
 intemperate supper, he retired to rest, and the next morning
 the emperor Jovian was found dead in his bed.","('the next morning', 'TIME'), ('Jovian', 'PERSON')"
"After the death of Jovian the throne of the Roman world
 remained ten days (19) without a master.","('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('ten days', 'DATE'), ('19', 'DATE')"
"After the ratification of the treaty, and the delivery of
 hostages, Valens returned in triumph to Constantinople, and
 the Goths remained in a state of tranquillity about six
 years, till they were violently impelled against the Roman
 empire by an innumerable host of Scythians, who appeared to
 issue from the frozen regions of the North.(149)","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('about six\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Scythians', 'NORP'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('149', 'CARDINAL')"
"After the submission of the Venedi,
 the conqueror advanced, without resistance, as far as the
 confines of the Aestii,(142) an ancient people, whose name is 
 still preserved in the province of Esthonia.","('Venedi', 'NORP'), ('Aestii', 'NORP'), ('142', 'CARDINAL'), ('Esthonia', 'GPE')"
"After they had 
 acquired an accurate knowledge of the maritime provinces of
 the West they extended the scene of their depredations, and
 the most sequestered places had no reason to presume on
 their security.","('West', 'LOC')"
"After this signal victory Valentinian returned to his winter
 quarters at Treves, where he indulged the public joy by the
 exhibition of splendid and triumphal games.(93)","('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Treves', 'ORG'), ('93', 'CARDINAL')"
"After wandering some time among the woods and mountains of
 Phrygia, he was betrayed by his desponding followers,
 conducted to the Imperial camp, and immediately beheaded.","('Phrygia', 'GPE'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"All ranks of subjects who had
 been injured or oppressed under the reign of Julian were
 invited to support their public accusations.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"Amidst the boundless plains of Gaetulia and the innumerable
 valleys of Mount Atlas, it was impossible to prevent the
 escape of Firmus; and if the usurper could have tired the
 patience of his antagonist, he would have secured his person
 in the depth of some remote solitude, and expected the hopes
 of a future revolution.","('Gaetulia', 'LOC'), ('Mount Atlas', 'LOC'), ('Firmus', 'ORG')"
"Among the
 princes of the Alemanni, Macrianus, who, with a Roman name,
 had assumed the arts of a soldier and a statesman, deserved
 his hatred and esteem.","('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Macrianus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"An anxious regard 
 to his personal safety was the ruling principle of the
 administration of Valens.","('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"An army of 
 four-score thousand Burgundians soon appeared on the banks
 of the Rhine, and impatiently required the support and
 subsidies which Valentinian had promised; but they were
 amused with excuses and delays, till at length, after a
 fruitless expectation, they were compelled to retire.","('four-score thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Valentinian', 'ORG')"
"Another division, or
 rather army, of the enemy, after the cruel and wanton
 devastation of the adjacent country, reposed themselves on
 the shady banks of the Moselle.","('Moselle', 'GPE')"
"Arintheus, who in strength, beauty, and
 valour excelled all the heroes of the age, attacked with a
 small troop a superior body of the rebels.","('Arintheus', 'PERSON')"
"As
 soon as the Christians of the West had extricated themselves
 from the snares of the creed of Rimini, they happily
 relapsed into the slumber of orthodoxy; and the small
 remains of the Arian party, that still subsisted at Sirmium
 or Milan, might be considered rather as objects of contempt
 than of resentment.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Rimini', 'GPE'), ('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Sirmium', 'ORG'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"As
 soon as the zeal of informers was encouraged by the
 ministers of Valens and Valentinian, they could not refuse
 to listen to another charge too frequently mingled in the
 scenes of domestic guilt, a charge of a softer and less
 malignant nature, for which the pious though excessive
 rigour of Constantine had recently decreed the punishment of
 death.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"As he had resolved to complete the destruction of the
 Quadi by a second campaign, he fixed his winter-quarters at
 Bregetio, on the Danube, near the Hungarian city of
 Presburg.","('Quadi', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('winter-quarters', 'DATE'), ('Bregetio', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Hungarian', 'NORP'), ('Presburg', 'GPE')"
"As long as he wrestled with his equals in the bold competition of an active and ambitious life, Valentinian was seldom injured, and never insulted, with impunity: if his prudence was arraigned, his
 spirit was applauded; and the proudest and most powerful generals were apprehensive of provoking the resentment of a fearless soldier.","('Valentinian', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as Igmazen was satisfied that his enemy had strength and resolution to execute the fatal menace, he consented to purchase a necessary peace by the sacrifice of a guilty fugitive.","('Igmazen', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as he
 ascended the throne he transmitted a circular epistle to all
 the governors of provinces, in which he confessed the divine
 truth and secured the legal establishment of the Christian
 religion.","('Christian', 'NORP')"
"As soon as he was informed that the village
 where she stopped only to dine was almost encompassed by the
 barbarians, he hastily placed her in his own chariot, and
 drove full speed till he reached the gates of Sirmium, which
 were at the distance of six-and-twenty miles.","('Sirmium', 'PRODUCT'), ('six-and-twenty miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"As soon as the death of Julian had
 relieved the barbarians from the terror of his name, the
 most sanguine hopes of rapine and conquest excited the
 nations of the East, of the North, and of the South.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('South', 'LOC')"
"As the guardian of domestic
 happiness and virtue, Valentinian applied this severe remedy
 to the growing evil.","('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"As they were incapable of
 furnishing the four thousand camels and the exorbitant
 present which he required before he would march to the
 assistance of Tripoli, his demand was equivalent to a
 refusal, and he might justly be accused as the author of the
 public calamity.","('four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tripoli', 'GPE')"
Associates his brother Valens.,"('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"At
 this tremendous sentence the troops fell prostrate on the
 ground, deprecated the indignation of their sovereign, and
 protested that if he would indulge them in another trial,
 they would approve themselves not unworthy of the name of
 Romans, and of his soldiers.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"At 
 length, when the hour was supposed to be propitious,
 Valentinian showed himself from a lofty tribunal; the
 judicious choice was applauded, and the new prince was
 solemnly invested with the diadem and the purple, amidst the
 acclamations of the troops, who were disposed in martial
 order round the tribunal.","('the hour', 'TIME'), ('Valentinian', 'PERSON')"
"At first he lurked in the villages of
 Bithynia, continually changing his habitation and his
 disguise. (36)","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Bithynia', 'GPE')"
"At first he pitied their
 blindness; by degrees he was provoked at their obstinacy;
 and he insensibly hated those sectaries to whom he was an
 object of hatred. (67)","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"At length, when the repetition of complaint
 had been justified by the repetition of public misfortunes,
 the notary Palladius was sent from the court of Treves to
 examine the state of Africa and the conduct of Romanus.","('Palladius', 'PERSON'), ('Treves', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Romanus', 'PERSON')"
"At the
 signal of the general assault, the Roman troops encompassed
 and ascended the mountain of Solicinium on three different
 sides.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Solicinium', 'LOC'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the dawn of day they were drawn up near the
 baths of Anastasia, and Procopius, clothed in a purple
 garment more suitable to a player than to a monarch,
 appeared, as if he rose from the dead, in the midst of
 Constantinople.","('Anastasia', 'LOC'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"At the death of his father the royal youth was in
 the seventeenth year of his age, and his virtues already
 justified the favourable opinion of the army and people.","('the seventeenth year', 'DATE')"
"At the head of a
 well-disciplined army of cavalry, infantry, and light
 troops, Jovinus advanced, with cautious and rapid steps, to
 Scarponna,(90) in the territory of Metz, where he surprised a 
 large division of the Alemanni before they had time to run
 to their arms; and flushed his soldiers with the confidence
 of an easy and bloodless victory.","('Jovinus', 'NORP'), ('Scarponna', 'PERSON'), ('90', 'CARDINAL'), ('Metz', 'GPE'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON')"
"At the head of a small
 body of troops, which seldom exceeded three thousand five
 hundred men, the Roman general advanced with a steady
 prudence, devoid of rashness or of fear, into the heart of a
 country where he was sometimes attacked by armies of twenty
 thousand Moors.","('three thousand five\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('twenty\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moors', 'NORP')"
"Athanaric was provoked, or compelled, to risk a battle,
 which he lost, in the plains; and the pursuit was rendered
 more bloody by the cruel precaution of the victorious
 generals, who had promised a large reward for the head of
 every Goth that was brought into the Imperial camp.","('Athanaric', 'PERSON'), ('Goth', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"Athanaric, who, on this
 occasion, appears to have consulted his private interest,
 without expecting the orders of his sovereign, supported his
 own dignity, and that of his tribe, in the personal
 interview which was proposed by the ministers of Valens.","('Athanaric', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"Athanasius had reason to
 hope that he should be allowed either the merit of a
 successful prediction, or the excuse of a grateful though
 ineffectual prayer.(7)
Jovian proclaims universal toleration.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Jovian', 'PERSON')"
"Athanasius still reigned at Alexandria; the thrones
 of Constantinople and Antioch were occupied by Arian
 prelates; and every episcopal vacancy was the occasion of a
 popular tumult.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Arian', 'NORP')"
"Before
 Valentinian could pass the Alps, the villages of Gaul were
 in flames; before his general Dagalaiphus could encounter
 the Alemanni, they had secured the captives and the spoil in
 the forests of Germany.","('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Dagalaiphus', 'GPE'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"Before Valentinian divided the provinces, he reformed the
 administration of the empire.","('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"Before he could procure any certain
 intelligence that the emperor of the West had fixed the
 choice of a general, or that a fleet of transports was
 collected at the mouth of the Rhone, he was suddenly
 informed Theodosius recovers Africa.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Rhone', 'LOC'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"Before he had
 attained the ninth year of his age the royal youth received
 from the hands of his indulgent father the purple robe and
 diadem, with the title of Augustus; the election was
 solemnly ratified by the consent and applause of the armies
 of Gaul,(156) and the name of Gratian was added to the names 
 of Valentinian and Valens in all the legal transactions of
 the Roman government.","('the ninth year', 'DATE'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('156', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Before his departure from Antioch, he
 assured Jovian that his orthodox devotion would be rewarded
 with a long and peaceful reign.","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Jovian', 'PERSON')"
"Beyond the utmost limits of the Moors, the vast and
 inhospitable desert of the South extends above a thousand
 miles to the banks of the Niger.","('Moors', 'LOC'), ('South', 'LOC'), ('a thousand\r\n miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Niger', 'LOC')"
Britain; III.,"('Britain', 'GPE')"
"But
 Gratian resided, without apprehension, in the palace of
 Treves, whilst at the distance of many hundred miles
 Valentinian suddenly expired in the camp of Bregetio.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Treves', 'GPE'), ('many hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Bregetio', 'GPE')"
"But
 they were strictly enjoined not to commit the first
 hostilities, which might be understood as a breach of the
 treaty; and such was the implicit obedience of the Roman
 general, that they retreated, with exemplary patience, under
 a shower of Persian arrows, till they had clearly acquired a
 just title to an honourable and legitimate victory.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"But as
 our attention is no longer engaged by the contrast of
 freedom and servitude, of recent greatness and of actual
 misery, we should turn with horror from the frequent
 executions which disgraced, both at Rome and Antioch, the
 reign of the two brothers.(53) Valens was of a timid,(54) and 
 Valentinian of a choleric, disposition.(55)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('53', 'CARDINAL'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"But as he left, either by his wives or concubines, a very
 numerous posterity, the wealthy inheritance was eagerly
 disputed, and Zamma, one of his sons, was slain in a
 domestic quarrel by his brother Firmus.","('Zamma', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Firmus', 'PERSON')"
"But in the calmer moments of reflection, when the mind of
 Valens was not agitated by fear, or that of Valentinian by
 rage, the tyrant resumed the sentiments, or at least the
 conduct, of the father of his country.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"But in the provinces of the East, from
 the Euxine to the extremity of Thebais, the strength and
 numbers of the hostile factions were more equally balanced;
 and this equality, instead of recommending the counsels of
 peace, served only to perpetuate the horrors of religious
 war.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Euxine', 'LOC'), ('Thebais', 'GPE')"
"But the
 daring spirit of the pirates braved the perils both of the
 sea and of the shore: their skill was confirmed by the
 habits of enterprise; the meanest of their mariners was
 alike capable of handling an oar, of rearing a sail, or of
 conducting a vessel and the Saxons rejoiced in the
 appearance of a tempest, which concealed their design, and
 dispersed the fleets of the enemy. (105)","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('105', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the active spirit of the Heruli was subdued
 by the slow and steady perseverance of the Goths; and, after
 a bloody action, in which the king was slain, the remains of
 that warlike tribe became an useful accession to the camp of
 Hermanric.","('Heruli', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Hermanric', 'GPE')"
"But the count, long exercised
 in the arts of corruption, had despatched a swift and trusty
 messenger to secure the venal friendship of Remigius, master
 of the offices.","('Remigius', 'PERSON')"
"But the forces of Sapor were continually
 renewed and increased; the hopeless courage of the garrison
 was exhausted; the strength of the walls yielded to the
 assault; and the proud conqueror, after wasting the
 rebellious city with fire and sword, led away captive an
 unfortunate queen, who, in a more auspicious hour, had been
 the destined bride of the son of Constantine.(135)","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('a more auspicious hour', 'TIME'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('135', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the imprudent and unhappy Africans soon
 discovered that, in this rash insurrection, they had not
 sufficiently consulted their own strength or the abilities
 of their leader.","('Africans', 'NORP')"
"But the inquisition into the crime of magic,
 which, under the reign of the two brothers, was so
 rigorously prosecuted both at Rome and Antioch, was
 interpreted as the fatal symptom, either of the displeasure
 of Heaven or of the depravity of mankind.(43)","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"But the intemperance which gratified their appetites
 retarded their progress; and before the Goths could receive
 any certain intelligence of the defeat and death of
 Procopius, they perceived, by the hostile state of the
 country, that the civil and military powers were resumed by
 his successful rival.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON')"
"But the most honourable circumstance of the character of
 Valentinian is the firm and temperate impartiality which he
 uniformly preserved in an age of religious contention.","('Valentinian', 'PERSON')"
"But the partial and powerful favour of Mellobaudes
 encouraged him to challenge his legal judges, to obtain
 repeated delays for the purpose of procuring a crowd of
 friendly witnesses, and, finally, to cover his guilty
 conduct by the additional guilt of fraud and forgery.","('Mellobaudes', 'PERSON')"
"But the scarcity of iron obliged the Aestian warriors
 to content themselves with wooden clubs; and the reduction
 of that wealthy country is ascribed to the prudence, rather
 than to the arms, of Hermanric.","('Aestian', 'NORP'), ('Hermanric', 'ORG')"
"But the tedious
 enumeration of the unknown and uninteresting tribes of
 Africa may be reduced to the general remark, that they were
 all of the swarthy race of the Moors; that they inhabited
 the back settlements of the Mauritanian and Numidian
 provinces, the country, as they have since been termed by
 the Arabs, of dates and of locusts,(125) and that, as the 
 Roman power declined in Africa, the boundary of civilised
 manners and cultivated land was insensibly contracted.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Moors', 'NORP'), ('Mauritanian', 'NORP'), ('Numidian', 'NORP'), ('Arabs', 'NORP'), ('125', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"But the wisdom and authority of
 the legislator are seldom victorious in a contest with the
 vigilant dexterity of private interest: and Jerom, or
 Ambrose, might patiently acquiesce in the justice of an
 ineffectual or salutary law.","('Jerom', 'PERSON'), ('Ambrose', 'PERSON')"
"But the wise 
 monarch, instead of aspiring to the conquest of Germany,
 confined his attention to the important and laborious
 defence of the Gallic frontier, against an enemy whose
 strength was renewed by a stream of daring volunteers, which
 incessantly flowed from the most distant tribes of the
 North.(94)","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('94', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the zeal
 of a great people, who instantly flew to arms, intimidated
 the praefect: Death of Athanius, A.D. 373.","('Athanius', 'PERSON'), ('373', 'CARDINAL')"
"But they still
 possessed arms and courage; their courage was animated by
 despair, and they obtained the usual reinforcement of the
 cavalry of their Sarmatian allies.","('Sarmatian', 'NORP')"
"But this truce of twelve years, which was
 inforced by the wise and vigorous government of Valentinian,
 by suspending the repetition of mutual injuries, contributed
 to soften the manners, and abate the prejudices, of the
 religious factions.","('twelve years', 'DATE'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"But we may be assured, from the evidence of reason as well as history, that the two marriages of Valentinian with Severa and with Justina were successively contracted, and that he used the ancient permission of divorce, which was still allowed by the laws, though it was condemned by the church.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Severa', 'PERSON'), ('Justina', 'PERSON')"
"By degrees he ventured into the capital, 
 trusted his life and fortune to the fidelity of two friends,
 a senator and an eunuch, and conceived some hopes of success
 from the intelligence which he obtained of the actual state
 of public affairs.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"By his marriage with the
 grand-daughter of Constantine, the son of Valentinian
 acquired all the hereditary rights of the Flavian family,
 which, in a series of three Imperial generations, were
 sanctified by time, religion, and the reverence of the
 people.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Flavian', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"By his timid
 councils, Para was alternately supported, and recalled, and
 restored, and betrayed.","('Para', 'PERSON')"
"By the
 unanimous consent of the Iberians, the country was equally
 divided between the rival princes; and Aspacuras, who owed
 his diadem to the choice of Sapor, was Obliged to declare
 that his regard for his children, who were detained as
 hostages by the tyrant, was the only consideration which
 prevented him from openly renouncing the alliance of Persia.","('Iberians', 'NORP'), ('Aspacuras', 'PERSON'), ('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"By the first letters which he despatched
 from the camp of Mesopotamia, he had delegated the military
 command of Gaul and Illyricum to Malarich, a brave and
 faithful officer of the nation of the Franks, and to his
 father-in-law, Count Lucillian, who had formerly
 distinguished his courage and conduct in the defence of
 Nisibis.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Mesopotamia', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Illyricum', 'PERSON'), ('Malarich', 'PERSON'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Lucillian', 'PERSON'), ('Nisibis', 'PERSON')"
"By the habits of chastity and temperance,
 which restrain the appetites and invigorate the faculties,
 Valentinian preserved his own and the public esteem.","('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"Carthage would have trembled at the 
 strange intelligence that the countries on either side of
 the equator were filled with innumerable nations who
 differed only in their colour from the ordinary appearance
 of the human species; and the subjects of the Roman empire
 might have anxiously expected that the swarms of barbarians
 which issued from the North would soon be encountered from
 the South by new swarms of barbarians, equally fierce and
 equally formidable.","('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('South', 'LOC')"
"Conquests of Hermanric 
V.During a peaceful interval of thirty years, the Romans
 secured their frontiers, and the Goths extended their
 dominions.","('Hermanric', 'GPE'), ('thirty years', 'DATE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"Constans
 visited his British dominions: but we may form some estimate
 of the importance of his achievements by the language of
 panegyric, which celebrates only his triumph over the
 elements, or, in other words, the good fortune of a safe and
 easy passage from the port of Boulogne to the harbour of
 Sandwich.(112)","('Constans', 'PERSON'), ('British', 'NORP'), ('Boulogne', 'GPE'), ('Sandwich', 'GPE'), ('112', 'CARDINAL')"
"Count
 Sebastian, with the bands of Italy and Illyricum, was
 ordered to invade their country, most probably on the side
 of Rhaetia.","('Sebastian', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Illyricum', 'GPE'), ('Rhaetia', 'PERSON')"
"Damasus, bishop of Rome, who was constrained to stigmatise
 the avarice of his clergy by the publications of the law of
 Valentinian, had the good sense, or the good fortune, to
 engage in his service the zeal and abilities of the learned
 Jerom; and the grateful saint has celebrated the merit and
 purity of a very ambiguous character.(80) But the splendid vices of the church of Rome, under the reign of Valentinian and Damasus, have been curiously observed by the historian Ammianus, who delivers his impartial sense in these expressive words:—","('Damasus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Jerom', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Damasus', 'NORP'), ('Ammianus', 'PERSON')"
"Death of Jovian, February 17.","('Death of Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('February 17', 'DATE')"
"Disappointed in their attempts against the walls of Sirmium,
 the indignant barbarians turned their arms against the
 master-general of the frontier, to whom they unjustly
 attributed the murder of their king.","('Sirmium', 'ORG')"
"During the first moments of his tumultuous reign he
 was astonished and terrified by the gloomy silence of the
 people, who were either ignorant of the cause or
 apprehensive of the event.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Equitius could bring
 into the field no more than two legions, but they contained
 the veteran strength of the Maesian and Pannonian bands.","('Equitius', 'ORG'), ('no more than two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maesian', 'NORP'), ('Pannonian', 'NORP')"
"Even Sirmium
 might not have been secure if the Quadi and Sarmatians had
 diligently advanced during the general consternation of the
 magistrates and people.","('Sirmium', 'ORG'), ('Quadi', 'NORP'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP')"
"Every messenger who escaped across the British channel
 conveyed the most melancholy and alarming tidings to the
 ears of Valentinian, and the emperor was soon informed that
 the two military commanders of the province had been
 surprised and cut off by the barbarians.","('British', 'NORP'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Every production
 of art and nature, every object of convenience or luxury,
 which they were incapable of creating by labour or procuring
 by trade, was accumulated in the rich and fruitful province
 of Britain.(114)","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('114', 'CARDINAL')"
"Every step which they gained increased their ardour,
 and abated the resistance of the enemy: and after their
 united forces had occupied the summit of the hill, they
 impetuously urged the barbarians down the northern descent,
 where Count Sebastian was posted to intercept their retreat.","('Sebastian', 'PERSON')"
"Every tide might float down the Elbe whole fleets
 of canoes, filled with hardy and intrepid associates, who
 aspired to behold the unbounded prospect of the ocean, and
 to taste the wealth and luxury of unknown worlds.","('Elbe', 'LOC')"
Feb. 17-26.,"('Feb. 17-26', 'DATE')"
February 26.,"('February 26', 'DATE')"
"Foreign wars, A.D. 364-375.","('364-375', 'CARDINAL')"
"From
 the coast of Kent, to the extremity of Caithness and Ulster,
 the memory of a Celtic origin was distinctly preserved in
 the perpetual resemblance of language, of religion, and of
 manners: and the peculiar characters of the British tribes
 might be naturally ascribed to the influence of accidental
 and local circumstances; (109)","('Kent', 'GPE'), ('Caithness', 'LOC'), ('Ulster', 'LOC'), ('Celtic', 'NORP'), ('British', 'NORP'), ('109', 'CARDINAL')"
"From Tyana he
 continued his hasty march to Ancyra, capital of the province
 of Galatia, A.D. 364.","('Tyana', 'GPE'), ('Ancyra', 'GPE'), ('Galatia', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 364', 'DATE')"
"From the
 extremity of Italy and Asia the young and the aged were
 dragged in chains to the tribunals of Rome and Antioch.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"From the age of Constantine to that of
 the Plantagenets this rapacious spirit continued to
 instigate the poor and hardy Caledonians: but the same
 people whose generous humanity seems to inspire the songs of
 Ossian was disgraced by a savage ignorance of the virtues of
 peace and of the laws of war.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Plantagenets', 'NORP'), ('Caledonians', 'NORP'), ('Ossian', 'PERSON')"
"Gratian dissembled his resentment till he could safely
 punish or disgrace the authors of the conspiracy; and though
 he uniformly behaved with tenderness and regard to his
 infant colleague, he gradually confounded, in the
 administration of the Western empire, the office of a
 guardian with the authority of a sovereign.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"He
 affected to praise the prudent and moderate conduct of the
 king of Armenia; and the unsuspicious Tiranus was persuaded,
 by the repeated assurances of insidious friendship, to
 deliver his person into the hands of a faithless and cruel
 enemy.","('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('Tiranus', 'PERSON')"
"He
 persisted in his declaration that it was impossible for him,
 without incurring the guilt of perjury, ever to set his foot
 on the territory of the empire; and it is more than probable
 that his regard for the sanctity of an oath was confirmed by
 the recent and fatal examples of Roman treachery.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"He
 skilfully directed their strenuous efforts to repair and
 strengthen the decayed fortifications, and procured the
 seasonable and effectual assistance of a company of archers
 to protect the capital of the Illyrian provinces.","('Illyrian', 'NORP')"
"He
 suffered the ordinary fate of an unsuccessful usurper, but
 the acts of cruelty which were exercised by the conqueror,
 under the forms of legal justice, excited the pity and
 indignation of mankind.(42)
Severe inquisition into the crime of magic at Rome and Antioch, A.D. 373, etc  
 Such indeed are the common and natural fruits of despotism
 and rebellion.","('42', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 373', 'DATE')"
"He
 was pardoned, however, and still employed by a prince who
 esteemed his merit, (23) and in the various events of the 
 Persian war he improved the reputation which he had already
 acquired on the banks of the Rhine.","('23', 'DATE'), ('the \r\n Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"He affected,
 however, to receive the modest application of Gabinius, king
 of the Quadi, with some attention and regard; but this
 artful civility concealed a dark and bloody design, and the
 credulous prince was persuaded to accept the pressing
 invitation of Marcellinus.","('Gabinius', 'PERSON'), ('Quadi', 'NORP'), ('Marcellinus', 'PERSON')"
"He attempted to
 deceive, by an apparent submission, the vigilance of the
 Roman general, to seduce the fidelity of his troops, and to
 protract the duration of the war by successively engaging
 the independent tribes of Africa to espouse his quarrel or
 to protect his flight.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"He cheerfully accepted the choice of the
 army, declared that he should always consider the son of
 Justina as a brother, not as a rival, and advised the
 empress, with her son Valentinian, to fix their residence at
 Milan, in the fair and peaceful province of Italy while he
 assumed the more arduous command of the countries beyond the
 Alps.","('Justina', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Alps', 'LOC')"
"He enjoyed the glory of a second refusal;
 and, when the virtues of the father were alleged in favour
 of the son, the praefect, with the firmness of a
 disinterested patriot, declared to the electors that the
 feeble age of the one, and the inexperienced youth of the
 other, were equally incapable of the laborious duties of
 government.","('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"He forgot
 the provocation, remembered only the injury, and advanced
 into the country of the Quadi with an insatiate thirst of
 blood and revenge.","('Quadi', 'NORP')"
"He had
 condemned, with the consent of the most rational Pagans, the
 licence of nocturnal sacrifices; but he immediately admitted
 the petition of Praetextatus, proconsul of Achaia, who
 represented that the life of the Greeks would become dreary
 and comfortless if they were deprived of the invaluable
 blessing of the Eleusinian mysteries.","('Pagans', 'NORP'), ('Praetextatus', 'PERSON'), ('Achaia', 'PERSON'), ('Greeks', 'NORP'), ('Eleusinian', 'NORP')"
"He invaded the adjacent
 countries of the North, and twelve considerable nations,
 whose names and limits cannot be accurately defined,
 successively yielded to the superiority of the Gothic arms.
 (141)","('North', 'LOC'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('141', 'CARDINAL')"
"He is acknowledged by the army, A.D. 364.","('364', 'CARDINAL')"
"He is executed at Carthage, A.D. 376  
 Africa had been lost by the vices of Romanus it was restored
 by the virtues of Theodosius, and our curiosity may be
 usefully directed to the inquiry of the respective treatment
 which the two generals received from the Imperial court.","('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Romanus', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"He justly observes
 that in the recent changes both religions had been
 alternately disgraced by the seeming acquisition of
 worthless proselytes, of those votaries of the reigning
 purple who could pass, without a reason and without a blush,
 from the church to the temple, and from the altars of
 Jupiter to the sacred table of the Christians.(10)
His progress from Antioch.","('Jupiter', 'LOC'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antioch', 'GPE')"
"He marched in person, with
 a considerable part of the forces of Gaul, from the banks of
 the Moselle; and to the suppliant ambassadors of the
 Sarmatians, who met him on the way, he returned a doubtful
 answer, that as soon as he reached the scene of action he
 should examine and pronounce.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Moselle', 'NORP'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP')"
"He naturally addressed himself
 to Eudoxus,(66) bishop of the Imperial city; and if the 
 ignorant monarch was instructed by that Arian pastor in the
 principles of heterodox theology, his misfortune, rather
 than his guilt, was the inevitable consequence of his
 erroneous choice.","('Eudoxus', 'PERSON'), ('66', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Arian', 'NORP')"
"He never aspired, like
 Constantius, to the fame of a profound theologian; but, as
 he had received with simplicity and respect the tenets of
 Eudoxus, Valens resigned his conscience to the direction of
 his ecclesiastical guides, and promoted by the influence of
 his authority the reunion of the Athanasian heretics to the
 body of the Catholic church.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Eudoxus', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Athanasian', 'NORP'), ('Catholic', 'NORP')"
"He possessed, however,
 one quality which recommended him to Valentinian, and
 preserved the domestic peace of the empire: a devout and
 grateful attachment to his benefactor, whose superiority of
 genius, as well as of authority, Valens humbly and
 cheerfully acknowledged in every action of his life.(28)","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('28', 'CARDINAL')"
"He seized the favourable
 moment of navigation, and securely landed the numerous and
 veteran bands of the Heruli and Batavians, the Jovians and
 the Victors.","('Heruli', 'NORP'), ('Batavians', 'NORP'), ('Jovians', 'NORP'), ('Victors', 'NORP')"
"He then marched against the Venedi; unskilled in
 the use of arms, and formidable only by their numbers, which
 filled the wide extent of the plains of modern Poland.","('Venedi', 'NORP'), ('Poland', 'GPE')"
"He was received as the 
 deliverer of his country, and, as soon as it appeared that
 Romanus was formidable only to a submissive province, the
 tyrant of Africa became the object of universal contempt.","('Romanus', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"He was subdued by the perseverance
 of Theodosius, who had formed an inflexible determination
 that the war should end only by the death of the tyrant, and
 that every nation of Africa which presumed to support his
 cause should be involved in his ruin.","('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"Her person was saved from danger, and the republic
 from disgrace, by the active zeal of Messalla, governor of
 the provinces.","('Messalla', 'PERSON')"
"His
 ambassadors loudly complained, at the court of Valens, of
 the infraction of the ancient and solemn alliance which had
 so long subsisted between the Romans and the Goths.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"His
 death, which happened in the full maturity of a reign of
 seventy years, changed in a moment the court and councils of
 Persia, and their attention was most probably engaged by
 domestic troubles and the distant efforts of a Carmanian
 war.(137)","('seventy years', 'DATE'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Carmanian', 'NORP'), ('137', 'CARDINAL')"
"His Two Sons, Gratian and Valentinian II., Succeed to the Western Empire","('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian II.', 'ORG')"
"His dead body, the only present which Igmazen could offer to the conqueror, was
 carelessly thrown upon a camel; and Theodosius, leading back his victorious troops to Sitifi, was saluted by the warmest acclamations of joy and loyalty. (123)","('Igmazen', 'PERSON'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Sitifi', 'GPE'), ('123', 'CARDINAL')"
"His defeat and death, A.D. 366.","('A.D. 366', 'DATE')"
"His dominions, which
 extended from the Danube to the Baltic, included the native
 seats, and the recent acquisitions, of the Goths; and he
 reigned over the greatest part of Germany and Scythia with
 the authority of a conqueror, and sometimes with the cruelty
 of a tyrant.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Baltic', 'LOC'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'PERSON')"
"His edict, (77) addressed to Damasus, 
 bishop of Rome, was publicly read in the churches of the
 city.","('77', 'DATE'), ('Damasus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"His eyes, his voice, his
 colour, his gestures, expressed the violence of his
 ungoverned fury; and while his whole frame was agitated with
 convulsive passion a large blood-vessel suddenly burst in
 his body, and Valentinian fell speechless into the arms of
 his attendants.","('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"His father Nabal was one of the richest and most powerful of
 the Moorish princes who acknowledged the supremacy of Rome.","('Nabal', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Moorish', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"His generals passed the Bosphorus, and subdued,
 without an effort, the unarmed but wealthy provinces of
 Bithynia and Asia.","('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Bithynia', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"His inquiries were
 managed with so much dexterity and success, that he
 compelled the citizens of Leptis, who had sustained a recent
 siege of eight days, to contradict the truth of their own
 decrees and to censure the behaviour of their own deputies.","('Leptis', 'PERSON'), ('eight days', 'DATE')"
"His manly countenance, deeply
 marked with the impression of sense and spirit, inspired his
 friends with awe, and his enemies with fear; and, to second
 the efforts of his undaunted courage, the son of Gratian had
 inherited the advantages of a strong and healthy
 constitution.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON')"
"Hostilities and peace, A.D. 367, 368, 369.","('A.D. 367', 'FAC'), ('368', 'CARDINAL'), ('369', 'CARDINAL')"
I Germany.,"('Germany', 'GPE')"
"I am at a loss how to vary the
 narrative of similar crimes; or how to relate that, in the
 course of the same year, but in remote parts of the empire,
 the inhospitable table of two Imperial generals was stained
 with the royal blood of two guests and allies, inhumanly
 murdered by their order, and in their presence.","('the same year', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"If
 the events of war accused the courage or conduct of the
 king, he was immediately deposed; and the injustice of his
 subjects made him responsible for the fertility of the earth
 and the regularity of the seasons, which seemed to fall more
 properly within the sacerdotal department.(97)","('97', 'CARDINAL')"
"If in the 
 neighbourhood of the commercial and literary town of Glasgow
 a race of cannibals has really existed, we may contemplate
 in the period of the Scottish history the opposite extremes
 of savage and civilised life.","('Glasgow', 'GPE'), ('Scottish', 'NORP')"
"If the ecclesiastics were
 checked in the pursuit of personal emolument, they would
 exert a more laudable industry to increase the wealth of the
 church; and dignify their covetousness with the specious
 names of piety and patriotism.(79)
Ambition and luxury of Damascus, bishop of Rome.","('Damascus', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"If the fact were not
 established by the most unquestionable evidence, we should
 appear to abuse the credulity of our readers by the
 description of the vessels in which the Saxon pirates
 ventured to sport in the waves of the German Ocean, the
 British Channel, and the Bay of Biscay.","('Saxon', 'NORP'), ('the German Ocean', 'LOC'), ('the\r\n British Channel', 'LOC'), ('the Bay of Biscay', 'LOC')"
"If the geographical accuracy of Ammianus had been
 fortunately bestowed on the British exploits of Theodosius,
 we should have traced, with eager curiosity, the distinct
 and domestic footsteps of his march.","('Ammianus', 'PERSON'), ('British', 'NORP'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"If the severity of
 Valentinian had been rightly directed, it would have fallen
 on the guilty head of Romanus.","('Valentinian', 'GPE'), ('Romanus', 'PERSON')"
"In a
 season of tranquillity Sallust had resigned without a
 murmur, but, as soon as the public safety was attacked, he
 ambitiously solicited the pre-eminence of toil and danger,
 and the restoration of that virtuous minister to the
 praefecture of the East was the first step which indicated
 the repentance of Valens, and satisfied the minds of the
 people.","('a\r\n season', 'DATE'), ('Sallust', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"In a moment of impatience and
 despair, Procopius embarked in a merchant-vessel which made
 sail for Constantinople, and boldly aspired to the rank of a
 sovereign because he was not allowed to enjoy the security
 of a subject.","('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"In a solemn assembly of the civil and military powers of the
 empire, the diadem was again unanimously offered to the
 praefect Sallust.","('Sallust', 'PERSON')"
"In every election the
 claims of the Arian candidate obtained the preference; and
 if they were opposed by the majority of the people, he was
 usually supported by the authority of the civil magistrate,
 or even by the terrors of a military force.","('Arian', 'NORP')"
"In his march from Sandwich to London,
 Theodosius defeated several parties of the barbarians,
 released a multitude of captives, and, after distributing to
 his soldiers a small portion of the spoil, established the
 fame of disinterested justice by the restitution of the
 remainder to the rightful proprietors.","('Sandwich', 'GPE'), ('London', 'GPE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON')"
"In many cities the temples were
 shut or deserted; the philosophers, who had abused their
 transient favour, thought it prudent to shave their beards
 and disguise their profession; and the Christians rejoiced
 that they were now in a condition to forgive or to revenge
 the injuries which they had suffered under the preceding
 reign.","('Christians', 'NORP')"
"In one of the suburbs of that capital, (27) thirty days after his own 
 elevation, he bestowed the title of Augustus on his brother
 Valens: and as the boldest patriots were convinced that
 their opposition, without being serviceable to their
 country, would be fatal to themselves, the declaration of
 his absolute will was received with silent submission.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('27', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirty days', 'DATE'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"In private families the
 sentiments of nature were extinguished by the blind fury of
 zeal and revenge; the majesty of the laws was violated or
 abused; the cities of the East were stained with blood; and
 the most implacable enemies of the Romans were in the bosom
 of their country.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"In that sequestered region he remained
 many months, exposed to the hardships of exile, of solitude,
 and of want; his melancholy temper brooding over his
 misfortune, and his mind agitated by the just apprehension
 that, if any accident should discover his name, the
 faithless barbarians would violate, without much scruple,
 the laws of hospitality.","('many months', 'DATE')"
"In the annual assembly of the three cities,
 they nominated two deputies to lay at the feet of
 Valentinian the customary offering of a gold victory, and to
 accompany this tribute of duty, rather than of gratitude,
 with their humble complaint that they were ruined by the
 enemy and betrayed by their governor.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"In the beginning of the ensuing year the military force of the whole nation, in deep and solid
 columns, broke through the barrier of the Rhine during the
 severity of a northern winter.","('the beginning of the ensuing year', 'DATE'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"In the capital of the empire the
 females of noble and opulent houses possessed a very ample
 share of independent property; and many of those devout
 females had embraced the doctrines of Christianity, not only
 with the cold assent of the understanding, but with the
 warmth of affection, and perhaps with the eagerness of
 fashion.","('Christianity', 'NORP')"
"In the castle or palace of Mediana,
 only three miles from Naissus, they executed the solemn and
 final division of the Roman empire.(32) Valentinian bestowed 
 on his brother the rich praefecture of the East, from the
 Lower Danube to the confines of Persia; whilst he reserved
 for his immediate government the warlike praefectures of
 Illyricum, Italy, and Gaul, from the extremity of Greece to
 the Caledonian rampart and from the rampart of Caledonia to
 the foot of Mount Atlas.","('Mediana', 'GPE'), ('three miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Naissus', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('the\r\n Lower Danube', 'LOC'), ('Persia', 'LOC'), ('Illyricum', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Caledonian', 'NORP'), ('Caledonia', 'GPE'), ('Mount Atlas', 'LOC')"
"In the course of their slow 
 and distant navigations they must always have been exposed
 to the danger, and very frequently to the misfortune, of
 shipwreck; and the naval annals of the Saxons were
 undoubtedly filled with the accounts of the losses which
 they sustained on the coasts of Britain and Gaul.","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'GPE')"
"In the first
 years of the reign of Theodosius, a Persian embassy arrived
 at Constantinople to excuse the unjustifiable measures of
 the former reign, and to offer, as the tribute of
 friendship, or even of respect, a splendid present of gems,
 of silk, and of Indian elephants.(138)
Adventures of Para, king of Armenia","('the first\r\n years', 'DATE'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('Persian', 'NORP'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Indian', 'NORP'), ('138', 'CARDINAL'), ('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"In the general picture of the affairs of the East under the
 reign of Valens, the adventures of Para form one of the most
 striking and singular objects.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the heat of action,
 calmly taking off his helmet, he showed his grey hairs and
 venerable countenance, saluted the soldiers of Procopius by
 the endearing names of children and companions, and exhorted
 them no longer to support the desperate cause of a
 contemptible tyrant, but to follow their old commander, who
 had so often led them to honour and victory.","('Procopius', 'PERSON')"
"In the important station of the Upper
 Danube, the conqueror of Britain checked and defeated the
 armies of the Alemanni, before he was chosen to suppress the
 revolt of Africa.","('the Upper\r\n Danube', 'LOC'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"In the march from Antioch he had reached
 his quarters at Ancyra, when he was unexpectedly summoned,
 without guilt and without intrigue, to assume, in the
 forty-third year of his age, the absolute government of the
 Roman empire.","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Ancyra', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n forty-third year', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the meanwhile Valentinian was alarmed and perplexed by
 the doubtful intelligence of the revolt of the East.","('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"In the midst of a splendid entertainment, he was
 bound in chains of silver, as an honor due to the blood of
 the Arsacides; and, after a short confinement in the Tower
 of Oblivion at Ecbatana, he was released from the miseries
 of life, either by his own dagger or by that of an assassin.","('Arsacides', 'NORP'), ('the Tower\r\n of Oblivion', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Ecbatana', 'GPE')"
"In the space of seven months the Roman troops, who were now
 returned to Antioch, had performed a march of fifteen
 hundred miles, in which they had endured all the hardships
 of war, of famine, and of climate.","('the space of seven months', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('fifteen\r\n hundred miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"In the time of Julian
 he provoked the danger of disgrace by the contempt which he
 publicly expressed for the reigning religion; (22) and it 
 should seem, from his subsequent conduct, that the
 indiscreet and unseasonable freedom of Valentinian was the
 effect of military spirit rather than of Christian zeal.","('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('22', 'CARDINAL'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"In the two
 engagements of Thyatira (41) and Nacolia the unfortunate 
 Procopius was deserted by his troops, who were seduced by
 the instructions and example of their perfidious officers.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Thyatira', 'PERSON'), ('41', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nacolia', 'PERSON'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON')"
"In the unsuspicious moment of a
 Christian festival, Rando, a bold and artful chieftain, who
 had long meditated his attempt, suddenly passed the Rhine,
 entered the defenceless town, and retired with a multitude
 of captives of either sex.","('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Rando', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"Instead of increasing the weight of taxes, which in the
 space of forty years had been gradually doubled, he reduced,
 in the first years of his reign, one fourth of the tribute
 of the East. (63)","('the\r\n space of forty years', 'DATE'), ('the first years of his reign', 'DATE'), ('one fourth', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('63', 'CARDINAL')"
"Instead of leading the nations of Germany and
 Scythia to the banks of the Danube, or even to the gates of
 Constantinople, the aged monarch of the Goths resigned to
 the brave Athanaric the danger and glory of a defensive war,
 against an enemy who wielded with a feeble hand the powers
 of a mighty state.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Scythia', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Athanaric', 'NORP')"
"It is certain that, in the declining age of the Roman
 empire, Caledonia, Ireland, and the Isle of Man were
 inhabited by the Scots, and that the kindred tribes, who
 were often associated in military enterprise, were deeply
 affected by the various accidents of their mutual fortunes.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Caledonia', 'GPE'), ('Ireland', 'GPE'), ('the Isle of Man', 'GPE'), ('Scots', 'NORP')"
"It is not from the master of Innocence that we
 should expect the tender regard for the welfare of his
 subjects which prompted Valentinian to condemn the
 exposition of newborn infants,(60) and to establish fourteen 
 skilful physicians, with stipends and privileges, in the
 fourteen quarters of Rome.","('Innocence', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('fourteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('the\r\n fourteen quarters', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"It is probable that in some remote period of antiquity the
 fertile plains of Ulster received a colony of hungry Scots;
 and that the strangers of the North, who had dared to
 encounter the arms of the legions, spread their conquests
 over the savage and unwarlike natives of a solitary island.","('Ulster', 'GPE'), ('Scots', 'NORP'), ('North', 'LOC')"
"It should
 seem probable, however, that the most numerous auxiliaries
 of the Saxons were furnished by the nations who dwelt along
 the shores of the Baltic.","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Baltic', 'LOC')"
"It was his intention that the arts of rhetoric and grammar
 should be taught, in the Greek and Latin languages, in the
 metropolis of every province; and as the size and dignity of
 the school was usually proportioned to the importance of the
 city, the academies of Rome and Constantinople claimed a
 just and singular pre-eminence.","('Greek', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Latin', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE')"
"It was the opinion of Valentinian
 that his soldiers must learn to fear their commander before
 they could cease to fear the enemy.","('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
January,"('January', 'DATE')"
"January 1. where Jovian assumed, with his infant son, the name and ensigns of the consulship. (14) Dadastana,(15) an obscure town, almost at an equal distance between Ancyra and
 Nice, was marked for the fatal term of his journey and his
 life.","('January 1.', 'DATE'), ('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('Dadastana', 'PERSON'), ('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ancyra', 'GPE'), ('Nice', 'GPE')"
"Jovian was educated in the profession of
 Christianity; and as he marched from Nisibis to Antioch, the
 banner of the Cross, the LABARUM of Constantine, which was
 again displayed at the head of the legions, announced to the
 people the faith of their new emperor.","('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('Nisibis', 'PERSON'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Jovinus, who had viewed the
 ground with the eye of a general, made his silent approach
 through a deep and woody vale, till he could distinctly
 perceive the indolent security of the Germans.","('Jovinus', 'PERSON'), ('Germans', 'NORP')"
June.,"('June', 'DATE')"
"Let us not 
 hesitate to indulge a liberal pride that, in the present
 age, the enlightened part of Europe has abolished(44) a cruel 
 and odious prejudice, which reigned in every climate of the
 globe and adhered to every system of religious opinions.(45)","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('44', 'CARDINAL'), ('45', 'CARDINAL')"
"Lupicinus
 advanced by hasty marches to bring the legions of Syria to
 the aid of Valens.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"Macrianus was afterwards admitted to the honour of a
 personal conference with the emperor, and the favours which
 he received fixed him, till the hour of his death, a steady
 and sincere friend of the republic.(100)
The Saxons.","('Macrianus', 'PERSON'), ('the hour', 'TIME'), ('100', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saxons', 'NORP')"
"Malarich had declined an office to which he thought
 himself unequal, and Lucillian was massacred at Rheims, in
 an accidental mutiny of the Batavian cohorts.(12) But the 
 moderation of Jovinus, master-general of the cavalry, who
 forgave the intention of his disgrace, soon appeased the
 tumult and confirmed the uncertain minds of the soldiers.","('Malarich', 'PERSON'), ('Lucillian', 'PERSON'), ('Rheims', 'PERSON'), ('Batavian', 'NORP'), ('Jovinus', 'PERSON')"
March 28,"('March 28', 'DATE')"
May 28,"('May 28', 'DATE')"
"May 2d. and the archbishop was permitted to end his
 life in peace and in glory, after a reign of forty-seven
 years.","('May 2d.', 'DATE'), ('forty-seven\r\n years', 'DATE')"
"Notwithstanding their
 services, their fatigues, and the approach of winter, the
 timid and impatient Jovian allowed only to the men and
 horses a respite of six weeks.","('winter', 'DATE'), ('Jovian', 'NORP'), ('six weeks', 'DATE')"
"On a sudden they
 heard the sound of the Roman trumpet; they saw the enemy in
 their camp.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"On the sixth
 day after the death of Valentinian, the infant prince of the
 same name, who was only four years old, was shown, in the
 arms of his mother, to the legions, and solemnly invested,
 by military acclamation, with the titles and ensigns of
 supreme power.","('the sixth\r\n day', 'DATE'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('four years old', 'DATE')"
"On this
 slight foundation a huge superstructure of fable was
 gradually reared by the bards and the monks; two orders of
 men who equally abused the privilege of fiction.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"One
 philosopher and two lawyers; five sophists and ten
 grammarians for the Greek, and three orators and ten
 grammarians for the Latin tongue; besides seven scribes, or,
 as they were then styled, antiquarians, whose laborious pens
 supplied the public library with fair and correct copies of
 the classic writers.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Latin', 'NORP'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"Para suppressed
 his indignation, dissembled his fears, and, after secretly
 preparing his escape, mounted on horseback with three
 hundred of his faithful followers.","('three\r\n hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"Para was invited to a Roman banquet, which had
 been prepared with all the pomp and sensuality of the East;
 the hall resounded with cheerful music, and the company was
 already heated with wine, when the count retired for an
 instant, drew his sword, and gave the signal of the murder.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"Perhaps the method of annals would
 more forcibly express the urgent and divided cares of the
 two emperors; but the attention of the reader, likewise,
 would be distracted by a tedious and desultory narrative.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Praetextatus was a philosophic Pagan, a man of learning, of taste, and
 politeness; who disguised a reproach in the form of a jest,
 when he assured Damasus that if he could obtain the
 bishopric of Rome, he himself would immediately embrace the
 Christian religion.(87)","('Praetextatus', 'PERSON'), ('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('Damasus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('87', 'CARDINAL')"
"Procopius
 had been hastily promoted from the obscure station of a
 tribune and a notary to the joint command of the army of
 Mesopotamia; the public opinion already named him as the
 successor of a prince who was destitute of natural heirs;
 and a vain rumour was propagated by his friends or his
 enemies, that Julian, before the altar of the Moon at
 Carrhae, had privately invested Procopius with the Imperial
 purple.(35) He endeavoured, by his dutiful and submissive 
 behaviour, to disarm the jealousy of Jovian, resigned
 without a contest his military command, and retired, with
 his wife and family, to cultivate the ample patrimony which
 he possessed in the province of Cappadocia.","('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Mesopotamia', 'GPE'), ('Julian', 'PERSON'), ('Moon', 'LOC'), ('Carrhae', 'GPE'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE')"
"Restoration of Britain by Theodosius, A.D. 367-370","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Theodosius', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 367-370', 'DATE')"
"Romanus, elated by
 impunity and irritated by resistance, was still continued in
 the military command, till the Africans were provoked, by
 his avarice, to join the rebellious standard of Firmus, the
 Moor.(121)
Revolt of Firmus.","('Romanus', 'PERSON'), ('Africans', 'NORP'), ('Firmus', 'ORG'), ('121', 'CARDINAL'), ('Firmus', 'ORG')"
"Sauromaces, who reigned in that country by the
 permission of the emperors, was expelled by a superior
 force, and, as an insult on the majesty of Rome, the king of
 kings placed a diadem on the head of his abject vassal
 Aspacuras.","('Sauromaces', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Aspacuras', 'PERSON')"
September 28.,"('September 28', 'DATE')"
"Severa was the mother of Gratian, who seemed to unite every claim which could entitle him to the undoubted succession of the Western empire.","('Severa', 'PERSON'), ('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"Several candidates were proposed, and, after
 weighing the objections of character or situation, they were
 successively rejected: Election and character of Valentinian.","('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"Several of
 the guilty accomplices of Firmus were abandoned according to
 ancient custom, to the tumult of a military execution; many
 more, by the amputation of both their hands, continued to
 exhibit an instructive spectacle of horror; the hatred of
 the rebels was accompanied with fear, and the fear of the
 Roman soldiers was mingled with respectful admiration.","('Firmus', 'ORG'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Severus, count of
 the domestics, was hastily despatched, and as suddenly
 recalled, by the court of Treves.","('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Treves', 'PERSON')"
"She was shown to the multitude in the arms of her
 adopted father, and, as often as she passed through the
 ranks, the tenderness of the soldiers was inflamed into
 martial fury:(38)","('38', 'CARDINAL')"
"Since
 the conversion of the Armenians and Iberians, those nations
 considered the Christians as the favourites, and the Magians
 as the adversaries, of the Supreme Being; the influence of
 the clergy over a superstitious people was uniformly exerted
 in the cause of Rome; and as long as the successors of
 Constantine disputed with those of Artaxerxes the
 sovereignty of the intermediate provinces, the religious
 connection always threw a decisive advantage into the scale
 of the empire.","('Armenians', 'NORP'), ('Iberians', 'NORP'), ('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Magians', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Artaxerxes', 'PERSON')"
"Six thousand of the Alemanni were slain, four thousand were
 wounded; and the brave Jovinus, after chasing the flying
 remnant of their host as far as the banks of the Rhine, July.","('Six thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('four thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jovinus', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('July', 'DATE')"
"Six weeks before the death of Jovian,
 his infant son had been placed in the curule chair, adorned
 with the title of Nobilissimus and the vain ensigns of the
 consulship.","('Six weeks', 'DATE'), ('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('Nobilissimus', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"Six years after the death of Constantine the destructive
 inroads of the Scots and Picts required the presence of his
 youngest son, who reigned in the Western empire.","('Six years', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Scots', 'NORP'), ('Picts', 'NORP'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"Sixteen years afterwards he was still
 alive; but he had already been deprived of an eye, and his
 afflicted mother expected, every hour, that the innocent
 victim would be torn from her arms, to appease with his
 blood the suspicions of the reigning prince.(18)
Vacancy of the throne.","('Sixteen years afterwards', 'DATE'), ('every hour', 'TIME'), ('18', 'CARDINAL')"
"Sixty thousand blacks are annually
 embarked from the coast of Guinea, never to return to their
 native country; but they are embarked in chains;(132) and 
 this constant emigration which in the space of two centuries
 might have furnished armies to overrun the globe, accuses
 the guilt of Europe and the weakness of Africa.","('Sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Guinea', 'GPE'), ('132', 'CARDINAL'), ('two centuries', 'DATE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"So improvident was the
 assassin Marcellinus, that he chose the moment when the
 bravest veterans had been drawn away to suppress the revolt
 of Firmus, and the whole province was exposed, with a very
 feeble defence, to the rage of the exasperated barbarians.","('Marcellinus', 'PERSON'), ('Firmus', 'ORG')"
"Some ecclesiastic, of real
 or apparent sanctity, was chosen to direct their timorous
 conscience, and to amuse the vacant tenderness of their
 heart: and the unbounded confidence which they hastily
 bestowed was often abused by knaves and enthusiasts, who
 hastened from the extremities of the East, to enjoy, on a
 splendid theatre, the privileges of the monastic profession.","('East', 'LOC')"
"Some of the
 prisoners were saved from the edge of the sword to shed
 their blood in the amphitheatre; and the orator Symmachus
 complains that twenty-nine of those desperate savages, by
 strangling themselves with their own hands, had disappointed
 the amusement of the public.","('Symmachus', 'PERSON'), ('twenty-nine', 'CARDINAL')"
"State of the church, A.D. 363.","('A.D. 363', 'DATE')"
"Such
 punishments were frequently inflicted on the leaders of the
 Homoousian party; and the misfortune of four-score
 ecclesiastics of Constantinople, who, perhaps accidentally,
 were burnt on shipboard, was imputed to the cruel and
 premeditated malice of the emperor and his Arian ministers.","('the\r\n Homoousian party', 'ORG'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Arian', 'NORP')"
"Such reflections tend to
 enlarge the circle of our ideas, and to encourage the
 pleasing hope that New Zealand may produce in some future
 age the Hume of the Southern Hemisphere.","('New Zealand', 'GPE'), ('Hume', 'PERSON'), ('the Southern Hemisphere', 'LOC')"
"Such vain terrors 
 disturbed the peace of society and the happiness of
 individuals, and the harmless flame which insensibly melted
 a waxen image might derive a powerful and pernicious energy
 from the affrighted fancy of the person whom it was
 maliciously designed to represent. (50)","('50', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such were the weak and wicked
 maxims of the Roman administration, that, to attain a
 doubtful object of political interest, the laws of nations,
 and the sacred rights of hospitality, were inhumanly
 violated in the face of the world.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"THE death of Julian had left the public affairs of the
 empire in a very doubtful and dangerous situation.","('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"That celebrated name, in which
 we have a clear and domestic interest, escaped the notice of
 Tacitus; and in the maps of Ptolemy it faintly marks the
 narrow neck of the Cimbric peninsula, and three small
 islands towards the mouth of the Elbe.(101)","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('Ptolemy', 'LOC'), ('the Cimbric peninsula', 'LOC'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Elbe', 'LOC'), ('101', 'CARDINAL')"
"That prudent emperor, who diligently practised the wise
 maxims of Diocletian, was studious to foment and excite the
 intestine divisions of the tribes of Germany.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"That royal maid,
 who had innocently supported the revolt of Procopius, was
 now the destined wife of the heir of the Western empire.","('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP')"
"That school consisted of thirty-one
 professors in different branches of learning.","('thirty-one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 Danube, which separated the dominions of the two independent
 nations, was chosen for the scene of the conference.","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 Scottish nation, with mistaken pride, adopted their Irish
 genealogy: and the annals of a long line of imaginary kings
 have been adorned by the fancy of Boethius and the classic
 elegance of Buchanan.(111)
Their invasion of Britain, A.D. 343-366","('Scottish', 'NORP'), ('Irish', 'NORP'), ('Boethius', 'PERSON'), ('Buchanan', 'PERSON'), ('111', 'CARDINAL'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('A.D. 343-366', 'DATE')"
"The
 arms and fortifications of the Gallic frontier checked the
 fury of their just resentment; and their massacre of the
 captives served to embitter the hereditary feud of the
 Burgundians and the Alemanni.","('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Alemanni', 'NORP')"
"The
 authority of Count Romanus had been suspended by the
 master-general of the cavalry, and he was committed to safe
 and honourable custody till the end of the war.","('Romanus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 avocations of a military life had diverted his youth from
 the elegant pursuits of literature; he was ignorant of the
 Greek language and the arts of rhetoric; but, as the mind of
 the orator was never disconcerted by timid perplexity, he
 was able, as often as the occasion prompted him, to deliver
 his decided sentiments with bold and ready elocution.","('Greek', 'LANGUAGE')"
"The
 bloody and obstinate conflict lasted a whole summer's day,
 with equal valour and with alternate success.","(""a whole summer's day"", 'DATE')"
"The
 difficulties of a German war forced him to confine his
 immediate care to the safety of his own dominions; and, as
 every channel of communication was stopped or corrupted, he
 listened, with doubtful anxiety, to the rumours which were
 industriously spread that the defeat and death of Valens had
 left Procopius sole master of the Eastern provinces.","('German', 'NORP'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Procopius', 'PERSON'), ('Eastern', 'NORP')"
"The
 emperor of the East, and the Judge of the Visigoths,
 accompanied by an equal number of armed followers, advanced
 in their respective barges to the middle of the stream.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Visigoths', 'PERSON')"
"The
 immense fortunes of the Roman ladies were gradually consumed
 in lavish alms and expensive pilgrimages; and the artful
 monk, who had assigned himself the first, or possibly the
 sole place, in the testament of his spiritual daughter,
 still presumed to declare, with the smooth face of
 hypocrisy, that he was only the instrument of charity, and
 the steward of the poor.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"The
 obstinacy with which they disputed the vain honours of rank
 and precedency was the cause of their destruction, and,
 while they acted with separate forces and divided councils,
 they were surprised and slaughtered by the active vigour of
 the Sarmatian horse.","('Sarmatian', 'NORP')"
"The
 passions which had been so long suppressed by the presence
 of a master immediately revived in the Imperial council, and
 the ambitious design of reigning in the name of an infant
 was artfully executed by Mellobaudes and Equitius, who
 commanded the attachment of the Illyrian and Italian bands.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Mellobaudes', 'PERSON'), ('Equitius', 'PERSON'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
"The
 rigid impartiality of Palladius was easily disarmed.","('Palladius', 'GPE')"
"The
 submission of the barbarians appeased the resentment of
 Valens and his council: the emperor listened with
 satisfaction to the flattering and eloquent remonstrance of
 the senate of Constantinople, which assumed, for the first
 time, a share in the public deliberations; and the same
 generals, Victor and Arintheus, who had successfully
 directed the conduct of the war, were empowered to regulate
 the conditions of peace.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('the senate of Constantinople', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Victor', 'PERSON'), ('Arintheus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 treasure deposited in that strong fortress tempted the
 avarice of Sapor; but the danger of Olympias, the wife or
 widow of the Armenian king, excited the public compassion
 and animated the desperate valour of her subjects and
 soldiers.","('Sapor', 'PERSON'), ('Olympias', 'NORP'), ('Armenian', 'NORP')"
"The
 two bold headlands of Caledonia almost touch the shores of a
 spacious island, which obtained, from its luxuriant
 vegetation, the epithet of Green; and has preserved, with a
 slight alteration, the name of Erin, or Ierne, or Ireland.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caledonia', 'GPE'), ('Erin', 'PERSON'), ('Ierne', 'PERSON'), ('Ireland', 'GPE')"
"The
 victorious Goths, who were not inferior in numbers,
 prevailed in the contest, by the decisive advantages of
 exercise and discipline.","('Goths', 'NORP')"
"The 
 present age is satisfied with the simple and rational
 opinion that the islands of Great Britain and Ireland were
 gradually peopled from the adjacent continent of Gaul.","('Great Britain', 'GPE'), ('Ireland', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'LOC')"
"The Alemanni invade Gaul , A.D. 365.","('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('365', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Alemanni, unable to prevent the devastation of
 their villages, fixed their camp on a lofty and almost
 inaccessible mountain in the modern duchy of Wirtemberg, and
 resolutely expected the approach of the Romans.","('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Wirtemberg', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The Batavians were
 degraded from their rank, stripped of their arms and
 condemned to be sold for slaves to the highest bidder.","('Batavians', 'NORP')"
The Britain.,"('Britain', 'GPE')"
"The Christians had
 forgotten the spirit of the Gospel, and the Pagans had
 imbibed the spirit of the church.","('Christians', 'NORP'), ('Pagans', 'NORP')"
The Danube—Death of Valentinian—,"('The Danube—Death of Valentinian', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
The EAST.,"('EAST', 'ORG')"
"The East; and V. The Danube - will impress a more distinct image of the military
 state of the empire under the reigns of Valentinian and
 Valens.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
The East—,"('East', 'LOC')"
"The Euphrates was
 protected by the valour of Arintheus.","('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Arintheus', 'PERSON')"
"The Goths had contracted an hereditary attachment for the
 Imperial house of Constantine, of whose power and liberality
 they had received so many signal proofs.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The Government and Death of Jovian—Election of Valentinian, who Associates His Brother Valens, and Makes the Final Division of the Eastern and Western Empires—Revolt of Procopius—Civil and Ecclesiastical Administration—Germany—Britain—Africa.—","('Government', 'ORG'), ('Death of Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('Valentinian', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Makes the Final Division of the Eastern and Western Empires', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Civil and Ecclesiastical Administration', 'ORG'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"The Heruli, who inhabited the marshy lands near the lake 
 Maeotis, were renowned for their strength and agility; and
 the assistance of their light infantry was eagerly
 solicited, and highly esteemed, in all the wars of the
 barbarians.","('Heruli', 'PERSON'), ('Maeotis', 'LOC')"
"The Homoousians were fortified by the
 reconciliation of fifty-nine Macedonian, or Semi-Arian,
 bishops but their secret reluctance to embrace the divinity
 of the Holy Ghost clouded the splendour of the triumph; and
 the declaration of Valens, who, in the first years of his
 reign, had imitated the impartial conduct of his brother,
 was an important victory on the side of Arianism.","('Homoousians', 'NORP'), ('fifty-nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('Macedonian', 'NORP'), ('Semi-Arian', 'NORP'), ('the Holy Ghost', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('the first years', 'DATE'), ('Arianism', 'ORG')"
"The Persians were surprised and repulsed under the
 walls of Artogerassa by a bold and well-concerted sally of
 the besieged.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Artogerassa', 'PERSON')"
"The Quadi
 complained that the ground for an intended fortress had been
 marked out on their territories, and their complaints were
 urged with so much reason and moderation, that Equitius,
 master-general of Illyricum, consented to suspend the
 prosecution of the work till he should be more clearly
 informed of the will of his sovereign.","('Quadi', 'PERSON'), ('Equitius', 'PERSON'), ('Illyricum', 'ORG')"
"The Quadi were much declined from
 that formidable power which in the time of Marcus Antoninus,
 had spread terror to the gates of Rome.","('Quadi', 'NORP'), ('Marcus Antoninus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The Roman
 army was saved by an inglorious, perhaps a necessary,
 treaty;(1) and the first moments of peace were consecrated by the pious Jovian to restore the domestic tranquillity of the
 church and state.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Jovian', 'NORP')"
"The Roman province was reduced 
 to the state of civilised and peaceful servitude: the rights
 of savage freedom were contracted to the narrow limits of
 Caledonia.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Caledonia', 'GPE')"
"The Romans at
 length prevailed, with the loss of about twelve hundred men.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('about twelve hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Saxon boats drew so little water that
 they could easily proceed four-score or an hundred miles up
 the great rivers; their weight was so inconsiderable that
 they were transported on waggons from one river to another;
 and the pirates who had entered the mouth of the Seine or of
 the Rhine might descend,  A.D. 371 with the rapid stream of the Rhone,
 into the Mediterranean.","('Saxon', 'NORP'), ('four-score or an hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Seine', 'LOC'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('A.D. 371', 'FAC'), ('Rhone', 'LOC'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC')"
"The Saxons, surrounded and outnumbered, were forced to
 relinquish their spoil, and to yield a select band of their
 tall and robust youth to serve in the Imperial armies.","('Saxons', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"The Scots and Picts. 
 II.","('Scots', 'NORP'), ('Picts', 'NORP')"
"The acclamations of the
 people seated him once more on the archiepiscopal throne,
 and he wisely accepted or anticipated the invitation of
 Jovian.","('Jovian', 'PERSON')"
"The active policy of Valentinian was
 continually employed in adding new fortifications to the
 security of the frontier; but the abuse of this policy
 provoked the just resentment of the barbarians.","('Valentinian', 'GPE')"
"The aged Sallust, who had long observed the irregular
 fluctuations of popular assemblies, proposed, under pain of
 death, that none of those persons whose rank in the service
 might excite a party in their favour, should appear in
 public on the day of the inauguration","('Sallust', 'PERSON'), ('the day', 'DATE')"
"The alliance of Faustina, the widow of the
 emperor Constantius, who intrusted herself and her daughter
 to the hands of the usurper, added dignity and reputation to
 his cause.","('Faustina', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"The ambassadors of the Alemanni had been offended by the
 harsh and haughty behaviour of Ursacius, master of the
 offices;(88) who, by an act of unseasonable parsimony, had 
 diminished the value, as well as the quantity, of the
 presents to which they were entitled, either from custom or
 treaty, on the accession of a new emperor.","('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Ursacius', 'PERSON'), ('88', 'CARDINAL')"
"The ancients, who had a
 very faint and imperfect knowledge of the great peninsula of
 Africa, were sometimes tempted to believe that the torrid
 zone must ever remain destitute of inhabitants;(126) and they 
 sometimes amused their fancy by filling the vacant space
 with headless men, or rather monsters,(127) with horned and 
 cloven-footed satyrs,(128) with fabulous centaurs,(129) and 
 with human pigmies, who waged a bold and doubtful warfare
"The appellation of
 Hendinos was given to the king or general, and the title
 of Sinistus to the high-priest of the nation.","('Hendinos', 'PERSON'), ('Sinistus', 'PERSON')"
"The archbishop, who asserted,
 with inflexible pride, (72) the truth of his opinions and the dignity of his rank, was left in the free possession of his conscience and his throne.","('72', 'CARDINAL')"
"The art of magic, as it
 was more cruelly punished, was more strictly proscribed: but
 the emperor admitted a formal distinction to protect the
 ancient methods of divination, which were approved by the
 senate and exercised by the Tuscan haruspices.","('Tuscan', 'NORP')"
"The arts of magic were equally 
 condemned by the public opinion and by the laws of Rome,
 but, as they tended to gratify the most imperious passions
 of the heart of man, they were continually proscribed and
 continually practised.(48)","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The banks of the Rhine, from its source to the 
 straits of the ocean, were closely planted with strong
 castles and convenient towers; new works and new arms were
 invented by the ingenuity of a prince who was skilled in the
 mechanical arts; and his numerous levies of Roman and
 barbarian youth were severely trained in all the exercises
 of war.","('Rhine', 'FAC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The body of Jovian 
 was sent to Constantinople to be interred with his
 predecessors, and the sad procession was met on the road by
 his wife Charito, the daughter of Count Lucillian, who still
 wept the recent death of her father, and was hastening to
 dry her tears in the embraces of an Imperial husband.","('Jovian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Charito', 'PERSON'), ('Lucillian', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"The body of the people was infected with
 a spirit of discontent: they regretted the justice and the
 abilities of Sallust, who had been imprudently dismissed
 from the praefecture of the East.","('Sallust', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The cages of those trusty guards were always placed near the bed-chamber of Valentinian, who frequently amused his eyes with the grateful spectacle of seeing them tear and devour the bleeding limbs of the malefactors who were abandoned to their rage.","('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"The calamities which the afflicted provincials 
 continued to experience from foreign war and domestic
 tyranny were aggravated by the feeble and corrupt
 administration of the eunuchs of Constantius; and the
 transient relief which they might obtain from the virtues of
 Julian was soon lost by the absence and death of their
 benefactor.","('Constantius', 'ORG'), ('Julian', 'PERSON')"
"The cause of the Gothic war, A.D. 366","('the Gothic war', 'EVENT'), ('A.D. 366', 'DATE')"
"The celerity and success
 with which he executed an important commission recommended
 him to the favour of Jovian, and to the honourable command
 of the second school, or company, of Targeteers of the
 domestic guards.","('Jovian', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Targeteers', 'ORG')"
"The charge of the Tripolitans was declared to
 be false and frivolous, and Palladius himself was sent back
 from Treves to Africa with a special commission to discover
 and prosecute the authors of this impious conspiracy against
 the representatives of the sovereign.","('Tripolitans', 'PERSON'), ('Palladius', 'PERSON'), ('Treves', 'LOC'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"The circumstantial narrative has been composed by the friends and admirers of Basil; and as soon as we have
 stripped away a thick coat of rhetoric and miracle, we shall
 be astonished by the unexpected mildness of the Arian tyrant, who admired the firmness of his character, or was apprehensive, if he employed violence, of a general revolt in the province of Cappadocia.","('Basil', 'PERSON'), ('Arian', 'NORP'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE')"
"The citizens of
 London, who had almost despaired of their safety, threw open
 their gates, and, as soon as Theodosius had obtained from
 the court of Treves the important aid of a military
 lieutenant and a civil governor, he executed with wisdom and
 vigour the laborious task of the deliverance of Britain.","('London', 'GPE'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Treves', 'PERSON'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"The city of Artogerassa(134) was the only place of 
 Armenia which presumed to resist the effort of his arms.","('Artogerassa', 'GPE'), ('134', 'CARDINAL'), ('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"The coarse and
 undistinguishing pencil of Ammianus has delineated his
 bloody figures with tedious and disgusting accuracy.","('Ammianus', 'PERSON')"
"The consternation of the Pagan world was dispelled by a wise and gracious edict of toleration, in which Jovian explicitly declared that, although he should severely punish
 the sacrilegious rites of magic, his subjects might
 exercise, with freedom and safety, the ceremonies of the
 ancient worship.","('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('Jovian', 'PERSON')"
"The contending parties supported their
 claims by mutual reproaches of perfidy and ambition; and it
 should seem that the original treaty was expressed in very
 obscure terms, since they were reduced to the necessity of
 making their inconclusive appeal to the partial testimony of
 the generals of the two nations who had assisted at the
 negotiations.(136)","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('136', 'CARDINAL')"
"The country was alarmed, and the two roads, which were only
 separated by an interval of three miles, had been occupied
 by a thousand archers on horseback, under the command of a
 count and a tribune.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('three miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('a thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
The cruelty of Valentinian and Valens.,"('Valentinian', 'NORP'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"The cultivation of the earth might introduce a
 more accurate separation of property, and the habits of a
 sedentary life; but the love of arms and rapine was still
 the ruling passion of the Picts, and their warriors, who
 stripped themselves for a day of battle, were distinguished,
 in the eyes of the Romans, by the strange fashion of
 painting their naked bodies with gaudy colours and fantastic
 figures.","('Picts', 'NORP'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The death of Athanasius was the signal of the
 persecution of Egypt; and the Pagan minister of Valens, who
 forcibly seated the worthless Lucius on the archiepiscopal
 throne, purchased the favour of the reigning party by the
 blood and sufferings of their Christian brethren.","('Athanasius', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Pagan', 'NORP'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Lucius', 'PERSON'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The decent, but peremptory, refusal of these
 extravagant demands was signified to the barbarians by
 Victor, master-general of the cavalry, who expressed, with
 force and dignity, the just complaints of the emperor of the
 East.(146)","('Victor', 'PERSON'), ('146', 'CARDINAL')"
"The dispassionate
 judgment of the Western emperor could clearly perceive, and
 accurately pursue, his own and the public interest; and the
 sovereign of the East, who imitated with equal docility the
 various examples which he received from his elder brother,
 was sometimes guided by the wisdom and virtue of the
 praefect Sallust.","('Western', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Sallust', 'PERSON')"
"The disputed 
 possession of some salt-pits(98) engaged the Alemanni and the 
 Burgundians in frequent contests: the latter were easily
 tempted by the secret solicitations and liberal offers of
 the emperor; and their fabulous descent from the Roman
 soldiers who had formerly been left to garrison the
 fortresses of Drusus was admitted with mutual credulity, as
 it was conducive to mutual interest. (99)","('98', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Drusus', 'PERSON')"
"The domestic assassin was instigated and protected
 by the Romans; (92) and the violation of the laws of humanity 
 and justice betrayed their secret apprehension of the
 weakness of the declining empire.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('92', 'CARDINAL')"
"The eagerness of the troops, who pressed
 him to nominate his colleague, was justified by the
 dangerous situation of public affairs; and Valentinian
 himself was conscious that the abilities of the most active
 mind were unequal to the defence of the distant frontiers of
 an invaded monarchy.","('Valentinian', 'NORP')"
"The eastern coast of Caledonia may be considered as a
 level and fertile country, which, even in a rude state of
 tillage, was capable of producing a considerable quantity of
 corn; and the epithet of cruitnich, or wheat-eaters,
 expressed the contempt or envy of the carnivorous
 highlander.","('Caledonia', 'GPE')"
"The emperor Valens, who respected the obligations of the
 treaty, and who was apprehensive of involving the East in a
 dangerous war, ventured with slow and cautious measures, to
 support the Roman party in the kingdoms of Iberia and
 Armenia.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('the Roman party', 'ORG'), ('Iberia', 'LOC'), ('Armenia', 'GPE')"
"The emperor could not sustain
 the indiscreet and malicious raillery of the people of
 Antioch.(11) He was impatient to possess the palace of 
 Constantinople, and to prevent the ambition of some
 competitor who might occupy the vacant allegiance of Europe;
 but he soon received the grateful intelligence that his
 authority was acknowledged from the Thracian Bosphorus to
 the Atlantic ocean.","('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('the Thracian Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Atlantic', 'LOC')"
"The emperor devoutly assisted at
 the solemn service of the cathedral; and, instead of a
 sentence of banishment, subscribed the donation of a
 valuable estate for the use of an hospital which Basil had
 lately founded in the neighbourhood of Casarea.(73) 3. I am not able to discover that any law (such as Theodosius afterwards enacted against the Arians) was published by Valens against the Athanasian sectaries; and the edict which
 excited the most violent clamours may not appear so extremely reprehensible.","('Basil', 'PERSON'), ('Casarea', 'GPE'), ('73', 'CARDINAL'), ('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Theodosius', 'PERSON'), ('Arians', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Athanasian', 'NORP')"
"The emperor had observed that several of his subjects, gratifying their lazy disposition under the pretence of religion, had associated themselves
 with the monks of Egypt; and he directed the count of the East to drag them from their solitude, and to compel those deserters of society to accept the fair alternative of renouncing their temporal possessions, or of discharging the public duties of men and citizens.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The emperor himself, with a light and
 unencumbered band, condescended to pass the Rhine, marched
 fifty miles into the country, and would infallibly have
 seized the object of his pursuit, if his judicious measures
 had not been defeated by the impatience of the troops.","('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('fifty miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"The emperor in person, accompanied by his son
 Gratian, passed the Rhine at the head of a formidable army,
 which was supported on both flanks by Jovinus and Severus,
 the two master-generals of the cavalry and infantry of the
 West.","('Gratian', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Jovinus', 'PERSON'), ('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"The emperor of the West established his temporary
 residence at Milan, and the emperor of the East returned to
 Constantinople to assume the dominion of fifty provinces, of
 whose language he was totally ignorant.(33)
