Sentence,Entities
(110),"('110', 'CARDINAL')"
(111),"('111', 'CARDINAL')"
(112),"('112', 'CARDINAL')"
(43),"('43', 'CARDINAL')"
(45),"('45', 'CARDINAL')"
(53),"('53', 'CARDINAL')"
"(7)
Ambition of Galerius disappointed by two revolutions 
 But, within less than eighteen months, two unexpected
 revolutions overturned the ambitious schemes of Galerius.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('less than eighteen months', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Galerius', 'ORG')"
"1. The horrid practice, so familiar to the
 ancients, of exposing or murdering their newborn infants,
 was becoming every day more frequent in the provinces, and
 especially in Italy.","('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
31st March,"('31st March', 'DATE')"
"A
 general act of oblivion quieted the minds and settled the
 property of the people both in Italy and in Africa. (72)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"A
 large body of Moors deserted to the enemy, allured by the
 promise of a large donative ; and, if it be true that they
 had been levied by Maximian in his African war, preferring
 the natural feelings of gratitude to the artificial ties of
 allegiance.","('Moors', 'NORP'), ('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('his African war', 'EVENT')"
"A considerable
 part of his victorious army was transported over the
 Bosphorus in small vessels, and the decisive engagement was
 fought soon after their landing on the heights of
 Chrysopolis, or, as it is now called, of Scutari.","('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Chrysopolis', 'GPE'), ('Scutari', 'PERSON')"
"A contemporary writer assigns two other
 causes for the failure of the expedition; but they are both
 of such a nature that a cautious historian will scarcely
 venture to adopt them.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"A formidable army of sycophants
 and delators invaded Africa; the rich and the noble were
 easily convicted of a connection with the rebels, and those
 among them who experienced the emperor's clemency were only
 punished by the confiscation of their estates.","('Africa', 'LOC')"
"A secret but irrevocable
 sentence of death was pronounced against the usurper he
 obtained only the same favour which he had indulged to
 Severus, and it was published to the world that, oppressed
 by the remorse of his repeated crimes, he strangled himself
 with his own hands.","('Severus', 'PERSON')"
"A very minute survey
 appears to have been taken of their real estates; and,
 wherever there was the slightest suspicion of concealment,
 torture was very freely employed to obtain a sincere
 declaration of their personal wealth.  (21)","('very minute', 'TIME')"
"A.D. 274
 I.","('A.D. 274', 'DATE')"
"A.D. 306 28th October  
 Maxentius was the son of the emperor Maximian, and he had
 married the daughter of Galerius.","('A.D. 306 28th', 'DATE'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
A.D. 306 July 25.,"('A.D. 306', 'DATE'), ('July 25', 'DATE')"
A.D. 306-312,"('A.D. 306-312', 'DATE')"
A.D. 307.,"('307', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 308six emperors.,"('A.D. 308six', 'DATE')"
A.D. 310.,"('310', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 311.,"('311', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 312.,"('312', 'CARDINAL')"
"A.D. 313
Maximin had
 been the secret ally of Maxentius, and, without being
 discouraged by his fate, he resolved to try the fortune of a
 civil war.","('A.D. 313', 'DATE'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON')"
A.D. 313.,"('313', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 314,"('A.D. 314', 'DATE')"
A.D. 315. 8th Oct,"('A.D. 315', 'DATE'), ('8th Oct', 'DATE')"
A.D. 322,"('A.D. 322', 'DATE')"
A.D. 323,"('A.D. 323', 'DATE')"
A.D. 323.,"('323', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 324,"('A.D. 324', 'DATE')"
"About
 forty miles from thence a more severe contest awaited him.","('About\r\n forty miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"About that time the avarice of Galerius, or perhaps
 the exigencies of the state, had induced him to make a very
 strict and rigorous inquisition into the property of his
 subjects for the purpose of a general taxation, both on
 their lands and on their persons.","('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"According to the forms of 
 the constitution, Severus acknowledged the supremacy of the
 western emperor; but he was absolutely devoted to the
 commands of his benefactor Galerius, who, reserving to
 himself the intermediate countries from the confines of
 Italy to those of Syria, firmly established his power over
 three-fourths of the monarchy.","('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('over\r\n three-fourths', 'CARDINAL')"
"According to the system of
 government instituted by Diocletian, Italy, and perhaps
 Africa, were designed for his department in the empire.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"After a fruitless
 negotiation, in which the two princes attempted to seduce
 the fidelity of each other's adherents, they had recourse to
 arms.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"After a signal victory over the Franks
 and Alemanni, several of their princes were exposed by his
 order to the wild beasts in the amphitheatre of Treves, and
 the people seem to have enjoyed the spectacle, without
 discovering, in such a treatment of royal captives, anything
 that was repugnant to the laws of nations or of humanity. (41)
Tyranny of Maxentius in Italy and Africa.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Treves', 'LOC'), ('Maxentius', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"After he had lost the assistance, and
 disdained the moderate counsels, of Diocletian, the second
 period of his active life was a series of public calamities
 and personal mortifications, which were terminated, in about
 three years, by an ignominious death.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('about\r\n three years', 'DATE')"
"After the death of Galerius, her ample
 possessions provoked the avarice, and her personal
 attractions excited the desires, of his successor, Maximin.
  (81)","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON')"
"After the death of Maximian, his titles 
 according to the established custom, had been erased, and
 his statues thrown down with ignominy.","('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"After the defeat of Maxentius the victorious emperor passed
 no more than two or three months in Rome, which he visited
 twice during the remainder of his life to celebrate the
 solemn festivals of the tenth and of the twentieth years of
 his reign.","('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('three months', 'DATE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('the tenth and of the twentieth years', 'DATE')"
"Among so many crimes and misfortunes, occasioned by the
 passions of the Roman princes, there is some pleasure in
 discovering a single action which may be ascribed to their
 virtue.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"An hundred
 and thirty of these were furnished by Egypt and the adjacent
 coast of Africa.","('An hundred\r\n and thirty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"An hundred and ten sailed from the ports of
 Phoenicia and the isle of Cyprus; and the maritime countries
 of Bithynia, Ionia, and Caria were likewise obliged to
 provide an hundred and ten galleys.","('An hundred and ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Phoenicia', 'GPE'), ('Cyprus', 'GPE'), ('Bithynia', 'GPE'), ('Ionia', 'GPE'), ('Caria', 'GPE'), ('an hundred and ten', 'CARDINAL')"
"An hundred and thirty vessels were
 destroyed, five thousand men were slain, and Amandus, the
 admiral of the Asiatic fleet, escaped with the utmost
 difficulty to the shores of Chalcedon.","('An hundred and thirty', 'CARDINAL'), ('five thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Amandus', 'PERSON'), ('Asiatic', 'NORP'), ('Chalcedon', 'GPE')"
"An incursion of the Franks had summoned Constantine,
 with a part of his army, to the banks of the Rhine, the
 remainder of the troops were stationed in the southern
 provinces of Gaul, which lay exposed to the enterprises of
 the Italian emperor, and a considerable treasure was
 deposited in the city of Arles.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Arles', 'GPE')"
"An inroad of the Franks summoned Constantine to the
 Rhine, and the hostile approach of the sovereign of Asia
 demanded the immediate presence of Licinius.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON')"
"An obscure stranger was therefore raised to the throne of
 Italy, and the son of the late emperor of the West was left
 to enjoy the luxury of a private fortune in a villa a few
 miles distant from the capital.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('a few\r\n miles', 'QUANTITY')"
And conduct at Rome,"('Rome', 'GPE')"
"And if we except the
 death of Maximian, the reign of Constantine in Gaul seems to
 have been the most innocent and even virtuous period of his
 life.","('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"And yet a year had scarcely elapsed after the
 death of Maximin before the victorious emperors turned their
 arms against each other.","('a year', 'DATE'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON')"
"Anulinus, the Praetorian praefect, declared
 himself in favour of Maxentius, and drew after him the most
 considerable part of the troops accustomed to obey his
 commands.","('Anulinus', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON')"
"Apprehensive of the fatal consequences of
 delay, Constantine gave orders for an immediate assault; but
 the scaling-ladders were found too short for the height of
 the walls, and Marseilles might have sustained as long a
 siege as it formerly did against the arms of Caesar, if the
 garrison, conscious either of their fault or of their
 danger, had not purchased their pardon by delivering up the
 city and the person of Maximian.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Marseilles', 'GPE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'NORP')"
"As Maximin was alike destitute of abilities and of virtue,
 he was lamented neither by the people nor by the soldiers.","('Maximin', 'PERSON')"
"As a very regular series of
 the Imperial laws commences about this period, it would not
 be difficult to transcribe the civil regulations which
 employed the leisure of Constantine.","('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"As it was not possible to find in the capital of the
 empire a sculptor who was capable of adorning that public
 monument, the arch of Trajan, without any respect either for
 his memory or for the rules of propriety, was stripped of
 its most elegant figures.","('Trajan', 'PERSON')"
"As she
 had not any children herself, she condescended to adopt the
 illegitimate son of her husband, and invariably displayed
 towards the unhappy Candidianus the tenderness and anxiety
 of a real mother.","('Candidianus', 'PERSON')"
"As soon as Diocletian and Maximian had resigned the purple,
 their station, according to the rules of the new
 constitution, was filled by the two Caesars, Constantius and
 Galerius, who immediately assumed the title of Augustus. (1)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('Constantius', 'ORG'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('1', 'CARDINAL')"
"As soon as he was
 informed that Constantine was advancing towards him, he
 detached a large body of cavalry, which was defeated in an
 engagement near Brescia, and pursued by the Gallic legions
 as far as the gates of Verona.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Brescia', 'GPE'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Verona', 'GPE')"
"As soon as the
 Hellespont was open, a plentiful convoy of provisions flowed
 into the camp of Constantine, who had already advanced the
 operations of the siege.","('Hellespont', 'PRODUCT'), ('Constantine', 'GPE')"
"As soon as this obstacle was removed, the tranquillity of the Roman world was easily restored.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"At the head of 
 about forty thousand soldiers, he marched to encounter an
 enemy whose numbers were at least four times superior to his
 own.","('about forty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('at least four', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the head of a powerful army
 collected from Illyricum and the East, he entered Italy,
 resolved to revenge the death of Severus and to chastise the
 rebellious Romans; or, as he expressed his intentions, in
 the furious language of a barbarian, to extirpate the
 senate, and to destroy the people by the sword.","('Illyricum', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"At the head of his legions
 he passed the Danube, after repairing the bridge which had
 been constructed by Trajan, penetrated into the strongest
 recesses of Dacia, (100) and, when he had inflicted a severe 
 revenge, condescended to give peace to the suppliant Goths,
 on condition that, as often as they were required, they
 should supply his armies with a body of forty thousand
 soldiers. (101)","('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Dacia', 'PRODUCT'), ('100', 'CARDINAL'), ('Goths', 'NORP'), ('forty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('101', 'CARDINAL')"
"At the same time 
 Severus, a faithful servant, addicted to pleasure but not
 incapable of business, was sent to Milan to receive from the
 reluctant hands of Maximian the Caesarian ornaments and the
 possession of Italy and Africa. (6)","('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Caesarian', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('6', 'CARDINAL')"
Battle of Cibalis.,"('Battle of Cibalis', 'PERSON')"
Battle of Hadrianople.,"('Battle of Hadrianople', 'PERSON')"
"Battle of TurinA
 numerous army of Italians was assembled, under the
 lieutenants of Maxentius, in the plains of Turin.","('TurinA', 'GPE'), ('Italians', 'NORP'), ('Maxentius', 'GPE'), ('Turin', 'GPE')"
"Before
 he could establish his authority, or finish the negotiation
 which he appears to have entered into with his son
 Maxentius, the celerity of Constantine defeated all his
 hopes.","('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Before 
 Maxentius left Rome he consulted the Sibylline books.","('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Sibylline', 'PERSON')"
"Before he was surrounded, he prudently removed
 his person and treasures to Chalcedon in Asia; and as he was
 always desirous of associating companions to the hopes and
 dangers of his fortune, he now bestowed the title of Caesar
 on Martinianus, who exercised one of the most important
 offices of the empire. (109)
Battle of Chrysopolis
Such were still the resources, and such the abilities, of
 Licinius that, after so many successive defeats, he
 collected in Bithynia a new army of fifty or sixty thousand
 men, while the activity of Constantine was employed in the
 siege of Byzantium.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Martinianus', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('109', 'CARDINAL'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Bithynia', 'GPE'), ('fifty or sixty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Byzantium', 'GPE')"
"Besides the
 regular members of the senate, their sons, their
 descendants, and even their relations, enjoyed the vain
 privileges and supported the heavy burdens of the senatorial
 order; nor will it any longer excite our surprise that
 Constantine should be attentive to increase the number of
 persons who were included under so useful a description. (76)","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Birth, education and escape of Constantine.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"But
 the performance of the promised favour was either attended
 with so much delay, or accompanied with so many unequal
 conditions, that the fidelity of Bassianus was alienated
 rather than secured by the honourable distinction which he
 had obtained.","('Bassianus', 'ORG')"
"But
 the temper of mankind was altered, and it was no longer
 esteemed infamous for a Roman to survive his honour and
 independence.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But Constantine was in the
 thirty-second year of his age, in the full vigour both of
 mind and body, at the time when the eldest of his brothers
 could not possibly be more than thirteen years old.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n thirty-second year', 'DATE'), ('more than thirteen years old', 'DATE')"
"But Galerius, who was
 well acquainted with his character, soon obliged him to
 leave his dominions, and the last refuge of the disappointed
 Maximian was the court of his son-in-law Constantine. (33)","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('33', 'CARDINAL')"
"But Severus could obtain only
 an easy death and an Imperial funeral.","('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"But he survived his misfortune only three or four
 months.","('only three or four\r\n months', 'DATE')"
"But it was impossible that minds like those of 
 Maximian and his son could long possess in harmony an
 undivided power.","('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"But the
 skill of Maximian had concerted a prudent system of defence.","('Maximian', 'ORG')"
"But the
 tyrant of Italy rashly ventured to provoke a formidable
 enemy whose ambition had been hitherto restrained by
 considerations of prudence rather than by principles of
 justice.  (48)","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"But the
 veteran legions of Illyricum rallied under the standard of a
 leader who had been trained to arms in the school of Probus
 and Diocletian.","('Illyricum', 'ORG'), ('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"But the actions of Constantine were guided by
 reason, and not by resentment.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"But the armies of Rome, placed at a secure distance
 from danger, were enervated by indulgence and luxury.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"But the execution of Candidianus was an act of
 the blackest cruelty and ingratitude.","('Candidianus', 'PERSON')"
"But the impotent
 resentment of Maximian was no longer to be dreaded; and the
 moderate Constantius, though he might despise the dangers,
 was humanely apprehensive of the calamities, of civil war.","('Maximian', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"But the most important
 of his institutions are intimately connected with the new
 system of policy and religion, which was not perfectly
 established till the last and peaceful years of his reign.","('the last and peaceful years', 'DATE')"
"But the naval preparations of Constantine were in every
 respect much inferior to those of Licinius.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON')"
"But the strength of that warlike
 nation was now restored by a peace of near fifty years; a
 new generation had arisen, who no longer remembered the
 misfortunes of ancient days: the Sarmatians of the lake
 Maeotis followed the Gothic standard either as subjects or
 as allies, and their united force was poured upon the
 countries of Illyricum.","('near fifty years', 'DATE'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Maeotis', 'PERSON'), ('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('Illyricum', 'GPE')"
"But the vigilant emperor discovered
 the conspiracy before it was ripe for execution; and, after
 solemnly renouncing the alliance of Bassianus, despoiled him
 of the purple, and inflicted the deserved punishment on his
 treason and ingratitude.","('Bassianus', 'PERSON')"
"But these grateful prospects were soon
 succeeded by horror and astonishment; and the bloody
 executions which stained the palace of Nicomedia
 sufficiently convinced her that the throne of Maximin was
 filled by a tyrant more inhuman than himself.","('Nicomedia', 'PERSON'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON')"
"But these obscure anecdotes are 
 sufficiently refuted by an impartial view of the character
 and conduct of Diocletian.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"But when we recollect with how much ease, in the  more ancient civil wars, the zeal of party and the habits of military obedience had converted the native citizens of Rome
 into her most implacable enemies, we shall be inclined to
 distrust this extreme delicacy of strangers and barbarians
 who had never beheld Italy till they entered it in a hostile
 manner.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"By consenting to receive that honour from Maximian,
 Constantine seemed to embrace the cause of Rome and of the
 senate; but his professions were ambiguous, and his
 assistance slow and ineffectual.","('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"By suppressing the troops which were 
 usually stationed in Rome, Constantine gave the fatal blow
 to the dignity of the senate and people, and the disarmed
 capital was exposed, without protection, to the insults or
 neglect of its distant master.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"By this extraordinary effort
 of diligence, he arrived, with a harassed but formidable
 army, on the banks of the Thracian Bosphorus before the
 lieutenants of Licinius were apprised of his hostile
 intentions.","('the Thracian Bosphorus', 'ORG'), ('Licinius', 'ORG')"
"By this important service Turin
 deserved to experience the clemency and even favour of the
 conqueror.","('Turin', 'GPE')"
"By this victory of Constantine the Roman 
 world was again united under the authority of one emperor,
 thirty-seven years after Diocletian had divided his power
 and provinces with his associate Maximian.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('thirty-seven years', 'DATE'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"Byzantium surrendered to the power of Maximin
 after a siege of eleven days.","('Byzantium', 'GPE'), ('Maximin', 'PRODUCT'), ('eleven days', 'DATE')"
"Calling forth that spirit and
 those abilities by which he had deserved the friend ship of
 Galerius and the Imperial purple, he prepared himself for
 the contest, collected the forces of the East, and soon
 filled the plains of Hadrianople with his troops, and the
 Straits of the Hellespont with his fleet.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Hadrianople', 'LOC'), ('the\r\n Straits of the Hellespont', 'PRODUCT')"
"Campona, Margus, and Bononia, appear
 to have been the scenes of several memorable sieges and
 battles;  (99) and though Constantine encountered a very 
 obstinate resistance, he prevailed at length in the contest,
 and the Goths were compelled to purchase an ignominious
 retreat by restoring the booty and prisoners which they had
 taken.","('Campona', 'GPE'), ('Margus', 'PERSON'), ('Bononia', 'GPE'), ('99', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Goths', 'NORP')"
"Caprice or flattery had tempted Maxentius with the hopes of
 conquest; but these aspiring hopes soon gave way to the
 habits of pleasure and the consciousness of his
 inexperience.","('Maxentius', 'PERSON')"
Character and situation of Constantius,"('Constantius', 'GPE')"
"Citadels, constructed with no less
 skill than labour and expense, command every avenue into the
 plain, and on that side render Italy almost inaccessible to
 the enemies of the king of Sardinia. (54)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Sardinia', 'GPE'), ('54', 'CARDINAL')"
Civil war between Constantine and Maxentius.,"('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Maxentius', 'GPE')"
"Clemency, temperance, and moderation distinguished
 the amiable character of Constantius, and his fortunate
 subjects had frequently occasion to compare the virtues of
 their sovereign with the passions of Maximian, and even with
 the arts of Diocletian. (2)","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('2', 'CARDINAL')"
"Concealing, or at least attempting to conceal,
 from the public knowledge the misfortunes of his arms, (60) he 
 indulged himself in a vain confidence, which deferred the
 remedies of the approaching evil without deferring the evil
 itself.","('60', 'CARDINAL')"
"Confiding in the superiority of his genius and
 military power, he determined, without any previous injury,
 to exert them for the destruction of Licinius, whose
 advanced age and unpopular vices seemed to offer a very easy
 conquest.  (103)","('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('103', 'CARDINAL')"
"Constantia, his wife, and the sister of Constantine,
 interceded with her brother in favour of her husband, and
 obtained from his policy, rather than from his compassion, a
 solemn promise, confirmed by an oath, that after the
 sacrifice of Martinianus, and the resignation of the purple,
 Licinius himself should be permitted to pass the remainder
 of his life in peace and affluence.","('Constantia', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Martinianus', 'PERSON'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON')"
"Constantine
 directed his march from Thessallica towards that part of
 Thrace, till he found himself stopped by the broad and rapid
 stream of the Hebrus, and discovered the numerous army of
 Licinius, which filled the steep ascent of the hill, from
 the river to the city of Hadrianople.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Thessallica', 'GPE'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Hebrus', 'GPE'), ('Licinius', 'GPE'), ('Hadrianople', 'GPE')"
"Constantine
 received the mention of Valens with indignation and
 contempt.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON')"
"Constantine had always apprehended that the tyrant would
 consult the dictates of fear, and perhaps of prudence; and
 that, instead of risking his last hopes in a general
 engagement, he would shut himself up within the walls of
 Rome.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Constantine had lately given his
 sister Anastasia in marriage to Bassianus, a man of a
 considerable family and fortune, and had elevated his new
 kinsman to the rank of Caesar.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Anastasia', 'PERSON'), ('Bassianus', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"Constantine had taken post in a
 defile about half a mile in breadth, between a steep hill
 and a deep morass, and in that situation he steadily
 expected and repulsed the first attack of the enemy.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('about half a mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Constantine informed him of the
 melancholy event of his father's death, modestly asserted
 his natural claim to the succession, and respectfully
 lamented that the affectionate violence of his troops had
 not permitted him to solicit the Imperial purple in the
 regular and constitutional manner.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
Constantine no longer hesitated.,"('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Constantine passes the Alps 
 When Hannibal marched from Gaul into Italy, he was obliged
 first to discover and then to open a way over mountains, and
 through savage nations that had never yielded a passage to a
 regular army.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Hannibal', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Constantine preferred the road of the Cottian Alps, or, as
 it is now called, of Mount Cenis, and led his troops with
 such active diligence, that he descended into the plain of
 Piedmont before the court of Maxentius had received any
 certain intelligence of his departure from the banks of the
 Rhine.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('the Cottian Alps', 'LOC'), ('Mount Cenis', 'LOC'), ('Piedmont', 'GPE'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"Constantine was almost perpetually in motion, to
 exercise the legions or to inspect the state of the
 provinces.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Crispus and the young Constantine were soon afterwards declared Caesars in the West, while the younger Licinius was invested with the same dignity in the East.","('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"Crispus, a youth of the most
 amiable character, who had received with the title of Caesar
 the command of the Rhine, distinguished his conduct as well
 as valour in several victories over the Franks and Alemanni,
 and taught the barbarians of that frontier to dread the
 eldest son of Constantine, and the grandson of Constantius.
  (98)","('Crispus', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Alemanni', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('98', 'DATE')"
"Crispus, the emperor's eldest son,
 was intrusted with the execution of this daring enterprise,
 which he performed with so much courage and success, that he
 deserved the esteem, and most probably excited the jealousy,
 of his father.","('Crispus', 'PERSON')"
December,"('December', 'DATE')"
"Defeat and death of Severus
 According to the advice, or rather the orders, of his
 colleague, the emperor Severus immediately hastened to Rome,
 in the full confidence that, by his unexpected celerity, he
 should easily suppress the tumult of an unwarlike populace,
 commanded by a licentious youth.","('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Diocletian made several ineffectual efforts
 to alleviate the misfortunes of his daughter; and, as the
 last return that he expected for the Imperial purple, which
 he had conferred upon Maximin, he entreated that Valeria
 might be permitted to share his retirement of Salona, and to
 close the eyes of her afflicted father. (83)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Valeria', 'PERSON'), ('Salona', 'PERSON')"
"Diocletian was sincerely desirous of withdrawing
 himself from the world; he considered Galerius, who had
 married his daughter, as the firmest support of his family
 and of the empire; and he consented, without reluctance,
 that his successor should assume the merit as well as the
 envy of the important nomination.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"Discontent of the Romans at the apprehension of taxes
 II.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Distinguished by the splendour of his arms, he charged in
 person the cavalry of his rival; and his irresistible attack
 determined the fortune of the day.","('the day', 'DATE')"
"During the short period of his
 prosperity, he considered the rank of Caesar as unworthy of
 the age and merit of Licinius, and rather chose to reserve
 for him the place of Constantius, and the empire of the
 West.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"During the whole march Maxentius hung
 on their rear, but he very prudently declined a general
 engagement with those brave and desperate veterans.","('Maxentius', 'ORG')"
"During the whole of
 this melancholy transaction, it appears that Fausta
 sacrificed the sentiments of nature to her conjugal duties.
  (35)
Death of Galerius.","('Fausta', 'PERSON'), ('35', 'CARDINAL'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"Even Sicily
 furnished its proportion of troops; and the armies of
 Maxentius amounted to one hundred and seventy thousand foot
 and eighteen thousand horse.","('Sicily', 'GPE'), ('Maxentius', 'GPE'), ('one hundred and seventy thousand foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('eighteen thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Every hour increased 
 the danger of Constantine and the anxiety of his father,
 who, by repeated letters, expressed the warmest desire of
 embracing his son.","('Every hour', 'TIME'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Exploits like these were no doubt honourable 
 to Constantine and beneficial to the state; but it may
 surely be questioned whether they can justify the
 exaggerated assertion of Eusebius, that ALL SCYTHIA, as far
 as the extremity of the North, divided as it was into so
 many names and nations of the most various and savage
 manners, had been added by his victorious arms to the Roman
 empire. (102)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Eusebius', 'PERSON'), ('North', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('102', 'CARDINAL')"
February,"('February', 'DATE')"
First civil war between them.,"('First', 'ORDINAL')"
"For some time the policy of Galerius
 supplied him with delays and excuses, but it was impossible
 long to refuse so natural a request of his associate without
 maintaining his refusal by arms.","('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"For the first, and indeed for the last time, 
 the Roman world was administered by Six emperors.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Six', 'CARDINAL')"
"Forty thousand Moors and Carthaginians had
 been raised since the reduction of Africa.","('Forty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Carthaginians', 'NORP'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"From the inconsiderable forces which in 
 this important contest two such powerful monarchs brought
 into the field, it may be inferred that the one was suddenly
 provoked, and that the other was unexpectedly surprised.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Games and festivals were 
 instituted to preserve the fame of his victory, and several
 edifices, raised at the expense of Maxentius, were dedicated
 to the honour of his successful rival.","('Maxentius', 'PERSON')"
General peace and laws of Constantine.,"('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Habituated to the baths and theatres of Rome, they took the
 field with reluctance, and were chiefly composed of veterans
 who had almost forgotten, or of new levies who had never
 acquired, the use of arms and the practice of war.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Had he persevered in this resolution, he might have ended
 his life with less dignity, indeed, than in his first
 retirement, yet, however, with comfort and reputation.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Had they not been restrained by motives of a more
 interested nature, they would probably have answered
 Galerius in the words of Caesar's veterans:","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"He
 survived his retreat from Italy about four years; and,
 wisely relinquishing his views of universal empire, he
 devoted the remainder of his life to the enjoyment of
 pleasure and to the execution of some works of public
 utility, among which we may distinguish the discharging into
 the Danube the superfluous waters of the lake Pelso, and the
 cutting down the immense forests that encompassed it: an
 operation worthy of a monarch, since it gave an extensive
 country to the agriculture of his Pannonian subjects. (36)","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('about four years', 'DATE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Pelso', 'LOC'), ('Pannonian', 'NORP'), ('36', 'CARDINAL')"
"He 
 was received with respect by that artful prince, and with
 the appearance of filial tenderness by the empress Fausta.","('Fausta', 'PERSON')"
"He consented to leave his rival, or, as he again styled Licinius, his friend and brother, in the possession of Thrace, Asia Minor, Syria, and Egypt; but the provinces of Pannonia, Dalmatia, Dacia, Macedonia, and Greece were yielded to the Western empire, and the dominions of Constantine now extended from the confines of Caledonia to the extremity of Peloponnesus.","('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Asia Minor', 'LOC'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Pannonia', 'GPE'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE'), ('Dacia', 'GPE'), ('Macedonia', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Caledonia', 'GPE'), ('Peloponnesus', 'GPE')"
"He considered with
 attention the approaching contest between the masters of
 Italy and the emperor of the East, and was prepared to
 consult his own safety or ambition in the event of the war.
  (24)
Galerius invades Italy","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('24', 'CARDINAL'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"He constructed artificial mounds of
 earth of an equal height with the ramparts of Byzantium.","('Byzantium', 'GPE')"
"He deserved his fate;
 but we should find more reason to applaud the humanity of
 Constantine if he had spared an old man, the benefactor of
 his father and the father of his wife.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"He ended his life in the Imperial palace of
 York, fifteen months after he had received the title of
 Augustus, and almost fourteen years and a half after he had
 been promoted to the rank of Caesar.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('York', 'GPE'), ('fifteen months', 'DATE'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('almost fourteen years and a half', 'DATE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON')"
"He entreated; but 
 as he could no longer threaten, his prayers were received
 with coldness and disdain; and the pride of Maximin was
 gratified in treating Diocletian as a suppliant, and his
 daughter as a criminal.","('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"He filled Rome
 and Italy with armed troops, connived at their tumults,
 suffered them with impunity to plunder, and even to
 massacre, the defenceless people;  (46) and indulging them in 
 the same licentiousness which their emperor enjoyed,
 Maxentius often bestowed on his military favourites the
 splendid villa, or the beautiful wife, of a senator.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('46', 'DATE'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON')"
"He gave a
 private audience to the ambassadors who, in the name of the
 senate and people, conjured him to deliver Rome from a
 detested tyrant; and, without regarding the timid
 remonstrances of his council, he resolved to prevent the
 enemy, and to carry the war into the heart of Italy. (50)
Preparations","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('50', 'CARDINAL')"
"He had a wife still alive; but divorce was permitted by  the Roman law, and the fierce passions of the tyrant demanded an immediate gratification.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"He had no sooner expired in 
 his palace of Nicomedia than the two emperors, who were
 indebted for their purple to his favour, began to collect
 their forces, with the intention either of disputing or of
 dividing the dominions which he had left without a master.","('Nicomedia', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"He had promised his sister Constantia in
 marriage to that prince; but the celebration of the nuptials
 was deferred till after the conclusion of the war, and the
 interview of the two emperors at Milan, which was appointed
 for that purpose, appeared to cement the union of their
 families and interests.","('Constantia', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Milan', 'GPE')"
"He had the good fortune to 
 suppress a slight rebellion in Africa.","('Africa', 'LOC')"
"He inflicted the same treatment to which a defeat 
 would have exposed his own person and family, put to death
 the two sons of the tyrant, and carefully extirpated his
 whole race.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"He is acknowledged by Galerius, who gives him only the title of Caesar, and that of Augustus to Severus But his resentment insensibly
 subsided; and when he recollected the doubtful chance of
 war, when he had weighed the character and strength of his
 adversary, he consented to embrace the honourable
 accommodation which the prudence of Constantine had left
 open to him.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"He made his entry into the Imperial palace of
 Milan, and almost all the cities of Italy between the Alps
 and the Po not only acknowledged the power, but embraced
 with zeal the party of Constantine. (56)","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Po', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('56', 'CARDINAL')"
"He moved out of Syria, towards the frontiers of
 Bithynia, in the depth of winter.","('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Bithynia', 'GPE'), ('winter', 'DATE')"
"He persisted in the wise
 resolution of maintaining a balance of power in the divided
 empire, and he no longer hated Galerius when that aspiring
 prince had ceased to be an object of terror. (28)
Elevation of Licius to the rank of Augustus;A.d. 307.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('28', 'CARDINAL'), ('Elevation of Licius', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('307', 'CARDINAL')"
"He resolved to chastise as well
 as to repulse the insolent barbarians who had dared to
 invade the territories of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"He retired to 
 Nicomedia, rather with the view of gaining some time for
 negotiation than with the hope of any effectual defence.","('Nicomedia', 'PERSON')"
"He then encompassed Verona with
 strong lines, pushed his attacks with prudent vigour, and
 repelled a desperate sally of Pompeianus.","('Verona', 'GPE'), ('Pompeianus', 'PRODUCT')"
"He was
 unable to sustain the contempt of the Roman people.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"He was about eighteen years of age when his 
 father was promoted to the rank of Caesar; but that
 fortunate event was attended with his mother's divorce; and
 the splendour of an Imperial alliance reduced the son of
 Helena to a state of disgrace and humiliation.","('about eighteen years of age', 'DATE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Helena', 'PERSON')"
"He was at
 first received with humanity and treated with respect.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"He was detained some days
 under the walls of Heraclea; and he had no sooner taken
 possession of that city than he was alarmed by the
 intelligence that Licinius had pitched his camp at the
 distance of only eighteen miles.","('some days', 'DATE'), ('Heraclea', 'GPE'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('only eighteen miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"He was now advancing towards the twentieth year of his age,
 and the royalty of his birth, though unsupported either by
 merit or ambition, was sufficient to exasperate the jealous
 mind of Licinius.  (80)","('the twentieth year', 'DATE'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('80', 'CARDINAL')"
"He was the natural son
 of Galerius, the friend and benefactor of Licinius.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON')"
"He was well acquainted with the character and
 sentiments of Galerius, and sufficiently apprised that, if
 he wished to live, he must determine to reign.","('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"His
 diligence preserved his wife, his son, and his treasures,
 which he had deposited at Sirmium.","('Sirmium', 'ORG')"
"His
 father had undertaken a second journey into Gaul, with the
 hope of persuading Constantine, who had assembled an army on
 the frontier, to join the pursuit, and to complete the
 victory.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
His alliance with Licinius.,"('Licinius', 'ORG')"
"His ambassador, Mistrianus, was admitted
 to the audience of Constantine: he expatiated on the common
 topics of moderation and humanity, which are so familiar to
 the eloquence of the vanquished; represented in the most
 insinuating language that the event of the war was still
 doubtful, whilst its inevitable calamities were alike
 pernicious to both the contending parties; and declared that
 he was authorised to propose a lasting and honourable peace
 in the name of the two emperors his masters.","('Mistrianus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"His ample magazines secured him against the danger of
 famine; and as the situation of Constantine admitted not of
 delay, he might have been reduced to the sad necessity of
 destroying with fire and sword the Imperial city, the
 noblest reward of his victory, and the deliverance of which
 had been the motive, or rather indeed the pretence, of the
 civil war. (65)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('65', 'CARDINAL')"
"His ancient
 dignity, his experience, and his fame in arms added strength
 as well as reputation to the party of Maxentius. (22)","('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"His behaviour, in
 the first days of his reign, and the honourable reception
 which he gave to young Candidianus, inspired Valeria with a
 secret satisfaction, both on her own account, and on that of
 her adopted son.","('the first days', 'DATE'), ('Candidianus', 'PERSON'), ('Valeria', 'PERSON')"
"His birth and alliance
 seemed to offer him the fairest promise of succeeding to the
 empire; but his vices and incapacity procured him the same
 exclusion from the dignity of Caesar which Constantine had
 deserved by a dangerous superiority of merit.","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"His body, swelled by an intemperate course of life
 to an unwieldy corpulence, was covered with ulcers, and
 devoured by innumerable swarms of those insects who have
 given their name to a most loathsome disease; (37) but as 
 Galerius had offended a very zealous and powerful party
 among his subjects, his sufferings, instead of exciting
 their compassion, have been celebrated as the visible
 effects of divine justice.  (38)","('37', 'CARDINAL'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"His body, which had sunk very deep into the 
 mud, was found with some difficulty the next day.","('the next day', 'DATE')"
"His confused multitude of new levies was easily vanquished
 by the experienced veterans of the West.","('West', 'LOC')"
"His death was
 immediately succeeded by the elevation of Constantine.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"His death, which happened at Tarsus, was variously
 ascribed to despair, to poison, and to the divine justice.","('Tarsus', 'GPE')"
His dominion shared between Maximin and Licinius,"('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON')"
"His fame in
 arms, and, above all, the success of the Persian war, had
 elated his haughty mind, which was naturally impatient of a
 superior, or even of an equal.","('the Persian war', 'EVENT')"
"His military
 skill and the firmness of his troops restored the day and
 obtained a decisive victory.","('the day', 'DATE')"
"His nomination had been ratified by the
 consent of Licinius; and that artful prince, by the means of
 his emissaries, soon contrived to enter into a secret and
 dangerous correspondence with the new Caesar, to irritate
 his discontents, and to urge him to the rash enterprise of
 extorting by violence what he might in vain solicit from the
 justice of Constantine.","('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"His situation was almost desperate, but the efforts of despair are sometimes formidable, and the good sense of Constantine preferred a great and certain advantage to a third trial of the chance of arms.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('third', 'ORDINAL')"
"His son, who had
 persecuted and deserted him when alive, affected to display
 the most pious regard for his memory, and gave orders that a
 similar treatment should be immediately inflicted on all the
 statues that had been erected in Italy and Africa to the
 honour of Constantine.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"If Licinius persisted much longer in the
 defence, he exposed himself to be involved in the ruin of
 the place.","('Licinius', 'PERSON')"
"If it were possible to rely
 on the partial testimony of an injudicious writer, we might
 ascribe the abdication of Diocletian to the menaces of
 Galerius, and relate the particulars of a private
 conversation between the two princes, in which the former
 discovered as much pusillanimity as the latter displayed
 ingratitude and arrogance.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"In his
 flight he bestowed the precarious title of Caesar on Valens,
 his general of the Illyrian frontier. (89)
Battle of Mardia","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP'), ('89', 'CARDINAL')"
"In his last moments Constantius bequeathed 
 to his eldest son the care of the safety, as well as
 greatness, of the family; conjuring him to assume both the
 authority and the sentiments of a father with regard to the
 children of Theodora.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Theodora', 'PERSON')"
"In the
 West, Constantine and Maxentius affected to reverence their
 father Maximian.","('West', 'LOC'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"In the East, Licinius and Maximin honoured
 with more real consideration their benefactor Galerius.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"In the age of Constantine the peasants of the
 mountains were civilised and obedient subjects; the country
 was plentifully stocked with provisions, and the stupendous
 highways which the Romans had carried over the Alps opened
 several communications between Gaul and Italy.  (55)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('55', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the full confidence that
 the approaching death of Constantius would leave him sole
 master of the Roman world we are assured that he had
 arranged in his mind a long succession of future princes,
 and that he meditated his own retreat from public life after
 he should have accomplished a glorious reign of about twenty
 years.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('about twenty\r\n years', 'DATE')"
"In the late civil wars, the fortifications of that place, so
 justly considered as the key of Europe and Asia, had been
 repaired and strengthened; and as long as Licinius remained
 master of the sea, the garrison was much less exposed to the
 danger of famine than the army of the besiegers.","('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON')"
"In the sixth year of his reign Constantine visited
 the city of Autun, and generously remitted the arrears of
 tribute, reducing at the same time the proportion of their
 assessment from twenty-five to eighteen thousand heads,
 subject to the real and personal capitation. (40)","('the sixth year', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Autun', 'GPE'), ('twenty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('eighteen thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the use of victory Constantine neither deserved the
 praise of clemency nor incurred the censure of immoderate
 rigour. (71)","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"In this exalted state of glory it was impossible that
 Constantine should any longer endure a partner in the
 empire.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"In this place we might
 relate a wonderful exploit of Constantine which, though it
 can scarcely be paralleled either in poetry or romance, is
 celebrated, not by a venal orator devoted to his fortune,
 but by an historian, the partial enemy of his fame.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Indolence and fears of Maxentius
 While Constantine signalised his conduct and valour in the
 field, the sovereign of Italy appeared insensible of the
 calamities and danger of a civil war which raged in the
 heart of his dominions.","('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"Instead of
 following Constantius in the West, he remained in the
 service of Diocletian, signalising his valour in the wars of
 Egypt and Persia, and gradually rose to the honourable
 station of a tribune of the first order.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"Instead of imitating their eastern 
 pride and magnificence, Constantius preserved the modesty of
 a Roman prince.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It
 was in vain that, a few months after his abdication, his
 successors dedicated, under his name, those magnificent
 baths whose ruins still supply the ground as well as the
 materials for so many churches and convents.  (20)","('a few months', 'DATE'), ('20', 'CARDINAL')"
"It had been cemented by the freedom and dangers
 of a military life; they had advanced almost by equal steps
 through the successive honours of the service; and as soon
 as Galerius was invested with the Imperial dignity, he seems
 to have conceived the design of raising his companion to the
 same rank with himself.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"It is scarcely possible to observe a more decisive symptom of weakness, either in the character of the prince, or in the constitution of the government. (97)","('97', 'CARDINAL')"
"It is uncertain whether Maximian was previously
 acquainted with the conspiracy; but as soon as the standard
 of rebellion was erected at Rome, the old emperor broke from
 the retirement where the authority of Diocletian had
 condemned him to pass a life of melancholy solitude, and
 concealed his returning ambition under the disguise of
 paternal tenderness.","('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"It may be presumed 
 that an Imperial lover was seldom reduced to sigh in vain;
 but whenever persuasion proved ineffectual, he had recourse
 to violence; and there remains one memorable example of a
 noble matron who preserved her chastity by a voluntary
 death.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"It required such a fortunate mixture of
 different tempers and abilities as could scarcely be found,
 or even expected, a second time; two emperors without
 jealousy, two Caesars without ambition and the same general
 interest invariably pursued by four independent princes.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Caesars', 'ORG'), ('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"It still remains an authentic monument to contradict and
 confound those venal orators who were too well satisfied with their own situation to discover either vice or misery under the government of a generous sovereign. (94) 2. The 
 laws of Constantine against rapes were dictated with very little indulgence for the most amiable weaknesses of human nature; since the description of that crime was applied not only to the brutal violence which compelled, but even to the gentle seduction which might persuade, an unmarried woman, under the age of twenty-five, to leave the house of her parents.","('94', 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('the age of twenty-five', 'DATE')"
"It was
 insinuated to them that gratitude and liberality held a
 distinguished place among the virtues of Constantine; nor
 did that artful prince show himself to the troops till they
 were prepared to salute him with the names of Augustus and
 Emperor.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"It was fixed without
 consulting the interest or inclination of the princes of the
 West.","('West', 'LOC')"
"It was necessary to accept this humiliating condition; and the unhappy Valens, after a reign of a few days, was deprived of the purple and of his life.","('Valens', 'PERSON'), ('a few days', 'DATE')"
"It was not
 without great difficulty, and after several fruitless
 attempts, that Constantine found means to pass the river at
 some distance above the city, and in a place where the
 torrent was less violent.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"It was stipulated by the same treaty that three royal youths,
 the sons of the emperors, should be called to the hopes of the succession.","('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was the wish, and it soon
 became the hope, of every citizen that, after expelling from
 Italy their foreign tyrants, they should elect a prince who,
 by the place of his residence, and by his maxims of
 government, might once more deserve the title of Roman
 emperor.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"It was under his reign that
 the method of exacting a free gift from the senators was
 first invented; and as the sum was insensibly increased, the
 pretences of levying it, a victory, a birth, a marriage, or
 an Imperial consulship, were proportionately multiplied. (44)","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"It was with equal surprise and pleasure that, 
 on his arrival at a place called Saxa Rubra, about nine
 miles from Rome,  (66) he discovered the army of Maxentius 
 prepared to give him battle.  (67)","('Saxa Rubra', 'ORG'), ('about nine\r\n miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('66', 'DATE'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON')"
"Its
 principal strength consisted in a species of heavy cavalry,
 which the Romans, since the decline of their discipline, had
 borrowed from the nations of the East.","('Romans', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"July 3. 
 Instead of embracing such an active resolution, which might
 have changed the whole face of the war, the prudent Licinius
 expected the approach of his rival in a camp near
 Hadrianople, which he had fortified with an anxious care
 that betrayed his apprehension of the event.","('July 3', 'DATE'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Hadrianople', 'GPE')"
"Leaving the palace of Nicomedia 
 in the night, he travelled post through Bithynia, Thrace,
 Dacia, Pannonia, Italy, and, amidst the joyful acclamations
 of the people, reached the port of Boulogne in the very
 moment when his father was preparing to embark for Britain.
  (14)
Death of Constantius, and elevation of Constantine.","('Nicomedia', 'GPE'), ('Bithynia, Thrace,\r\n Dacia', 'GPE'), ('Pannonia', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Boulogne', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('14', 'CARDINAL'), ('Death of Constantius', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Licinius passed through
 that city, and, breaking down the bridge on the Save,
 hastened to collect a new army in Dacia and Thrace.","('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Dacia', 'GPE'), ('Thrace', 'GPE')"
"Licinius solicited and accepted the pardon of
 his offences, laid himself and his purple at the feet of his
 lord and master, was raised from the ground with insulting
 pity, was admitted the same day to the imperial banquet, and
 soon afterwards was sent away to Thessalonica, which had
 been chosen for the place of his confinement.","('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Thessalonica', 'GPE')"
"Licinius, whose manners as well as
 character were not unlike his own, seems to have engaged
 both his affection and esteem.","('Licinius', 'PERSON')"
"Many days were spent
 in doubtful and distant skirmishes; but at length the
 obstacles of the passage and of the attack were removed by
 the intrepid conduct of Constantine.","('Many days', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"March 
Before Constantine marched into Italy he had secured the
 friendship, or at least the neutrality, of Licinius, the
 Illyrian emperor.","('March', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP')"
"Maxentius considered himself as the legal
 sovereign of Italy, elected by the Roman senate and people;
 nor would he endure the control of his father, who
 arrogantly declared that by his name and abilities the rash
 youth had been established on the throne.","('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('the Roman senate', 'ORG')"
Maxentius declared emperor at Rome.,"('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Maxentius had imbibed the same implacable aversion to the
 senate which had characterised most of the former tyrants of
 Rome; nor was it possible for his ungrateful temper to
 forgive the generous fidelity which had raised him to the
 throne and supported him against all his enemies.","('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Maxentius, who considered the
 Praetorian guards as the firmest defence of his throne, had
 increased them to their ancient establishment; and they
 composed, including the rest of the Italians who were
 enlisted into his service, a formidable body of four-score
 thousand men.","('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Italians', 'NORP'), ('four-score\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Maxentius, who openly
 avowed his pretensions to the whole monarchy of the West,
 had already prepared a very considerable force to invade the
 Gallic provinces on the side of Rhaetia; and though he could
 not expect any assistance from Licinius, he was flattered
 with the hope that the legions of Illyricum, allured by his
 presents and promises, would desert the standard of that
 prince and unanimously declare themselves his soldiers and
 subjects.  (49)","('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Rhaetia', 'PERSON'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Illyricum', 'NORP')"
"Maximian conducted the captive emperor to Rome, and gave him
 the most solemn assurances that he had secured his life by
 the resignation of the purple.","('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Maximian either craftily
 invented, or hastily credited, a vain report of the death of
 Constantine.","('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Maximian gives his daughter Fausta, and the title of Augustus, to Constantine.","('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Fausta', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"Maximian, who conducted the siege in person, was
 soon convinced that he might waste his time and his army in
 the fruitless enterprise, and that he had nothing to hope
 either from force or famine.","('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"Misfortunes of Maximian 
 When Maximian had reluctantly abdicated the empire, the
 venal orators of the times applauded his philosophic
 moderation.","('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"Notwithstanding the recent
 tradition which assigns for her father a British king, (8) we 
 are obliged to confess that Helena was the daughter of an
 innkeeper; but at the same time we may defend the legality
 of her marriage against those who have represented her as
 the concubine of Constantius.  (9)","('British', 'NORP'), ('8', 'CARDINAL'), ('Helena', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
"Notwithstanding the superiority of his age and dignity, the
 indefatigable Maximian passed the Alps, and, courting a
 personal interview with the sovereign of Gaul, carried with
 him his daughter Fausta as the pledge of the new alliance.","('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Fausta', 'PERSON')"
Nov 11.,"('Nov 11', 'DATE')"
Of Galerius,"('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"On the first news of his perfidy and ingratitude,
 that prince returned by rapid marches from the Rhine to the
 Saone, embarked on the last-mentioned river at Chalons, and,
 at Lyons trusting himself to the rapidity of the Rhone,
 arrived at the gates of Arles with a military force which it
 was impossible for Maximian to resist, and which scarcely
 permitted him to take refuge in the neighbouring city of
 Marseilles.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Saone', 'NORP'), ('Chalons', 'GPE'), ('Lyons', 'PERSON'), ('Rhone', 'LOC'), ('Arles', 'GPE'), ('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Marseilles', 'GPE')"
"Period of civil wars and confusion A.D. 305-323
 THE balance of power established by Diocletian subsisted no
 longer than while it was sustained by the firm and dexterous
 hand of the founder.","('A.D. 305-323', 'DATE'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Pleasure was still the only business
 of Maxentius.","('Maxentius', 'GPE')"
"Rome had long since been accustomed
 to submit on the approach of a conqueror; nor could the
 temporary enthusiasm of the people have long contended
 against the discipline and valour of the legions.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Rome, according to the expression of an orator,
 recalled her armies, and the unfortunate Severus, destitute
 of force and of counsel, retired, or rather fled, with
 precipitation to Ravenna.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE')"
"Rome, which had so long regretted the absence,
 lamented, during the six years of his reign, the presence of
 her sovereign. (47)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('the six years', 'DATE')"
"Ruricius Pompeianus, a general
 distinguished by his valour and ability, had under his
 command the city of Verona, and all the troops that were
 stationed in the province of Venetia.","('Ruricius Pompeianus', 'PERSON'), ('Verona', 'GPE'), ('Venetia', 'GPE')"
Second civil war between Constantine and Licinius.,"('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'GPE'), ('Licinius', 'GPE')"
"Sensible of the
 increasing difficulties of his enterprise, the haughty
 Galerius made the first advances towards a reconciliation,
 and despatched two of his most considerable officers to
 tempt the Roman princes by the offer of a conference, and
 the declaration of his paternal regard for Maxentius, who
 might obtain much more from his liberality than he could
 hope from the doubtful chance of war.  (25)","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('25', 'CARDINAL')"
"She represented to the persons whom Maximin had employed on this occasion,  On this repulse, the love of Maximin was converted into fury; and as
 witnesses and judges were always at his disposal, it was
 easy for him to cover his fury with an appearance of legal
 proceedings, and to assault the reputation as well as the
 happiness of Valeria.","('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Valeria', 'PERSON')"
"Siege and battle of Verona
 From Milan to Rome, the Emilian and Flaminian highways
 offered an easy march of about four hundred miles; but
 though Constantine was impatient to encounter the tyrant, he
 prudently directed his operations against another army of
 Italians, who, by their strength and position, might either
 oppose his progress, or, in case of a misfortune, might
 intercept his retreat.","('Verona', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Emilian', 'NORP'), ('Flaminian', 'NORP'), ('about four hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Italians', 'NORP')"
"Siege of Byzantium, and naval victory of Crispus","('Siege of Byzantium', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Crispus', 'PERSON')"
"Since 
 Italy was no longer the seat of government, the naval
 establishments of Misenum and Ravenna had been gradually
 neglected; and as the shipping and mariners of the empire
 were supported by commerce rather than by war, it was
 natural that they should the most abound in the industrious
 provinces of Egypt and Asia.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Misenum', 'GPE'), ('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"So signal 
 a victory was celebrated by a magnificent triumph, and
 Maxentius exposed to the eyes of the people the spoils and
 captives of a Roman province.","('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
Submission and death of Licinius,"('Licinius', 'PERSON')"
"Such was the
 unworthy fate of the wife and daughter of Diocletian.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"That he might remove every suspicion, he resigned the
 Imperial purple a second time,  (34) professing himself at 
 length convinced of the vanity of greatness and ambition.","('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('34', 'DATE')"
"That intrepid
 general, when he had used every means of defence that the
 strength of the place or that of the garrison could afford,
 secretly escaped from Verona, anxious not for his own but
 for the public safety.","('Verona', 'GPE')"
"That wise prince, who sincerely
 wished to decline a war, with the difficulty and importance
 of which he was sufficiently acquainted, at first dissembled
 the insult, and sought for redress by the milder expedients
 of negotiation, till he was convinced that the hostile and
 ambitious designs of the Italian emperor made it necessary
 for him to arm in his own defence.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
"The
 Praetorians, conscious that their offences were beyond the
 reach of mercy, were animated by revenge and despair.","('Praetorians', 'PERSON')"
"The
 abdication of Diocletian and Maximian was succeeded by
 eighteen years of discord and confusion.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'PERSON'), ('eighteen years', 'DATE')"
"The
 apparent harmony of the empire was still preserved, and
 Constantine, who already possessed the substance, expected,
 without impatience, an opportunity of obtaining the honours
 of supreme power.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The
 circus resounded with their indignant clamours, and they
 tumultuously besieged the gates of the palace, reproaching
 the pusillanimity of their indolent sovereign, and
 celebrating the heroic spirit of Constantine.  (63)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('63', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 emperor of the West had only twenty thousand, and the
 sovereign of the East no more than five-and-thirty thousand,
 men.","('West', 'LOC'), ('only twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('more than five-and-thirty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 foundation of Constantinople, and the establishment of the
 Christian religion, were the immediate and memorable
 consequences of this revolution.","('Constantinople', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP')"
"The
 guardians of these ancient oracles were as well versed in
 the arts of this world as they were ignorant of the secrets
 of fate; and they returned him a very prudent answer, which
 might adapt itself to the event, and secure their
 reputation, whatever should be the chance of arms. (64)
Victory of Constantine near Rome.A.D. 312. 28th Oct.","('64', 'CARDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('312. 28th Oct', 'DATE')"
"The
 opposition of interest, and the memory of a recent war,
 divided the empire into two great hostile powers; but their
 mutual fears produced an apparent tranquillity, and even a
 feigned reconciliation, till the death of the elder princes,
 of Maximian, and more particularly of Galerius, gave a new
 direction to the views and passions of their surviving
 associates.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"The
 prudent father had judged him too young to sustain the
 weight of a diadem; but he hoped that, under the protection
 of princes who were indebted to his favour for the imperial
 purple, Candidianus might pass a secure and honourable life.","('Candidianus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 return of light displayed the victory of Constantine, and a
 field of carnage covered with many thousands of the
 vanquished Italians.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italians', 'NORP')"
"The
 skilful evolutions of Constantine divided and baffled this
 massy column of cavalry.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The
 troops on both sides displayed the same valour and
 discipline; and the victory was once more decided by the
 superior abilities of Constantine, who directed a body of
 five thousand men to gain an advantageous height, from
 whence, during the heat of the action, they attacked the
 rear of the enemy, and made a very considerable slaughter.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('five thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 wealth of Rome supplied an inexhaustible fund for his vain
 and prodigal expenses, and the ministers of his revenue were
 skilled in the arts of rapine.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The 
 first time that Constantine honoured the senate with his
 presence he recapitulated his own services and exploits in a
 modest oration, assured that illustrious order of his
 sincere regard, and promised to re-establish its ancient
 duty and privileges.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The 
 opinion of their own importance, and the assurance that
 Britain, Gaul, and Spain would acquiesce in their
 nomination, were diligently inculcated to the legions by the
 adherents of Constantine.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The 
 tranquillity of those elegant recesses of ease and luxury
 was disturbed by the impatient murmurs of the Romans, and a
 report was insensibly circulated that the sums expended in
 erecting those buildings would soon be required at their
 hands.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The Alps were then guarded by nature, they 
 are now fortified by art.","('Alps', 'LOC')"
"The British expedition, and an easy victory over the
 barbarians of Caledonia, were the last exploits of the reign
 of Constantius.","('British', 'NORP'), ('Caledonia', 'GPE'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON')"
The Gothic war.,"('The Gothic war', 'EVENT')"
"The Goths, who in the time
 of Claudius and Aurelian had felt the weight of the Roman
 arms, respected the power of the empire, even in the midst
 of its intestine divisions.","('Goths', 'NORP'), ('Claudius', 'PERSON'), ('Aurelian', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Hellespont and the Thracian
 Bosphorus formed their mutual boundary, and the banks of
 those narrow seas, which flowed in the midst of the Roman
 world, were covered with soldiers, with arms and with
 fortifications.","('Hellespont', 'PERSON'), ('the Thracian\r\n Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Parthian captives appear prostrate at the feet of a
 prince who never carried his arms beyond the Euphrates; and
 curious antiquarians can still discover the head of Trajan
 on the trophies of Constantine.","('Parthian', 'NORP'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The Praetorian guards
 felt how strongly their own interest and safety were
 connected with his cause; and a third army was soon
 collected, more numerous than those which had been lost in
 the battles of Turin and Verona.","('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Turin', 'GPE'), ('Verona', 'GPE')"
"The Roman world was now divided between Constantine and
 Licinius, the former of whom was master of the West, and the
 latter of the East.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The ambitious spirit of Galerius was scarcely reconciled
 to the disappointment of his views upon the Gallic provinces
 before the unexpected loss of Italy wounded his pride as
 well as power in a still more sensible part.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The answer of Valeria
 was such as became the daughter and widow of emperors; but it was tempered by the prudence which her defenceless condition compelled her to observe.","('Valeria', 'PERSON')"
"The army consisted
 of one hundred and fifty thousand foot and fifteen thousand
 horse, and as the cavalry was drawn, for the most part, from
 Phrygia and Cappadocia, we may conceive a more favourable
 opinion of the beauty of the horses than of the courage and
 dexterity of their riders.","('one hundred and fifty thousand foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('fifteen thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Phrygia', 'GPE'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE')"
"The army of Gaul
 was drawn up in two lines, according to the usual practice
 of war; but their experienced leader, perceiving that the
 numbers of the Italians far exceeded his own, suddenly
 changed his disposition, and, reducing the second, extended
 the front of his first line to a just proportion with that
 of the enemy Such evolutions, which only veteran troops can
 execute without confusion in a moment of danger, commonly
 prove decisive; but as this engagement began towards the
 close of the day, and was contested with great obstinacy
 during the whole night, there was less room for the conduct
 of the generals than for the courage of the soldiers.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italians', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the whole night', 'TIME')"
"The aspect of this cavalry was formidable, their weight
 almost irresistible; and as, on this occasion, their
 generals had drawn them up in a compact column or wedge,
 with a sharp point, and with spreading flanks, they
 flattered themselves that they should easily break and
 trample down the army of Constantine.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The behaviour of
 Constantia, and her relation to the contending parties,
 naturally recalls the remembrance of that virtuous matron
 who was the sister of Augustus and the wife of Antony.","('Constantia', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Antony', 'PERSON')"
The brothers and sisters of Constantine,"('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The cause was
 solemnly pleaded before the Praetorian guards; and those
 troops, who dreaded the severity of the old emperor,
 espoused the party of Maxentius. (32)","('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('32', 'CARDINAL')"
"The cavalry of Maxentius
 was principally composed either of unwieldy cuirassiers or
 of light Moors and Numidians.","('Maxentius', 'GPE'), ('Moors', 'NORP'), ('Numidians', 'NORP')"
"The celerity of Constantine's march has been compared to the
 rapid conquest of Italy by the first of the Caesars; nor is
 the flattering parallel repugnant to the truth of history,
 since no more than fifty-eight days elapsed between the
 surrender of Verona and the final decision of the war.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Caesars', 'LOC'), ('fifty-eight days', 'DATE'), ('Verona', 'GPE')"
"The children of Constantius by his second marriage were six
 in number, three of either sex, and whose Imperial descent
 might have solicited a preference over the meaner extraction
 of the son of Helena.","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Helena', 'PERSON')"
"The city of Susa, however, which is situated at the
 foot of Mount Cenis, was surrounded with walls, and provided
 with a garrison sufficiently numerous to check the progress
 of an invader; but the impatience of Constantine's troops
 disdained the tedious forms of a siege.","('Susa', 'GPE'), ('Mount Cenis', 'LOC'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The city was accessible only by a narrow 
 peninsula towards the west, as the other three sides were
 surrounded by the Adige, a rapid river, which covered the
 province of Venetia, from whence the besieged derived an
 inexhaustible supply of men and provisions.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Adige', 'GPE'), ('Venetia', 'GPE')"
"The commencement of the action was not limited to any term of years, and the consequences of the sentence were extended to the innocent offspring of such an irregular union. (95)","('years', 'DATE')"
"The confusion then became general, and the 
 dismayed troops of Maxentius, pursued by an implacable
 enemy, rushed by thousands into the deep and rapid stream of
 the Tiber.","('Maxentius', 'GPE'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tiber', 'LOC')"
"The conqueror had never received any injury from the father
 of that unhappy youth, and the short and obscure reign of
 Severus, in a distant part of the empire, was already
 forgotten.","('Severus', 'PERSON')"
"The conquest of
 Macedonia, as we have already observed, had delivered the
 Roman people from the weight of personal taxes.","('Macedonia', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The credulity of Zosimus prevailed so
 strongly over his passion that, among the events of the
 memorable battle of Hadrianople, he seems to have selected
 and embellished, not the most important, but the most
 marvellous.","('Zosimus', 'PERSON'), ('Hadrianople', 'PERSON')"
"The death of Maximin seemed to
 assure the empresses of a favourable alteration in their
 fortune.","('Maximin', 'PERSON')"
"The death of Severianus will admit of less
 excuse, as it was dictated neither by revenge nor by policy.","('Severianus', 'PERSON')"
"The deaths of Maximian and of Galerius
 reduced the number of emperors to four.","('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL')"
"The decent,
 and even obstinate, resistance which he chose to affect (16) 
 was contrived to justify his usurpation; nor did he yield to
 the acclamations of the army till he had provided the proper
 materials for a letter, which he immediately despatched to
 the emperor of the East.","('16', 'CARDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"The defeat of the two
 wings left the infantry without any protection on its
 flanks, and the undisciplined Italians fled without
 reluctance from the standard of a tyrant whom they had
 always hated, and whom they no longer feared.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Italians', 'NORP')"
"The emissaries of Maximian easily
 persuaded his credulity that a conspiracy was formed to
 betray the town, and prevailed upon his fears not to expose
 himself to the discretion of an irritated conqueror, but to
 accept the faith of an honourable capitulation.","('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"The emperor himself attempted to escape back into
 the city over the Milvian bridge, but the crowds which
 pressed together through that narrow passage forced him into
 the river, where he was immediately drowned by the weight of
 his armour. (69)","('the Milvian bridge', 'FAC')"
"The emperor himself had assumed the more difficult and 
 important province of the Danube.","('Danube', 'LOC')"
"The emperor, attentive to the motions, and
 informed of the approach of so formidable an enemy, left a
 part of his legions to continue the operations of the siege,
 whilst, at the head of those troops on whose valour and
 fidelity he more particularly depended, he advanced in
 person to engage the general of Maxentius.","('Maxentius', 'GPE')"
"The empire was
 afflicted by five civil wars; and the remainder of the time
 was not so much a state of tranquillity as a suspension of
 arms between several hostile monarchs, who, viewing each
 other with an eye of fear and hatred, strove to increase
 their respective forces at the expense of their subjects.","('five', 'CARDINAL')"
"The empress herself, together with
 her mother Prisca, was condemned to exile; and as they were
 ignominiously hurried from place to place before they were
 confined to a sequestered village in the deserts of Syria,
 they exposed their shame and distress to the provinces of
 the East, which, during thirty years, had respected their
 august dignity.","('Prisca', 'PERSON'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('thirty years', 'DATE')"
"The engagement lasted two days; and in the
 evening of the first, the contending fleets, after a
 considerable and mutual loss, retired into their respective
 harbours of Europe and Asia.","('two days', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The enterprise was as full of danger as of glory; and the
 unsuccessful event of two former invasions was sufficient to
 inspire the most serious apprehensions.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"The fame of Constantine has rendered posterity attentive
 to the most minute circumstances of his life and actions.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The favour of the people and soldiers, who had
 named him as a worthy candidate for the rank of Caesar,
 served only to exasperate the jealousy of Galerius; and
 though prudence might restrain him from exercising any open
 violence, an absolute monarch is seldom at a loss how to
 execute a sure and secret revenge. (12)","('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('12', 'CARDINAL')"
"The figure of
 Constantine was tall and majestic; he was dexterous in all
 his exercises, intrepid in war, affable in peace; in his
 whole conduct the active spirit of youth was tempered by
 habitual prudence; and while his mind was engrossed by
 ambition, he appeared cold and insensible to the allurements
 of pleasure.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The final abolition of the Praetorian guards was a measure
 of prudence as well as of revenge.","('Praetorian', 'NORP')"
"The first battle was fought near Cibalis, a city of
 Pannonia, situated on the river Save, about fifty miles
 above Sirmium. (88)","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Cibalis', 'GPE'), ('Pannonia', 'GPE'), ('about fifty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Sirmium', 'ORG')"
"The first emotions of
 Galerius were those of surprise, disappointment, and rage;
 and, as he could seldom restrain his passions, he loudly
 threatened that he would commit to the flames both the
 letter and the messenger.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"The first of
 these was Daza, or, as he was afterwards called, Maximin,
 whose mother was the sister of Galerius.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Daza', 'PERSON'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"The flames were extinguished by the care of Constantine, and
 the remains of Susa preserved from total destruction.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Susa', 'PERSON')"
"The fleet was composed of three
 hundred and fifty galleys of three ranks of oars.","('three\r\n hundred and fifty', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')"
"The flourishing cities of Cirtha and Carthage,
 and the whole extent of that fertile country, were wasted by
 fire and sword.","('Cirtha', 'GPE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"The flower of the western armies had followed
 Constantius into Britain, and the national troops were
 reinforced by a numerous body of Alemanni, who obeyed the
 orders of Crocus, one of their hereditary chieftains.","('Constantius', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON'), ('Crocus', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"The fortifications of Ravenna were able to resist
 the attempts, and the morasses that surrounded the town were
 sufficient to prevent the approach, of the Italian army.","('Ravenna', 'GPE'), ('Italian', 'NORP')"
"The fortified
 camp of Licinius was taken by assault the evening of the
 battle; the greater part of the fugitives, who had retired
 to the mountains, surrendered themselves the next day to the
 discretion of the conqueror; and his rival, who could no
 longer keep the field, confined himself within the walls of
 Byzantium. (107)","('Licinius', 'GPE'), ('the next day', 'DATE'), ('Byzantium', 'GPE'), ('107', 'CARDINAL')"
"The genius, the success, and the
 aspiring temper of Constantine, may seem to mark him out as
 the aggressor; but the perfidious character of Licinius
 justifies the most unfavourable suspicions, and by the faint
 light which history reflects on this transaction (86) we may 
 discover a conspiracy fomented by his arts against the
 authority of his colleague.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('86', 'DATE')"
"The gloomy passions of his
 soul, shame, vexation, and rage, were inflamed by envy on
 the news of Constantine's success; but the hopes of
 Maxentius revived with the public discontent, and he was
 easily persuaded to unite his personal injury and
 pretensions with the cause of the Roman people.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The grateful senate repaid these
 unmeaning professions by the empty titles of honour which it
 was yet in their power to bestow; and, without presuming to
 ratify the authority of Constantine, they passed a decree to
 assign him the first rank among the three Augusti who
 governed the Roman world.  (73)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Augusti', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('73', 'CARDINAL')"
"The great Constantine was 
 most probably born at Naissus, in Dacia; (10) and it is not 
 surprising that, in a family and province distinguished only
 by the profession of arms, the youth should discover very
 little inclination to improve his mind by the acquisition of
 knowledge.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Naissus', 'GPE'), ('Dacia', 'GPE'), ('10', 'CARDINAL')"
"The hardy
 legions of Gaul had long defended the frontiers of the
 empire against the barbarians of the North; and in the
 performance of that laborious service their valour was
 exercised and their discipline confirmed.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('North', 'LOC')"
"The haughty refusal of Licinius,
 when he was required to deliver up the criminals who had
 taken refuge in his dominions, confirmed the suspicions
 already entertained of his perfidy; and the indignities
 offered at Almona, on the frontiers of Italy, to the statues
 of Constantine, became the signal of discord between the two
 princes. (87)","('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Almona', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('87', 'CARDINAL')"
"The honours of seniority and precedence were allowed to the
 former of those princes, and he continued under a new
 appellation to administer his ancient department of Gaul,
 Spain, and Britain.","('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"The hopes of uniting the western provinces to his empire
 were disappointed by the elevation of Constantine; whilst
 Italy and Africa were lost by the successful revolt of
 Maxentius.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Maxentius', 'GPE')"
"The humanity of
 Constantine, moved, perhaps, by some recent and
 extraordinary instances of despair, engaged him to address
 an edict to all the cities of Italy, and afterwards of
 Africa, directing immediate and sufficient relief to be
 given to those parents who should produce before the
 magistrates the children whom their own poverty would not
 allow them to educate.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"The importance of the occasion called for the presence and
 abilities of Galerius.","('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"The incredible speed which
 Maximin exerted in his flight is much more celebrated than
 his prowess in the battle.","('Maximin', 'PERSON')"
"The inexperienced
 youth still betrayed by his manners and language his rustic
 education, when, to his own astonishment, as well as that of
 the world, he was invested by Diocletian with the purple,
 exalted to the dignity of Caesar, and intrusted with the
 sovereign command of Egypt and Syria.  (5)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('5', 'CARDINAL')"
"The intrepid mind of Constantine had been
 trained from his earliest youth to war, to action, and to
 military command.","('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The invader found every place hostile, fortified, and
 inaccessible; and though he forced his way as far as Narni,
 within sixty miles of Rome, his dominion in Italy was
 confined to the narrow limits of his camp.","('Narni', 'PERSON'), ('sixty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The judicious retreat of Licinius saved the
 remainder of his troops from a total defeat; but when he
 computed his loss, which amounted to more than twenty
 thousand men, he thought it unsafe to pass the night in the
 presence of an active and victorious enemy.","('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('more than twenty\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('the night', 'TIME')"
"The last years of Galerius were less shameful and
 unfortunate; and though he had filled with more glory the
 subordinate station of Caesar than the superior rank of
 Augustus, he preserved, till the moment of his death, the
 first place among the princes of the Roman world.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The legions
 of Constantine were levied in the warlike provinces of
 Europe; action had confirmed their discipline, victory had
 elevated their hopes, and there were among them a great
 number of veterans, who, after seventeen glorious campaigns
 under the same leader, prepared themselves to deserve an
 honourable dismission by a last effort of their valour. (105)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('seventeen', 'CARDINAL'), ('105', 'CARDINAL')"
"The legions of Galerius exhibited a very melancholy proof of
 their disposition by the ravages which they committed in
 their retreat.","('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"The life and freedom of 
 Maximian were, however, respected, and he retired from Italy
 into Illyricum, affecting to lament his past conduct, and
 secretly contriving new mischiefs.","('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Illyricum', 'GPE')"
"The long
 absence of the emperors had filled Rome with discontent and
 indignation; and the people gradually discovered that the
 preference given to Nicomedia and Milan was not to be
 ascribed to the particular inclination of Diocletian, but to
 the permanent form of government which he had instituted.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Nicomedia', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The loss of two battles, and of 
 his bravest veterans, reduced the fierce spirit of Licinius
 to sue for peace.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Licinius', 'GPE')"
"The maritime
 cities of Greece sent their respective quotas of men and
 ships to the celebrated harbour of Piraeus and their united
 forces consisted of no more than two hundred small vessels;
 a very feeble armament, if it is compared with those
 formidable fleets which were equipped and maintained by the
 republic of Athens during the Peloponnesian war. (106)","('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Piraeus', 'GPE'), ('more than two hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('the Peloponnesian war', 'EVENT'), ('106', 'CARDINAL')"
"The marriage was celebrated at Arles with every circumstance
 of magnificence; and the ancient colleague of Diocletian,
 who again asserted his claim to the Western empire,
 conferred on his son-in-law and ally the title of Augustus.","('Arles', 'GPE'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Western', 'NORP'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
"The memory of Licinius was branded with infamy, his statues
 were thrown down, and by a hasty edict, of such mischievous
 tendency that it was almost immediately corrected, all his
 laws and all the judicial proceedings of his reign were at
 once abolished.","('Licinius', 'PERSON')"
"The mind of Galerius was the most susceptible of the sterner
 passions, but it was not, however, incapable of a sincere
 and lasting friendship.","('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"The missile weapons on both sides were soon
 exhausted; the two armies, with equal valour, rushed to a
 closer engagement of swords and spears, and the doubtful
 contest had already lasted from the dawn of the day to a
 late hour of the evening, when the right wing, which
 Constantine led in person, made a vigorous and decisive
 charge.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('the dawn of the day to a\r\n late hour of the evening', 'TIME'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The most distinguished adherents of Maxentius
 must have expected to share his fate, as they had shared his
 prosperity and his crimes; but when the Roman people loudly
 demanded a greater number of victims, the conqueror
 resisted, with firmness and humanity, those servile
 clamours, which were dictated by flattery as well as by
 resentment.","('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The most odious parts of this edict were softened or repealed in the subsequent reigns; (96) and even Constantine himself very frequently  alleviated, by partial acts of mercy, the stern temper of
 his general institutions.","('96', 'DATE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The most opulent paid annually
 eight pounds of gold, the next class paid four, the last
 two, and those whose poverty might have claimed an exemption
 were assessed however, at seven pieces of gold.","('eight pounds', 'QUANTITY'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL')"
"The name of Maximian, the popular arts of his
 son, the secret distribution of large sums, and the promise
 of still more liberal rewards, checked the ardour and
 corrupted the fidelity of the Illyrian legions; and when
 Galerius at length gave the signal of the retreat, it was
 with some difficulty that he could prevail on his veterans
 not to desert a banner which had so often conducted them to
 victory and honour.","('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Illyrian', 'NORP'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"The name, as well as the situation of Maxentius,
 determined in his favour the popular enthusiasm.","('Maxentius', 'PERSON')"
"The narrow neck of land which joined that place
 to the continent was fortified against the besiegers, whilst
 the sea was open, either for the escape of Maximian, or for
 the succours of Maxentius, if the latter should choose to
 disguise his invasion of Gaul under the honourable pretence
 of defending a distressed, or, as he might allege, an
 injured father.","('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The naval
 commanders of Constantine were summoned to his camp, and
 received his positive orders to force the passage of the
 Hellespont, as the fleet of Licinius, instead of seeking and
 destroying their feeble enemy, continued inactive in those
 narrow straits, where its superiority of numbers was of
 little use or advantage.","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('Hellespont', 'GPE'), ('Licinius', 'GPE')"
"The necessity, the
 importance, and the difficulties of the siege of Verona,
 immediately presented themselves to the sagacious mind of
 Constantine. (57)","('Verona', 'GPE'), ('Constantine', 'PERSON')"
"The news of his promotion was no sooner 
 carried into the East, than Maximin, who governed, or rather
 oppressed, the countries of Egypt and Syria, betrayed his
 envy and discontent, disdained the inferior name of Caesar,
 and, notwithstanding the prayers as well as arguments of
 Galerius, exacted, almost by violence, the equal title of
 Augustus. (30)","('East', 'LOC'), ('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('30', 'CARDINAL')"
"The offers of 
 Galerius were rejected with firmness, his perfidious
 friendship refused with contempt, and it was not long before
 he discovered that unless he provided for his safety by a
 timely retreat, he had some reason to apprehend the fate of
 Severus.","('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Severus', 'PERSON')"
"The officers of experience and
 ability who had served under the banners of Maximian were at
 length compelled to inform his effeminate son of the
 imminent danger to which he was reduced; and, with a freedom
 that at once surprised and convinced him, to urge the
 necessity of preventing his ruin by a vigorous exertion of
 his remaining power.","('Maximian', 'PERSON')"
"The permission of the
 journey was reluctantly granted, and, whatever precautions
 the emperor might have taken to intercept a return, the
 consequences of which he with so much reason apprehended,
 they were effectually disappointed by the incredible
 diligence of Constantine. (13)","('Constantine', 'PERSON'), ('13', 'CARDINAL')"
"The place of his birth, as well as the condition of his
 mother Helena, have been the subject not only of literary
 but of national disputes.","('Helena', 'PERSON')"
"The plain of Mardia in Thrace was the theatre of a second
 battle no less obstinate and bloody than the former.","('Mardia', 'PERSON'), ('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')"
"The policy of
 Galerius preferred such associates as would never disgrace
 the choice, nor dispute the commands, of their benefactor.","('Galerius', 'PERSON')"
"The praefect of the city and
 a few magistrates, who maintained their fidelity to Severus,
 were massacred by the guards; and Maxentius, invested with
 the Imperial ornaments, was acknowledged, by the applauding
 senate and people, as the protector of the Roman freedom and
 dignity.","('Severus', 'PERSON'), ('Maxentius', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The privileges 
 which had exalted Italy above the rank of the provinces were
 no longer regarded: and the officers of the revenue already
 began to number the Roman people, and to settle the
 proportion of the new taxes.","('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The provinces of Asia
 fell to the share of Maximin, and those of Europe augmented
 the portion of Licinius.","('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Maximin', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Licinius', 'ORG')"
"The provinces of the East, delivered from the terrors of
 civil war, cheerfully acknowledged the authority of
 Licinius. (79)
Cruelty of Licinius","('East', 'LOC'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON'), ('Licinius', 'PERSON')"
"The provincials of Gaul, Spain, and Britain, sensible of his
 worth, and of their own happiness, reflected with anxiety on
 the declining health of the emperor Constantius, and the
 tender age of his numerous family, the issue of his second
