Sentence,Entities
(45),"('45', 'CARDINAL')"
(5),"('5', 'CARDINAL')"
2/.,"('2', 'CARDINAL')"
"3/. To appoint the proconsuls and presidents of the provinces, and to confer on all the magistrates their civil jurisdiction.","('3', 'CARDINAL')"
4/.,"('4', 'CARDINAL')"
"5/. To give force and validity, by their decrees, to such as they should approve of the emperor's edicts.","('5', 'CARDINAL')"
6/.,"('6', 'CARDINAL')"
"A behaviour so very opposite to that of his amiable 
 predecessor afforded no favourable presage of the new reign:
 and the Romans, deprived of power and freedom, asserted
 their privilege of licentious murmurs. (69)","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"A charge supported by such decisive proof was admitted without contradiction, and the legions, with repeated acclamations, acknowledged the justice and authority of the emperor Diocletian."" (107)
Defeat and death of Carinus.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('107', 'CARDINAL'), ('Carinus', 'PERSON')"
"A considerable number of elephants, taken in the
 defeat of the Carthaginian army, were driven through the
 circus by a few slaves, armed only with blunt javelins. (90)","('Carthaginian', 'NORP')"
"A considerable tribute of corn, cattle, and horses,
 the only wealth of barbarians, was reserved for the use of
 the garrisons which Probus established on the limits of
 their territory.","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"A decree immediately passed, without a
 dissenting voice to ratify the election of the eastern
 armies, and to confer on their chief all the several
 branches of the Imperial dignity; the names of Caesar and
 Augustus, the title of Father of his country, the right of
 making in the same day three motions in the senate,(27) the 
 office of Pontifex Maximus, the tribunitian power, and the
 proconsular command; a mode of investiture which, though it
 seemed to multiply the authority of the emperor, expressed
 the constitution of the ancient republic.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('27', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pontifex Maximus', 'PERSON')"
"A fleet stationed
 in one of the harbours of the Euxine fell into the hands of
 the Franks; and they resolved, through unknown seas, to
 explore their way from the mouth of the Phasis to that of
 the Rhine.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Euxine', 'PRODUCT'), ('Franks', 'NORP'), ('Phasis', 'PRODUCT'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"A general assembly
 of the army was appointed to be held at Chalcedon, whither
 Aper was transported in chains, as a prisoner and a
 criminal.","('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('Aper', 'PERSON')"
"A tribune, whose wife he had seduced, seized the
 opportunity of revenge, and by a single blow extinguished
 civil discord in the blood of the adulterer. (109)","('109', 'CARDINAL')"
"A vacant tribunal was erected in the midst of the
 camp, and the generals and tribunes formed a great military
 Council.","('Council', 'ORG')"
A.D. 275.,"('275', 'CARDINAL')"
A.D. 276.,"('A.D. 276', 'DATE')"
"About the reign of Hadrian, when that mode of
 defence began to be practised, these garrisons were
 connected and covered by a strong entrenchment of trees and
 palisades.","('Hadrian', 'PERSON')"
"Above twenty years 
 before, the emperor Valerian, with his usual penetration,
 had discovered the rising merit of the young soldier, on
 whom he conferred the rank of tribune long before the age
 prescribed by the military regulations.","('twenty years \r\n before', 'DATE'), ('Valerian', 'PERSON')"
"Africa and
 Pontus, the Rhine, the Danube, the Euphrates, and the Nile,
 by turns afforded him the most splendid occasions of
 displaying his personal prowess and his conduct in war.","('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Pontus', 'LOC'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Euphrates', 'LOC'), ('Nile', 'LOC')"
"Against the
 remainder, who refused peace, the Roman emperor waged, in
 person, a successful war.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"All that had yet passed at Rome was no more than a
 theatrical representation, unless it was ratified by the
 more substantial power of the legions.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Among the useful conditions of peace imposed by Probus on
 the vanquished nations of Germany was the obligation of
 supplying the Roman army with sixteen thousand recruits, the
 bravest and most robust of their youth.","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('sixteen thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"Among the various multitude 
 of those fierce invaders, we may distinguish, with some
 degree of clearness, three great armies, or rather nations,
 successively vanquished by the valour of Probus.","('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Probus', 'ORG')"
"An 
 oracle was remembered which marked the river Tigris as the
 fatal boundary of the Roman arms.","('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"An army thus employed constituted perhaps the
 most useful as well as the bravest portion of Roman
 subjects.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"An event somewhat similar but much less authentic is supposed to have happened after the death of Romulus, who, in his life and character, bore some affinity with Aurelian.","('Romulus', 'PERSON'), ('Aurelian', 'PERSON')"
"An hundred
 thousand Bastarnae, expelled from their own country,
 cheerfully accepted an establishment in Thrace, and soon
 imbibed the manners and sentiments of Roman subjects. (48)","('An hundred\r\n thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bastarnae', 'NORP'), ('Thrace', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('48', 'CARDINAL')"
"As soon as the tumult of acclamations subsided, Tacitus
 attempted to decline the dangerous honour, and to express
 his wonder that they should elect his age and infirmities to
 succeed the martial vigour of Aurelian.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('Aurelian', 'PERSON')"
"At one moment it seemed to rise out of the
 earth, like the garden of the Hesperides, and was afterwards
 broken into the rocks and caverns of Thrace.","('one moment', 'TIME'), ('Hesperides', 'NORP'), ('Thrace', 'LOC')"
"Aurelian was indebted to him for the conquest of Egypt, and
 still more indebted for the honest courage with which he
 often checked the cruelty of his master.","('Aurelian', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"Authority of the senate, 
 The administration of Tacitus was not unworthy of his life
 and principles.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"Before his departure for this
 distant expedition, Carus conferred on his two sons, Carinus
 and Numerian, the title of Caesar, and, investing the former
 with almost an equal share of the Imperial power, directed
 the young prince first to suppress some troubles which had
 arisen in Gaul, and afterwards to fix the seat of his
 residence at Rome, and to assume the government of the
 Western provinces.","('Carus', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Carinus', 'PERSON'), ('Numerian', 'PERSON'), ('Caesar', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Before we enter upon the memorable reign of that prince, it
 will be proper to punish and dismiss the unworthy brother of
 Numerian.","('Numerian', 'PERSON')"
"Born and educated in
 a private station, the election of their father raised them
 at once to the rank of princes; and his death, which
 happened about sixteen months afterwards, left them the
 unexpected legacy of a vast empire.","('about sixteen months afterwards', 'DATE')"
"But
 the advantage which Carinus had obtained by the valour of
 his soldiers he quickly lost by the infidelity of his
 officers.","('Carinus', 'PERSON')"
"But
 the experience of the world, from China to Britain, has
 exposed the vain attempt of fortifying any extensive tract
 of country.","('China', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE')"
"But 
 the expectations of Probus were too often disappointed.","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"But a report soon circulated through the camp, at first in
 secret whispers, and at length in loud clamours, of the
 emperor's death, and of the presumption of his ambitious
 minister, who still exercised the sovereign power in the
 name of a prince who was no more.","('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"But as the fame of warriors 
 is built on the destruction of human kind, we may naturally
 suspect that the sanguinary account was multiplied by the
 avarice of the soldiers, and accepted without any very
 severe examination by the liberal vanity of Probus.","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"But as the former part of his prediction was verified by the victory, so the latter was disappointed by the clemency, of Probus.","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"But of all the invaders of Gaul, the most formidable were
 the Lygians, a distant people who reigned over a wide domain
 on the frontiers of Poland and Silesia. (36)","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Lygians', 'NORP'), ('Poland', 'GPE'), ('Silesia', 'GPE'), ('36', 'CARDINAL')"
"But the elevation of
 Constantius was for a while deferred; and as soon as the
 father's death had released Carinus from the control of fear
 or decency, he displayed to the Romans the extravagancies of
 Elagabalus, aggravated by the cruelty of Domitian. (82)","('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Carinus', 'PERSON'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Elagabalus', 'PERSON'), ('Domitian', 'PERSON')"
"But the fortune and activity of Probus
 triumphed over every obstacle.","('Probus', 'ORG')"
But the glory and life of Tacitus were of short duration.,"('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"But the losses which they suffered in the march, the battle, and the retreat, broke the power of the nation: nor is the Lygian name ever repeated in the history either of Germany or of the empire.","('Lygian', 'PERSON'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"But the reign of Carus was destined to expose 
 the vanity of predictions.","('Carus', 'PERSON')"
"But the talents of Numerian were rather 
 of the contemplative than of the active kind.","('Numerian', 'PERSON')"
"But this vain 
 prodigality, which the prudence of Diocletian might justly
 despise, was enjoyed with surprise and transport by the
 Roman people.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"But, in the prosecution of a favourite scheme, the best of
 men, satisfied with the rectitude of their intentions, are
 subject to forget the bounds of moderation, nor did Probus
 himself sufficiently consult the patience and disposition of
 his fierce legionaries. (60)","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"But, in the time of Numa and Romulus, the arms of the people were controlled by the authority of the Patricians; and the balance of freedom was easily preserved in a small and virtuous community.","('Numa', 'GPE'), ('Romulus', 'PERSON'), ('Patricians', 'NORP')"
"By the order of Probus, a great quantity of large 
 trees, torn up by the roots, were transplanted into the
 midst of the circus.","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"Carinus possessed arms and treasures sufficient to
 support his legal title to the empire.","('Carinus', 'PERSON')"
"Carus defeats the Sarmatians, and marches into the East;.","('Carus', 'PERSON'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"Carus, Diocletian,
 Maximian, Constantius, Galerius, Asclepiodatus,
 Annibalianus, and a crowd of other chiefs, who afterwards
 ascended or supported the throne, were trained to arms in
 the severe school of Aurelian and Probus. (33)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Maximian', 'NORP'), ('Constantius', 'NORP'), ('Galerius', 'PERSON'), ('Asclepiodatus', 'NORP'), ('Annibalianus', 'NORP'), ('Aurelian', 'ORG'), ('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('33', 'CARDINAL')"
"Carus, taking off a cap which he wore to conceal his
 baldness, assured the ambassadors that, unless their master
 acknowledged the superiority of Rome, he would speedily
 render Persia as naked of trees as his own head was
 destitute of hair.","('Carus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
Character and elevation of the emperor Probus.,"('Probus', 'PERSON')"
Character of Tacitus.,"('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
Conduct of the army and senate after the death of Aurelian.,"('Aurelian', 'PERSON')"
"Conscious that the station which he had filled
 exposed him to some suspicions, Diocletian ascended the
 tribunal, and, raising his eyes towards the Sun, made a
 solemn profession of his own innocence, in the presence of
 that all seeing Deity. (106)","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Sun', 'PERSON'), ('Deity', 'PERSON'), ('106', 'CARDINAL')"
Daring enterprise of the Franks.,"('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"Disdaining to shed their blood for the
 amusement of the populace, they killed their keepers, broke
 from the place of their confinement, and filled the streets
 of Rome with blood and confusion.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Election of the Emperor Diocletian, A.D. 284, Sept 17","('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('A.D. 284', 'DATE'), ('Sept 17', 'DATE')"
"Faunus hails the approach of
 that hero, who, receiving on his shoulders the sinking
 weight of the Roman world, shall extinguish war and faction,
 and once again restore the innocence and security of the
 golden age. (70)","('Faunus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
February 3. A Peaceful interregnum of eight months,"('February 3', 'DATE'), ('eight months', 'DATE')"
"Five hundred voices repeated at once, in eloquent confusion,
 that the greatest of the Roman princes, Numa, Trajan,
 Hadrian, and the Antonines, had ascended the throne in a
 very advanced season of life; that the mind, not the body, a
 sovereign, not a soldier, was the object of their choice;
 and that they expected from him no more than to guide by his
 wisdom the valour of the legions.","('Five hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Numa', 'PERSON'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Hadrian', 'PERSON'), ('Antonines', 'PERSON')"
"Flattery
 and hope painted in the most lively colours the fall of
 Persia, the conquest of Arabia, the submission of Egypt, and
 a lasting deliverance from the inroads of the Scythian
 nations. (75)","('Persia', 'GPE'), ('Arabia', 'GPE'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('75', 'CARDINAL')"
"For a short season they might
 wander in arms through the empire, but in the end they were
 surely destroyed by the power of warlike emperor.","('a short season', 'DATE')"
"From a similar 
 principle, Probus exercised his legions in covering with
 rich vineyards the hills of Gaul and Pannonia, and two
 considerable spots are described which were entirely dug and
 planted by military labour. (59)","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'LOC'), ('Pannonia', 'LOC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"From the
 neighbourhood of Neustadt and Ratisbon on the Danube, it
 stretched across hills, valleys, rivers, and morasses, as
 far as Wimpfen on the Neckar, and at length terminated on
 the banks of the Rhine, after a winding course of near two
 hundred miles.","('Neustadt', 'GPE'), ('Ratisbon', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Wimpfen', 'GPE'), ('Neckar', 'FAC'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('near two\r\n hundred miles', 'QUANTITY')"
"From the assiduous
 study of his immortal ancestor he derived the knowledge of
 the Roman constitution and of human nature.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"From the island of Sicily the Franks
 proceeded to the Columns of Hercules, trusted themselves to
 the ocean, coasted round Spain and Gaul, and, steering their
 triumphant course through the British Channel, at length
 finished their surprising voyage by landing in safety on the
 Batavian or Frisian shores. (50)","('Sicily', 'LOC'), ('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('the Columns of Hercules', 'ORG'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Gaul', 'GPE'), ('the British Channel', 'LOC'), ('Batavian', 'NORP'), ('Frisian', 'NORP'), ('50', 'CARDINAL')"
"Germany, exhausted by the
 ill-success of the last emigration, was astonished by his
 presence.","('Germany', 'GPE')"
"Great numbers
 of the Alani, appeased by the punctual discharge of the
 engagements which Aurelian had contracted with them,
 relinquished their booty and captives, and quietly retreated
 to their own deserts beyond the Phasis.","('Alani', 'PERSON'), ('Aurelian', 'NORP'), ('Phasis', 'PRODUCT')"
"Great numbers of Franks and Gepidae were settled 
 on the banks of the Danube and the Rhine.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Gepidae', 'PERSON'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('Rhine', 'LOC')"
"Had Germany been reduced into the state of 
 a province, the Romans, with immense labour and expense,
 would have acquired only a more extensive boundary to defend
 against the fiercer and more active barbarians of Scythia.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Romans', 'NORP'), ('Scythia', 'GPE')"
"He attacked the 
 Isaurians in their mountains, besieged and took several of
 their strongest castles, (31) and flattered himself that he 
 had for ever suppressed a domestic foe whose independence so
 deeply wounded the majesty of the empire.","('Isaurians', 'NORP'), ('31', 'CARDINAL')"
"He broke the wandering power of the Sarmatian tribes,
 and by the terror of his arms compelled those barbarians to
 relinquish their spoil.","('Sarmatian', 'NORP')"
He builds a wall from the Rhine to the Danube.,"('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
He celebrates the Roman games.,"('Roman', 'NORP')"
"He delivers Gaul from the invasion of the Germans, 
 But the most important service which Probus rendered to the
 republic was the deliverance of Gaul, and the recovery of
 seventy flourishing cities oppressed by the barbarians of
 Germany who, since the death of Aurelian, had ravaged that
 great province with impunity.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('seventy', 'CARDINAL'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Aurelian', 'GPE')"
"He drove
 back the Franks into their morasses; a descriptive
 circumstance from whence we may infer that the confederacy
 known by the manly appellation of Free already occupied the
 flat maritime country, intersected and almost overflown by
 the stagnating waters of the Rhine, and that several tribes
 of the Frisians and Batavians had acceded to their alliance.","('Franks', 'PERSON'), ('Free', 'PERSON'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Frisians', 'NORP'), ('Batavians', 'NORP')"
"He engaged their esteem by a spirited declaration
 that, although his age might disable him from the
 performance of military exploits, his counsels should never
 be unworthy of a Roman general, the successor of the brave
 Aurelian. (16)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Aurelian', 'PERSON'), ('16', 'CARDINAL')"
"He enjoyed, at
 least before his elevation, an acknowledged character of
 virtue and abilities; (65) but his austere temper insensibly 
 degenerated into moroseness and cruelty; and the imperfect
 writers of his life almost hesitate whether they shall not
 rank him in the number of Roman tyrants. (66)","('65', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('66', 'CARDINAL')"
"He even entertained some thoughts of
 compelling the Germans to relinquish the exercise of arms,
 and to trust their differences to the justice, their safety
 to the power, of Rome.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"He expired at Tyana in Cappadocia, after a reign of
 only six months and about twenty days. (19)
 .","('Tyana', 'GPE'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE'), ('only six months', 'DATE'), ('about twenty days', 'DATE'), ('19', 'CARDINAL')"
He gives audience to the Pesian ambassadors.,"('Pesian', 'NORP')"
"He gloried in the
 title of Roman Citizen; and affected to compare the purity
 of his blood with the foreign and even barbarous, origin of
 the preceding emperors; yet the most inquisitive of his
 contemporaries, very far from admitting his claim, have
 variously deduced his own birth, or that of his parents,
 from Illyricum, from Gaul, or from Africa. (64)","('Roman Citizen', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Illyricum', 'NORP'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
He had more than once solicited the usurper himself to place some confidence in the mercy of a sovereign who so highly esteemed his character that he had punished as a malicious informer the first who related the improbable news of his defection. (52),"('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('52', 'CARDINAL')"
"He had passed two months in the delightful
 privacy of Baiae, when he reluctantly obeyed the summons of
 the consul to resume his honourable place in the senate, and
 to assist the republic with his counsels on this important
 occasion.","('two months', 'DATE'), ('Baiae', 'PERSON')"
"He had twice been invested
 with the consular dignity, (7) and enjoyed with elegance and 
 sobriety his ample patrimony of between two and three
 millions sterling. (8)","('between two and three\r\n millions sterling', 'MONEY')"
"He is elected emperor,
 He arose to speak, when, from every quarter of the house, he
 was saluted with the names of Augustus and Emperor.","('Augustus', 'PERSON')"
He is succeeded by his two sons Carinus and Numerian.,"('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Carinus', 'PERSON'), ('Numerian', 'PERSON')"
"He ravaged
 Mesopotamia, cut in pieces whatever opposed his passage,
 made himself master of the great cities of Seleucia and
 Ctesiphon (which seem to have surrendered without
 resistance), and carried his victorious arms beyond the
 Tigris. (74)","('Mesopotamia', 'LOC'), ('Seleucia', 'GPE'), ('Ctesiphon', 'PERSON'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('74', 'CARDINAL')"
"He reminded the assembly of the evils which
 Rome had endured from the vices of headstrong and capricious
 youths, congratulated them on the election of a virtuous and
 experienced senator, and with a manly, though perhaps a
 selfish, freedom, exhorted Tacitus to remember the reasons
 of his elevation, and to seek a successor, not in his own
 family, but in the republic.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"He slightly insinuated that the precarious loyalty of the soldiers depended on the chance of every hour and of every accident; but he represented, with the most convincing eloquence, the various dangers that
 might attend any farther delay in the choice of an emperor.","('every hour', 'TIME')"
"He studied to heal the  wounds which Imperial pride, civil discord, and military violence had inflicted on the constitution, and to restore, at least, the image of the ancient republic as it had been preserved by the policy of Augustus and the virtues of Trajan and the Antonines.","('Imperial', 'NORP'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('Trajan', 'PERSON'), ('Antonines', 'PERSON')"
"He used the victory with his
 accustomed moderation, and spared the fortunes as well as
 the lives of their innocent families. (54)
Triumph of the emperor Probus.","('Triumph of the emperor Probus', 'PERSON')"
"He vanquished the Burgundians, a considerable people of the
 Vandalic race.","('Burgundians', 'NORP'), ('Vandalic', 'NORP')"
"His
 eloquence, however it was applauded by the senate, was
 formed not so much on the model of Cicero as on that of the
 modern declaimers; but in an age very far from being
 destitute of poetical merit, he contended for the prize with
 the most celebrated of his contemporaries, and still
 remained the friend of his rivals; a circumstance which
 evinces either the goodness of his heart, or the superiority
 of his genius. (101)","('Cicero', 'PERSON'), ('101', 'CARDINAL')"
"His  dutiful address to the senate displayed the sentiments, or
 at least the language, of a Roman patriot:","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"His acknowledged merit, and the success of his arms against
 Florianus, left him without an enemy or a competitor.","('Florianus', 'PERSON')"
"His constitution
 was destroyed by the hardships of the Persian war; and he
 had contracted, from the heat of the climate,(102) such a 
 weakness in his eyes, as obliged him, in the course of a
 long retreat, to confine himself to the solitude and
 darkness of a tent or litter.","('the Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('102', 'CARDINAL')"
"If we can prefer personal merit to accidental greatness, we
 shall esteem the birth of Tacitus more truly noble than that
 of kings.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"If we confine ourselves solely to the hunting of wild
 beasts, however we may censure the vanity of the design or
 the cruelty of the execution, we are obliged to confess that
 neither before nor since the time of the Romans so much art
 and expense have ever been lavished for the amusement of the
 people.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"In
 the course of a few months he successively married and
 divorced nine wives, most of whom he left pregnant; and,
 notwithstanding this legal inconstancy, found time to
 indulge such a variety of irregular appetites as brought
 dishonour on himself and on the noblest houses of Rome.","('a few months', 'DATE'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In 
 the same hour, but at the distance of nine hundred miles
 from Rome, his brother expired; and a sudden revolution
 transferred into the hands of a stranger the sceptre of the
 house of Carus. (99)
Return of Numerian with the army from Persia.","('the same hour', 'TIME'), ('nine hundred miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Carus', 'PERSON'), ('99', 'CARDINAL'), ('Numerian', 'NORP'), ('Persia', 'GPE')"
"In one of the hottest days of summer,
 as he severely urged the unwholesome labour of draining the
 marshes of Sirmium, the soldiers, impatient of fatigue, on a
 sudden threw down their tools, grasped their arms, and broke
 out into a furious mutiny.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('the hottest days of summer', 'DATE'), ('Sirmium', 'GPE')"
"In the Gallic war he discovered some degree of
 personal courage;(80) but from the moment of his arrival at 
 Rome he abandoned himself to the luxury of the capital, and
 to the abuse of his fortune.","('the Gallic war', 'EVENT'), ('80', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"In the Lygian 
 nation the Arii held the first rank by their numbers and
 fierceness.","('Lygian', 'NORP'), ('Arii', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')"
"In the decoration of these scenes the Roman emperors
 displayed their wealth and liberality; and we read on
 various occasions that the whole furniture of the
 amphitheatre consisted either of silver, or of gold, or of
 amber. (96)","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"In the midst of this glittering pageantry, the emperor
 Carinus, secure of his fortune, enjoyed the acclamations of
 the people, the flattery of his courtiers, and the songs of
 the poets, who, for want of a more essential merit, were
 reduced to celebrate the divine graces of his person. (98)","('Carinus', 'PERSON')"
"In the most corrupt of times
 Carinus was unworthy to live: Numerian deserved to reign in
 a happier period.","('Carinus', 'PERSON'), ('Numerian', 'PERSON')"
"In the place of so rude a bulwark, the emperor
 Probus constructed a stone wall of a considerable height and
 strengthened it by towers at convenient distances.","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"In the room of the
 Praetorian praefect, whom he put to death, Carinus
 substituted one of the ministers of his looser pleasures.","('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Carinus', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"In the spring the
 forces of the East and of the West encountered each other in
 the plains of Margus, a small city of Maesia, in the
 neighbourhood of the Danube. (108)","('the spring', 'DATE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Margus', 'LOC'), ('Maesia', 'GPE'), ('Danube', 'LOC'), ('108', 'CARDINAL')"
"Instead of reducing the warlike natives of Germany to the
 condition of subjects, Probus contented himself with the
 humble expedient of raising a bulwark against their inroads.","('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"Intelligence, he said, was already received that the Germans had passed the Rhine and occupied some of the strongest and most opulent cities of Gaul.","('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Gaul', 'LOC')"
"Into
 Britain, and most probably into Cambridgeshire, (46) he 
 transported a considerable body of Vandals.","('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Cambridgeshire', 'GPE'), ('46', 'DATE'), ('Vandals', 'PRODUCT')"
"It is more than probable that these elegant trifles never
 reached the ears of a veteran general who, with the consent
 of the legions, was preparing to execute the long suspended
 design of the Persian war.","('the Persian war', 'EVENT')"
"It may not be useless to
 recapitulate some of the most important prerogatives which the senate appeared to have regained by the election of Tacitus. (13) 1/.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('13', 'CARDINAL'), ('1', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was a building of an elliptic 
 figure, five hundred and sixty-four feet in length, and four
 hundred and sixty-seven in breadth, founded on fourscore
 arches, and rising, with four successive orders of
 architecture, to the height of one hundred and forty feet.
 (92)","('five hundred and sixty-four feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('four\r\n hundred and sixty-seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('one hundred and forty feet', 'QUANTITY')"
"It was not till eight months after the death of Carus that
 the Roman army, returning by slow marches from the banks of
 the Tigris, arrived on those of the Thracian Bosphorus.","('eight months', 'DATE'), ('Carus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Tigris', 'LOC'), ('the Thracian Bosphorus', 'LOC')"
"It was reported of Hannibal that, in 
 order to preserve his troops from the dangerous temptations
 of idleness, he had obliged them to form large plantations
 of olive-trees along the coast of Africa. (58)","('Hannibal', 'PERSON'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('58', 'CARDINAL')"
"It was time that the emperor should
 revisit Rome, and celebrate his own glory and the general
 happiness.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Its scattered ruins,
 universally ascribed to the power of the Daemon, now serve
 only to excite the wonder of the Swabian peasant.","('Swabian', 'NORP')"
"Leaving the senators
 to enjoy their dream of freedom and ambition, Tacitus
 proceeded to the Thracian camp, and was there by the
 Praetorian praefect, presented to the assembled troops as
 the prince whom they themselves had demanded, and whom the
 senate had bestowed.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('Thracian', 'NORP'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP')"
"More than twenty years afterwards, when
 the courtiers of Diocletian represented to their frugal
 sovereign the name and popularity of his munificent
 predecessor, he acknowledged that the reign of Carinus had
 indeed been a reign of pleasure. (83)","('More than twenty years afterwards', 'DATE'), ('Diocletian', 'PERSON'), ('Carinus', 'EVENT')"
"Most
 of the exploits which distinguished his reign were achieved
 by the personal valour and conduct of the emperor, insomuch
 that the Writer of his Life expresses some amazement how, in
 so short a time, a single man could be present in so many
 distant wars.","('the Writer of his Life', 'PERSON')"
"Nine of the most considerable princes repaired to
 his camp, and fell prostrate at his feet.","('Nine', 'CARDINAL')"
"Nor could these artificial supplies, however repeated by 
 succeeding emperors, restore the important limit of Gaul and
 Illyricum to its ancient and native vigour.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('Illyricum', 'NORP')"
"Notwithstanding some traces of art and 
 preparation, we may discover in this scene the manners of
 Carus, and the severe simplicity which the martial princes
 who succeeded Gallienus had already restored in the Roman
 camps.","('Carus', 'PERSON'), ('Gallienus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Notwithstanding the severe
 justice which he exercised against the assassins of Probus,
 to whose favour and esteem he was highly indebted, he could
 not escape the suspicion of being accessory to a deed from
 whence he derived the principal advantage.","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"On the twenty-fifth of September, near eight months after the murder of Aurelian, the consul convoked an assembly of the senate, and reported the doubtful and dangerous situation of the empire.","('the twenty-fifth of September', 'DATE'), ('eight months', 'DATE'), ('Aurelian', 'PERSON')"
"One of his doorkeepers(81) he intrusted 
 with the government of the city.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('81', 'DATE')"
"One of these, known under the 
 name of Mount Alma, was situated near Sirmium, the country
 where Probus was born, for which he ever retained a partial
 affection, and whose gratitude he endeavoured to secure, by
 converting into tillage a large and unhealthy tract of
 marshy ground.","('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mount Alma', 'LOC'), ('Sirmium', 'GPE'), ('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"Posterity admires, and will long admire, the awful remains
 of the amphitheatre of Titus who so well deserved the
 epithet of Colossal. (91)","('Titus', 'PERSON'), ('Colossal', 'PERSON')"
"Probus
 therefore judged it more expedient to defer the execution of
 so great a design; which was indeed rather of specious than
 solid utility. (40)","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"Provoked by
 such treatment, which they considered as trifling and
 perfidious, the Alani had recourse to their own valour for
 their payment and revenge; and as they moved with the usual
 swiftness of Tartars, they had soon spread themselves over
 the provinces of Pontus, Cappadocia, Cilicia, and Galatia.","('Alani', 'PERSON'), ('Tartars', 'NORP'), ('Pontus', 'GPE'), ('Cappadocia', 'GPE'), ('Cilicia', 'GPE'), ('Galatia', 'PERSON')"
"Reigns of Tacitus, Probus, and Carus, and his sons.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Carus', 'PERSON')"
"Revolt of Saturninus in the East;
 Notwithstanding the vigilance and activity of Probus, it was
 almost impossible that he could at once contain in obedience
 every part of his wide-extended dominions.","('Saturninus', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"Rome and the East received with
 transport the news of such important advantages.","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC')"
"SUCH was the unhappy condition of the Roman emperors, that,
 whatever might be their conduct, their fate was commonly the
 same.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
Saturninus might perhaps have embraced the generous offer had he not been restrained by the obstinate distrust of his adherents.,"('Saturninus', 'ORG')"
"Seconded by an army of brave and
 experienced veterans, in a few weeks he delivered the
 provinces of Asia from the terror of the Scythian invasion.
 (17)
Death of the emperor Tacitus.","('a few weeks', 'DATE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('17', 'CARDINAL'), ('Death of the emperor Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"Sept, 25.","('Sept, 25', 'DATE')"
"Since the expedition of Maximin, the Roman generals had
 confined their ambition to a defensive war against the
 nations of Germany, who perpetually pressed on the frontiers
 of the empire.","('Maximin', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Germany', 'GPE')"
"Sixty-four vomitories 
 (for by that name the doors were very aptly distinguished)
 poured forth the immense multitude; and the entrances,
 passages, and staircases were contrived with such exquisite
 skill, that each person, whether of the senatorial, the
 equestrian, or the plebeian order, arrived at his destined
 place without trouble or confusion.","('Sixty-four', 'CARDINAL')"
"Such a treaty was
 humbly received by the Germans as it pleased the conqueror
 to dictate.","('Germans', 'NORP')"
Tacitus is acknowledged by the army.,"('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"Tacitus, who
 desired by the abilities of his generals to supply his own
 deficiency of military talents, named him commander-in-chief
 of all the eastern provinces, with five times the usual
 salary, the promise of the consulship, and the hope of a
 triumph.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('five', 'CARDINAL')"
"Ten elks, and as many camelopards, the loftiest 
 and most harmless creatures that wander over the plain of
 Sarmatia and Ethiopia, were contrasted with thirty African
 hyenas and ten Indian tigers, the most implacable savages of
 the torrid zone.","('Ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sarmatia', 'GPE'), ('Ethiopia', 'GPE'), ('thirty', 'CARDINAL'), ('African', 'NORP'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Indian', 'NORP')"
That amiable prince attempted even to save the unhappy Saturninus from the fury of the soldiers.,"('Saturninus', 'PRODUCT')"
"That general, a man of merit and experience, was driven into
 rebellion by the absence of his sovereign, the levity of the
 Alexandrian people, the pressing instances of his friends
 and his own fears; but from the moment of his elevation he
 never entertained a hope of empire or even of life.","('Alexandrian', 'NORP')"
"The
 contest, however, was still unequal; nor could the most able
 leader, at the head of the effeminate troops of Egypt and
 Syria, encounter, with any hopes of victory, the legions of
 Europe, whose irresistible strength appeared to support the
 brother of Tacitus.","('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 fate of the wall which Probus erected may confirm the
 general observation.","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"The
 hardy frontier of the Rhine and Danube still produced minds
 and bodies equal to the labours of the camp; but a perpetual
 series of wars had gradually diminished their numbers.","('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"The
 intelligence which he soon received of the conduct of
 Carinus filled him with shame and regret; nor had he
 concealed his resolution of satisfying the republic by a
 severe act of justice, and of adopting, in the place of an
 unworthy son, the brave and virtuous Constantius, who at
 that time was governor of Dalmatia.","('Carinus', 'PERSON'), ('Constantius', 'PERSON'), ('Dalmatia', 'GPE')"
"The
 legions halted at Chalcedon in Asia, while the court passed
 over to Heraclea, on the European side of the Propontis. (104)","('Chalcedon', 'GPE'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Heraclea', 'GPE'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('Propontis', 'PRODUCT'), ('104', 'CARDINAL')"
"The
 opulent city of Syracuse, in whose port the navies of Athens
 and Carthage had formerly been sunk, was sacked by a handful
 of barbarians, who massacred the greatest part of the
 trembling inhabitants.","('Syracuse', 'GPE'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE')"
"The
 successful rashness of a party of Franks was attended,
 however, with such memorable consequences that it ought not
 be passed unnoticed.","('Franks', 'PERSON')"
"The 
 troops, as if satiated with the exercise of power, again
 conjured the senate to invest one of its own body with the
 Imperial purple.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"The Alani invade Asia, and are repulsed by Tacitus.","('Alani', 'NORP'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"The Gothic nation courted the
 alliance of so warlike an emperor. (30)","('Gothic', 'NORP'), ('30', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Imperial pavilion was strictly guarded by his
 most trusty adherents; and during many days Aper delivered
 to the army the supposed mandates of their invisible
 sovereign. (103)
Death of Numerian.","('The Imperial pavilion', 'FAC'), ('Aper', 'PERSON'), ('103', 'CARDINAL')"
"The Lygii were defeated in a general engagement, and Semno, the most renowned of their chiefs, fell alive into the hands of Probus.","('Lygii', 'PERSON'), ('Semno', 'PERSON'), ('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"The Persian councils were distracted by domestic
 factions, and the greater part of their forces were detained
 on the frontiers of India.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('India', 'GPE')"
"The Persians expressed their desire of being
 introduced to the presence of the Roman emperor.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The Roman senators heard, without surprise, that another
 emperor had been assassinated in his camp; they secretly
 rejoiced in the fall of Aurelian; but the modest and dutiful
 address of the legions, when it was communicated in full
 assembly by the consul, diffused the most pleasing
 astonishment.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Aurelian', 'EVENT')"
"The administration of all
 affairs, civil as well as military, was devolved on Arrius
 Aper, the Praetorian praefect, who, to the power of his
 important office, added the honour of being father-in-law to
 Numerian.","('Arrius\r\n Aper', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP'), ('Numerian', 'PERSON')"
"The ambition of the Persian king kept the East in perpetual alarms; Egypt, Africa, and Illyricum were exposed to foreign and domestic arms; and the
 levity of Syria would prefer even a female sceptre to the sanctity of the Roman laws.","('Persian', 'NORP'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Illyricum', 'LOC'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The ambition of the aspiring generals was
 checked by their mutual fears; and young Numerian, with his
 absent brother Carinus, were unanimously acknowledged as
 Roman emperors.","('Numerian', 'PERSON'), ('Carinus', 'PERSON'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The arms of Probus had now suppressed all the foreign and
 domestic enemies of the state.","('Probus', 'ORG')"
"The arrangements which their new situation required
 were probably deferred till the return of the younger
 brother to Rome, where a triumph was decreed to the young
 emperors for the glorious success of the Persian war. (100)","('Rome', 'GPE'), ('the Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')"
"The arts of Diocletian inflamed the general
 discontent; and the winter was employed in secret intrigues
 and open preparations for a civil war.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"The authority of the senate expired with Probus; nor was the
 repentance of the soldiers displayed by the same dutiful
 regard for the civil power which they had testified after
 the unfortunate death of Aurelian.","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Aurelian', 'PERSON')"
"The authority of the senate, in the nomination of the consuls, was exercised with such independent freedom, that no regard
 was paid to an irregular request of the emperor in favour of his brother Florianus.","('Florianus', 'PERSON')"
"The chastisement of those
 cities, and of their auxiliaries the savages of the South,
 is said to have alarmed the court of Persia,(32) and the 
 Great King sued in vain for the friendship of Probus.","('South', 'LOC'), ('Persia', 'GPE'), ('32', 'CARDINAL'), ('the \r\n Great King', 'GPE'), ('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"The children of Tacitus and
 Florianus were permitted to descend into a private station,
 and to mingle with the general mass of the people.","('Tacitus', 'NORP'), ('Florianus', 'PERSON')"
"The collection prepared by the younger Gordian for 
 his triumph, and which his successor exhibited in the
 secular games, was less remarkable by the number than by the
 singularity of the animals.","('Gordian', 'PERSON')"
"The conduct of Tacitus was suitable to
 his age and station.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"The consul then, addressing himself to Tacitus, the first of the senators,(4) required 
 his opinion on the important subject of a proper candidate
 for the vacant throne.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('4', 'CARDINAL')"
"The country which now forms the circle of Swabia had been
 left desert in the age of Augustus by the emigration of its
 ancient inhabitants. (41)","('Swabia', 'GPE'), ('Augustus', 'PERSON'), ('41', 'CARDINAL')"
"The dangerous frontier of Rhaetia he so
 firmly secured that he left it without the suspicion of an
 enemy.","('Rhaetia', 'GPE')"
"The death of Aurelian,
 however, is remarkable by its extraordinary consequences.","('Aurelian', 'PERSON')"
"The decline of the Roman state, far different from its infancy, was attended with every circumstance that could banish from an interregnum the prospect of obedience and harmony: an immense and tumultuous capital, a wide extent of empire, the servile equality of despotism, an army of four hundred thousand mercenaries and
 the experience of frequent revolutions.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('four hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The deliverance
 of Gaul is reported to have cost the lives of four hundred thousand of the invaders; a work of labour to the Romans, and of expense to the emperor, who gave a piece of gold for the head of every barbarian. (39)","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('four hundred thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The discontent would have evaporated in idle
 murmurs, had not the general of the East, the heroic Probus,
 boldly declared himself the avenger of the senate.","('East', 'LOC'), ('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"The election of Carus was
 decided without expecting the approbation of the senate, and
 the new emperor contented himself with announcing, in a cold
 and stately epistle, that he had ascended the vacant throne.
 (68)","('Carus', 'PERSON')"
"The emperor
 dispersed them through all the provinces, and distributed
 this dangerous reinforcement, in small bands of fifty or
 sixty each, among the national troops; judiciously observing
 that the aid which the republic derived from the barbarians
 should be felt but not seen.","('fifty or\r\n sixty', 'CARDINAL')"
"The experience of so many princes, whom 
 he had esteemed or endured, from the vain follies of
 Elagabalus to the useful rigour of Aurelian, taught him to
 form a just estimate of the duties, the dangers, and the
 temptations of their sublime station.","('Elagabalus', 'GPE'), ('Aurelian', 'PERSON')"
"The eyes of Tacitus were scarcely closed before his brother
 Florianus showed himself unworthy to reign by the hasty
 usurpation of the purple, without expecting the approbation
 of the senate.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('Florianus', 'PERSON')"
"The feeble
 emperor was unable to subdue their obstinate prejudice, and
 the Persians wondered at the unexpected retreat of a
 victorious enemy. (79)
Vices of Carinus.","('Persians', 'NORP'), ('79', 'CARDINAL')"
"The feeble elegance of Italy and the internal
 provinces could no longer support the weight of arms.","('Italy', 'GPE')"
"The fertility of the soil soon 
 attracted a new colony from the adjacent provinces of Gaul.","('Gaul', 'LOC')"
"The flower of the legions maintained their stations on the banks of the Bosphorus, and the Imperial standard awed the less powerful camps of Rome and of the provinces.","('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The future fortunes of
 the candidate depended on the chance or conduct of the
 present hour.","('the\r\n present hour', 'TIME')"
"The generals and
 magistrates appointed by Aurelian continued to execute their
 ordinary functions; and it is observed that a proconsul of
 Asia was the only considerable person removed from his
 office in the whole course of the interregnum.","('Aurelian', 'PERSON'), ('Asia', 'LOC')"
"The gradual 
 decline of his health might have induced them to believe
 that his death was natural; but the concealment was
 interpreted as an evidence of guilt, and the measures which
 Aper had taken to secure his election became the immediate
 occasion of his ruin.","('Aper', 'PERSON')"
"The hardy veterans of his
 rival, accustomed to cold climates, sickened and consumed
 away in the sultry heats of Cilicia, where the summer proved
 remarkably unwholesome.","('Cilicia', 'GPE')"
"The hunting or exhibition of wild beasts was conducted with
 a magnificence suitable to a people who styled themselves
 the masters of the world; nor was the edifice appropriated
 to that entertainment less expensive of Roman greatness.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The imprudence of Probus is said to
 have inflamed the discontent of his troops.","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"The intelligence of the mysterious fate of the late emperor
 was soon carried from the frontiers of Persia to Rome; and
 the senate, as well as the provinces, congratulated the
 accession of the sons of Carus.","('Persia', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Carus', 'PERSON')"
"The judgment of the senate
 was confirmed by the consent of the Roman people and of the
 Praetorian guards.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Praetorian', 'NORP')"
"The legions who, from the opposite shores of the Bosphorus,
 could almost distinguish the flames of the cities and
 villages impatiently urged their general to lead them
 against the invaders.","('Bosphorus', 'LOC')"
"The military discipline which reigned in the camps of Probus
 was less cruel than that of Aurelian, but it was equally
 rigid and exact.","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Aurelian', 'PERSON')"
The ministers of the Great King trembled and retired.,"('the Great King', 'PERSON')"
"The more daring Probus pursued his Gallic
 victories, passed the Rhine, and displayed his invincible
 eagles on the banks of the Elbe and the Neckar.","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Gallic', 'NORP'), ('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Elbe', 'LOC'), ('Neckar', 'PRODUCT')"
"The most
 distinguished merit of those two officers was their
 respective prowess, of the one in the combats of Bacchus, of
 the other in those of Venus, (53) yet neither of them were 
 destitute of courage and capacity, and both sustained with
 honour the august character which the fear of punishment had
 engaged them to assume, till they sunk at length beneath the
 superior genius of Probus.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bacchus', 'PERSON'), ('Venus', 'LOC'), ('53', 'CARDINAL'), ('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"The navigation of the Nile, so important
 to Rome itself, was improved; and temples, bridges,
 porticoes, and palaces, were constructed by the hands of the
 soldiers, who acted by turns as architects, as engineers,
 and as husbandmen. (57)","('Nile', 'LOC'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The old
 emperor, animated with the fame and prospect of victory,
 pursued his march, in the midst of winter, through the
 countries of Thrace and Asia Minor, and at length, with his
 younger son Numerian, arrived on the confines of the Persian
 monarchy.","('Thrace', 'LOC'), ('Asia Minor', 'LOC'), ('Numerian', 'PERSON'), ('Persian', 'NORP')"
"The oldest of the citizens, recollecting the
 spectacles of former days, the triumphal pomp of Probus or
 Aurelian, and the secular games of the emperor Philip,
 acknowledged that they were all surpassed by the superior
 magnificence of Carinus. (84)
Spectacles of Rome.","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Aurelian', 'PERSON'), ('Philip', 'PERSON'), ('Carinus', 'PERSON'), ('84', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The only consolation of their fallen
 state was the remembrance of transient greatness, and a
 distant hope, the child of a flattering prophecy, that, at
 the end of a thousand years, a monarch of the race of
 Tacitus should arise, the protector of the senate, the
 restorer of Rome, and the conqueror of the whole earth. (22)","('the end of a thousand years', 'DATE'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('22', 'CARDINAL')"
"The only merit of the administration of Carinus that history
 could record, or poetry celebrate, was the uncommon
 splendour with which, in his own and his brother's name, he
 exhibited the Roman games of the theatre, the circus, and
 the amphitheatre.","('Carinus', 'ORG'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The palace, and even the Imperial table, was filled with
 singers, dancers, prostitutes, and all the various retinue
 of vice and folly.","('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"The peasants of Illyricum, who had already given Claudius
 and Aurelian to the sinking empire, had an equal right to
 glory in the elevation of Probus. (23)","('Illyricum', 'PERSON'), ('Claudius', 'PERSON'), ('Aurelian', 'PERSON'), ('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('23', 'CARDINAL')"
"The poet who describes the games of Carinus, in 
 the character of a shepherd attracted to the capital by the
 fame of their magnificence, affirms that the nets designed
 as a defence against the wild beasts were of gold wire; that
 the porticoes were gilded; and that the belt or circle which
 divided the several ranks of spectators from each other was
 studded with a precious mosaic of beautiful stones. (97)","('Carinus', 'WORK_OF_ART')"
"The public expected that the successor of
 Carus would pursue his father's footsteps, and, without
 allowing the Persians to recover from their consternation,
 would advance sword in hand to the palaces of Susa and
 Ecbatana. (77)","('Carus', 'PERSON'), ('Persians', 'NORP'), ('Susa', 'PERSON'), ('Ecbatana', 'PERSON'), ('77', 'CARDINAL')"
"The reciprocal offer was pressed
 and rejected at least three times, and, whilst the obstinate
 modesty of either party was resolved to receive a master
 from the hands of the other, eight months insensibly
 elapsed; an amazing period of tranquil anarchy, during which
 the Roman world remained without a sovereign, without an
 usurper, and without a sedition.","('at least three', 'CARDINAL'), ('eight months', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The reign of
 Probus corresponded with this fair beginning.","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"The reluctance of Tacitus, and it might possibly be sincere,
 was encountered by the affectionate obstinacy of the senate.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"The reverence for the Roman constitution,
 which yet influenced the camp and the provinces, was
 sufficiently strong to dispose them to censure, but not to
 provoke them to oppose, the precipitate ambition of
 Florianus.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Florianus', 'NORP')"
"The revolt of Saturninus was scarcely extinguished in the
 East before new troubles were excited in the West by the
 rebellion of Bonosus and Proculus in Gaul.","('Saturninus', 'GPE'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('Bonosus', 'PERSON'), ('Proculus', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
"The safety of Illyricum was confirmed 
 by a memorable defeat of the Sarmatians; sixteen thousand of
 those barbarians remained on the field of battle, and the
 number of captives amounted to twenty thousand.","('Illyricum', 'PRODUCT'), ('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('sixteen thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The senator Tacitus was then seventy-five 
 years of age. (6)","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('seventy-five \r\n years of age', 'DATE')"
"The slopes of the vast concave,
 which formed the inside, were filled and surrounded with
 sixty or eighty rows of seats, of marble likewise, covered
 with cushions, and capable of receiving with ease above
 fourscore thousand spectators. (93)","('sixty or eighty', 'CARDINAL'), ('thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('93', 'CARDINAL')"
"The sons of Carus never saw each other after their father's
 death.","('Carus', 'PERSON')"
"The spacious and shady forest was
 immediately filled with a thousand ostriches, a thousand
 stags, a thousand fallow-deer, and a thousand wild boars;
 and all this variety of game was abandoned to the riotous
 impetuosity of the multitude.","('a thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('a thousand', 'CARDINAL')"
"The spectacles of Carinus may therefore be best illustrated
 by the observation of some particulars which history has
 condescended to relate concerning those of his predecessors.","('Carinus', 'ORG')"
"The speech of Falconius was
 enforced by a general acclamation.","('Falconius', 'PERSON')"
"The strength of Aurelian had crushed on every side the
 enemies of Rome.","('Aurelian', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The strength of the
 legions was, indeed, a pledge of their sincerity, since
 those who may command are seldom reduced to the necessity of
 dissembling; but could it naturally be expected that a hasty
 repentance would correct the inveterate habits of four-score
 years?","('four-score\r\n years', 'DATE')"
"The successor of Artaxerxes, Varanes, or Bahram, though he
 had subdued the Segestans, one of the most warlike nations
 of Upper Asia,(72) was alarmed at the approach of the Romans, 
 and endeavoured to retard their progress by a negotiation of
 peace.","('Artaxerxes', 'ORG'), ('Varanes', 'PERSON'), ('Bahram', 'PERSON'), ('Segestans', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Upper Asia', 'LOC'), ('72', 'CARDINAL'), ('Romans', 'NORP')"
"The third, and
 afterwards the tenth, legion were intrusted to the command
 of Probus, who, in every step of his promotion, showed
 himself superior to the station which he filled.","('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('tenth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Probus', 'PERSON')"
The threats of Carus were not without effect.,"('Carus', 'PERSON')"
"The throne was vacant during twelve months till the election of a Sabine philosopher, and the public peace was guarded in the same manner by the union of the several orders of the state.","('twelve months', 'DATE'), ('Sabine', 'NORP')"
"The tower 
 was instantly forced, and a thousand swords were plunged at
 once into the bosom of the unfortunate Probus.","('a thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"The tragedy of the succeeding
 day consisted in the massacre of an hundred lions, an equal
 number of lionesses, two hundred leopards, and three hundred
 bears. (86)","('the succeeding\r\n day', 'DATE'), ('an hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('two hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('three hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"The tribune soon
 justified his choice by a victory over a great body of
 Sarmatians, in which he saved the life of a near relation of
 Valerian; and deserved to receive from the emperor's hand
 the collars, bracelets, spears, and banners, the mural and
 the civic crown, and all the honourable rewards reserved by
 ancient Rome for successful valour.","('Sarmatians', 'NORP'), ('Valerian', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"The triumph due to the valour of Probus was
 conducted with a magnificence suitable to his fortune; and
 the people, who had so lately admired the trophies of
 Aurelian, gazed with equal pleasure on those of his heroic
 successor. (55)","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Aurelian', 'PERSON')"
"The troops, so lately 
 returned from the Persian war, had acquired their glory at
 the expense of health and numbers, nor were they in a
 condition to contend with the unexhausted strength of the
 legions of Europe.","('the Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('Europe', 'LOC')"
"The troops, terrified with
 the fate of Carus and with their own danger, called aloud on
 young Numerian to obey the will of the gods, and to lead
 them away from this inauspicious scene of war.","('Carus', 'PERSON'), ('Numerian', 'NORP')"
"The troubles
 excited by the usurper Firmus in the Upper Egypt had never
 been perfectly appeased, and the cities of Ptolemais and
 Coptos, fortified by the alliance of the Blemmyes still
 maintained an obscure rebellion.","('Firmus', 'PRODUCT'), ('the Upper Egypt', 'LOC'), ('Ptolemais', 'GPE'), ('Coptos', 'GPE'), ('Blemmyes', 'PERSON')"
"The ungrateful rumour reached his ears,
 and induced him to seek the retirement of one of his villas
 in Campania.","('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Campania', 'GPE')"
"The unoffending strength with which Nature
 has endowed the greater quadrupeds was admired in the
 rhinoceros, the hippopotamus of the Nile,(88) and a majestic 
 troop of twenty-two elephants. (89)","('Nature', 'ORG'), ('Nile', 'LOC'), ('88', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty-two', 'CARDINAL'), ('89', 'CARDINAL')"
"The useful spectacle served to impress the Roman soldier
 with a just contempt for those unwieldy animals; and he no
 longer dreaded to encounter them in the ranks of war.","('Roman', 'NORP')"
"The voice of 
 congratulation and flattery was not however silent; and we
 may still peruse, with pleasure and contempt, an eclogue
 which was composed on the accession of the emperor Carus.","('Carus', 'PERSON')"
"The voice of 
 the people had already named Tacitus as the citizen the most
 worthy of empire.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"The wisdom of Probus embraced a
 great and beneficial plan of replenishing the exhausted
 frontiers by new colonies of captive or fugitive barbarians,
 on whom he bestowed lands, cattles instruments of husbandry,
 and every encouragement that might engage them to educate a
 race of soldiers for the service of the republic.","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"Their faithful general asserted the honour of the Roman
 arms, and often laid at their feet crowns of gold and
 barbaric trophies, the fruits of his numerous victories. (28)","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('28', 'CARDINAL')"
"Their numbers were diminished by
 frequent desertion, the passes of the mountains were feebly
 defended; Tarsus opened its gates; and the soldiers of
 Florianus, when they had permitted him to enjoy the Imperial
 title about three months, delivered the empire from civil
 war by the easy sacrifice of a prince whom they despised. (20)","('Tarsus', 'GPE'), ('Florianus', 'NORP'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('about three months', 'DATE'), ('20', 'CARDINAL')"
"Their ranks were broken, and, for a
 moment, Diocletian despaired of the purple and of life.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"Then, assuming the tone of a sovereign and a judge, he commanded that Aper; should be brought in chains to the foot of the tribunal.","('Aper', 'ORG')"
"There occurs, however, a single instance in
 the first Punic war in which the senate wisely connected
 this amusement of the multitude with the interest of the
 state.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Punic war', 'EVENT')"
"These  lofty expectations were, however, soon disappointed; nor, indeed, was it possible that the armies and the provinces should long obey the luxurious and unwarlike nobles of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"These pressing though
 tumultuary instances were seconded by a more regular oration
 of Metius Falconius, the next on the consular bench to
 Tacitus himself.","('Metius Falconius', 'PERSON'), ('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"They
 then lamented their fatal rashness, forgot the severity of
 the emperor whom they had massacred, and hastened to
 perpetuate, by an honourable monument, the memory of his
 virtues and victories. (63)
Election and character of Carus.","('Carus', 'PERSON')"
"They easily escaped through the Bosphorus and the
 Hellespont, and, cruising along the Mediterranean, indulged
 their appetite for revenge and plunder by frequent descents
 on the unsuspecting shores of Asia, Greece, and Africa.","('Bosphorus', 'LOC'), ('Hellespont', 'PRODUCT'), ('Mediterranean', 'LOC'), ('Asia', 'LOC'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Africa', 'LOC')"
"They had been established by Probus on
 the seacoast of Pontus, with a view of strengthening the
 frontier against the inroads of the Alani.","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Pontus', 'PERSON'), ('Alani', 'PERSON')"
"They had wandered in quest of booty from the
 banks of the Oder to those of the Seine.","('Oder', 'LOC'), ('Seine', 'LOC')"
"They soon announced to the multitude that their
 choice had fallen on Diocletian, commander of the domestics
 or bodyguards, as the person the most capable of revenging
 and succeeding their beloved emperor.","('Diocletian', 'PERSON')"
"They were again
 vanquished by the active vigour of Probus, who, in a short
 reign of about six years, (29) equalled the fame of ancient 
 heroes, and restored peace and order to every province of
 the Roman world.","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('about six years', 'DATE'), ('29', 'DATE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"They were faithful to
 their engagements; but when they arrived on the Roman
 frontier Aurelian was already dead, the design of the
 Persian war was at least suspended, and the generals who,
 during the interregnum, exercised a doubtful authority, were
 unprepared either to receive or to oppose them.","('Roman', 'NORP'), ('Aurelian', 'PERSON'), ('the\r\n Persian war', 'EVENT')"
"They were twelve in number, who, in successive pairs, each during the space of two months, filled the year, and represented the dignity of that ancient office.","('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('the space of two months', 'DATE'), ('the year', 'DATE')"
"This important barrier, uniting the two 
 mighty streams that protected the provinces of Europe,
 seemed to fill up the vacant space through which the
 barbarians, and particularly the Alemanni, could penetrate
 with the greatest facility into the heart of the empire.","('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Alemanni', 'NORP')"
"Those barbarians, allured
 by presents and subsidies, had promised to invade Persia
 with a numerous body of light cavalry.","('Persia', 'GPE')"
"Though a 
 soldier, he had received a learned education; though a
 senator, he was invested with the first dignity of the army;
 and in an age when the civil and military professions began
 to be irrecoverably separated from each other, they were
 united in the person of Carus.","('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Carus', 'PERSON')"
"Though it was every
 moment in their power to repeal the disgraceful edict of
 Gallienus, the proud successors of the Scipios patiently
 acquiesced in their exclusion from all military employments.","('Gallienus', 'PERSON'), ('Scipios', 'PERSON')"
"To accomplish these salutary ends,
 the constant residence of an Imperial governor, supported by
 a numerous army, was indispensably requisite.","('Imperial', 'NORP')"
"To determine the list, or, as it was then styled, the College of Consuls.","('the College of Consuls', 'ORG')"
"To invest one of their body, under the title  of emperor, with the general command of the armies and the government of the frontier provinces.","('one', 'CARDINAL')"
"To protect these new subjects, a line of frontier 
 garrisons was gradually extended from the Rhine to the
 Danube.","('Rhine', 'LOC'), ('Danube', 'LOC')"
"To sustain with temper
 this rapid elevation, an uncommon share of virtue and
 prudence was requisite; and Carinus, the elder of the
 brothers, was more than commonly deficient in those
 qualities.","('Carinus', 'PERSON')"
"To these several branches of authority we may add some inspection over the finances, since, even in the stern reign of Aurelian, it was in their power to divert a part of the revenue from the
 public service.","('Aurelian', 'GPE')"
"Transported in the depth of winter from the soft retirement
 of Campania to the foot of Mount Caucasus, he sunk under the
 unaccustomed hardships of a military life.","('Campania', 'GPE'), ('Mount Caucasus', 'LOC')"
"Treves, Milan, Aquileia,
 Thessalonica, Corinth, Athens, Antioch, Alexandria, and
 Carthageto claim their obedience, and to inform them of
 the happy revolution which had restored the Roman senate to
 its ancient dignity.","('Treves', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Aquileia', 'GPE'), ('Thessalonica', 'GPE'), ('Corinth', 'GPE'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Antioch', 'GPE'), ('Alexandria', 'GPE'), ('Carthage', 'GPE'), ('Roman', 'NORP')"
"Twenty zebras displayed their
 elegant forms and variegated beauty to the eyes of the Roman
 people. (87)","('Twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('Roman', 'NORP'), ('87', 'CARDINAL')"
Two of these epistles are still extant.,"('Two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Two shepherds, avoiding the noontide heat, retire into the
 cave of Faunus.","('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Faunus', 'PERSON')"
Usurpation and death of his brother Florianus,"('Florianus', 'PERSON')"
"We cannot on this occasion forget the 
 desperate courage of about fourscore gladiators, reserved,
 with near six hundred others, for the inhuman sports of the
 amphitheatre.","('near six hundred', 'CARDINAL')"
"We likewise possess two very singular fragments of the
 private correspondence of the senators on this occasion.","('two', 'CARDINAL')"
"Whatever flattering expectations he had conceived of
 reconciling the public disorders, Tacitus soon was convinced
 that the licentiousness of the army disdained the feeble
 restraint of laws, and his last hour was hastened by anguish
 and disappointment.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON')"
"When Carus 
 assumed the purple he was about sixty years of age, and his
 two sons, Carinus and Numerian, had already attained the
 season of manhood. (67)","('Carus', 'PERSON'), ('about sixty years of age', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Carinus', 'PERSON'), ('Numerian', 'PERSON'), ('season', 'DATE')"
"When Probus ascended the Imperial throne he was
 about forty-four years of age ;(24) in the full possession of 
 his fame, of the love of the army, and of a mature vigour of
 mind and body.","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG'), ('about forty-four years of age', 'DATE'), ('24', 'DATE')"
"When Probus commanded in Egypt, he executed
 many considerable works for the splendour and benefit of
 that rich country.","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Egypt', 'GPE')"
"When Tacitus was elected by the senate he
 resigned his ample patrimony to the public service,(21) an 
 act of generosity specious in appearance, but which
 evidently disclosed his intention of transmitting the empire
 to his descendants.","('Tacitus', 'PERSON'), ('21', 'CARDINAL')"
"When the emperor Carus undertook the Persian war, he was
 induced, by motives of affection as well as policy, to
 secure the fortunes of his family by leaving in the hands of
 his eldest son the armies and provinces of the West.","('Carus', 'PERSON'), ('the Persian war', 'EVENT'), ('West', 'LOC')"
"When the emperor marched to the relief of
 Gaul, he devolved the command of the East on Saturninus.","('Gaul', 'PERSON'), ('the East on Saturninus', 'LOC')"
"When the legions had indulged their grief and repentance for
 the death of Probus, their unanimous consent declared Carus,
 his Praetorian praefect, the most deserving of the Imperial
 throne.","('Probus', 'PERSON'), ('Carus', 'PERSON'), ('Praetorian', 'PERSON'), ('Imperial', 'ORG')"
"When this respectful epistle was read by the consul, the
 senators were unable to disguise their satisfaction that
 Probus should condescend thus humbly to solicit a sceptre
 which he already possessed.","('Probus', 'PERSON')"
"While the populace gazed 
 with stupid wonder on the splendid show, the naturalist
 might indeed observe the figure and properties of so many
 different species, transported from every part of the
 ancient world into the amphitheatre of Rome.","('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Whilst the deceased emperor was making preparations for a
 second expedition into the East, he had negotiated with the
 Alani, a Scythian people, who pitched their tents in the
 neighbourhood of the lake Maetis.","('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('Alani', 'PERSON'), ('Scythian', 'NORP'), ('Maetis', 'LOC')"
"With
 rude curiosity they broke into the imperial tent, and
 discovered only the corpse of Numerian. (105)","('Numerian', 'PERSON'), ('105', 'CARDINAL')"
"With the
 senators Carinus affected a lofty and regal demeanour,
 frequently declaring that he designed to distribute their
 estates among the populace of Rome.","('Carinus', 'PERSON'), ('Rome', 'GPE')"
"Within a few years after his death it
 was overthrown by the Alemanni.","('a few years', 'DATE'), ('Alemanni', 'PERSON')"
"Yet the arms and  discipline of the Romans easily discomfited these horrid
 phantoms.","('Romans', 'NORP')"
"Yet, even in the transport of their
 rage and grief, the troops observed a regular proceeding,
 which proves how firmly discipline had been re-established
 by the martial successors of Gallienus.","('Gallienus', 'ORG')"
"Yet, notwithstanding all these temptations, the discipline and memory of Aurelian still restrained the seditious temper of the troops, as well as the fatal ambition of their leaders.","('Aurelian', 'PERSON')"
and carries his arms into Germany.,"('Germany', 'GPE')"
revolt of Bonosus and Proculus in Gaul.,"('Bonosus', 'PERSON'), ('Gaul', 'PERSON')"
